<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Interviews</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/interviews/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#47 I Know Where You Took That Photo Last Summer</title>
		<link>/2013/08/47-i-know-where-you-took-that-photo-last-summer/</link>
		<comments>/2013/08/47-i-know-where-you-took-that-photo-last-summer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Debunkable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Downloadable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Duval County School Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Khalil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SAInT Academy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sandalwood High School]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7914</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/08/IKnowWhereYouTookThatPhotoLastSummer-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="I Know Where You Took That Photo Last Summer, the blockbuster thriller staring Jennifer Love Hewitt, Sarah Michelle Gellar, Ray Hollister and Tom Braun." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />On this episode we were joined in the studio by Mike Khalil, the Lead Coordinator at Sandalwood High School&#8217;s SAInT Academy. We also have a great Debunkable segment and we finally have a name for the app segment! Don&#8217;t forget, <a href="/2013/08/47-i-know-where-you-took-that-photo-last-summer/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/08/47-i-know-where-you-took-that-photo-last-summer/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/08/IKnowWhereYouTookThatPhotoLastSummer-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="I Know Where You Took That Photo Last Summer, the blockbuster thriller staring Jennifer Love Hewitt, Sarah Michelle Gellar, Ray Hollister and Tom Braun." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_7922" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/08/IKnowWhereYouTookThatPhotoLastSummer.png" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-7922" alt="I Know Where You Took That Photo Last Summer, the blockbuster thriller staring Jennifer Love Hewitt, Sarah Michelle Gellar, Ray Hollister and Tom Braun." src="/media/2013/08/IKnowWhereYouTookThatPhotoLastSummer-300x300.png"  width="300" height="300"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I Know Where You Took That Photo Last Summer, the 2013 blockbuster thriller starring Jennifer Love Hewitt, Sarah Michelle Gellar, Ray Hollister and Tom Braun.</p></div>
<p>On this episode we were joined in the studio by Mike Khalil, the Lead Coordinator at Sandalwood High School&rsquo;s SAInT Academy. We also have a great Debunkable segment and we finally have a name for the app segment!</p>
<p dir="ltr">Don&rsquo;t forget, we&rsquo;re almost at the end of the $50 Amazon Gift Card giveaway! If Deemable Tech gets at least 500 subscribers on iTunes and at least 200 subscribers on YouTube by the end of August, we are going to give away an Amazon Gift Card worth $50!</p>
<p>To be eligible to win the $50 Amazon Gift Card, you need to subscribe to us on&nbsp;<a href="http://youtube.com/DeemableTech">YouTube</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/deemable-tech/id540595466" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iTunes</a>, like us on&nbsp;<a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable">Facebook</a>&nbsp;and follow us on&nbsp;<a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable">Twitter</a>. Then, send us an email at&nbsp;giftcard@deemable.com.&nbsp;In that email, include your Facebook name, Twitter and YouTube username. We&rsquo;ll pick one eligible email at random and we&rsquo;ll announce it on the show.&nbsp;The links to all of our social network profiles are in the top right corner of the website under the heading, Follow Deemable Tech.</p>
<p>Also, the Deemable Tech app is now available for&nbsp;<a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/deemable-tech/id671758316" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iPhone, iPod touch and iPad in the App Store</a>&nbsp;and for&nbsp;<a>Android phones and tablets in the Google Play store</a>. You can find a link to the app simply by visiting&nbsp;<a href="http://deemable.com/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/Deemable.com">Deemable.com</a>&nbsp;on your mobile device.</p>
<p>One last thing! Don&rsquo;t forget to vote for Ray and Tom in Folio Weekly&rsquo;s Best of Jax for Hottest Local Celebrity. Go to&nbsp;<a title="Folio Weekly Best of Jax" href="http://folioweekly.com/bestofjax" target="_blank">http://folioweekly.com/bestofjax</a>&nbsp;to enter your vote!</p>
<span class="embed-youtube" style="text-align:center; display: block;"><iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="752" height="453" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5AaQAZz5krQ?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
<p><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-7914-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-18.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-18.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-18.mp3</a></audio><br><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-18.mp3">#47 I Know Where You Took That Photo Last Summer</a></p>
<h4>ROUGH TRANSCRIPT</h4>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: I&rsquo;m Tom Braun,</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: and this is Deemable Tech, tech help worth listening to.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: This week&rsquo;s episode of the Deemable Tech podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: And, by audible.com. Hey did you know, you, just because you are listening to Deemable Tech, you can get a FREE audiobook download at <a href="http://www.audibletrial.com/Deemable">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a></p>
<p dir="ltr">Over 100,000 titles to choose from for your iPhone, Android, Kindle or mp3 player like&hellip;</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: The Hobbit, which of course was released as a major motion picture last year. In this fantasy classic, master storyteller J.R.R. Tolkien creates a bewitching world filled with delightful creatures and thrilling dangers. Narrator Rob Inglis will hold listeners of all ages spellbound with his skillful portrayal of hobbits, dwarves, and enchanted beasts.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Or if you&rsquo;re not into little people with hairy toes going on adventures, you can download any other audiobook you want for free. Just go to <a href="http://www.audibletrial.com/Deemable">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a> to download your free audiobook.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? Give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at <a href="mailto:questions@deemable.com">questions@deemable.com</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: So, we are coming towards the end of our contest to win a $50 Amazon Gift Card. To be eligible, Subscribe to us on YouTube and iTunes. Then, like us on Facebook, and follow us on Twitter. Then, send us an email to <a href="mailto:giftcard@deemable.com">giftcard@deemable.com</a>. In that email, tell us your Facebook, Twitter and YouTube username. &nbsp;We&rsquo;ll pick one eligible email at random and we&rsquo;ll announce it here on the show.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: To make it easy for you, we have a picture of a big $50 Amazon Card and the instructions on the top right of our website at Deemable.com.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So, go subscribe, like and follow us, and get your emails in so you can win that $50 gift card.</p>
<p>RAY: And this is the last week to vote for us, Ray and Tom for Hottest Local Celebrity in Folio Weekly&rsquo;s 2013 Best of Jax contest. Make sure to vote for us at folioweekly.com/bestofjax And yes, we are trying to win Hottest Local Celebrity. Don&rsquo;t laugh! We&rsquo;re really trying to win. Go to folioweekly.com/bestofjax and vote for Ray and Tom!</p>
<p dir="ltr">All right, well before we jump into your questions, we have a guest in the studio, Mike Khalil.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Mike Khalil is the SAInT Academy Coordinator at Sandalwood High School here in Jacksonville, Florida. Welcome to the show Mike.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Tell us first, what does SAInT in SAInT Academy stand for? Looking at your logo it looks like most of the letters in SAInT are in all caps?</p>
<p dir="ltr">What is an information technology academy?</p>
<p dir="ltr">And, what is it that you teach in the Academy?</p>
<p dir="ltr">How did the program begin?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Are the kids able to do hands-on work?</p>
<p dir="ltr">What are some of the benefits for students?</p>
<p dir="ltr">How do people and businesses in the community get involved?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Do students get college credit for the courses?</p>
<p dir="ltr">How do students get into the SAInT Academy? Is it a Magnet program?</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://xkcd.com/627/">XKCD How to be a computer expert flowchart</a></p>
<p dir="ltr">&mdash;&mdash;</p>
<p dir="ltr">SAINT Academy is a program that allows students to fully experience high school while gaining skills in business and information technology. They earn a regular diploma, attend a regular neighborhood school, and attend regular classes. They take one or two computer-based electives per year, and get opportunities to compete against other students and meet important people in the community who can help them attain their college and career goals.</p>
<p dir="ltr">We recruit 8th graders while they are in middle school, and they begin the program in 9th grade, they stay in the program all throughout high school. It&rsquo;s not just an elective, but a career-themed academy where we help students prepare for college and the workforce &mdash; writing resumes, interview skills, things like that, but since it&rsquo;s IT it&rsquo;s a little but different from most vocational academies. We&rsquo;re fully aware that most IT workers go to college; it&rsquo;s very hard to get a job in the field without a college degree, so we&rsquo;re very focused on Academics as well as vocational study, and most our students in fact are in honors or AP classes.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&mdash;&mdash;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Alright, thanks for coming in Mike. Before we let you go, where can people find out more information about the SAInT Academy?</p>
<p dir="ltr">SAINT web site: <a href="http://sandalwoodhigh.org/">http://sandalwoodhigh.org/</a></p>
<p dir="ltr">Thanks again.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&mdash;&mdash;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Alright, well, we have to take a quick break, but when we come back we have answers to your tech questions, a Debunkable segment, and we finally have a name for the App segment.&nbsp;You&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So we have a question that we answered a long time ago, but I&rsquo;m not sure if we ever told the listener the answer! They sent us another email about it, and I couldn&rsquo;t find the question in our previous show notes, so let&rsquo;s answer it again.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Maliery writes: I was recently given the opportunity of updating my system. Ever since, whenever I send text messages, post on Facebook, or even write on the S note, my text all of a sudden gets erased. It&rsquo;s similar to a CTRL+a action, but I do not perform this step. Also, my google keyboard fails after of number of selections of the predictive messages. I think if I select 5/6 words, it will stop working. None of things ever happened when I was using the prior Jelly Bean update.&nbsp;Galaxy S III</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: First of all, I have a question for you:</p>
<p dir="ltr">* Jen from ?The IT Crowd&rsquo;: Have you tried turning it off and on. *</p>
<p dir="ltr">Yeah, the number one thing I would try is to reset your phone. Just hold down the power button while the phone is on. When the device options pop-up appears select reset and let the phone do its thing.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Hopefully that will clear it up. If you are using a keyboard other than the default keyboard, you can go to that application under Settings &gt; Application Manager and then clear the cache. That will delete all the data stored for the keyboard and if there&rsquo;s corrupt data it will get rid of it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">If none of these solutions work, I would try using a different keyboard app. Android phones allow you to change what keyboard app you use. There are a couple preinstalled on your Samsung Galaxy S3. From the home screen hit the menu button, select settings, and then find ?Language and input&rsquo;. You can change what keyboards are enabled and select a default from this menu.</p>
<p dir="ltr">You can download alternate keyboards. A couple popular keyboard apps are the SwiftKey and the Google Keyboard. I highly recommend the SwiftKey app. It costs about two bucks but its amazing. I highly recommend it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">There is also Swype, but for some reason you have to sideload that app, typically by downloading it to a laptop, connecting your phone, and installing. But I find that SwiftKey does everything Swype does and more.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: So, to sum up &ndash; reboot the phone. If that doesn&rsquo;t work, clear the cache for your keyboard app under the Application Manager. If you are still having problems, try a different keyboard.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Those are my suggestions. I&rsquo;ll be honest, Maliery&rsquo;s problem is kind of a weird one. If none of those work it might be an issue with the phone itself. You may need to be prepared to take it back to the store. But before you get to the nuclear options, you should definitely try these ideas.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So, we&rsquo;ve been seeing this alot on Facebook and we had to investigate it.</p>
<h3 dir="ltr">DEBUNKABLE</h3>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://kyeos.wordpress.com/2013/05/10/warning-if-you-take-photos-with-your-cell-phone/">http://kyeos.wordpress.com/2013/05/10/warning-if-you-take-photos-with-your-cell-phone/</a></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 30px;">?Warning? If you, your kids or grand kids take pics from your phone?WATCH THIS!</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 30px;">This is truly alarming ? please take the time to watch. At the end they&rsquo;ll tell you how to set your phone so you don&rsquo;t run this risk!</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 30px;">PLEASE PASS THIS INFO TO ANYONE YOU KNOW WHO TAKES PICTURES WITH THEIR CELL OR SMART PHONE AND POSTS THEM ONLINE.</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 30px;">I want everyone of you to watch this and then be sure to share with all your family and friends.</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 30px;">It&rsquo;s REALLY important info, about what your posting things on your cell phones can do TO YOU!!!</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 30px;">Too much technology out there these days so beware???..</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 30px;">PLEASE TAKE THE TIME TO WATCH THIS VIDEO, AND TAKE THE RECOMMENDED PRECAUTIONS.</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 30px;">If you have children or grandchildren you NEED to watch this. I had no idea this could happen from taking pictures on the blackberry or cell phone. It&rsquo;s scary.&rdquo;</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 30px;">Any time something is that important that we HAVE to watch it now, well we have to watch it now. Here&rsquo;s a clip from the video:</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left: 30px;">Play Audio from Video</p>
<p dir="ltr">&hellip;home, work, or even school of the person in the pic.</p>
<p dir="ltr">OK, let&rsquo;s pause it right there. First of all, this isn&rsquo;t new technology. This has been around for quite a few years. At least as far back as when the first iPhone came out. The video itself is from 2010. Second of all, no, they cannot find the home, work or even school of the person in the pic.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Classic news fear mongering&nbsp;Legitimate concern, blown way out of proportion</p>
<p dir="ltr">If you have geo-tagging turned on the location where you took the picture is stored in the picture. Geo-tagging is not the scariest thing in the world, Geo-tagging can be great. Have you ever pulled out a picture from a shoe box and wondered, now where was that taken? With geo-tagging, you don&rsquo;t have to wonder. It tells you where it was taken. So, with some apps, you can use your photos like a map on a road trip.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So, yes, if you take pictures in your bedroom, park, school, work, then yes, someone who knows how to take GPS coordinates and convert them into locations on a map will be able to figure out where that picture was taken. Not many people know how to do that. Fortunately, most stalkers and creeps don&rsquo;t know how to do that.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But, then the good folks at 41 Action News make sure that the creeps know how to do it</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N2vARzvWxwY&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=2m00s">2:00</a></p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://icanstalku.com/">icanstalku.com</a> is a great site with good information on how to disable geo-tagging services on your smart phone.</p>
<p dir="ltr">If you do want to disable location services on your photos, here&rsquo;s how you do it on your iPhone. and on your Android&hellip;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Android</p>
<p dir="ltr">All you need to do is fire up your camera app, and then go to settings. Depending on what phone you have, you may need to tap a gear icon, slide the settings out from the edge of your phone, or hit the settings button on your phone. Regardless, you should see an ?Store GPS&rsquo; or ?Store location&rsquo; setting. Turn it off.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The reality is, it&rsquo;s a lot easier for a kidnapper, or worse, to just grab a kid. I haven&rsquo;t heard of any cases where this has been done. Usually, the attacker is known to the child or it&rsquo;s just a random act. So, while it&rsquo;s smart to be aware of what information you are inadvertently posting about your child that could possibly be used to harm him or her, it isn&rsquo;t something that should invoke terror in your heart. This isn&rsquo;t really that dangerous.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>My son recently gave his mother an iPad 4 as a birthday gift he bought earlier this year because he wanted an iPad mini instead</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">What&rsquo;s the best way to delete all his data and accounts on the iPad 4 without him losing all his saved email, contacts, iTunes, Apps etc.? Both Ipads are still registered under his accounts.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Settings &gt; General &gt; Reset &gt; Erase All Content and Settings</p>
<p>&nbsp;Make sure to backup and sync the iPad 4 before you do that because if you forgot to get anything off of it, you&rsquo;re not getting it after you do that!</p>
<h1 dir="ltr">Downloadable</h1>
<h3 dir="ltr">COUCH TO 5K (from Active.net)</h3>
<ul><li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Available on iPhone and Android</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Sets achievable goals and schedule</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">App tells you when to walk and when to run, for increasingly lengths each session.</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">App plays random songs from a playlist of your choosing.</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Customizable voices.</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Tracks your route on a map, logs each session.</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Suggests 5K that you can enter once you have completed you training.</p>
</li>
</ul><h3 dir="ltr">RYMDKAPSEL</h3>
<ul><li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Game for iOS or Android.</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Swedish for ?space capsule&rsquo;.</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">It&rsquo;s a strategy game. You allocate tiny rectangular minions to resource management while you try and construct a space station out of Tetris-like blocks.</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">You are attempting to reach and research four mysterious monoliths, as well as fend off successive waves of laser blasting aliens.</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">$3.99, no free-to-play gimmickry. 3-5 hours of super addictive gameplay.</p>
</li>
</ul><h4><a href="http://www.wififofum.net/"><span style="font-size: 1em;">WiFiFoFum</span></a></h4>
<h4 dir="ltr"><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/dream-talk-recorder/id445472628?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Dream Talk Recorder</a></h4>
<p>We&rsquo;ve got a voicemail from a listener. Let&rsquo;s play that.<br>
[Play voicemail]<br>
TOM: Okay, Ray, two phone lines on one iPhone. Can she do it?<br>
RAY: No. At least, not without major modifications to her phone at a hardware level. She would need a second sim card in her phone, and the iPhone 4 doesn&rsquo;t support dual sim cards.<br>
TOM: You might possibly be able to find some overseas company that does modifications like that&hellip;<br>
RAY: But that&rsquo;s probably not a good idea. I just think this is the wrong way to approach her problem.<br>
TOM: I agree. Basically she wants to have a way to filter out certain phone calls. The most obvious solution I can think of is: buy a second phone. It doesn&rsquo;t have to be an iPhone. Just go out and get yourself a $20 pre-paid feature phone. You can give people that number and just check it every so often.<br>
RAY: Yeah, that was my thought too.<br>
TOM: Alternatively, there she could block the calls.<br>
RAY: Yep. unfortunately there&rsquo;s no built in way to block a call. You can do it through your carrier or you can jailbreak it to automatically ignore calls from certain callers.<br>
There is a way to have two phone numbers that go to one phone though through Google Voice.<br>
Magic Jack<br>
WiFi connection</p>
<p dir="ltr">Thanks for all your questions, and keep them coming. Call us at our toll-free number, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com. Also, subscribe to the show! Search for Deemable Tech on iTunes or point your favorite podcast app to dmbl.co/pod.</p>
<p>Our producer is Sean Birch. Thanks to Robert Snyder for Video Production Assistance. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, and this is Deemable Tech. Thanks for listening. Have a great week.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#47 I Know Where You Took That Photo Last Summer" data-link="/2013/08/47-i-know-where-you-took-that-photo-last-summer/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#47 I Know Where You Took That Photo Last Summer" data-link="/2013/08/47-i-know-where-you-took-that-photo-last-summer/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/08/47-i-know-where-you-took-that-photo-last-summer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-18.mp3" length="60416000" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#46 Ray and Tom Discover Shakespeare</title>
		<link>/2013/08/46-ray-and-tom-discover-shakespeare/</link>
		<comments>/2013/08/46-ray-and-tom-discover-shakespeare/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 03:51:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Daveline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discovering Shakespeare]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7859</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/08/ShakespeareHipster-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Is Shakespeare a Hipster? He invented irony." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />On this episode of Deemable Tech, Ray and Tom talk to Adam Daveline, the founder of DiscoveringShakespeare.com, a Kickstarter project to build a database of&#160;fully produced monologues, scenes, and masterclasses of Shakespeare&#8217;s work available to anyone on the Internet. Then, <a href="/2013/08/46-ray-and-tom-discover-shakespeare/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/08/46-ray-and-tom-discover-shakespeare/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/08/ShakespeareHipster-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Is Shakespeare a Hipster? He invented irony." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p dir="ltr"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/08/Shakespeare.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-7862" alt="Shakespeare Invents Words" src="/media/2013/08/Shakespeare-221x300.jpg"  width="221" height="300"></a>On this episode of Deemable Tech, Ray and Tom talk to Adam Daveline, the founder of <a href="http://DiscoveringShakespeare.com/">DiscoveringShakespeare.com</a>, a Kickstarter project to build a database of&nbsp;fully produced monologues, scenes, and masterclasses of Shakespeare&rsquo;s work available to anyone on the Internet.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Then, after the break, Ray and Tom help Ric find a phone to use in Costa Rica, help Maliery decide if she should buy from Purchasing Power, and help Zoe get new games for her Kindle Fire.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Don&rsquo;t forget, we&rsquo;re still in the middle of the $50 Amazon Gift Card giveaway! If Deemable Tech gets at least 500 subscribers on iTunes and at least 200 subscribers on YouTube by the end of August, we are going to give away an Amazon Gift Card worth $50!</p>
<p>To be eligible to win the $50 Amazon Gift Card, you need to subscribe to us on&nbsp;<a href="http://youtube.com/DeemableTech">YouTube</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/deemable-tech/id540595466" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iTunes</a>, like us on&nbsp;<a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable">Facebook</a>&nbsp;and follow us on&nbsp;<a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable">Twitter</a>. Then, send us an email at&nbsp;giftcard@deemable.com.&nbsp;In that email, include your Facebook name, Twitter and YouTube username. We&rsquo;ll pick one eligible email at random and we&rsquo;ll announce it on the show.&nbsp;The links to all of our social network profiles are in the top right corner of the website under the heading, Follow Deemable Tech.</p>
<p>Also, the Deemable Tech app is now available for&nbsp;<a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/deemable-tech/id671758316" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iPhone, iPod touch and iPad in the App Store</a>&nbsp;and for&nbsp;<a>Android phones and tablets in the Google Play store</a>. You can find a link to the app simply by visiting&nbsp;<a href="http://deemable.com/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/Deemable.com">Deemable.com</a>&nbsp;on your mobile device.</p>
<p>One last thing! Don&rsquo;t forget to vote for Ray and Tom in Folio Weekly&rsquo;s Best of Jax for Hottest Local Celebrity. Go to&nbsp;<a title="Folio Weekly Best of Jax" href="http://folioweekly.com/bestofjax" target="_blank">http://folioweekly.com/bestofjax</a>&nbsp;to enter your vote!</p>
<span class="embed-youtube" style="text-align:center; display: block;"><iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="752" height="453" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9OdEof1fOYY?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
<p><audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-7859-2" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-11.mp3?_=2"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-11.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-11.mp3</a></audio><br><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-11.mp3">#46 Ray and Tom Discover Shakespeare</a></p>
<p dir="ltr">DRAFT TRANSCRIPT</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: I&rsquo;m Tom Braun,</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: and this is Deemable Tech, tech help worth listening to.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: This week&rsquo;s episode of the Deemable Tech podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: And, by audible.com. Hey did you know, you, just because you are listening to Deemable Tech, you can get a FREE audiobook download at <a href="http://www.audibletrial.com/Deemable">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a></p>
<p dir="ltr">Over 100,000 titles to choose from for your iPhone, Android, Kindle or mp3 player like&hellip;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Ender&rsquo;s Game, the Sci-Fi classic by Orson Scott Card that is coming out as to theaters in November starring Harrison Ford. If you&rsquo;re like Tom and you like to reread the book right before the movie comes out so you can gripe about the movie, check out Ender&rsquo;s Game on Audible. The Special 20th Anniversary Edition of the Hugo and Nebula Award-winning classic is now digitally remastered with a full cast production. It also contains an exclusive bonus: an original postscript written and recorded by the author himself, Orson Scott Card!</p>
<p dir="ltr">Or if you&rsquo;re like me, and you don&rsquo;t like to ruin the movie, you can download any other book you want for free. Just go to <a href="http://www.audibletrial.com/Deemable">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a> to download your free audiobook.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? Give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at <a href="mailto:questions@deemable.com">questions@deemable.com</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: So, as you probably already know know that we are in the middle of a contest. If we reach 200 subscribers on YouTube and 500 subscribers on iTunes by the end of August we are going to give away a $50 Amazon Gift Card. To be eligible, Subscribe to us on YouTube and iTunes. Then, like us on Facebook, and follow us on Twitter. Then, send us an email to <a href="mailto:giftcard@deemable.com">giftcard@deemable.com</a>. In that email, tell us your Facebook name, Twitter and YouTube username. &nbsp;We&rsquo;ll pick one eligible email at random and we&rsquo;ll announce it</p>
<p dir="ltr">To make it easy for you, we have a big $50 Amazon Card and the instructions on the top right of our website.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So, go subscribe, like and follow us, and get your emails in so you can win that $50 gift card.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: And don&rsquo;t forget, we are still in the running for Hottest Local Celebrity in Folio Weekly&rsquo;s 2013 Best of Jax contest. Make sure to vote for us at <a href="http://folioweekly.com/bestofjax">folioweekly.com/bestofjax</a></p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: All right, well before we jump into your questions, we have a guest on the phone.</p>
<p dir="ltr">We have Adam Daveline on the phone from New York City. Adam is the founder of <a href="http://DiscoveringShakespeare.com/">DiscoveringShakespeare.com</a>, an exciting Kickstarter project that is currently underway right now. Thanks for coming on the show Adam!</p>
<p dir="ltr">So, what are you doing up in New York?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Explain to us what Discovering Shakespeare is.</p>
<p dir="ltr">What gave you the inspiration for Discovering Shakespeare?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Are you doing this all by yourself or do you have a team working with you?</p>
<p dir="ltr">How will you build the site? Are you planning on using an open source platform like WordPress or are you building the site from the ground up?</p>
<p dir="ltr">How will you fund DS to keep it running?</p>
<p dir="ltr">What are some technical challenges you&rsquo;ve faced in creating DS?</p>
<p dir="ltr">You are trying to raise $18,031. When I first saw that amount I was racking my brain trying to figure out the significance. I thought there was some reference I was forgetting. But you&rsquo;ve got it figured out exactly what you need to make DS get off the ground. Give us a quick explanation, what is the money going to pay for?</p>
<p dir="ltr">How can people get involved?</p>
<h4>Ric writes, I need a simple phone for use in Costa Rica. I know very little about cell phones. The NY Times recommended the Nokia 2700 unlocked GSM quad band world phone, which I found at Myworldphone.com for $79. What else do I need and how can I make sure this phone will work before my trip?</h4>
<p>$79 is not bad, but I would wait until you get to Costa Rica and buy a phone there. Generally, you can get a feature phone much cheaper in countries outside of the US than you can in the US.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;ve already bought the Nokia 2700, you are good it will work in Costa Rica.</p>
<p>You definitely want to buy a SIM card in Costa Rica though. International roaming is much more expensive than buying a prepaid plan once you get there.</p>
<p>Now, whatever you do, don&rsquo;t buy a phone at the airport. That is the place where they will be the most expensive. If you&rsquo;re planning on staying for a while, what I would do is once you hit the ground, find the closest reputable hostel. They&rsquo;ll be able to direct you to tell you the best place to go. If you&rsquo;re staying at a hotel, the concierge will do the same.</p>
<h4 dir="ltr">Maliery asks Would you advise friends to avoid purchasing laptops from the Purchasing Power website?</h4>
<p dir="ltr">So, Purchasing Power is a site where you can buy things through payroll deduction. Instead of having to go down to the store to make your payment, your payment comes right out of your paycheck before you even see it. In order to buy from Purchasing Power, your company has to participate and offer the benefit.</p>
<p dir="ltr">From what I could tell, Purchasing Power seems to have brand name laptops. I would assume, if they&rsquo;re anything like most home shopping network channels and rent to own places, they are probably low powered machines, that are overpriced. Now, I am only guessing because I wasn&rsquo;t able to see the actual products without registering, and I didn&rsquo;t want to register. But, that&rsquo;s most likely what you&rsquo;ll find there. When a company doesn&rsquo;t get all of the money from a purchase up front, they have to make up the difference somewhere. If you buy it on credit, you pay the difference in interest. When you buy things on rent to own, they usually overcharge you. With computers, the way they stay competitive with the rest of the retail industry is that they will have the same computer at the same price as Best Buy, TigerDirect, etc, but they will have the model with the lower specs. It&rsquo;s like two car dealers selling two Ford Mustangs for the same price, but one has an supercharged V8 and the other has a 4 cylinder.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I am not an advocate of going into debt for electronics. I&rsquo;m not a devout Dave Ramsey follower, but I do believe that most things are not worth going into debt for, and gadgets are definitely not worth it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Now, this isn&rsquo;t exactly &ldquo;debt&rdquo; it&rsquo;s more like a rent to own program. It is definitely less risky for the company than offering credit cards because it&rsquo;s not like you can miss a payment, as long as you are working.</p>
<p dir="ltr">However, I don&rsquo;t know what happens if you lose your job. Do you have to return the computer? Do you have to pay the balance in full? I couldn&rsquo;t find that information. And that worries me. If they can&rsquo;t share that on the website in plain view, it&rsquo;s probably not in your best interest.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So, in answer to your question Maliery, I wouldn&rsquo;t do it.</p>
<h4>&nbsp;Zoe left a voicemail</h4>
<p dir="ltr">First thing is you have to make sure that you have your parent&rsquo;s permission before you call someone.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Second, you need to make sure that you parent&rsquo;s permission to download apps. If you do, you can download games from the Amazon App Store.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Now, parent&rsquo;s you&rsquo;ll really like this. There&rsquo;s something really awesome on the Kindle Fire called <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/feature.html/?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;docId=1000863021&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;tag=deemtech-20">Kindle FreeTime Unlimited</a>. For $4.99 a month or 2.99 if you are an Amazon Prime subscriber, you get access for your child to over a 1,000 app in the Amazon App Store that are age appropriate for your child. The best part is that you can control how long they can use the Kindle for apps, videos, books, games, etc.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So, for instance, Zoe can only play games and videos for a total of two hours a day. But she can read books on her Kindle as long as she wants.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So, to answer your question, Zoe, if you want to have more time to play games on your Kindle, I would suggest that you make sure to be on your best behavior, make sure to get your schoolwork done, and ask mommy very nicely and she might give you a little bit more time to play games.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-size: 2em;">OUTRO</span></p>
<p dir="ltr">Thanks for all your questions, and keep them coming. Call us at our toll-free number, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com. Also, subscribe to the show! Search for Deemable Tech on iTunes or point your favorite podcast app to dmbl.co/pod.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Our producer is Sean Birch. Thanks to Robert Snyder for Video Production Assistance. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, and this is Deemable Tech. Thanks for listening. Have a great week.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#46 Ray and Tom Discover Shakespeare" data-link="/2013/08/46-ray-and-tom-discover-shakespeare/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#46 Ray and Tom Discover Shakespeare" data-link="/2013/08/46-ray-and-tom-discover-shakespeare/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/08/46-ray-and-tom-discover-shakespeare/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-11.mp3" length="37749656" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#44 Angel Torres, Aurora App 2.0, and Deemable Tech App 1.0</title>
		<link>/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/</link>
		<comments>/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 15:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angel Torres]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aurora App]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Logica]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7757</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/07/DeemableTechEpisode44AngelTorres-e1375109234120-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Deemable Tech Episode 44 Angel Torres and Aurora App 2.0" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />On this episode of Deemable Tech, Angel Torres from The Logica visits us in the studio again to tell us what he&#8217;s been up to since One Spark, and to tell us about some big news from the Aurora App. <a href="/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/07/DeemableTechEpisode44AngelTorres-e1375109234120-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Deemable Tech Episode 44 Angel Torres and Aurora App 2.0" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/07/DeemableTechEpisode44AngelTorres.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-7761" alt="Deemable Tech Episode 44 Angel Torres and Aurora App 2.0" src="/media/2013/07/DeemableTechEpisode44AngelTorres-300x164.jpg"  width="300" height="164"></a>On this episode of Deemable Tech, Angel Torres from <a href="http://www.thelogica.com/">The Logica</a> visits us in the studio again to tell us what he&rsquo;s been up to since One Spark, and to tell us about some big news from the Aurora App. Also, we help Amber remove a forgotten PIN restriction on her iPhone, and we helped Lynda figure out why apps keep redone loading on her iPod touch after she deleted them.</p>
<p>We also announced an Amazon Gift Card give away! We really need your help growing our show, and what better way to do that than through bribery! That&rsquo;s right, if Deemable Tech gets at least 500 subscribers on iTunes and at least 200 subscribers on YouTube by the end of August, we are going to give away an Amazon Gift Card worth $50!</p>
<p>To be eligible to win the $50 Amazon Gift Card, you have to Subscribe to us on <a href="http://youtube.com/DeemableTech">YouTube</a> and <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/deemable-tech/id540595466" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iTunes</a>, Like us on <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable">Facebook</a> and follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable">Twitter</a>. Then, send us an email at giftcard@deemable.com. In that email, tell us your Facebook name, Twitter and YouTube username. We&rsquo;ll pick one eligible email at random and we&rsquo;ll announce it on the show. You got to do all of it and include all of it in the email. If you don&rsquo;t, you&rsquo;re disqualified! We&rsquo;re gonna check!</p>
<p>Now, remember, we can&rsquo;t give away the $50 Amazon Gift Card unless we hit 500 subscribers on iTunes and 200 subscribers on YouTube by the end of August. So, you&rsquo;ve got to tell your friends about Deemable Tech, and tell them to subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes and YouTube! Not only does this put you in the running for a $50 Amazon Gift Card, but it will really help us to grow Deemable Tech. So, whether you do it out of altruistic motives, or out of pure selfishness, make sure to tell everyone you know about Deemable Tech, and make sure to like us on <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable">Facebook</a>, Subscribe to us on <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/deemable-tech/id540595466" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iTunes</a> and <a href="http://youtube.com/DeemableTech">YouTube</a> and Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable">Twitter</a>! The links to all of our profiles are in the top right corner of the website under the heading, Follow Deemable Tech.</p>
<p>Also, we almost forgot to mention that we launched the Deemable Tech app! The Deemable Tech app is now available for <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/deemable-tech/id671758316" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iPhone, iPod touch and iPad in the App Store</a> and for <a>Android phones and tablets in the Google Play store</a>. You can find a link to the app simply by visiting <a href="Deemable.com">Deemable.com</a> on your mobile device. On the Deemable Tech app you can listen or watch the latest episodes of Deemable Tech, read the latest articles, and submit questions right on your smart phone or tablet. You can receive notifications on your phone when new articles and episodes are posted too! Thanks to all of our Kickstarter supporters. We couldn&rsquo;t have done it without you.</p>
<p>All that, plus our app recommendations of the week on this episode of Deemable Tech!</p>
<span class="embed-youtube" style="text-align:center; display: block;"><iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="752" height="453" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1ElfXftGY40?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
<p><audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-7757-3" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-28.mp3?_=3"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-28.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-28.mp3</a></audio><br><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-28.mp3">#44 Angel Torres and the Aurora App 2.0</a></p>
<p>DRAFT TRANSCRIPT</p>
<h4>SEGMENT A INTRO</h4>
<p>RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>TOM: I&rsquo;m Tom Braun,</p>
<p>RAY: and this is Deemable Tech, tech help worth listening to.</p>
<p>RAY: This week&rsquo;s episode of the Deemable Tech podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p>And, by audible.com &ndash; Deemable Tech listeners can get a FREE audiobook download at <a href="http://audibletrial.com/Deemable">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a> Over 100,000 titles to choose from for your iPhone, Android, Kindle or mp3 player.</p>
<p>TOM: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? Give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at questions@deemable.com.</p>
<h4>Amazon Gift Card Contest Announcement</h4>
<p>RAY: Tonight, on Deemable Tech, folks, we need you to do us a favor. If you like the show, if you want to hear more episodes of Deemable Tech, we need you to do something for us. We need you to tell your friends about us. We need you to share us on Facebook, tweet about us on Twitter, just send an email to your friends and tell them to check us out. Or if you talk to people in real life, you can tell them there. Give them a call on the phone.</p>
<p>You know how Tinkerbell would die if people don&rsquo;t believe in her? Well, we&rsquo;re kinda like that. Except the energy that we depend on is Subscriptions, Likes, and Follows.</p>
<p>If you haven&rsquo;t done it already,<br>
Subscribe to us on <a href="http://youtube.com/DeemableTech">YouTube</a> and <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/deemable-tech/id540595466" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iTunes</a>.<br>
Like us on <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable">Facebook</a> and follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable">Twitter</a>.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ll be honest, right now, the Deemable Tech community is pretty small. We only have about 150 subscribers on our podcast, we have about 25 subscribers on YouTube. We do have about 1,000 likes on Facebook and followers on Twitter, but the subscribers is what really counts, because those are people who are actually watching or listening to the show.</p>
<p>Tell you what, I have a deal for you. If we hit 500 subscribers on iTunes and 200 subscribers on YouTube, I&rsquo;ll give away an Amazon gift card. Sound good?</p>
<p>TOM: How much?</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what you have to do to be eligible to receive a $50 Amazon Gift Card. You have to Subscribe to us on <a href="http://youtube.com/DeemableTech">YouTube</a> and <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/deemable-tech/id540595466" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iTunes</a>, Like us on <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable">Facebook</a> and follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable">Twitter</a>, and send us an email at giftcard@deemable.com. In that email, tell us your Facebook name, Twitter and YouTube username. We&rsquo;ll pick one eligible email at random and we&rsquo;ll announce it on the show. You got to include all of it. If you don&rsquo;t you&rsquo;re disqualified. We need that information because we&rsquo;re gonna check! If you didn&rsquo;t like us, you&rsquo;re disqualified. etc.</p>
<p>You can like us on <a href="http://dmbl.co/gp">Google Plus</a> too, but nobody really cares.</p>
<p>On this week&rsquo;s episode we have a special guest, back with us in the studio again, Angel Torres, the CEO and founder of The Logica, a web and app development company. You might know him from when he was on the show back in February, or you might know him if you came to One Spark. Thanks for coming on the show, Angel.</p>
<p>So, I want to ask you about what&rsquo;s been going on with the Aurora App, and any other projects that The Logica is up to that you can talk about, but I&rsquo;m sure you&rsquo;ve heard about the changes at One Spark that are coming for One Spark 2014. I want to see what you think about that too. Sound fun?</p>
<p>All right, but first, let&rsquo;s talk about apps.</p>
<h4>That App Segment</h4>
<p><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ifttt/id660944635" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">IFTTT &ndash; If This Then That</a></p>
<p><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/limbo-game/id656951157?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">LIMBO Game</a></p>
<p><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/aurora-app/id632041573" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Aurora App</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>All right, well let&rsquo;s answer a couple of listener&rsquo;s questions.</p>
<p>Amber wrote in and asked, at some point I created a PIN number for my iPhone&rsquo;s &ldquo;Restrictions&rdquo; setting. I can&rsquo;t remember it now, and I have 9 failed passcode attempts. Will I ever be able to get in and change my restrictions&hellip; or will I be stuck with in-app purchases turned off forever? Help! How can I fix this?<br>
Well, hopefully you have synced your iPhone with iTunes on your computer at least once before. If you have this going to be a lot easier. All you&rsquo;ll have to do is open iTunes, and plug your iPhone in, and that will reset the count of how many times you can enter the passcode. So, theoretically you could enter pin numbers until the end of time. Hopefully at some point you&rsquo;ll be able to figure out what your pin number was.<br>
If you can&rsquo;t figure out what your pin number was, then that&rsquo;s a slightly bigger problem. You&rsquo;re going to have to backup your iPhone, and then restore it from that backup. That will clear the PIN number. But, that will only work, if you have synced your iPhone with iTunes on your computer in the past. If you haven&rsquo;t, you&rsquo;re going to have to reset your iPhone to factory settings. That is why I said I hope that you have synced it before, because if you haven&rsquo;t, you&rsquo;re going to lose all your settings and all your stuff on your iPhone.<br>
So, what I would do is start by plugging in your iPhone and trying those passcodes again, and keep track of which ones you&rsquo;ve tried, especially if you&rsquo;re only doing a four digit pin code. I mean there&rsquo;s only 9,999 options. You&rsquo;ve got to hit it eventually, right?<br>
We will include a link to instructions how to reset your iPhone to factory settings, and how to restore your iPhone from a previous back up in the show notes for the episode.</p>
<p><a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1212">iOS: Forgotten passcode or device disabled after entering wrong passcode</a></p>
<p>Lynda asked I keep deleting apps off of my iPod touch, but they keep reinstalling whenever the app gets updated. Why? It&rsquo;s driving me crazy. I want to be able to delete apps and for them to stay deleted. What&rsquo;s going on? I am running iOS 6.1.3 on a 4th generation iPod. I am running iTunes on my Windows 7 laptop. iTunes syncs over the WiFi.</p>
<p>I am going to guess that you probably don&rsquo;t keep your laptop running all the time. Here&rsquo;s what I think is happening: You are connecting to iTunes, and syncing. Then, later you install an app, and delete it before you sync with your computer again. Now what happens, is the next time you sync your computer with your iPod, iTunes downloads the app, and then it sees that you don&rsquo;t have the new app on your iPod. So, in trying to be helpful, it reinstalls it on your iPod for you. Now, you&rsquo;re probably only just noticing it when the App Store has an update for the app.</p>
<p><a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/ht4539">How to enable Automatic Downloads on your computer and on your iPhone, iPad and iPod touch</a></p>
<p>QUESTIONS FOR ANGEL</p>
<p>How did things turn out for you guys at One Spark?<br>
What would you do different?<br>
Are you planning on entering One Spark 2014?<br>
What happening with the Aurora app?<br>
What projects are working on now?</p>
<p>Changes for One Spark 2014 http://beonespark.tumblr.com/post/55001047087/one-spark-2014-press-release</p>
<p>More money up for grabs: $300,000<br>
Distributed differently:<br>
$200,000 guaranteed crowdfund distributed solely on public vote,<br>
five $10,000 bonuses awarded to the top-voted creator in each category,<br>
five $10,000 juried prizes and immediate individual contributions from attendees.<br>
Other changes<br>
Five creator categories, art, innovation, music, science and technology<br>
More walkable, concentrated event footprint that will include 20 square blocks and additional programming throughout.<br>
Significant number of additional voting and information kiosk locations.</p>
<h4>SPONSOR</h4>
<p>For the listeners of the Deemable Tech podcast, Audible is offering a free audiobook download with a free 30-day trial to give you the opportunity to check out their service.</p>
<p>To download your free audiobook today go to <a href="http://audibletrial.com/Deemable">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a>. Again, that&rsquo;s audibletrial.com/Deemable for your free audiobook!</p>
<h4>OUTRO</h4>
<p>Thanks for all your questions, and keep them coming. Call us at our toll-free number, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com. Also, subscribe to the show! Search for Deemable Tech on iTunes or point your favorite podcast app to dmbl.co/pod.</p>
<p>Our producer is Sean Birch. Thanks to Robert Snyder for Video Production Assistance. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, and this is Deemable Tech. Thanks for listening. Have a great week.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#44 Angel Torres, Aurora App 2.0, and Deemable Tech App 1.0" data-link="/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#44 Angel Torres, Aurora App 2.0, and Deemable Tech App 1.0" data-link="/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-28.mp3" length="65736620" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Episode 32 &#8211; Alert The Boss, You Need to Disable Java Now!</title>
		<link>/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/</link>
		<comments>/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 05:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adecco Ignite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alert The Boss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Citrix Online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GoToWebinar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[java]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One Spark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Text Message]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=6888</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/02/AlertTheBoss-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Alert The Boss" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week on Deemable Tech Ray was joined by guest host Kenny Kwaak and by John Martinelli and Evan Diamond from Alert The Boss, a creation that is going to part of One Spark, a crowd funding festival happening in <a href="/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/02/AlertTheBoss-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Alert The Boss" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-6890" alt="Alert The Boss" src="/media/2013/02/AlertTheBoss.png" width="180" height="180">This week on Deemable Tech Ray was joined by guest host Kenny Kwaak and by John Martinelli and Evan Diamond from Alert The Boss, a creation that is going to part of <a title="One Spark: The World's Crowdfunding Festival " href="http://beonespark.com/" target="_blank">One Spark</a>, a crowd funding festival happening in Jacksonville, Florida April 17-21, 2013. Be sure to come and visit Alert The Boss at <a title="121 Atlantic Place at 121 W Forsyth Street." href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=121+west+forsyth+street+jacksonville+fl&amp;daddr=121+W+Forsyth+St,+Jacksonville,+FL+32202&amp;hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;hnear=0x88e5b7170a2cf03d:0xbe5b62b1e970c1ff,121+W+Forsyth+St,+Jacksonville,+FL+32202&amp;gl=us&amp;t=h&amp;z=16" target="_blank">121 Atlantic Place</a>&nbsp;and Deemable Tech at a <a title="Adecco Ignite at 6 E Bay Street" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=6+east+bay+street+jacksonville+fl&amp;daddr=6+E+Bay+St,+Jacksonville,+FL+32202&amp;hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;hnear=0x88e5b719e5c78a97:0xc1e72ae59093be92,6+E+Bay+St,+Jacksonville,+FL+32202&amp;gl=us&amp;t=h&amp;z=16" target="_blank">Adecco Ignite</a> during One Spark, and make sure to vote for Alert The Boss and Deemable Tech at One Spark!</p>
<p>After the break, Ray and Kenny answered one question that got skipped at the <a title="Deemable Tech Live at Bold Bean!" href="http://dmbl.co/e31">Live Event last week</a>. Mike wants to know why he can&rsquo;t hear the sound on the Citrix Online webinars that he attends. The guys tell him to fix the disease, not treat the symptoms.</p>
<p>All that and more, on this episode of Deemable Tech!</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img title="Subscribe on iTunes" alt="" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" width="160" height="59"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">subscribe to the show in iTunes by clicking here</a>, or&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech Podcast!" href="http://dmbl.co/pod">subscribe to the show in another podcast reader by clicking here</a>. Also,&nbsp;make sure to leave us a review in iTunes. The more reviews we have the higher we&rsquo;ll be listed in iTunes and the more listeners will see our show!</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-6888-4" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-25.mp3?_=4"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-25.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-25.mp3</a></audio><p><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-25.mp3" target="_blank">Download Episode 32 &ndash; Alert The Boss You Need to Disable Java Now!</a></p>
<p>Need tech help? Got a problem or tech question about your computer, phone or tablet? Give us a call and leave us a voice mail at 1-888-972-9868, or send us an email to questions at deemable dot com. We&rsquo;ll answer them on the show.</p>
<h4>Links mentioned on this week&rsquo;s show:</h4>
<ul><li><a title="AlertTheBoss! | Get instant feedback from your customers BEFORE they leave your business!" href="https://alerttheboss.com/" target="_blank">AlertTheBoss!</a></li>
<li><a title="Facebook | Alert The Boss" href="https://www.facebook.com/AlertTheBoss" target="_blank">Like AlertTheBoss on Facebook</a></li>
<li><a title="Gizmodo | How To Disable Java in Your Browser" href="http://gizmodo.com/5975475/how-to-disable-java-in-your-browser" target="_blank">Gizmodo &ndash; How To Disable Java in Your Browser</a></li>
</ul><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Episode 32 - Alert The Boss, You Need to Disable Java Now!" data-link="/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Episode 32 - Alert The Boss, You Need to Disable Java Now!" data-link="/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-25.mp3" length="50022609" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Episode 30 &#8211; Angel Ayala Torres and the Awesome Aurora App</title>
		<link>/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/</link>
		<comments>/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 03:35:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aurora App]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=6826</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/02/AuroraApp-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Aurora App" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week on Deemable Tech Ray and Tom were joined in the studio by Angel Ayala Torres, the&#160;CEO and founder of The Logica, a web and app development company that has a very interesting app that they are going to <a href="/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/02/AuroraApp-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Aurora App" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/02/AuroraApp.png" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright wp-image-6828" alt="Aurora App" src="/media/2013/02/AuroraApp.png"  width="280" height="160"></a></p>
<p>This week on Deemable Tech Ray and Tom were joined in the studio by Angel Ayala Torres, the&nbsp;CEO and founder of <a title="The Logica Creative Studio" href="http://www.thelogica.com/" target="_blank">The Logica</a>, a web and app development company that has a very interesting app that they are going to be releasing very soon called <a title="AuroraApp" href="http://auroraapp.com/" target="_blank">Aurora</a>. Both Deemable Tech and Aurora will be at <a title="One Spark: The World's Crowdfunding Festival " href="http://beonespark.com/" target="_blank">One Spark</a>, a crowd funding festival happening in Jacksonville, Florida April 17-21, 2013. Be sure to come and visit Aurora&rsquo;s booth at <a title="CoWork Jax | CoWorking Space in Downtown Jacksonville" href="http://www.coworkjax.com/" target="_blank">CoWork&nbsp;Jax</a> at <a title="5 W. Forsyth Street" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=5+W.+Forsyth+St.&amp;hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;hnear=5+W+Forsyth+St,+Jacksonville,+Duval,+Florida+32202&amp;t=h&amp;z=16" target="_blank">Forsyth and Main Street</a>&nbsp;and Deemable Tech&rsquo;s booth at a yet to be&nbsp;disclosed location, and make sure to vote for Aurora and Deemable Tech at One Spark!</p>
<p>All that and more, on this episode of Deemable Tech!</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img title="Subscribe on iTunes" alt="" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" width="160" height="59"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">subscribe to the show in iTunes by clicking here</a>, or&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech Podcast!" href="http://dmbl.co/pod">subscribe to the show in another podcast reader by clicking here</a>. Also,&nbsp;make sure to leave us a review in iTunes. The more reviews we have the higher we&rsquo;ll be listed in iTunes and the more listeners will see our show!</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-6826-5" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-11.mp3?_=5"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-11.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-11.mp3</a></audio><p><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-11.mp3" target="_blank">Download Episode 30 &ndash; Angel Ayala Torres and the Awesome Aurora App</a></p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget, next week is our Live Event at Bold Bean Coffee Roasters! &nbsp;Monday, February 18th, 7 PM Bold Bean Coffee Roasters on Stockton Street. If you&rsquo;re in Jacksonville, come visit us and listen to the show live.&nbsp;<a title="Deemable Tech Live at Bold Bean Coffee Roasters!" href="http://dmbl.co/dtatbb" target="_blank">RSVP on Facebook</a>.</p>
<p>Send in your questions for our live event.</p>
<p>Need tech help? Got a problem or tech question about your computer, phone or tablet? Give us a call and leave us a voice mail at 1-888-972-9868, or send us an email to questions at deemable dot com. We&rsquo;ll take the best questions and answer them on the show.</p>
<h4>Links mentioned on this week&rsquo;s show:</h4>
<ul><li><a title="AuroraApp - Coming Soon 2013" href="http://AuroraApp.com/" target="_blank">AuroraApp.com</a></li>
<li><a title="Aurora App on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/auroraapp" target="_blank">Aurora on Facebook</a></li>
<li><a title="Aurora (meetaurora) on Twitter" href="https://twitter.com/meetaurora" target="_blank">Aurora on Twitter</a></li>
</ul><ul><li><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/the-dark-knight-rises-z+/id542656871?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">The Dark Knight Rises Z+</a></li>
<li><a href="http://invaders.soulbit7.com/">AR Invaders</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.dishpointer.com/">DishPointer</a></li>
<li><a href="http://golfscapeapp.com/">Golfscape GPS Rangefinder</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vitotechnology.com/star-walk.html">Star Walk</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.gosoftworks.com/GoSkyWatch/GoSkyWatch.html">GoSkyWatch Planetarium</a></li>
</ul><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Episode 30 - Angel Ayala Torres and the Awesome Aurora App" data-link="/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Episode 30 - Angel Ayala Torres and the Awesome Aurora App" data-link="/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-11.mp3" length="39000607" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
