<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; TigerDirect</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/tigerdirect/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#77 The Title Of This Episode Is A GIF</title>
		<link>/2015/03/77-the-title-of-this-episode-is-a-gif/</link>
		<comments>/2015/03/77-the-title-of-this-episode-is-a-gif/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 20:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cogito]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Credit Cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facial Recognition Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GIFs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RadioShack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartwatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Target]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TigerDirect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9865</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/03/chair_spin_still-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="chair_spin_still" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week the guys geek out over Tesla adding an autopilot feature to their electric cars, mourn the death of TigerDirect retail stores, and wonder if they can follow in Google&#8217;s footsteps and communicate purely through GIFs. Plus, Ray shares <a href="/2015/03/77-the-title-of-this-episode-is-a-gif/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/03/77-the-title-of-this-episode-is-a-gif/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/03/chair_spin_still-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="chair_spin_still" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div style="width: 409px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="" src="http://i.imgur.com/u43u8TL.gif" alt="The Deemable Tech guys spinning in their chairs." width="399" height="366"><p class="wp-caption-text">If Google can do it, we can too! The title of this episode is this GIF.</p></div>
<p>This week the guys geek out over Tesla adding an autopilot feature to their electric cars, mourn the death of TigerDirect retail stores, and wonder if they can follow in Google&rsquo;s footsteps and communicate purely through GIFs. Plus, Ray shares his thoughts on the Cogito smartwatch.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>If you haven&rsquo;t <a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/ca/podcast/deemable-tech-wjct/id540595466?mt=2" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">subscribed to Deemable Tech</a> yet, get on it! Subscribe to <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">Deemable Tech&nbsp;in iTunes</a>,&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a> or&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech Podcast!" href="http://dmbl.co/pod">subscribe to the show in another podcast reader</a>. Make sure to leave us a review in iTunes and Stitcher. The more reviews we have the higher we&rsquo;ll be listed, and the more listeners will see our show.</p>
<p>And make sure to&nbsp;share us on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-9865-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/deemabletech_2015_03_27.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/deemabletech_2015_03_27.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/deemabletech_2015_03_27.mp3</a></audio><h2>This Week&rsquo;s Run Down</h2>
<h3>Tesla Announces Software Update for Cars Which Adds &ldquo;Autopilot&rdquo; Feature</h3>
<p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk held a press conference this week at which he announced that late model <a href="http://www.informationweek.com/it-life/tesla-model-s-autopilot-coming-soon-elon-musk-claims-/d/d-id/1319564" target="_blank">Teslas will be getting a software update that will give them a new feature called &lsquo;autopilot</a>.&rsquo; The autopilot feature will bring ordinary Tesla electric cars that much closer to being self-driving, enabling them to stay in their lane on a well-marked highway without driver intervention. Musk claimed that the autopilot technology would enable to a driver to make it from San Francisco to Seattle without steering.</p>
<p>Musk also announced a feature called Range Assurance which will alert Tesla drivers when the charge in their car is getting too low to make it to the nearest charging station.</p>
<h3>$10 Million Target Credit Card Data Breach Settlement Gets Preliminary Approval</h3>
<p>You probably remember the massive data breach that hit Target during the 2013 holiday season where tens of millions of credit cards were stolen right out of their systems. A class action lawsuit was filed and now Target is preparing to settle? for $10 million dollars.</p>
<p>If that amount seems low to you, it is because Target is not going to do the usual thing and send five dollars to every customer whose card number was stolen. Instead, card holders can only be reimbursed if they can show that they were actually hurt by the data breach. They need to have had fraudulent charges placed on their card that they were not reimbursed for, that negatively affected their credit score, or show that they spent a lot of time and money resolving the problem, or that it harmed them in some other way.</p>
<p>The proposed settlement is only preliminary, and members of the class action suit have until November 10th to object.</p>
<h3>RadioShack Puts Customer Data Up for Sale in Bankruptcy Auction</h3>
<p>RadioShack is on the auction block this week as its creditors attempt to sell the company?s assets &ndash; this apparently includes <a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/2901028/radioshack-puts-customers-personal-data-up-for-sale-in-bankruptcy-auction.html" target="_blank">a large chunk of customer data, including 65 million customer names and physical addresses and 13 million email addresses</a>. Consumer advocates are concerned, and Texas Attorney General Ken Paxton claims it may be illegal under state law. Texas does not allow companies to violate their own privacy policies and signage in RadioShack promises that they will not sell their private mailing list.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T is also opposing the sale of data because they say RadioShack is not entitled to personal information it collects from wireless sales. AT&amp;T wants the data destroyed to keep it from falling into competitors hands.</p>
<p>A bankruptcy court still has to approve the deal.</p>
<h3>TigerDirect Closing Retail Stores</h3>
<p>Speaking of defunct electronic stores, remember Circuit City&hellip; CompUSA&hellip; Ultimate Electronics? Well, TigerDirect bought them in the late aughts. Well, now <a href="http://jacksonville.com/business/2015-03-24/story/2-tigerdirect-electronics-stores-jacksonville-close" target="_blank">TigerDirect is joining them</a> in the electronic retail store afterlife. <a href="http://www.foxbusiness.com/markets/2015/03/03/brothers-guilty-fraud-at-systemax-computer-company-sent-to-federal-prison-by/" target="_blank">Two of the former executives for TigerDirect were recently sentenced to 60 and 80 months in jail</a> for a kickback scheme that cost the company $27 million. Apparently that hurt the company enough that the company decided to close all by two retail stores.</p>
<p>It makes me sad because TigerDirect was a &ldquo;dot com boom&rdquo; success story. They actually started as a catalog company, but transitioned into internet sales early. When all of the retail computer stores started dying, TigerDirect was holding strong, and they bought up the stores and their IP and entered the retail market. They did a fantastic job of turning stores like CompUSA and Circuit City, which were known for fancy displays and overpriced electronics, into stores with smart employees, simple displays and prices that competed with the Internet.</p>
<p>TigerDirect is going to continue selling computers, electronics and computer components on its website.</p>
<p>No word yet if NewEgg is planning on buying its stores, but that would be the perfect irony.</p>
<h3>Facial Recognition Software Leads To Arrest of Jacksonville Man Who Faked His Own Death</h3>
<p>Another thing the internet has ruined: <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2015/03/florida-man-initially-thought-dead-arrested-after-facial-recognition-match/" target="_blank">faking your own death</a>. <a href="http://jacksonville.com/news/metro/2015-03-23/story/facial-recognition-software-led-feds-jacksonville-businessman-once" target="_blank">Jacksonville businessman Jose Lantigua had been reported dead in Venezuela two years ago</a>. But when he attempted to apply for a new passport under his new, false identity <a href="http://jacksonville.com/news/metro/2015-03-23/story/facial-recognition-software-led-feds-jacksonville-businessman-once" target="_blank">the US State Department used facial recognition software to match him</a> to his original identity in their database. Federal agents then set up a sting operation and caught him wearing a brown toupee and ?a poorly dyed beard.?</p>
<p>Lantigua is wanted on numerous counts of insurance fraud, since his family attempted to collect on his life insurance policy after his death. The insurance company has long viewed this with suspicion.</p>
<h3>Google Responds to Reporter with GIF Instead of &ldquo;No Comment&rdquo;</h3>
<p>This week, Daily Dot writer Richard Lewis published a story about <a href="http://www.dailydot.com/esports/youtube-google-esports-livestreaming/" target="_blank">YouTube reportedly planning to relaunch its livestreaming platform with a focus on computer gaming and esports</a>. This is similar to Twitch, which Google tried to buy last year before it ended up being purchased by Amazon.</p>
<p>Lewis reached out to Google for a comment on the reports, and they apparently responded with something only Google could get away with. Instead of the usual &ldquo;no comment,&rdquo; the representative sent Lewis this animated GIF of a little girl shrugging. No text, just the GIF.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://replygif.net/i/855.gif" alt="An animated GIF of a girl shrugging her shoulders." width="500" height="228"></p>
<p>Lewis at first assumed that this was a joke, and said that he received a &ldquo;no comment&rdquo; response from Google in his story. The same representative sent another message saying that the GIF was, in fact, their official response.</p>
<h2>Reviews</h2>
<p>Ray shares his thoughts on the <a href="http://cogitowatch.com/" target="_blank">Cogito swartwatch</a> this week.</p>
<p>&mdash;-</p>
<p>If you have a comment, contact us at feedback at deemable.com or leave us a voicemail at 1-888-972-9868.</p>
<p>Help us decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story. Or vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Tech on Reddit" href="http://reddit.com/r/Deemable" target="_blank">reddit.com/r/Deemable</a></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#77 The Title Of This Episode Is A GIF" data-link="/2015/03/77-the-title-of-this-episode-is-a-gif/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#77 The Title Of This Episode Is A GIF" data-link="/2015/03/77-the-title-of-this-episode-is-a-gif/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/03/77-the-title-of-this-episode-is-a-gif/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/deemabletech_2015_03_27.mp3" length="45516833" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
