<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Samsung Galaxy</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/samsung-galaxy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#88 The One Where Marketing Told Us to Talk About &#8216;Jurassic World&#8217;</title>
		<link>/2015/06/88-the-one-where-marketing-told-us-to-talk-about-jurassic-world/</link>
		<comments>/2015/06/88-the-one-where-marketing-told-us-to-talk-about-jurassic-world/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 22:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[E3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kickstarter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LastPass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soylent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10105</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/06/soylent_one_week_box-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="soylent_one_week_box" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />OK, so we don&#8217;t really talk about&#160;Jurassic World on this episode. But Ray, Tom and Sean DO discuss some of the week&#8217;s tech news, including California&#8217;s new rules for Uber, the annual E3 video game trade show and more. Ray <a href="/2015/06/88-the-one-where-marketing-told-us-to-talk-about-jurassic-world/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/06/88-the-one-where-marketing-told-us-to-talk-about-jurassic-world/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/06/soylent_one_week_box-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="soylent_one_week_box" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>OK, so we don&rsquo;t really talk about&nbsp;Jurassic World on this episode. But Ray, Tom and Sean DO discuss some of the week&rsquo;s tech news, including California&rsquo;s new rules for Uber, the annual E3 video game trade show and more. Ray also reviews the food replacement product Soylent. All of that and more on this week&rsquo;s Deemable Tech!</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on our website, would you subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>? And, while you&rsquo;re there, would you leave a review and say a few nice things about us? The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="//reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there. We&rsquo;re also looking for a new admin to help manage and moderate our subreddit page. Submit a text post to our subreddit explaining why you would make a great admin.</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10105-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-19.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-19.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-19.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S RUN DOWN</h1>
<h2><b>California commission rules that Uber drivers are employees</b></h2>
<p>In what could be a major, precedent-setting decision for the so-called ?sharing economy,? the California Labor Commission has ruled that <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/06/18/business/uber-contests-california-labor-ruling-that-says-drivers-should-be-employees.html">ride-sharing company Uber?s drivers are employees, not independent contractors</a>. Uber has claimed that it is a logistics company and that drivers and passengers merely use its app to facilitate transactions.</p>
<p>However it seems that the Labor Commission took issue with this representation. It said that Uber controls the tools drivers use, monitors their approval ratings, and will terminate drivers whose approval ratings fall too low or who go too long without taking fares. The commission was ruling on the appeal of a labor commissioner?s award of $4,000 to Barbara Ann Berwick of San Francisco, who worked about two months for Uber last year.</p>
<p>If this ruling stands it could have huge consequences for Uber, currently valued at $40 billion. Uber is appealing the ruling.</p>
<h2><b>European court rules news website liable for anonymous comments made on it</b></h2>
<p>It?s a generally held legal principle that websites are not liable for offensive or infringing content users post on them if they remove that content when notified about it. In a surprising reversal, the European Court of Human Rights ruled this week that an Estonian news site called Delfi could be held responsible for anonymous and allegedly defamatory comments left on it. This goes against the existing European Union e-Commerce directive, which essentially has a version of the American DMCA. The court found the comments to be ?extreme? and Delfi?s efforts to control them to be insufficient &ndash; thus the ruling.</p>
<p>It?s not immediately clear what the effects of this ruling are. It doesn?t seem to change existing law, but could guide future European laws regarding what sort of content website operators can and cannot be held liable for.</p>
<h2><b>LastPass hacked</b></h2>
<p>If you use LastPass, and you haven?t changed your master password, stop listening to this podcast and do it RIGHT now. Seriously! Earlier this week, on its website <a href="http://lifehacker.com/lastpass-hacked-time-to-change-your-master-password-1711463571">LastPass announced it had detected an intrusion</a>. Don?t panic, but the hackers did get email addresses, password reminders, and authentication hashes. So, that could be used to access your account.</p>
<p>The good news is, as we have said before, LastPass has multiple layers of encryption and it?s likely that no account data was lost in the breach. That being said, you must go change your LastPass master password, right now if you didn?t already do it, and it would be smart to <a href="http://lifehacker.com/5938565/heres-everywhere-you-should-enable-two-factor-authentication-right-now">set up two-factor authentication</a>. We?re including a link in the show notes to Lifehacker?s article showing you how to do that if you?ve never done it before.</p>
<h2><b>The FTC takes legal action against Kickstarter creator</b></h2>
<p>One of the big stories of the internet over the last couple of years is crowdfunding campaigns, where sites like Kickstarter and IndieGogo allow people to back projects they?re excited about financially. Unfortunately, not all of those projects are on the up-and-up. Last week the FTC reported that <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2015/06/crowdfunding-project-creator-settles-ftc-charges-deception?utm_source=govdelivery">it had taken its first legal action against a crowdfunding campaign</a> &ndash; a Kickstarter-based project to create a board game called ?The Doom That Came To Atlantic City.? The FTC says that would-be creator Erik Chevalier had asked for $35,000 and wound up raising over $122,000 from 1,246 backers. Most of the backers pledged $75 or more in hopes of getting a backer reward that included pewter figurines. 14 months later, however, Chavalier had not provided any rewards and announced he was cancelling the game and would be refunding the money. No refunds were ever given.</p>
<p>The FTC has settled with Chevalier, forbidding him from ?making misrepresentations about any crowdfunding campaign and from failing to honor stated refund policies. He is also barred from disclosing or otherwise benefiting from customers? personal information, and failing to dispose of such information properly.?</p>
<p>Backers hoping for their money back are out of luck, though. The FTC would make Chevalier pay it back if he had it? but it appears that he doesn?t. It appears that the first rule of crowdfunding campaigns is still in full effect: let the buyer beware.</p>
<h2><b>AT&amp;T fined $100 million</b></h2>
<p>The FCC won?t let AT&amp;T be, or let AT&amp;T be AT&amp;T so let me see. The FCC is hitting <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/6/17/8796575/att-fined-100-million-fcc-misleading-unlimited-data-throttling">AT&amp;T with a $100 Million dollar fine</a> for telling customers they had unlimited data, when in fact they were throttling them when they hit an undisclosed limit.</p>
<p>Travis LeBlanc, the chief of the FCC Enforcement Bureau said in a statement &ldquo;Unlimited means unlimited. As today?s action demonstrates, the commission is committed to holding accountable those broadband providers who fail to be fully transparent about data limits.&rdquo;</p>
<p>On average, affected subscribers were throttled for 12 days a billing cycle. The fine is a drop in the bucket compared to the billions of dollars AT&amp;T has made from its so-called ?unlimited? plans. However, it is the largest fine proposal in the history of the FCC. The Federal Trade Commission also has a pending lawsuit against AT&amp;T for the same issue.</p>
<h2><b>SwiftKey vulnerability on Samsung Galaxy phones opens 600 million devices up to hacking</b></h2>
<p>Another day, another hack that potentially affects millions. Security researchers at the BlackHat security conference in London have demonstrated that <a href="http://arstechnica.com/security/2015/06/new-exploit-turns-samsung-galaxy-phones-into-remote-bugging-devices/">it is possible to exploit Samsung?s customized version of the SwiftKey keyboard</a> to allow hackers to secretly gain access to the phone?s camera and microphones, text messages, memory, and to install malicious apps. It appears that Samsung grants the SwiftKey app high level privileges but makes no effort to encrypt updates to the software. The SwiftKey app is used on virtually all Samsung Galaxy phones, which means about 600 million devices worldwide. There?s not much users can do to make themselves safer at this time, other than to avoid unsecured wifi, and even this will not make them absolutely safe. Simply not using the SwiftKey keyboard will not help. The only real fix will be a patch from Samsung.</p>
<h2>E3</h2>
<p>This week is the Electronic Entertainment Expo, the annual trade show for the video game industry. This is where game makers announce new games and technology, as well as show off games that are currently in production.</p>
<p>There were many announcements and interesting things at this year?s E3, so we?re not going to be able to cover all of them today. In fact, we?re actually recording this episode on Wednesday, so there may have been more this week than we are even aware of. But we did want to mention two things we thought were cool, and they were both from Microsoft.</p>
<p>First, Microsoft announced that their Cortana digital assistant that can currently be found on Windows Phone will be <a href="http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2486203,00.asp" target="_blank">coming to Android and the Xbox One</a>. This means that you will be able to perform common tasks on your Xbox using voice commands. No firm release dates for these, but Microsoft did say that the Xbox One version will be out ?this fall.?</p>
<p>Microsoft also showed off their Hololens augmented reality headset live onstage at E3.</p>
<p>The Hololens &mdash; which Microsoft announced a while ago yet we?ve never talked about it &mdash; are holographic glasses that let you see and interact with virtual objects and environments as if they existed in the real world. Unlike virtual reality headsets like the Oculus Rift, the Hololens is transparent so you can see the actual world around you.</p>
<p>During their presentation this week, Microsoft demoed this technology using everyone?s favorite game, Minecraft. Explaining it verbally won?t do it justice, so we have included a video of the demonstration in the show notes at Deemable.com. The presentation begins with a Microsoft developer wearing a Hololens playing Minecraft using an Xbox controller on a virtual screen on the wall he was looking at. He then gets up, stares at a table on stage and says ?Build World.? This results in the Hololens building a three dimensional version of the Minecraft world on top of the table, which the developer can move around and look at from different angles. He can also manipulate things by using voice commands and gestures.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xgakdcEzVwg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://www.polygon.com/2015/6/17/8788943/hololens-minecraft-demo">Polygon: Hololens hands-on review</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/davidthier/2015/05/05/report-microsofts-hololens-will-cost-significantly-more-400/">Forbes: Hololens will cost significantly more than $400</a></p>
<h2>St. Louis Cardinals allegedly hack the Houston Astros</h2>
<p>Time to talk about SPORTSBALL!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/06/17/sports/baseball/st-louis-cardinals-hack-astros-fbi.html">The St. Louis Cardinals are being investigated by the FBI and the Justice Department for allegedly hacking the Houston Astros</a>. What is a Cardinal or an Astro? A Cardinal is red birds that lives in Missouri and an Astro is a grey dog from the future that has a speech impediment. They get together to play sportsball with a baseball bat.</p>
<p>Why did the Cardinals hack the Astros? I have no idea. Were they trying to get secret sportsball techniques? Maybe. According to the New York Times, the database that was hacked contained statistics and values about the players and potential recruits.</p>
<p>The ?hack? looks like it was as complicated as using crappy passwords. Jeff Luhnow, who is now the Astro?s general manager was an executive at the Cardinals until 2011. He took some of the front office personnel from the Cardinals when he left. Investigators compared a list of passwords used by the staff when they worked for the Cardinals and they apparently used the same ones at the Astros.</p>
<h1>REVIEW</h1>
<p>Ray shares his experience with the food replacement product <a href="https://www.soylent.com/" target="_blank">Soylent</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_10106" style="width: 669px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/media/2015/06/soylent_pour.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-large wp-image-10106" src="/media/2015/06/soylent_pour-1024x813.jpg"  alt="Image credit: Soylent" width="659" height="523"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: Soylent</p></div>
<p>&mdash;</p>
<p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable&nbsp;dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/06/88-the-one-where-marketing-told-us-to-talk-about-jurassic-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-19.mp3" length="50394065" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#71 The Episode Where We Can&#8217;t Say Words In The Script</title>
		<link>/2015/02/71-the-episode-where-we-cant-say-words-in-the-script/</link>
		<comments>/2015/02/71-the-episode-where-we-cant-say-words-in-the-script/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 21:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cable Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iCar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lenovo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LoopPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Superfish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time Warner]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9619</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/02/BlogOMG-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Everything in the news was pretty shocking." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Alright, this week is your last week to jump ship. If you don&#8217;t like hearing tech news, you need to unsubscribe from this show now. Otherwise, you&#8217;re gonna be stuck listening to us talk about the latest tech news and <a href="/2015/02/71-the-episode-where-we-cant-say-words-in-the-script/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/02/71-the-episode-where-we-cant-say-words-in-the-script/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/02/BlogOMG-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Everything in the news was pretty shocking." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-9619-2" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2015-02-20.mp3?_=2"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2015-02-20.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2015-02-20.mp3</a></audio><p>Alright, this week is your last week to jump ship. If you don&rsquo;t like hearing tech news, you need to unsubscribe from this show now. Otherwise, you&rsquo;re gonna be stuck listening to us talk about the latest tech news and listen to us review apps and gadgets! After this week, we won&rsquo;t remind you any more. You can always just go subscribe&nbsp;to <a title="Subscribe to Ask Deemable Tech" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/ca/podcast/ask-deemable-tech-wjct/id960516412?mt=2" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Ask Deemable Tech</a> if you want&nbsp;to hear us answer tech questions though. We&rsquo;ll always be there for you.</p>
<p>If you <em>do </em>like hearing about the latest happenings in the tech world, and haven&rsquo;t <a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/ca/podcast/deemable-tech-wjct/id540595466?mt=2" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">subscribed to Deemable Tech</a> yet, get on it! And make sure to&nbsp;share us on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a> ? all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>And help us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://reddit.com/r/Deemable" target="_blank">reddit.com/r/Deemable</a> or <a href="//reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> either way, it will take you to the same place.</p>
<div id="attachment_9621" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2015/02/BlogOMG.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-9621 size-medium" src="/media/2015/02/BlogOMG-300x215.jpg"  alt="Everything in the news was pretty shocking." width="300" height="215"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Everything in the news this week was pretty shocking.</p></div>
<h2>This Weeks Run Down</h2>
<h3>Apparently the FAA thinks it is 1967</h3>
<p>This Sunday, the <a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/faa-offers-framework-to-legalize-commercial-drones/" target="_blank">FAA finally released its proposal for regulations on unmanned commercial aircraft</a>, a.k.a. drones. The proposed requirements, are surprisingly ? or unsurprisingly, depending on who you ask ? arcane and draconian.</p>
<p>The drones must be under 55 pounds or 25 kilograms. They can only be operated in daylight, and within the operator&rsquo;s line of sight! They have to fly under 500 feet, no faster than 100 mph (Which those two aren&rsquo;t unreasonable) But, they also can NEVER fly over anyone except for the people flying the drone.</p>
<p>This pretty much shoots down any plans that Amazon had for Prime Air since delivering packages with a drone, kinda requires the drone to be out of sight for it to be useful. And it would almost certainly have to fly over some people to get to my porch.</p>
<p>Some drone startups aren&rsquo;t too concerned though. Drones could possibly be used for some commercial purposes, <a href="http://news.wjct.org/post/rules-get-sorted-out-drones-may-transform-agriculture-industry" target="_blank">like a farmer surveying his field from the sky</a>.</p>
<h3>Lenovo got caught with its hand in the cookie jar</h3>
<p><a href="http://thenextweb.com/insider/2015/02/19/lenovo-caught-installing-adware-new-computers/" target="_blank">The Next Web</a> is reporting that Lenovo has been installing adware on laptops. The adware, called Superfish, inserts third-party ads into your Google Searches and other websites, even those running with secure encryption, just like the kind of malware that <i>doesn&rsquo;t</i> intentionally come with your new computer.</p>
<p>Once users started complaining about the ads Lenovo was quick to roll back the program and to post directions on its website about how to uninstall it.</p>
<p>Lenovo said,</p>
<blockquote><p><i>Superfish was previously included on some consumer notebook products shipped in a short window between September and December to help customers potentially discover interesting products while shopping. &nbsp;However, user feedback was not positive.</i></p></blockquote>
<p>Unfortunately security researchers have discovered that simply uninstalling the software is not enough. Superfish also include a ?root certificate&rsquo; that allows any program that gains access to it to perform what are known as ?man in the middle&rsquo; attacks, potentially compromising the security of sensitive user information like banking passwords.</p>
<p>Lenovo initially denied the security vulnerability, but is now saying that it will release new software that will completely remove Superfish and any security certificates related to it.</p>
<p>In the meantime, laptops with Superfish installed are currently available from stores such as Best Buy. <i>Caveat emptor.</i></p>
<p>After the story broke, a <a href="https://filippo.io/Badfish/">developer put together a website</a> that lets Lenovo laptop owners find out if they are affected by the program, and <a href="http://thenextweb.com/insider/2015/02/19/lenovo-posts-superfish-removal-instructions-fails-acknowledge-severity-problem/" target="_blank">Lenovo&rsquo;s current instructions</a> include how to uninstall the basic Superfish program.</p>
<h3>LoopPay sold out to Samsung.</h3>
<p>In an <a title="LoopPay, Samsung, and the Digital Wallet Platform" href="http://www.looppay.com/announcement/" target="_blank">announcement Wednesday, LoopPay</a>, the company that makes the electronic wallet/phone case for the iPhone, let everyone know that they have been bought by Samsung. They will become a wholly owned subsidiary of Samsung Electronics America, Inc.</p>
<p>They haven&rsquo;t said anything about incorporating the LoopPay Digital wallet platform into Samsung devices. However, it seems to&nbsp;support&nbsp;the rumors that the next Galaxy phone will probably have LoopPay built into it.</p>
<p>Ray recently <a href="//2015/01/68-sean-wears-two-neckties/">reviewed the LoopPay CardCase on a previous episode of Deemable Tech</a>.</p>
<h3>Apple iCar?</h3>
<p>Wired is reporting that according to a lawsuit filed by electric-car battery manufacturer A123 Systems, <a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/02/lawsuit-claims-apple-poaching-engineers-build-car-battery-division/" target="_blank">Apple has been poaching engineers for its own large-scale car battery division</a>. The lawsuit alleges that an A123 engineer has been helping Apple woo senior-level engineers over to their company. This is adding fuel to rumors that Apple is working on its own electric car.</p>
<p>Other things hinting at this: Apple has over 600 employees that used to work in the automotive industry, including 46 that were formerly with Tesla. Tesla CEO Elon Musk told Bloomberg earlier this month that Apple has been offering $250,000 signing bonuses to entice Tesla employees to leave.</p>
<p>Also, a mysterious van registered to Apple has been spotted driving around San Francisco with an array of equipment including cameras mounted on top. People are speculating that this could be for a self-driving car or a street-mapping system.</p>
<p>In another interview with Bloomberg, former <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2015-02-18/former-gm-ceo-akerson-cautions-apple-on-trials-of-making-cars" target="_blank">GM CEO Dan Akerson said Apple should stay away from making cars</a>. Akerson said &ldquo;They&rsquo;d better think carefully if they want to get into the hard-core manufacturing. We take steel, raw steel, and turn it into car. They have no idea what they&rsquo;re getting into if they get into that.?</p>
<p>Sounds a lot like <a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/09/tech-time-warp-of-the-week-watch-steve-ballmer-laugh-at-the-original-iphone/">Steve Balmer&rsquo;s advice to Apple</a> many years ago about getting into making phones.</p>
<h3>Cable Companies Behaving Badly</h3>
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2015/02/time-warner-cable-calls-customer-ct-after-she-reports-cable-box-problem/%20" target="_blank">A Time Warner Cable customer reported to Ars Technica </a>today that she received a letter from the company in which her first name had been changed to, well, a word we can&rsquo;t say on this podcast. It starts with a &lsquo;c.&rsquo;</p>
<p>The letter read, ?Dear C<span style="text-decoration: underline;">*#!</span>&nbsp;Martinez? and then went tried to convince the customer not to cancel her cable.</p>
<p>The other major US cable company, Comcast, has been in the news several times in the past few months for similar cases. Comcast customers have reported receiving notices from the company in which their names were changed to things like &nbsp;&ldquo;dummy,&rdquo; &ldquo;<a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2015/01/more-comcast-customers-write-in-report-name-changes-of-whore-dummy/">whore</a>&rdquo; and &ldquo;<a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2015/02/comcast-customer-says-she-got-a-bill-addressed-to-super-bitch/">super bitch</a>.&rdquo; Comcast and Time Warner Cable announced last year that they plan to merge, pending Federal approval. However, both companies are notorious for their poor customer service and stories like these will not help their case.</p>
<p>Time Warner Cable stated that the name change was due to the actions of a third-party vendor. It apologized to Mrs. Martinez and offered her a free year of cable.</p>
<p>&mdash;-</p>
<p>Have a comment for the show? Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="//reddit" target="_blank">deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<p><em>Photo credit: &ldquo;<a href="https://flic.kr/p/58aVnJ" target="_blank">Blog OMG!</a>&rdquo; by&nbsp;<a class="owner-name truncate" title="Go to Mike Licht's photostream" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/notionscapital/" data-track="attributionNameClick" data-rapid_p="26">Mike Licht</a>&nbsp;is used under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/" target="_blank">CC BY 2.0</a>.</em></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/02/71-the-episode-where-we-cant-say-words-in-the-script/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2015-02-20.mp3" length="27617108" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dale asks, &#8220;How can I change the email password on my Samsung Galaxy S4?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2014/10/dale-asks-can-change-email-password-samsung-galaxy-s4/</link>
		<comments>/2014/10/dale-asks-can-change-email-password-samsung-galaxy-s4/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 16:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tom Braun]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9268</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/10/samsung_galaxy_s4-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image Credit: Simon / Pixabay" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Q: I recently changed my e-mail password, and now my Samsung Galaxy S4 phone will not show my e-mails. I assume the old password is somehow encoded in the phone. I cannot find a way within the &#8220;setting&#8221; folder to <a href="/2014/10/dale-asks-can-change-email-password-samsung-galaxy-s4/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2014/10/dale-asks-can-change-email-password-samsung-galaxy-s4/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/10/samsung_galaxy_s4-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image Credit: Simon / Pixabay" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><strong>Q: </strong>I recently changed my e-mail password, and now my Samsung Galaxy S4 phone will not show my e-mails. I assume the old password is somehow encoded in the phone. I cannot find a way within the &ldquo;setting&rdquo; folder to put the new password in to access the e-mails. How can I now access my e-mails on the S4?<span id="more-9268"></span></p>
<p><strong>A: </strong>Dale, it sounds like you are looking in the settings for the email app, but you won&rsquo;t find it there!</p>
<div id="attachment_9284" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2014/10/samsung_galaxy_s4.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-9284" src="/media/2014/10/samsung_galaxy_s4-300x225.jpg"  alt="Image Credit: Simon / Pixabay" width="300" height="225"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image Credit: Simon / Pixabay</p></div>
<p>Android phones, including the Samsung Galaxy models, store all the big, important passwords, like email accounts and social media accounts, in the same place. You need to bring up &ldquo;settings&rdquo;. Not the settings for the email app, but the main settings menu that you get to from the desktop.</p>
<p>Then you need to scroll way down. You&rsquo;re looking for a section called &ldquo;Accounts&rdquo;. Keep scrolling down until you find it. Under that you should see an option called &ldquo;Email&rdquo;. Tap that. Then tap &ldquo;Settings&rdquo;. Then tap your email address again. Now you should see a page with a bunch of options, including one that says &ldquo;password&rdquo; &ndash; tap that and enter your new password.</p>
<p>Basically, any time you want to change a major password you have to go under &ldquo;Accounts&rdquo; under your main settings. Your email login, your Facebook login, your Twitter login, your LinkedIn login, it&rsquo;s all stored there. These are all apps that have deep, native integration into the Android operating system, so it actually makes some sense for them to be stored down in the main settings of the phone.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s pretty similar to how it is handled on the iPhone and iPad too. Under the Settings app, you tap &ldquo;Mail, Contacts, and Calendars&rdquo;, then tap the account and tap your email address, then enter the correct password.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/10/dale-asks-can-change-email-password-samsung-galaxy-s4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Samsung’s Galaxy Gear Will Be A Result of Samsung Not Copying Apple</title>
		<link>/2013/09/samsungs-galaxy-gear-will-result-samsung-copying-apple/</link>
		<comments>/2013/09/samsungs-galaxy-gear-will-result-samsung-copying-apple/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 17:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Weisbein]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Gear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung Watch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8149</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/repost-us-6890369-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Samsung Galaxy Gear Mockup" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />We are just two days aware from the big Samsung event where the company will be announcing the Galaxy Note III and the Galaxy Gear (smartwatch).  Yesterday, VentureBeat published an article showing off what they said was the Galaxy Gear, only to later be dismissed as a prototype of the Galaxy Gear by GigaOM.  Prototype or not, those images got me thinking: the Samsung Galaxy Gear is literally the first tech product (since 2007) Samsung is creating without having seen Apple’s own take prior to releasing their version (unless &#8230;<p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/09/samsungs-galaxy-gear-will-result-samsung-copying-apple/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/repost-us-6890369-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Samsung Galaxy Gear Mockup" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div class="rpuEmbedCode">
<div class="rpuArticle rpuRepost-F12817A0440264F277336DF34602203E-top rpuNoTitle" style="margin:0;padding:0;">
<script src="https://1.rp-api.com/rjs/repost-article.js?3" type="text/javascript" data-cfasync="false"></script><a href="http://s.tt/1JZUw" class="rpuThumb" rel="norewrite">
<p><img src="/media/2013/09/repost-us-6890369.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy Gear Mockup" width="650" height="433" class="alignright size-full wp-image-8151"><br></p></a><a href="http://s.tt/1JZUw" class="rpuTitle" rel="norewrite"><strong>Samsung&rsquo;s Galaxy Gear Will Be A Result of Samsung Not Copying Apple</strong></a> (via <a href="http://s.tt/1JZUw" class="rpuHost" rel="norewrite">http://www.besttechie.com/</a>)
<p class="rpuSnip">
We are just two days aware from the big Samsung event where the company will be announcing the Galaxy Note III and the Galaxy Gear (smartwatch). Yesterday, VentureBeat published an article showing off what they said was the Galaxy Gear, only to later be dismissed as a prototype of the Galaxy Gear by GigaOM. Prototype or not, those images got me thinking: the Samsung Galaxy Gear is literally the first tech product (since 2007) Samsung is creating without having seen Apple&rsquo;s own take prior to releasing their version (unless &hellip;
</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><!-- put the "tease", "jump" or "more" break here --><br></p><hr id="system-readmore" style="display: none;"><span id="more-8149"></span><!--break--><br><hr class="at-page-break" style="display: none;"><div class="rpuEmbedCode">
<div class="rpuArticle rpuRepostMain rpuRepost-F12817A0440264F277336DF34602203E-bottom" style="display:none;">&nbsp;</div>
<div style="display: none;"><!-- How to customize this embed: http://www.repost.us/article-preview/hash/f12817a0440264f277336df34602203e --></div>
</div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/09/samsungs-galaxy-gear-will-result-samsung-copying-apple/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
