<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Zombies</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/zombies/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>PlayStation Network Goes Down</title>
		<link>/2011/04/playstation-network-goes-down/</link>
		<comments>/2011/04/playstation-network-goes-down/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Ahn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Call of Duty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NetFlix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Outage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlayStation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlayStation 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PSN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zombies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=2695</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nazi Zombies, you are free to roam the earth for a little while longer as Sony&#8217;s PlayStation Network has been out of service since 4/20. The PlayStation Network is Sony&#8217;s equivalent to Xbox LIVE, which allows for PlayStation 3 users <a href="/2011/04/playstation-network-goes-down/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/04/playstation-network-goes-down/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p style="text-align: left"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/gadgetlab/2010/03/psn.jpg" alt="" width="660" height="309"></p>
<p style="text-align: left">Nazi Zombies, you are free to roam the earth for a little while longer  as Sony&rsquo;s PlayStation Network has been out of service since 4/20.</p>
<p>The PlayStation Network is Sony&rsquo;s equivalent to Xbox LIVE, which allows for PlayStation 3 users to download games, download or stream movies and music, and have access to other services. More importantly, the network serves as the infrastructure for people to connect and play each other in multiplayer games such as Call of Duty. Oddly enough, the  network failure happened to coincide with the release of several  brand  new games including Mortal Kombat, Portal 2, SOCOM 4, and  inFAMOUS 2&rsquo;s beta release. While access to the network is free, content such as Netflix must be paid for by users, leaving them wondering whether they will be reimbursed if the outage lasts any longer.</p>
<p>A little over a year ago, Sony users of the non-slim PS3 had a <a title="similar outage" href="http://blog.us.playstation.com/2010/03/01/latest-info-on-playstation-network-status/" target="_blank">similar outage</a> on their PlayStation Network that was &ldquo;caused by a bug in the clock functionality incorporated in the system.&rdquo; Patrick Seybold, the Senior Director of Corporate Communications &amp; Social Media, posted a message yesterday on Sony&rsquo;s <a title="PSN Blog" href="http://blog.us.playstation.com/2011/04/21/latest-update-on-psn-outage/" target="_blank">PlayStation Blog</a> that said, &ldquo;While we are investigating the cause of the Network outage, we wanted to  alert you that it may be a full day or two before we&rsquo;re able to get  the&nbsp;service completely back up and running. Thank you very much for your  patience while we work to resolve this matter. Please stay tuned  to&nbsp;this space for more details, and we&rsquo;ll update you again as soon as we  can.&rdquo;</p>
<p>While there are an estimated 70 million users on the network worldwide, Sony is unable to clarify how many people are currently affected by the outage. However, players from all over the world have taken their Zombie rage to  popular social media sites like Twitter and Facebook to express their  displeasure with Sony. Got some spare time since you can&rsquo;t own some newbs? Check out some of the tweets found by a quick search of <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/%23PSN" target="_blank">#PSN on Twitter.</a></p>
<p>&ndash; Update 4/23 &ndash;</p>
<p>Patrick Seybold has made <a title="post" href="http://blog.us.playstation.com/2011/04/22/update-on-playstation-network-qriocity-services/" target="_blank">another post</a> on the PlayStation Blog regarding the ongoing issue:</p>
<p>&ldquo;An external intrusion on our system has affected our PlayStation Network  and Qriocity services. In order to conduct a thorough investigation and  to verify the smooth and secure operation of our network services going  forward, we turned off PlayStation Network &amp; Qriocity services on  the evening of Wednesday, April 20th. Providing quality entertainment  services to our customers and partners is our utmost priority. We are  doing all we can to resolve this situation quickly, and we once again  thank you for your patience. We will continue to update you promptly as  we have additional information to share.&rdquo;<a title="Photo" href="http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/gadgetlab/2010/03/psn.jpg" target="_blank"></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="Photo" href="http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/gadgetlab/2010/03/psn.jpg" target="_blank">Photo</a> by <a title="Charlie Sorrel" href="http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/author/mistercharlie/" target="_blank">Charlie Sorrel</a> via <a title="Wired" href="http://www.wired.com/" target="_blank">Wired</a></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/04/playstation-network-goes-down/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
