<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; electromagnetic</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/electromagnetic/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Cellphones: &#8220;Possibly&#8221; Killing You</title>
		<link>/2011/06/cellphones-possibly-killing-you/</link>
		<comments>/2011/06/cellphones-possibly-killing-you/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 19:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Ahn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carcinogens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cellphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electromagnetic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IARC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radiation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radiofrequency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=3424</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Meeting in Lyon, France, Member&#8217;s of the World Health Organization formed a panel in late May to discuss the potential carcinogenic hazards from exposure to radiofrequency electromagnetic fields, like those emitted by cellular phones and other wireless communications devices. <a href="/2011/06/cellphones-possibly-killing-you/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/06/cellphones-possibly-killing-you/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://cache.gawkerassets.com/assets/images/4/2011/05/cellcancerwho.jpg" alt="" width="369" height="207"></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Meeting in Lyon, France, Member&rsquo;s of the World Health Organization formed a panel in late May to discuss the potential carcinogenic hazards from exposure to  radiofrequency electromagnetic fields, like those emitted by cellular  phones and other wireless communications devices. The panel, which represents the <a title="IARC" href="http://www.iarc.fr/en/media-centre/pr/2011/pdfs/pr208_E.pdf" target="_blank">International Agency for Research on Cancer</a> (IARC), consisted of 31 scientists from 14 different countries. While the group did not conduct any new research, the panel reviewed    numerous existing studies that focused on the health effects of the   radiofrequency  magnetic fields emitted from cellphones, and concluded that there is a <em>possibility</em> that exposure to these low levels of radiation  might induce long-term health risks, including an increased risk of cancer.</p>
<p>The IARC panel classified cellphones under the category<em> Group 2B, </em>the same category as   certain dry cleaning chemicals, pesticides such as DDT, engine    exhaust, lead, and various  other industrial chemicals. However, the cellphone  industry was quick to point out that pickled vegetables and coffee also  made the <em>2B</em> designation, which is <a title="IARC" href="http://www.iarc.fr/en/media-centre/pr/2011/pdfs/pr208_E.pdf" target="_blank">defined by the IARC</a> below:</p>
<p>&ldquo;This category is used for agents for which there is limited evidence  of  carcinogenicity in humans and less than sufficient evidence of   carcinogenicity in experimental animals. It may also be used when there   is inadequate evidence of carcinogenicity in humans but there is   sufficient evidence of carcinogenicity in experimental animals. In some   instances, an agent for which there is inadequate evidence of   carcinogenicity in humans and less than sufficient evidence of   carcinogenicity in experimental animals together with supporting   evidence from mechanistic and other relevant data may be placed in this   group. An agent may be classified in this category solely on the basis   of strong evidence from mechanistic and other relevant data.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Major medical groups such as  the American Cancer Society and   the National Cancer Institute have reassured the public that there is little concern in regards to adverse health effects because cellphones emit nonionizing radiation &ndash; which are supposedly non-cancerous. In February, however, researchers from the National Institutes of Health published a study which found that less than an hour of cellphone usage can speed up brain activity at the area nearest to the phone antenna. This study was one of the most significant of its kind to document the measurable effects of the radio frequency signals to the brain.</p>
<p><a title="Brain Activity" href="http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/02/22/cellphone-use-tied-to-changes-in-brain-activity/" target="_blank">The New York Times reported</a>:</p>
<p>&ldquo;In the past, any concerns about the  health effects of cellphones have  been largely dismissed because the  radiofrequency waves emitted from  the devices are believed to be  benign. Cellphones emit nonionizing  radiation, waves of energy that are  too weak to break chemical bonds or  to set off the DNA damage known to  cause cancers. Scientists have said  repeatedly that there is no known  biological mechanism to explain how  nonionizing radiation might lead to  cancer or other health problems.</p>
<p>But the new study opens up an  entirely new potential area of  research. Although an increase in brain  glucose metabolism happens  during normal brain function, the question  is whether repeated  artificial stimulation as a result of exposure to  electromagnetic  radiation might have a detrimental effect.</p>
<p>Although speculative, one theory  about how an artificial increase in brain glucose metabolism could be  harmful is that it could potentially lead to the creation of molecules  called free radicals, which in excess can damage healthy cells. Or it  may be that repeated stimulation by electromagnetic radiation could set  off an inflammatory response, which studies suggest is associated with a  number of health problems, including cancer.&rdquo;</p>
<p>While there are no official recommendations for the public following the   study, the use of hands-free devices and text messaging may lower   exposure to radiofrequency electromagnetic waves emitted by cellphones. Even though all of this may seem alarming, the <em>Group 2B</em> designation simply means that there may (or may not) be a <em>possible</em> link between cellphone usage and certain forms of cancer. In other words, this is fearmongering at its finest, and <a title="Colbert" href="http://gizmodo.com/5807815/stephen-colbert-solves-this-whole-cellphone-radiation-problem" target="_blank">Stephen Colbert has already solved the problem</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="Photo" href="http://cache.gawkerassets.com/assets/images/4/2011/05/cellcancerwho.jpg" target="_blank">Photo</a> by <a title="Sam Biddle" href="http://gizmodo.com/people/SamBiddle/" target="_blank">Sam Biddle</a> via <a title="Gizmodo" href="http://gizmodo.com/" target="_blank">Gizmodo</a></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/06/cellphones-possibly-killing-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
