<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; One Spark</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/one-spark/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>2014 One Spark creators we are excited about</title>
		<link>/2014/04/one-spark-creators-excited/</link>
		<comments>/2014/04/one-spark-creators-excited/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 13:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crowdfunding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jacksonville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One Spark]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8696</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is our first day at One Spark. We haven&#8217;t seen any creators yet. But what we did is we searched through the One Spark website to see which creators we definitely wanted to check out while we were here. <a href="/2014/04/one-spark-creators-excited/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2014/04/one-spark-creators-excited/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p dir="ltr"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-8698" alt="One Spark logo" src="//media/2014/04/One-Spark-logo-300x199.jpg" width="300" height="199">This is our first day at One Spark. We haven&rsquo;t seen any creators yet. But what we did is we searched through the <a href="http://www.beonespark.com/">One Spark website</a> to see which creators we definitely wanted to check out while we were here. Now, this is in no way saying that these are the best tech creators here at One Spark, but these are the ones that got our attention.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.beonespark.com/discover/creator_projects/verti-bluetooth-item-finder">Verti Bluetooth item finder</a> &ndash;&nbsp;Urban Grind Coffee Company (50 N Laura)</p>
<p dir="ltr">This is similar to the <a href="http://www.thetileapp.com/">Tile</a> you may have seen advertised on Facebook. This is a small bluetooth device that you can attach to your key ring, or stick to something. If you lose your item, you can open the app on your iPhone or android smartphone, and find the item.</p>
<p dir="ltr">What makes the Verti different is that it has a button on it. So, if you lose your phone, you can press the button on the Verti and find your phone. Also, according to the creator, the Verti will have a much larger range 200 feet instead of the normal 50-100 feet.&nbsp;It also has motion detection so you can tell if an item has moved.</p>
<p dir="ltr">What I want to know is if you can replace the battery. A lot of these Bluetooth finders have batteries that cannot be replaced, Which means you have to buy a new one every time the battery dies.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.beonespark.com/discover/creator_projects/park-genius">Park Genius</a> &ndash; North Bank Riverwalk (341 South Hogan Street)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Instead of replacing the existing parking meters with electronic ones that can cost tens of thousands of dollars, their idea is to just augment them with a mobile app. All the city has to do is put a sticker on the parking meter that tells parkers that they can pay on the iOS or Android app, and the parking enforcement can check on their mobile device to see if you paid or not.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.beonespark.com/discover/creator_projects/world-s-lightest-electric-vehicle">Marbel</a> &ndash;&nbsp;SunTrust Building (76 N Laura Street)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Ultralight electric skateboard that can travel up to 10 miles with a top speed of 20 mph, and only weighs 9.9 pounds. The coolest part is that it also has an iOS app that you can use to control the ride!&nbsp;My inner twelve-year-old boy is thrilled.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.beonespark.com/discover/creator_projects/bucketwish">Bucketwish</a> &ndash;&nbsp;Jacksonville Bank Building (100 N Laura Street)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Bucketwish is a social network where you can post your wish list. It gives a fun way to share the crazy dreams and wishes that you want to do with your family, friends and strangers, and they can contribute to them and help make them happen.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The idea is, it&rsquo;s kind of like Make-A-Wish or Dreams Come True, but not just for kids with life threatening illnesses.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The idea behind Bucketwish sounds odd. Who would want to pay for you to live out your dream, but honestly Kickstarter would&rsquo;ve sounded insane just five years ago.</p>
<p dir="ltr">We&rsquo;ve seen this kind of thing happen on crowd funding sites, where someone will do it for someone else, Like what happened with the bus driver who was being harassed by the students. Someone saw that terrible video and then turn around and raised enough money for her to go on vacation. There was such a huge response, that he ended up raising over $750,000.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.beonespark.com/discover/creator_projects/wazinit">WaZINIT</a> &ndash;&nbsp;SunTrust Building (76 N Laura Street)</p>
<p dir="ltr">WaZINIT is an app that lets you scan the bar code of food products to see if they contain anything that you are trying to avoid. So, if you are allergic to peanuts, or you just don&rsquo;t like artificial sweeteners, WaZINIT would let you know whether to avoid it or not.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It reminded me of an app that we talked about on our show one time called secretly vegan. Secretly Vegan lists common supermarket products that are vegan. WaZINIT takes it one step further.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.beonespark.com/discover/creator_projects/get-brash">Brash</a> &ndash; The Jacksonville Landing, 2 Independent Drive</p>
<p dir="ltr">A universal gift card that is randomly filled with money throughout the day by various stores. But the money is only on the card for a limited amount of time.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The example they give on their profile page really explains it best. John Doe would get a text message saying &ldquo;Hey John, you just received a $23 gift from Kohl&rsquo;s! Hurry, that money is only good for 72 hours. BTW Kohl&rsquo;s has 20% all coats this week!&rdquo; John goes to Kohl&rsquo;s and uses his Brash Card like a normal gift card. But, if John doesn&rsquo;t spend that gift in time, that $23 goes directly back to Kohl&rsquo;s. Merchants are guaranteed nearly full return on marketing investment, consumers get a few extra bucks.&rdquo; Everybody is happy!</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.beonespark.com/discover/creator_projects/alerttheboss-com">Alert The Boss</a> &ndash;&nbsp;Visit Jacksonville (208 North Laura Street)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Alert the Boss is a text messaging service that allows customers to interact with businesses before they post a negative comment or complaint on a site like Yelp or Urbanspoon.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Evan Diamond from <a href="http://deemable.com/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/">Alert The Boss was on Deemable Tech last year</a> to talk about it before One Spark last year. At the time, Alert The Boss was really still just a concept. They were literally still working on the prototype right up until we started recording the podcast. In the year since then Alert the Boss has grown tremendously, and is a really great service.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.beonespark.com/discover/creator_projects/switchtick">SwitchTick</a> &ndash;&nbsp;The Jacksonville Landing (2 Independent Drive)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Switch take is a website that allows you to exchange items with other people. So, for example if you had a microwave that you no longer need, but you need a new recliner, you could trade someone for a recliner on SwitchTick</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.beonespark.com/discover/creator_projects/crtfreejax">#crtfreejax</a> &ndash;&nbsp;South Laura Street</p>
<p dir="ltr">This is something that we&rsquo;ve talked about on our radio segment and on our podcast before, you cannot just throw out computers, especially computer monitors. #crtfreejax wants to fabricate a machine that can recycle the Cathode Ray Tubes, which are the most difficult and dangerous part of computers.</p>
<h3 dir="ltr">Two projects that aren&rsquo;t tech related that we have to mention:</h3>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.beonespark.com/discover/creator_projects/dawgtown-the-animated-motion-picture">Dawgtown</a> &ndash; Icon Boutique (108 East Adams Street)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Dawgown is a hand-drawn animated movie by my friend Justin Murphy about a pitbull that is trying to escape the world of underground dogfighting. And, Al Letson, the host of State of the Re:Union is the voice of the MC in the movie.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.beonespark.com/discover/creator_projects/chomp-chips">Chomp Chips</a> &ndash;&nbsp;Chomp Chomp (106 W Adams Street)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Curry. Potato. Chips. That&rsquo;s all I have to say. If you haven&rsquo;t had them&hellip; you haven&rsquo;t lived. In fact, I have to wrap this up so I can go get some right now.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="2014 One Spark creators we are excited about" data-link="/2014/04/one-spark-creators-excited/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="2014 One Spark creators we are excited about" data-link="/2014/04/one-spark-creators-excited/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/04/one-spark-creators-excited/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Episode 36 &#8211; Printers Are Evil, But Fans Are Awesome!</title>
		<link>/2013/04/episode-36-printers-are-evil-but-fans-are-awesome/</link>
		<comments>/2013/04/episode-36-printers-are-evil-but-fans-are-awesome/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 03:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP printers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One Spark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Urban Spoon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7138</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/04/FansAreAwesome-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Fans Are Awesome" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Hey everybody! After recovering from One Spark, the Deemable Tech podcast is back with tech questions to answer. Thanks so much to everyone that stopped to see us at One Spark, especially everyone that voted for us, and took pictures <a href="/2013/04/episode-36-printers-are-evil-but-fans-are-awesome/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/04/episode-36-printers-are-evil-but-fans-are-awesome/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/04/FansAreAwesome-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Fans Are Awesome" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/04/FansAreAwesome.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright wp-image-7140" title="Fans Like Jose Are Awesome!" alt="Fans Like Jose Are Awesome!" src="//media/2013/04/FansAreAwesome-768x1024.jpg"  width="237" height="316"></a>Hey everybody! After recovering from One Spark, the Deemable Tech podcast is back with tech questions to answer. Thanks so much to everyone that stopped to see us at One Spark, especially everyone that voted for us, and took pictures with us, like Jose! We received 222 votes, which gave us $1,041.30 of the crowd fund. It&rsquo;s only a small part of what we need to fund a full hour-long public radio show, but it&rsquo;s a start! The best part was getting to meet our fans, and getting to tell over 1,500 people in person, face-to-face, about Deemable Tech. Now, without further ado, on to the show!</p>
<p><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-7138-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-04-29.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-04-29.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-04-29.mp3</a></audio><br><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-04-29.mp3">Episode 36 &ndash; Printers Are Evil, But Fans Are Awesome!</a></p>
<p><strong>DRAFT TRANSCRIPT</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, and this is Deemable Tech, technology worth talking about, and tech help worth listening to.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? Give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at <a href="mailto:questions@deemable.com">questions@deemable.com</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: This week&rsquo;s episode of the Deemable Tech podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p dir="ltr">And, by audible.com &ndash; get a FREE audiobook download at <a href="http://www.audibletrial.com/Deemable">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a> Over 100,000 titles to choose from for your iPhone, Android, Kindle or mp3 player.</p>
<p dir="ltr">*recap One Spark*</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Hey, let&rsquo;s answer some questions.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: We have a voicemail from Joti:</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Great question Joti! I remember meeting you at One Spark and discussing this. Thanks for sending this in!</p>
<p dir="ltr">So there are really a lot of great ?food&rsquo; apps out there for smart phones. Some are Vegan-specific, but some are general purpose apps which have Vegan and Vegetarian options.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Now Ray, I&rsquo;m not vegetarian. Actually, I&rsquo;m pretty&hellip; carnivorous. Are you?</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: *vamps* I&rsquo;m neither for it or against it. I like food</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Well even though I&rsquo;m not too likely to order the tofu-burger at a restaurant, I do have a app that I love and always use to find restaurants. It&rsquo;s Urban Spoon.</p>
<p dir="ltr">If you don&rsquo;t have Urban Spoon I suggest you get it regardless of your cuisine preferences. It is a really polished app, and more importantly it&rsquo;s widely used so it has a lot of accurate, updated information which is what you want in this kind of app.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I wanted to see if you can search for vegan restaurants with the UrbanSpoon app and you can, or at least for vegetarian restaurants. From the home screen select ?browse&rsquo; and then select ?types of food&rsquo; from the next screen. Then scroll down until you find ?vegetarian&rsquo;. Now, all you vegan folks, I realize that being vegan is not the same as being vegetarian. Stay with me here!</p>
<p dir="ltr">On the list of vegetarian restaurants I selected one that I know is vegan-friendly. If you scroll down the restaurant&rsquo;s profile a bit you&rsquo;ll see a list of categories applied to this restaurant. Hopefully if you pick a restaurant that is vegan friendly it will have the ?vegan friendly&rsquo; category listed here. When you see that click it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Voila! Now you get a listing of nearby restaurants that are ?vegan-friendly&rsquo;. And I&rsquo;m no vegan, but just eyeballing the list for my area it looks pretty accurate.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Another popular general-purpose food app is Yelp. If you have the Yelp app you can search for ?vegan&rsquo; from the main page, and it will pop up a list of restaurants. Actually, since Yelp isn&rsquo;t restaurant specific it will show you results like the nearby Grassroots Natural Market.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: UrbanSpoon didn&rsquo;t bring that up because it&rsquo;s not a restaurant.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: But it&rsquo;s a great resource for vegans and if you&rsquo;re vegan you would probably want to know about it. That&rsquo;s the good and bad thing about Yelp: it will give you more than just restaurants.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But Tom, you said there were some vegan-specific apps?</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Right. On Android, there&rsquo;s a vegan app called <a title="Happy Cow Vegin' Out Guide on the Amazon Appstore" href="http://amzn.to/186Ie24" target="_blank">Happy Cow: Vegin&rsquo; Out</a>. It works a lot like Yelp. The list it returned is pretty comprehensive and it did include the natural market. A lot of the restaurants don&rsquo;t have ratings, though. I suppose if this app takes off people will help it keep its information more up-to-date.</p>
<p dir="ltr">There are also numerous vegan recipe apps, like <a title="I'm Hungry: Vegetarian Recipes on the Amazon Appstore" href="http://amzn.to/ZuzEHp" target="_blank">I&rsquo;m Hungry: Vegetarian Recipes</a>. And if you can&rsquo;t find a vegan-specific store or restaurant and you&rsquo;re in a hurry, there&rsquo;s an app called <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mitchsaid.sveganfree">Secretly Vegan Free</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Wait, Tom, this app finds places that are&hellip; secretly free of vegans? Isn&rsquo;t that the opposite of what Joti wants?</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Hah, no, it sounds like that though. There should probably be a comma in the title: Secretly Vegan, Free. See, there&rsquo;s also a paid edition.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Ok that makes sense.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Secretly Vegan</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: (Free)</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: lists common supermarket products that are vegan. So you can hit up your local Qwik-e-Mart confident that the stuff you&rsquo;re grabbing off the shelves is vegan-approved.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Ray, what about apps for the iPhone and iPad?</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Well, there&rsquo;s an app called VeganXpress that is supposed to be on Android and iPhone that works like Secretly Vegan&hellip;Free. It tells you what you can find at fast food chains and restaurants that are vegan. It&rsquo;s $2.99 in the App Store, but I haven&rsquo;t been able to find it in the Google Play store, even though it is supposed to be in there.</p>
<p dir="ltr">There&rsquo;s a lot of vegan apps iOS, including <a title="Go Vegan!" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/go-vegan!/id480825777" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Go Vegan with Sarah Kramer</a> which is a vegan recipe app with over 50 recipes in it that&rsquo;s $4.99. There&rsquo;s also, <a title="Animal-Free" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/animal-free/id357422989" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Animal-Free</a> which is kind of like Secretly Vegan Free. With the app, you can scan the UPC code or type in the name of the food to determine if the contents of the food is animal or plant derived.</p>
<p dir="ltr">If you&rsquo;re a Food Truck lover, like I am, check out <a title="Roaming Hunger" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/roaming-hunger-v1.0/id423850578" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Roaming Hunger Food Truck Finder</a>. It shows you where all of the food trucks are within up to a 50 mile radius. You can limit the search to just trucks with vegan options. Unfortunately, the app does not include Jacksonville food trucks! Boo! I&rsquo;ve already complained to the app developer.</p>
<p dir="ltr">If you&rsquo;re thinking about going Vegan, but you haven&rsquo;t made the jump yet, check out <a title="21 Day Vegan Kickstart" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/21-day-vegan-kickstart/id390508658" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">21-Day Vegan Kickstart by Physicians Committee for Responsible Medicine</a>. ?The 21-Day Vegan Kickstart app? and I am reading this directly from the description, ?gives you recipes and resources to improve and regain your health and includes step-by-step recipe photos.?</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Ray writes&hellip; wait, I didn&rsquo;t write this.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: I think there&rsquo;s another guy named Ray, Ray.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Is his name Rayburn Hollister III?</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: No, probably not.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Yeah, I&nbsp;didn&rsquo;t&nbsp;think so. Anyway, Ray-who&rsquo;s-not-me writes:</p>
<p dir="ltr">I recently had a problem getting my HP 1300 All In One printer back on line using a Vista computer. When attempting to cancel an overlong print job, the printer was turned off and an attempt to cancel the print job by going to the printer icon and right clicking to cancel the job was made, but then the printer could not be put back online. I tried to (1) right click the printer icon to put back online, (2) went to printer properties and unchecked the print offline box, (3) unplugged and replugged the USB and power cables to the printer, (4) rebooted the computer, (5) uninstalled and attempted to reinstall the printer, and (6) downloaded the printer driver using both windows update and the HP web sites, all to no avail. Finally I (7) restored the computer to an earlier time when the printer was working and this fixed the problem. At one point when I was attempting to delete the printer, the circular icon continued to rotate indicating either that (1) the computer was in a continuous loop or (2) that the program had stopped working or was taking much too long, or (3) most probably the program was unresponsive. Why could I have had so much trouble getting the printer back online? I enjoy your show. Thanks for any suggestions to prevent this from happening again and/or how to get the printer back online short of restoring the computer OS to an earlier time.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Well Other-Ray, thanks for the question. It sounds like you did all the right things and took all the right steps. You unplugged the printer from the computer, power cycled both the computer and the printer, plugged the printer back in. When that didn&rsquo;t work you checked for updated drivers on HP&rsquo;s website. When even that didn&rsquo;t work, you uninstalled and reinstalled the printer software.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Those steps should have fixed the printer.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: So&hellip; why didn&rsquo;t they?</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Well Ray, there is only one possible conclusion: printers are evil.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Evil?</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Yes. They are malignant devices manufactured in the bowels of Hell. They were designed by the devil to bring pain and suffering to mankind.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Wow, okay Tom&hellip;</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Ray, do you know what blood is? It&rsquo;s Satan&rsquo;s printer ink.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: I&rsquo;m getting the impression you really don&rsquo;t like printers, Tom.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: You&rsquo;re picking up on that, are you?</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Yes. So why do you hate printers so much? What did they ever do to you?</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Ray, I&rsquo;ve told you I spent about a year living in Amsterdam, right?</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Right.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Well I was working as a social work volunteer for a half-way house there. I did all kinds of jobs there, but of course when they found out about my IT background they put me to work troubleshooting computer issues.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Do you know what 90% of the computer issues I had to fix were, Ray?</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: I think I can guess&hellip;</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: PRINTERS! PRINTERS PRINTERS PRINTERS! And it was always the same story: ?Oh, it was working normally and then I tried to print and it quit working for no reason.? And then if you were really lucky you power-cycled everything, unplugged the printer and plugged it back in, and it worked. If you weren&rsquo;t lucky, before you knew it you were at the local computer shop buying a new printer. Which would work fine for a couple of weeks before the inevitable happened&hellip;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Anyway, sorry, Other Ray, but there&rsquo;s no good reason your printer stopped working, other than that one day it&rsquo;s black soul awoke full of hatred for mankind and it took it out on you.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: So, anything you can add as far as suggestions for troubleshooting printers? Other than calling an exorcist?</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Well, I guess there are a couple of things. First, avoid pausing or cancelling printer jobs at all cost. That seems to inevitably cause printers to start spinning their wheels. To avoid having a big print job that runs amok, print big documents in chunks. Do ten, twenty pages at a time. That way you can make sure it&rsquo;s printing correctly before you throw a hundred pages of precious printer ink down the drain.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Other Ray mentioned he has an HP. HP actually has a diagnostic tool you can run to identify printer issues. I don&rsquo;t know how effective it would have been in this case, but it&rsquo;s worth a shot. We&rsquo;ll put <a href="http://h10025.www1.hp.com/ewfrf/wc/document?docname=c02762272&amp;lc=en&amp;cc=us&amp;dlc=en">a link to where you can download it</a> in the show notes. This utility tool works on Windows XP and up, but sadly not on Mac OS.</p>
<p dir="ltr">There is one last trick you can try when your printer is giving you the evil eye: restarting the printer service.</p>
<ul><li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Click on START</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">And then Go to RUN, which should pop up a small box for you.</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">In the Box type &ldquo;services.msc&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">A New pop up box should appear in front of you.</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">In that Box to go &ldquo;STANDARD&rdquo; and look for &ldquo;Print Spooler&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Just do a right click on that and click on Restart/Refresh</p>
</li>
</ul><p dir="ltr">Hopefully, maybe that will do the trick and get your printer running. But, I won&rsquo;t make any promises. Because Printers. Are. Evil.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Erica writes: I have a cheap Android phone on the Walmart 1 on 1 plan. I want to know what is a good, cheap app to download and edit photos on Android.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Thanks for the question Erica. Well, as is usually the case with Android, there are tons of photo editing apps out there. And many of them are free.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Just go to play.google.com/apps and search for ?photo editor&rsquo;. The <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sec.android.mimage.photoretouching&amp;feature=search_result#?t=W251bGwsMSwxLDEsImNvbS5zZWMuYW5kcm9pZC5taW1hZ2UucGhvdG9yZXRvdWNoaW5nIl0.">one I use came with my Samsung Galaxy S3</a> and it&rsquo;s called, inventively, ?Photo Editor&rsquo;, but you can also download it for free. We&rsquo;ll have a link in the show notes.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Another very popular app is <a title="PicSay Pro on the Amazon Appstore" href="http://amzn.to/15T9Ngc" target="_blank">PicSay</a>. PicSay has both a free and pro version. It has many of the same features, plus it allows you to export images from the app to Facebook or wherever you like.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Both of these apps allow you to apply your usual filters, like sepia toning or color inversion. You can also crop, rotate, sharpen and things like that. One thing I like is that both of them allow you to apply effects to the image by touch. So if you want to lighten part of an image you just run your finger over that part. That&rsquo;s pretty cool.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So I hope that helps you out, Erika. Generally speaking the benefit of having an Android is that the Google Play Market is loaded with free apps for everything. So when I need an app for something I&rsquo;ll usually download the top two or three based on starred ratings and then try them out for myself.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Thanks for all your questions, and keep them coming. Call us at our toll-free number, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com. Also, subscribe to the show! Search for Deemable Tech on iTunes or point your favorite podcast app to dmbl.co/pod.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Our producer is Sean Birch. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, and this is Deemable Tech.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Thanks for listening. Have a great week.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Episode 36 - Printers Are Evil, But Fans Are Awesome!" data-link="/2013/04/episode-36-printers-are-evil-but-fans-are-awesome/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Episode 36 - Printers Are Evil, But Fans Are Awesome!" data-link="/2013/04/episode-36-printers-are-evil-but-fans-are-awesome/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/04/episode-36-printers-are-evil-but-fans-are-awesome/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-04-29.mp3" length="35243154" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recovering from One Spark!</title>
		<link>/2013/04/recovering-from-one-spark/</link>
		<comments>/2013/04/recovering-from-one-spark/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 20:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One Spark]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7131</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="108" src="/media/2013/04/boy_sleeping_on_couch-e1366661515609-150x108.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="That&#039;s what Tom and Ray feel like this week after One Spark. :-)" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Hey folks, We just wanted to let you know that we did not do a podcast last night. You probably already figured that out since there was no new episode to download on your podcast reader. Tom, Sean and I <a href="/2013/04/recovering-from-one-spark/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/04/recovering-from-one-spark/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="108" src="/media/2013/04/boy_sleeping_on_couch-e1366661515609-150x108.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="That&#039;s what Tom and Ray feel like this week after One Spark. :-)" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/04/boy_sleeping_on_couch.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-7132" alt="He only made it this far" src="//media/2013/04/boy_sleeping_on_couch-300x217.jpg"  width="300" height="217"></a>Hey folks,</p>
<p>We just wanted to let you know that we did not do a podcast last night. You probably already figured that out since there was no new episode to download on your podcast reader. Tom, Sean and I (and Amber) are exhausted&nbsp;from One Spark, and we would probably babble incoherently&nbsp;if we got behind the microphones. (Hush, whoever said we already babble incoherently!) Thank you to everyone that came out to One Spark and voted for us. It was immensely humbling, and tons of fun, to meet so many of our fans that hear our segments on WJCT 89.9 FM and subscribe to the podcast. Now that One Spark is over, we&rsquo;ll get back to working on the Deemable Tech app and back to recording more shows and answering more tech help questions!</p>
<p>Thanks for reading, and have a great week! ?</p>
<p>&ndash; Ray</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Recovering from One Spark! " data-link="/2013/04/recovering-from-one-spark/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Recovering from One Spark! " data-link="/2013/04/recovering-from-one-spark/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/04/recovering-from-one-spark/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Episode 34 &#8211; We Made It! It&#8217;s All Your Fault! Thank You!</title>
		<link>/2013/03/episode-34-we-made-it-its-all-your-fault/</link>
		<comments>/2013/03/episode-34-we-made-it-its-all-your-fault/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 02:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App Store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Audible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disable Java]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I.M.A.G.I.C.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IMAGIC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jaibroken]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[java]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One Spark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S2]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7026</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/03/YouGetADeemableTechApp-e1364179811729-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="You Get A Deemable Tech App And You Get a Deemable Tech App. Everyone Gets A Deemable Tech App!!" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />On today&#8217;s episode we talk about when you should disable your Java, how to voice dial from a Samsung Galaxy S2, and how to send multiple pdfs from an iPad. Then, we were joined in the studio by Kai Kohl <a href="/2013/03/episode-34-we-made-it-its-all-your-fault/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/03/episode-34-we-made-it-its-all-your-fault/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/03/YouGetADeemableTechApp-e1364179811729-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="You Get A Deemable Tech App And You Get a Deemable Tech App. Everyone Gets A Deemable Tech App!!" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/03/YouGetADeemableTechApp.png" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-7030" alt="You Get A Deemable Tech App And You Get a Deemable Tech App. Everyone Gets A Deemable Tech App!!" src="//media/2013/03/YouGetADeemableTechApp-300x210.png"  width="300" height="210"></a></p>
<p>On today&rsquo;s episode we talk about when you should disable your Java, how to voice dial from a Samsung Galaxy S2, and how to send multiple pdfs from an iPad. Then, we were joined in the studio by Kai Kohl (NOT Khan, our apologies!) of <a href="theimagic.com">The I.M.A.G.I.C.</a>, a creation for One Spark. Listen in to find out about the awesome project that he&rsquo;s working on to bring an interactive gaming museum to Jacksonville.</p>
<p>We met the goal for <a href="http://dmbl.co/kick" target="_blank">Deemable Tech&rsquo;s Kickstarter Project</a>! We are starting work on the Deemable Tech app now. If you&rsquo;re reading this before March 25th at 7:00 PM you still have time to support our project. Any amount, $1, 5, 10, 15, 20, 50, 100, etc. helps. Click the link above and click the green Back This Pledge button. Thank you in advance!</p>
<p>Make sure to <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">subscribe to the show in iTunes by clicking here</a>, or <a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech Podcast!" href="http://dmbl.co/pod">subscribe to the show in another podcast reader by clicking here</a>. Also, make sure to leave us a review in iTunes. The more reviews we have the higher we&rsquo;ll be listed in iTunes and the more listeners will see our show!</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-7026-2" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-03-25.mp3?_=2"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-03-25.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-03-25.mp3</a></audio><p><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-03-25.mp3" target="_blank">Download Episode 34 &ndash; We Made It! It&rsquo;s All Your Fault! Thank You!</a></p>
<p>Need tech help? Got a problem or tech question about your computer, phone or tablet? Give us a call and leave us a voice mail at 1-888-972-9868, or send us an email to questions at deemable dot com. We&rsquo;ll answer them on the show.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.17em;">TRANSCRIPT</span></p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, and this is Deemable Tech, technology worth talking about, and tech help worth listening to.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? Give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at <a href="mailto:questions@deemable.com">questions@deemable.com</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: This week&rsquo;s episode of the Deemable Tech podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p dir="ltr">And, by audible.com &ndash; get a FREE audiobook download at <a href="http://www.audibletrial.com/Deemable">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a> Over 100,000 titles to choose from for your iPhone, Android, Kindle or mp3 player.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Today on the show, we&rsquo;ll be talking about when you should disable your Java.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Spoiler alert, the answer is <em>now</em>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: And, how to voice dial from a Samsung Galaxy S2</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: And how to send multiple pdfs from an iPad, and later in the show, we&rsquo;ll be joined in the studio by Kai Kohl of The I.M.A.G.I.C., a creation for One Spark. So, stay tuned for that. Let&rsquo;s jump right into our questions.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Skip writes: I use a Samsung Galaxy S II Skyrocket. I can use voice to create email, texts, enter stuff on the calendar, etc. However, I cannot figure how to use voice to dial, the way I used to on a BB phone. Can you assist?</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Thanks Skip! You know Ray, I had a revelation the other day.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Oh really?</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: What does the ?S&rsquo; in Samsung Galaxy S&hellip; whatever&hellip; stand for?</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Sumptuous?</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Wow, that&rsquo;s one that hadn&rsquo;t occurred to me. No Ray, I&rsquo;m pretty sure it&rsquo;s supposed to stand for ?Samsung&rsquo;. After all, S-Voice, S-Memo, S-Beam&hellip; those are all native Samsung apps where the S clearly stands for ?Samsung&rsquo;.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: But in that case we&rsquo;ve been saying the Samsung Galaxy Samsung 3.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Exactly! It&rsquo;s stupid. And the S is so generic. Why don&rsquo;t they go with Sam? Or Samantha? It could be like Siri, only&hellip; Sammy.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: *vamps*</p>
<p dir="ltr">Anyway, Tom, you still have not helped this poor gentleman out with his phone problem in any way.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Oh, right. Well, to bring up voice commands on the Samsung Galaxy Samsung 2 Skyrocket</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: *laughs*</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: You simply hold down the search button for a few seconds. Or you double-tap the menu button. One of those should bring up S-Voice and then you can say ?Call Ray Hollister? and it should call Ray. There were a few different versions of the Samsung 2, I mean S2, so you may have to experiment to find out which one method for you.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But it sounds like Skip already knows how to operate voice commands. After all he&rsquo;s using to do emailing and texting. Voice dialing is not separate from those functions so there isn&rsquo;t any reason for it to not work when everything else does. Not sure what&rsquo;s going on there.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The good news is, the GS2 runs Android. And on Android, if a stock app isn&rsquo;t working for you can always just download a different app. Choice Dialer Plus has gotten some good reviews. Another popular voice app for Android is Vlingo. That&rsquo;s V-lingo. So if you still can&rsquo;t get voice dialer to work on your native app, try downloading one of those.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Hope that helps, Skip! Enjoy using your Samsung Galaxy Samsung II Skyrocket!</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Last week on Morning Edition we told people that they needed to disable Java, <em>now</em>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Right, Tom and I had talked about it on the show a couple of weeks ago while you were out, Tom.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Right, but we felt it was so important for people to do that we covered it again in the Morning Edition spot, and we setup a page at <a title="Disable Java Now!" href="http://deemable.com/java" target="_blank">deemable.com/java</a> where everyone could go to get instructions on how to disable java in each web browser.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Yeah, we had a great response to it. In less than an hour after the segment aired, we already had 600 views on the page. By the end of the day, we had over 1,400 views, and over the next two days we had several hundred more. So, good job listening everyone!</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: But, we know that several thousand people listen to Morning Edition each day on 89.9 FM, so if you haven&rsquo;t done it yet, do it, now! Go to <a title="Disable Java Now!" href="http://deemable.com/java" target="_blank">deemable.com/java</a> and follow the directions and disable Java, <em>now</em>!</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: You better do it. He&rsquo;s just going to keep telling you to do it,&hellip;</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: <em>Now</em>!</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: OK, so we had some comments on the page that we wanted to address.</p>
<p dir="ltr">*Discuss comments on deemable.com/java</p>
<p dir="ltr">Thanks for all your comments.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Phillip writes, I have two questions. First, is there an app or a way to add multiple files (pdfs specifically) in an email on an iPad  Second, what is the most cost-effective way to extend WiFi for a PC? I have video lessons via Skype and my wireless router is on the other side of my house (and cannot be moved), this causes severe latency issues. Thank you for your help.</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Thank you for your question, Phillip.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Well, I know my co-host is going to rib me, because I&rsquo;m sure he can do this with his Android phone easier than you can do it on an iPad, but nonetheless, I will see if I can help you out here.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Sadly, there is no simple, easy, built-in way to do this. My greatest complaint with iOS is file management. Each app has their own way of managing documents, and they usually don&rsquo;t work together.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a title="GoDocs for Google Docs &amp; Drive" href="http://lightroomapps.com/products/godocs/" target="_blank">GoDocs</a> is probably the best app for the job. You have to have a Google Drive account, but you can take multiple pdfs that you have uploaded to your Google Drive account and send them in an email from the app. You can also upload pdfs to your Google Drive account in the app.</p>
<p dir="ltr">There&rsquo;s another app called <a title="GoodReader" href="http://www.goodiware.com/goodreader.html" target="_blank">Goodreader</a> that will do the trick as well.</p>
<p dir="ltr">If you&rsquo;re Jailbroken, you can use an app called <a title="iFile - Cydia" href="http://cydia.saurik.com/package/eu.heinelt.ifile" target="_blank">iFile</a>. There&rsquo;s a free version and a paid version. You don&rsquo;t need the paid version to send multiple files via email, but there&rsquo;s a lot of really cool things you can do with the paid version that you can&rsquo;t do with the free version. But, with iFile, you have access to everything on your iPhone, so tread carefully.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: About your Wi-Fi question, Phillip, we actually answered a similar question, a long, long time ago, way back in one of our first five episodes.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The best solution is an access point. An access point is like a WiFi router, except that you plug it into a WiFi router. It&rsquo;s only purpose is to extend your network. You must already have a router setup for it to work. You&rsquo;ll have to run an Ethernet cable from your router to your access point which needs to be close to where ever you need WiFi. They vary in price anywhere from $25 to $250, but you can usually find a good one for around $50.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: The best way to do it is to run an Ethernet cable through the wall, away from any electrical wires, and put an outlet on each end that mounts to the wall. Then, use a shorter cable to plug from the wall to the router, and from the wall to the access point. Most access points are relatively pretty plug and play, but you might have to make some adjustments to the firmware on the router or the access point. You&rsquo;ll have to follow the directions in the manual. Also, if you have an old router, you can usually set it up as an access point. You&rsquo;ll definitely have to go into the settings of the router to make it act as an access point or it might be ornery and fight with your other router as to who is the king of the network.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: All right, we have to take a quick break to thank our sponsors. We have a new sponsor, Audible. Audible is offering listeners of the Deemable Tech podcast a free audiobook download with a free 30-day trial to give you the opportunity to check out their service. If you enjoy listening to podcasts and you like reading great books, you&rsquo;ll love Audible.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: And, if you have a Kindle, like I do, you will really love this, with Whispersync for voice, if you get a book from Audible that you already have on your Kindle, your ebook and your audio book will stay synced together on multiple devices. So, for example, you can listen to your audio book in the car on your iPhone on the way to work, and then pick up right where you left off on your Kindle during lunch.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: So, Tom, do you have any recommendations for a good audio book?</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Snow Crash by Neal Stephenson</p>
<p dir="ltr">What about you, Ray. Do you have a recommendation?</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Starship Troopers by Robert A. Heinlein</p>
<p dir="ltr">You can download one of our picks, or another audiobook for free.</p>
<p dir="ltr">To download your free audiobook today go to <a title="Click here for a free audio book, and 30 day free trial to Audible.com " href="http://audibletrial.com/Deemable" target="_blank">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a>. Again, that&rsquo;s <a title="Click here for a free audio book, and 30 day free trial to Audible.com " href="http://audibletrial.com/Deemable" target="_blank">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a> for your free audiobook! And we thank Audible for their support of the Deemable Tech podcast.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: If you haven&rsquo;t already, show us some love and subscribe to our podcast in iTunes or your favorite podcast app. If you&rsquo;ve already subscribed, leave a review for us on iTunes. There&rsquo;s links to the iTunes page and our Facebook, Twitter, and Pinterest pages on the right-hand side of our website at Deemable.com.</p>
<p dir="ltr">You&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Welcome back to Deemable Tech. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, joined of course by my co-host, Tom Braun.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Now, we are joined in the studio by Kai Kohl, the creator of I.M.A.G.I.C. a creation for One Spark. Welcome to the show, Kai.</p>
<p dir="ltr">KAI: Thanks for having me on the show.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So, we&rsquo;ve talked about this before on the show, in April there is a festival coming to Jacksonville called One Spark. One Spark is a crowdfunding festival happening here in downtown Jacksonville, Florida, April 17th through the 21st. Creators from around the world are coming to Jacksonville to show off their creations and take home part of the $250,000 crowdfund. The interesting part about One Spark is that instead of winning a grand prize, first prize, second prize and so on, at One Spark, the $250,000 crowdfund will be distributed by public vote. So, if a creator gets 10% of the vote, at the end of the One Spark festival they&rsquo;ll be taking home $25,000!</p>
<p dir="ltr">Each registered voter will be able to vote once for each entry in the festival, but they can vote for as many entries as they like. That&rsquo;s the part I&rsquo;m thankful for because there are a lot of really incredible entries in this festival from all over the spectrum: Art, Music, Science and Technology.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Questions for Kai about I.M.A.G.I.C.</p>
<ul><li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">What is I.M.A.G.I.C.? What is your creation?</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">What are you doing the Kickstarter project for?</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Why did you name it I.M.A.G.I.C. (I&rsquo;m pretty sure I know why, but it&rsquo;ll be good to talk about.)</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Where did you get the idea for I.M.A.G.I.C.?</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">What has been the hardest part of getting I.M.A.G.I.C. started?</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">What does your wife think of your collection? Is she supportive?</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">How will you use the money you get from One Spark?</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">How will I.M.A.G.I.C. make money? Will it be a Profit or Non-Profit?</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Where do you see I.M.A.G.I.C. going from here? If you were to receive all the money in the crowdfund, what would happen? How would your life change as a result of I.M.A.G.I.C. becoming successful? What does success at I.M.A.G.I.C. look like?</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Where can our listeners find your exhibit at One Spark?</p>
</li>
</ul><p dir="ltr">Thanks for all your questions, and keep them coming. Call us at our toll-free number, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com. Also, subscribe to the show! Search for Deemable Tech on iTunes or point your favorite podcast app to dmbl.co/pod.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Also, make sure to come out to One Spark April 17-21 while you are there visit The IMAGIC at The Phoenix Taproom at W Forsyth St, and make sure to come by and visit Deemable Tech&rsquo;s booth at Ignite Adecco on Bay and Main Street, and make sure to vote for The IMAGIC and for Deemable Tech. If you haven&rsquo;t already registered to vote, go to <a title="One Spark" href="http://www.beonespark.com/" target="_blank">beonespark.com</a> and register now to vote.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a title="The I.M.A.G.I.C." href="http://theimagic.com/" target="_blank">theimagic.com</a></p>
<p dir="ltr"><a title="The International Museum of Art in Gaming and Interactive Creations" href="http://facebook.com/theimagic" target="_blank">facebook.com/theimagic</a></p>
<p dir="ltr"><a title="The I.M.A.G.I.C." href="https://twitter.com/theimagic" target="_blank">twitter.com/theimagic</a></p>
<p dir="ltr">Our producer is Sean Birch. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, and this is Deemable Tech.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Thanks for listening. Have a great week.</p>
<p>Support for Deemable Tech is provided by <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">A Small Orange</a>, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Episode 34 - We Made It! It's All Your Fault! Thank You!" data-link="/2013/03/episode-34-we-made-it-its-all-your-fault/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Episode 34 - We Made It! It's All Your Fault! Thank You!" data-link="/2013/03/episode-34-we-made-it-its-all-your-fault/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/03/episode-34-we-made-it-its-all-your-fault/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-03-25.mp3" length="47943262" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Episode 32 &#8211; Alert The Boss, You Need to Disable Java Now!</title>
		<link>/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/</link>
		<comments>/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 05:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adecco Ignite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alert The Boss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Citrix Online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GoToWebinar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[java]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One Spark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Text Message]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=6888</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/02/AlertTheBoss-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Alert The Boss" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week on Deemable Tech Ray was joined by guest host Kenny Kwaak and by John Martinelli and Evan Diamond from Alert The Boss, a creation that is going to part of One Spark, a crowd funding festival happening in <a href="/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/02/AlertTheBoss-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Alert The Boss" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-6890" alt="Alert The Boss" src="//media/2013/02/AlertTheBoss.png" width="180" height="180">This week on Deemable Tech Ray was joined by guest host Kenny Kwaak and by John Martinelli and Evan Diamond from Alert The Boss, a creation that is going to part of <a title="One Spark: The World's Crowdfunding Festival " href="http://beonespark.com/" target="_blank">One Spark</a>, a crowd funding festival happening in Jacksonville, Florida April 17-21, 2013. Be sure to come and visit Alert The Boss at <a title="121 Atlantic Place at 121 W Forsyth Street." href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=121+west+forsyth+street+jacksonville+fl&amp;daddr=121+W+Forsyth+St,+Jacksonville,+FL+32202&amp;hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;hnear=0x88e5b7170a2cf03d:0xbe5b62b1e970c1ff,121+W+Forsyth+St,+Jacksonville,+FL+32202&amp;gl=us&amp;t=h&amp;z=16" target="_blank">121 Atlantic Place</a>&nbsp;and Deemable Tech at a <a title="Adecco Ignite at 6 E Bay Street" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=6+east+bay+street+jacksonville+fl&amp;daddr=6+E+Bay+St,+Jacksonville,+FL+32202&amp;hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;hnear=0x88e5b719e5c78a97:0xc1e72ae59093be92,6+E+Bay+St,+Jacksonville,+FL+32202&amp;gl=us&amp;t=h&amp;z=16" target="_blank">Adecco Ignite</a> during One Spark, and make sure to vote for Alert The Boss and Deemable Tech at One Spark!</p>
<p>After the break, Ray and Kenny answered one question that got skipped at the <a title="Deemable Tech Live at Bold Bean!" href="http://dmbl.co/e31">Live Event last week</a>. Mike wants to know why he can&rsquo;t hear the sound on the Citrix Online webinars that he attends. The guys tell him to fix the disease, not treat the symptoms.</p>
<p>All that and more, on this episode of Deemable Tech!</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img title="Subscribe on iTunes" alt="" src="//media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" width="160" height="59"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">subscribe to the show in iTunes by clicking here</a>, or&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech Podcast!" href="http://dmbl.co/pod">subscribe to the show in another podcast reader by clicking here</a>. Also,&nbsp;make sure to leave us a review in iTunes. The more reviews we have the higher we&rsquo;ll be listed in iTunes and the more listeners will see our show!</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-6888-3" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-25.mp3?_=3"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-25.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-25.mp3</a></audio><p><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-25.mp3" target="_blank">Download Episode 32 &ndash; Alert The Boss You Need to Disable Java Now!</a></p>
<p>Need tech help? Got a problem or tech question about your computer, phone or tablet? Give us a call and leave us a voice mail at 1-888-972-9868, or send us an email to questions at deemable dot com. We&rsquo;ll answer them on the show.</p>
<h4>Links mentioned on this week&rsquo;s show:</h4>
<ul><li><a title="AlertTheBoss! | Get instant feedback from your customers BEFORE they leave your business!" href="https://alerttheboss.com/" target="_blank">AlertTheBoss!</a></li>
<li><a title="Facebook | Alert The Boss" href="https://www.facebook.com/AlertTheBoss" target="_blank">Like AlertTheBoss on Facebook</a></li>
<li><a title="Gizmodo | How To Disable Java in Your Browser" href="http://gizmodo.com/5975475/how-to-disable-java-in-your-browser" target="_blank">Gizmodo &ndash; How To Disable Java in Your Browser</a></li>
</ul><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Episode 32 - Alert The Boss, You Need to Disable Java Now!" data-link="/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Episode 32 - Alert The Boss, You Need to Disable Java Now!" data-link="/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/02/episode-32-alert-the-boss-you-need-to-disable-java-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-25.mp3" length="50022609" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
