<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; smartphone</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/smartphone/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#80 The Smartphone Wars Turn Deadly</title>
		<link>/2015/04/80-the-smartphone-wars-turn-deadly/</link>
		<comments>/2015/04/80-the-smartphone-wars-turn-deadly/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 16:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gigabit Pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York City]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One World Trade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time Warner Cable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9952</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/04/3905907831_cff11a8808_b-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="iPhone vs Android" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week, Comcast can&#8217;t keep itself out of the news. First, Comcast&#160;announces that it is&#160;bringing the fastest Interwebs in the country to Jacksonville (WOOT!) and other cities in Florida. Then, the FCC and the Justice Department rain on Comcast&#8217;s&#160;parade and <a href="/2015/04/80-the-smartphone-wars-turn-deadly/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/04/80-the-smartphone-wars-turn-deadly/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/04/3905907831_cff11a8808_b-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="iPhone vs Android" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="/media/2015/04/3905907831_cff11a8808_b.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright wp-image-9959 size-medium" src="/media/2015/04/3905907831_cff11a8808_b-300x200.jpg"  alt="iPhone vs Android" width="300" height="200"></a>This week, Comcast can&rsquo;t keep itself out of the news. First, Comcast&nbsp;announces that it is&nbsp;bringing the fastest Interwebs in the country to Jacksonville (WOOT!) and other cities in Florida. Then, the FCC and the Justice Department rain on Comcast&rsquo;s&nbsp;parade and lets&nbsp;it know they are not going to let it merge with Time Warner Cable. In other news, a paranoid dad flew a drone to school with his daughter, and two guys took the iPhone/Android fight way too far.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>If you haven?t <a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/ca/podcast/deemable-tech-wjct/id540595466?mt=2" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">subscribed to Deemable Tech</a> yet, get on it! Subscribe to <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">Deemable Tech&nbsp;in iTunes</a>,&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>or&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech Podcast!" href="http://dmbl.co/pod">subscribe to the show in another podcast reader</a>. Make sure to leave a review on iTunes and Stitcher. The more reviews posted,&nbsp;the higher Deemable Tech will&nbsp;be listed, and the more listeners will see the&nbsp;show.</p>
<p>And make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="//reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-9952-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/04/DeemableTech_2015-04-24.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/04/DeemableTech_2015-04-24.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/04/DeemableTech_2015-04-24.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S&nbsp;RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>Comcast Gigabit Pro</h3>
<p>People in Jacksonville and some other towns in Florida are going to be pretty excited next month. In a story Jessica Palombo contributed to Deemable.com, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2F2015%2F04%2Fcomcast-to-begin-offering-floridians-fastest-internet-in-the-country%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGVubtVCY6Eqqpd5B_PrGjLtXzZfA">Comcast is bringing the fastest fiber optic Internet service in the country</a>&nbsp;to a few cities in Florida, including our own fair town. The service, which is called Gigabit Pro, will actually have 2 Gbps download and upload speeds ? more than twice the speed of Google Fiber.</p>
<p>However, Comcast would not give a price for the new service. The next fastest service from Comcast is Extreme 505, which runs up to 505 Mbps up and down, and costs over $400 a month with taxes and fees.</p>
<h3>Comcast Drops Its Bid to Merge With Time Warner Cable</h3>
<p>Speaking of Comcast, earlier this week it was looking pretty &nbsp;looked bad for its merger with Time Warner Cable. According to Bloomberg, the <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.bloomberg.com%2Fnews%2Farticles%2F2015-04-17%2Fu-s-antitrust-lawyers-said-to-be-leaning-against-comcast-merger&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFxhG6OrQAnZUGZxB2U32vhPKpqPw">Justice Department&rsquo;s antitrust department was going to recommend blocking the merger</a>. And, the FCC was not negotiating the terms of the deal with Comcast, which made it look even less likely that it was going to go through.</p>
<p>But now, ?people with knowledge of the matter? have told Bloomberg that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.bloomberg.com%2Fnews%2Farticles%2F2015-04-23%2Fcomcast-said-planning-to-withdraw-offer-for-time-warner-cable&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGpwgeroBsNi-Il6dH68GJLDEdxDA">Comcast is backing out of the merger</a>. There was supposed to be a board meeting Thursday. And an official &nbsp;announcement will probably come Friday.</p>
<p>As the Verge pointed out in an editorial, throughout this whole process, Comcast has never answered this simple question: <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2015%2F4%2F22%2F8470873%2Fcomcast-twc-defense&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGjzkjudzu8zRpTX8T7KqYI5Ege2w">Why not compete?</a></p>
<h3>Verizon to offer custom pay TV packages, let customers choose monthly programming bundles</h3>
<p>And while we?re on the subject of Internet and TV providers, in move that is one small step closer to a la carte cable TV, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.reuters.com%2Farticle%2F2015%2F04%2F17%2Fverizon-fios-idUSL2N0XD36J20150417&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNE6PXxsPut3_sN_10ePy8zCVmVEfg">Verizon recently announced that they are rolling out a new pay TV service</a>&nbsp;that will let customers choose from channel bundles that they change monthly.</p>
<p>These Verizon FiOS ?Custom TV? packages will start at 65 dollars a month for broadband service, 36 fixed basic cable channels, and two genre-based channel packs that customers can swap or unsubscribe from after a month. You can also add packs for an extra 10 dollars. Verizon has seven of these packs to choose from, including sports and children?s programming.</p>
<p>Verizon says they are going after customers who want something in between giant, fully loaded cable packages and cheaper basic packages offered by their competitors.</p>
<h3>After &ldquo;Drone Dad&rdquo; follows his daughter to school, DJI Phantom 2 grounded</h3>
<p>Tennessee father Chris Early?s daughter decided she wanted to walk to the school bus by herself so he did what any tech-inclined father would do: <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Fgadgets%2F2015%2F04%2Fafter-drone-dad-follows-his-daughter-to-school-dji-phantom-2-grounded%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGXD6Y8ND_hBoQlLnXVuJ7a67pTjQ">he followed her with a drone</a>.</p>
<p>The drone was a model known as a DJI Phantom 2 which has a high def video camera mounted on it. Early followed his daughter with the drone. A local news station caught wind of this and the story went nationwide. Chris Early has been called ?overprotective?, ?the world?s most embarrassing father? and &lsquo;drone dad&rsquo;. As a result of all the attention he says he has grounded the drone for now.</p>
<h3>One World Trade Center Elevator Shows 515 Years Of New York City</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2F2015%2F04%2Fbreathtaking-one-world-trade-center-elevator-shows-515-years-of-new-york-city%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEk8BcDdWQz0n620aPnWXkM9Ovu0g">One World Trade Center has added an elevator that displays 515 years of New York City history in 50 seconds</a>.</p>
<p>The New York Times covered this story, but I wrote an article about it for Deemable.com.</p>
<p>While they haven?t developed time travel, the engineers and designers behind the elevators that takes guests to the observatory at the very top of One World Trade Center in New York City have come pretty close. When you board the elevators, you will see a panoramic view of New York City rising out of the underground in the 1500s all the way up through time to the 102nd floor today.</p>
<p>The elevator uses nine 75-inch screens to create the illusion that it is a glass-walled elevator traveling through time.</p>
<p>Along the way, you&rsquo;ll see the arrival of the Europeans, the Revolution and the rise of the skyscrapers. Inevitably, as time travels through the late-1900s, one of the Twin Towers enters your sight and just as quickly fades away as the 2000s begin. It is a touching, beautiful memorial to the history of the site. You can see The New York Times video of the elevator on our website at Deemable.com</p>
<h3>YouTube celebrates 10 year anniversary</h3>
<p>This week marks the <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.yahoo.com%2Ftech%2Fs%2Fyoutube-celebrates-10-anniversary-105136844.html&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHE6bPIHeiXJiT-PjpfPJtZbhFuzw">10 year anniversary of the first video being uploaded to YouTube</a>.</p>
<p>On April 23 2005, YouTube co-founder Jawed Karim posted a 19 second clip of elephants at the zoo titled &ldquo;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jNQXAC9IVRw">Me at the zoo</a>.&rdquo; &nbsp;In it, Karim discusses the elephants&rsquo; &ldquo;really, really, really long trunks&rdquo; and, well, that&rsquo;s all. Pretty tame compared to what you can find on YouTube today.</p>
<p>About a year after this video was posted, Google acquired YouTube for $1.6 billion.</p>
<p>According to reports, YouTube will mark the anniversary with a month-long celebration starting next week.</p>
<h3>Skycure Hack Can Use Wifi To Disable iOS Devices</h3>
<p>A research firm called Skycure reported that it has developed a hack based around a bug in iOS that could allow it to <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fmashable.com%2F2015%2F04%2F23%2Fhack-nearby-ios-devices%2F%3Futm_cid%3Dmash-com-fb-main-link&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEBwoGMoQQX1B7xKeTEhVRKLoCCdw">disable all nearby iOS devices using a wifi router</a>. The wifi router has to be configured in a specific way. It will then cause any device connected to it to keep crashing and rebooting in an endless loop. It can be combined with another hack that forces iOS devices to connect to that network. Essentially the only way to escape the endless cycle of rebooting would be to get out of range of the router.</p>
<p>Skycure has not publicly released technical specifications for the bug it used to create the hack to give Apple time to patch it.</p>
<h3>Argument Over Which Smartphone Is Better Turns Deadly</h3>
<p>Police in Tulsa, OK apprehended a man staggering around a parking lot late at night cut up and covered in blood. The man reported to them that he had been in a fight with his roommate over <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2015/04/android-versus-iphone-debate-escalates-into-stabbing-and-car-theft/" target="_blank">which smartphone was better &ndash; the iPhone or the new Samsung Galaxy</a>. iPhone versus Android fights can get heated, but most stop short of physical conflict. The man reported that he and his roommate had been drinking and wound up stabbing each other with broken beer bottles. Both were admitted to the hospital and are expected to make a full recovery. No word on whether either man was arrested or whether either had his mind changed about his preferred choice of phone.</p>
<h3>How many tabs does it take to get to the center of a Tootsie Pop?</h3>
<p>Redditor Peanut Butter Shudder suggested an answer to Ray&rsquo;s question. Last week during Shower Thoughts, Ray said he didn&rsquo;t know how many tabs he had ever opened in his life. Peanut Butter Shudder mentioned <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.tabforacause.org%2F%3Fr%3D11049744&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFxt1WhtHrRjahBv7lwele8dNCDOA">Tab for a Cause</a>&nbsp;on our reddit page (reddit.com/r/deemable) Tab for a Cause apparently tracks how many tabs you open and it has a bit of slacktivism built into it. If you install the browser extension, you&rsquo;ll raise money for charities simply by browsing the internet. Heck, why not?</p>
<h3>Who had the best segue?</h3>
<p>Vote! Send us an&nbsp;email to feedback at deemable dot com or leave us a voicemail at&nbsp;1-888-972-9868.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="//reddit" target="_blank">deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Photo credit: <a href="https://flic.kr/p/6X9Njt" target="_blank">iPhone vs Android</a>&nbsp;by <a href="http://nrkbeta.no/" rel="nofollow" data-rapid_p="27">nrkbeta.no</a> is licensed under&nbsp;<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/no/" rel="nofollow" data-rapid_p="28">Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0</a>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/04/80-the-smartphone-wars-turn-deadly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/04/DeemableTech_2015-04-24.mp3" length="31206644" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mara asks, &#8220;How can I block calls on my smartphone?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2014/08/mara-asks-can-block-calls-smartphone/</link>
		<comments>/2014/08/mara-asks-can-block-calls-smartphone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 02:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9133</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/08/dt_annoying_caller_block_calls-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="dt_annoying_caller_block_calls" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Q: Help me Deemable Tech, you&#8217;re my only hope! I keep getting calls on my smartphone from a strange number. When I pick up, no one is there. Is there any way I can block this annoyance? A: We&#8217;ve got <a href="/2014/08/mara-asks-can-block-calls-smartphone/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2014/08/mara-asks-can-block-calls-smartphone/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/08/dt_annoying_caller_block_calls-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="dt_annoying_caller_block_calls" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><script id="prx-p128086-embed" src="http://www.prx.org/p/128086/embed.js?size=small"></script></p>
<p><strong>Q:</strong> Help me Deemable Tech, you&rsquo;re my only hope! I keep getting calls on my smartphone from a strange number. When I pick up, no one is there. Is there any way I can block this annoyance?<span id="more-9133"></span></p>
<p><strong>A:</strong> We&rsquo;ve got good news for you, Mara: most smartphones these days have solid call blocking features.</p>
<p><strong>Blocking Calls On Android</strong></p>
<p><a href="/media/2014/08/dt_annoying_caller_block_calls.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-9134" src="/media/2014/08/dt_annoying_caller_block_calls-200x300.jpg"  alt="dt_annoying_caller_block_calls" width="200" height="300"></a>Most Android phones, depending on the model and carrier, should have some built-in features that will help you block calls. In the Settings menu, look for a sub-menu named &ldquo;Call&rdquo; or something similar. Tap that, and you will find a &ldquo;Blocked Calls&rdquo; menu. Some phones (like the Samsung Galaxy S3) also give you the option to simply block all unknown numbers.</p>
<p>If blocking a phone number entirely seems too drastic for you, there is an alternative. When you&rsquo;re viewing a contact on most Android phones, there is a settings option to send calls from that contact straight to your voicemail.</p>
<p>There are also a lot of call-blocking apps available in the Google Play Store, which you can find by searching &ldquo;call blocker.&rdquo; We recommend the free app Mr. Number, because it makes blocking calls and performing reverse phone number lookups easy. It also displays where unwanted calls are coming from, which is a nice bonus.</p>
<p><strong>Blocking Calls On iPhone</strong></p>
<p>Before the release of iOS 7, it wasn&rsquo;t possible to block calls on an iPhone. Now it&rsquo;s a built in feature.</p>
<p>To block calls from one of your contacts, open their contact card and scroll to the &ldquo;Block This Caller&rdquo; link at the bottom. Tapping that will allow you to block that person&rsquo;s phone calls, Facetime calls and text messages.</p>
<p>If you want to block someone who is not in your contact list, open the Phone app and go to the &ldquo;Recent Phone Calls&rdquo; list. Find the phone number you want to block, and find the icon next to the number that looks like a circle with a lowercase &ldquo;i&rdquo; in it. Tap that, and scroll to the bottom and to find the &ldquo;Block This Caller&rdquo; link.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re still running an older version of iOS, like iOS 6, you won&rsquo;t have this feature. Unfortunately, there also aren&rsquo;t any apps that you can use to block calls, because iPhone apps don&rsquo;t have access to the dialer. To work around this, you could create a contact for an unwanted number with a name like &ldquo;Ignore This,&rdquo; and download a silent ringtone for that number. However, we recommend just upgrading to iOS 7 if your phone supports it.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/08/mara-asks-can-block-calls-smartphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Downfall of Research in Motion</title>
		<link>/2011/06/the-downfall-of-research-in-motion/</link>
		<comments>/2011/06/the-downfall-of-research-in-motion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 15:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Ahn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackBerry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playbook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research in motion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RIM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=3621</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We may soon be saying R-I-P to R-I-M, the maker of the once beloved BlackBerry smartphone. After reducing their initial profit forecast roughly two months ago, Research in Motion announced its first quarter financial earnings results yesterday which were almost <a href="/2011/06/the-downfall-of-research-in-motion/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/06/the-downfall-of-research-in-motion/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="alignleft" src="http://fc06.deviantart.net/fs70/i/2010/259/6/1/research_in_motion_by_darkscher-d2yudz9.jpg" alt="" width="160" height="239"></p>
<p>We may soon be saying R-I-P to R-I-M, the maker of the once beloved BlackBerry smartphone. After reducing their initial profit forecast roughly two months ago, Research in Motion announced its first quarter financial earnings results yesterday which were almost $1 billion lower than expected. Although RIM managed to ship 13.2 million BlackBerry devices and 500,000 BlackBerry Playbook tablets during the quarter, the discouraging news of the drop in profit and revenue caused shares in the company to fall 14 percent in after-hours trading last night. Now, Research in Motion is going to cut costs through &ldquo;headcount reductions&rdquo;&hellip; meaning&nbsp;<a title="layoffs" href="http://www.businessinsider.com/research-in-motion-layoffs-2011-6#ixzz1PY1c9sNe" target="_blank">layoffs are on the way</a>.</p>
<p>RIM is quickly fading into oblivion behind the new giants in the business &ndash; Apple&rsquo;s iOS and Google&rsquo;s Android. Jarislowsky Fraser Ltd., Research in Motion&rsquo;s sixth-largest investor, just revealed that it would be dumping all of its 10.2 million shares in the company, with the chairman of the investment group leaving this <a title="Quote" href="http://www.businessinsider.com/rims-sixth-biggest-investor-dumps-stake-2011-6" target="_blank">ominous quote</a>,&rdquo;&nbsp;We are on the way out. The stake has been reduced by more than 50% or even more&hellip; They are resting on their laurels &hellip; Steve Jobs is a much better marketer than RIM.&rdquo;</p>
<p>So what is RIM&rsquo;s main problem? Delays in production&hellip; and the fact that their technology is not keeping up with competitors&rsquo;. No new products will be released by the company during the summer until August, the latest BlackBerry <a title="update" href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/btl/rims-conundrum-convincing-you-to-buy-a-blackberry-70-device/50934" target="_blank">OS 7.0 update</a> coming out won&rsquo;t even work for most of the current models, and who honestly wants to buy a <a title="PlayBook" href="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/223562/four_reasons_to_avoid_the_blackberry_playbook.html" target="_blank">PlayBook</a> over another tablet?</p>
<p>Co-CEO Jim Balsillie announced in a <a title="RIM" href="http://finance.yahoo.com/news/Research-In-Motion-Reports-ccn-2426498309.html?x=0&amp;.v=1" target="_blank">press release</a>:</p>
<p>&ldquo;Fiscal 2012 has gotten off to a challenging start. The slowdown we saw in the first quarter is continuing into Q2, and delays in new product introductions into the very late part of August is leading to a lower than expected outlook in the second quarter&hellip; RIM&rsquo;s business is profitable and remains solid overall with growing market share in numerous markets around the world and a strong balance sheet with almost $3 billion in cash. We believe that with the new products scheduled for launch in the next few months and realigning our cost structure, RIM will see strong profit growth in the latter part of fiscal 2012.&rdquo;</p>
<p>With investors&rsquo; confidence already shaken, this statement does not provide much reassurance, and the outlook is looking very grim for&nbsp;a company that was once considered the world leader in the smartphone market.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="Photo" href="http://fc06.deviantart.net/fs70/i/2010/259/6/1/research_in_motion_by_darkscher-d2yudz9.jpg" target="_blank">Photo</a> by <a title="darkscher" href="http://darkscher.deviantart.com/" target="_blank">darkscher</a> via <a title="DeviantArt" href="http://www.deviantart.com/" target="_blank">deviantART</a></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/06/the-downfall-of-research-in-motion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Must-Have Android Apps</title>
		<link>/2011/05/must-have-android-apps/</link>
		<comments>/2011/05/must-have-android-apps/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 16:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Ahn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android Market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Application]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[G1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T-Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=3030</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Android has come a long way since the inception of Google&#8217;s first Android-based smartphone, the HTC Dream. Better known as T-Mobile&#8217;s G1, the HTC Dream was the 3rd cell phone that I have ever owned, and I definitely saw promise <a href="/2011/05/must-have-android-apps/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/05/must-have-android-apps/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><h1><img class="aligncenter" src="http://s4.appbrain.com/screen?id=5317013346735400364&amp;i=1" alt="" width="231" height="385"></h1>
<p>Android has come a long way since the inception of Google&rsquo;s first Android-based smartphone, the HTC Dream. Better known as T-Mobile&rsquo;s G1, the HTC Dream was the 3rd cell phone that I have ever owned, and I definitely saw promise in Google&rsquo;s vision of an open-source platform. With over 1/3 of the smartphone market share, consumers are rapidly joining the bandwagon, and I&rsquo;d like to share some Android apps that I believe will make the transition more worthwhile. Click on the application name to view more information as well as screenshot previews; to view a complete list of the Android applications I have installed, click <a title="David's Apps" href="http://www.appbrain.com/user/DavidAhn" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h1>#1) <img src="http://lh6.ggpht.com/NlC6tgocLZqZQD_Jzd2O9eDEfbZFl4zn9j2nYZr0rxhg9l9pEsCLYHclzYv2jgSpVN8w551eJK3x3wgDQ84=s48" alt="Dropbox"><a title="Dropbox" href="http://www.appbrain.com/app/dropbox/com.dropbox.android" target="_blank">Dropbox</a> (Free)</h1>
<p><strong>&ldquo;Dropbox is a free service that lets you bring all your photos, docs, and  videos anywhere.  After you install Dropbox on your computer, any file  you save to your  Dropbox will automatically save to all your computers,  your Android  device, and even the Dropbox website! With the Dropbox app,  you can take everything that matters to you on the go.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Dropbox is a simple way for you to transfer or access files, <em>without </em>the need of a cable connecting your phone and your computer.<strong> </strong></p>
<h1>#2) <img src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/ilKNhi4RYyPVMyihFB6ZlHOvOTmoscNTUTWzU4lsgpGEiYSo-8IIIABHa492egHOIVsmAijRuPGt_Wz-5Q=s48" alt="Google Maps"><a title="Google Maps" href="http://www.appbrain.com/app/google-maps/com.google.android.apps.maps" target="_blank">Google Maps</a> (Free)</h1>
<p><strong>*Navigation: Free, voice-guided GPS navigation system</strong><br><strong>*Places: Find, rate, and get recommendations for places</strong><br><strong>*Latitude: See friends on the map and check in at places</strong></p>
<p>A free navigation system, what more could you ask for?<br><strong> </strong><strong> </strong></p>
<h1>#3) <img src="http://lh4.ggpht.com/2AwYGrYgj8JH2GjvRc1dKsP6rMfc8QlKT636zSDYa6VVKprh3MYT1C-s-_pe6osgR2sQ-2Rainhh2UABVg=s48" alt="Elixir"><a title="Elixir" href="http://www.appbrain.com/app/elixir/bt.android.elixir" target="_blank">Elixir</a> (Free)</h1>
<p><strong>&ldquo;Elixir is a system information application with highly  configurable  widgets. Displays information about battery, cpu usage,  memory usage,  internal and external storage (sd-card), display, wifi,  mobile network,  location services (gps), bluetooth, sync, airplane  mode, sensors, etc.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Elixir is a consolidated system information tool. I&rsquo;ve tried many others like it, but Elixir takes the cake&nbsp;<em>by far</em>. Not only is the UI simple and intuitive, but Tam&aacute;s Barta, the developer, listened to one of the suggestions I sent him via e-mail and immediately implemented it into his next update. He&rsquo;s constantly working on this app and with each update, it has only gotten better!</p>
<h1>#4) <img src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/RZy5jTRE7R1AuBFdzzpAucEynUkeN804bsASyTyy_M4qw31K4cCFgWLim7RTQQjrNr8RRKBVsSX0_gjF6H4=s48" alt="Smart Taskbar (sidebar)"><a title="Smart Taskbar" href="http://www.appbrain.com/app/smart-taskbar-%28sidebar%29/com.smart.taskbar" target="_blank">Smart Taskbar</a> (Free)</h1>
<p><strong>&ldquo;Launch any application instantly. Slide your finger or click  icon  anytime in any App to bring up a mini sidebar for super fast app   launching also works as app organizer, task switcher, task killer, and   shortcut manager.</strong></p>
<p><strong>If you want to use your phone one handed with  complete touch  experience, you find Android system takes too many steps  to complete  one simple job, or you need a faster way to get things  organized, get  Smart Taskbar to make your life easier.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Smart Taskbar is a convenient app that runs in the background; simply press the sidebar icon and it pulls up the app drawer without having to leave your current application.</p>
<h1>#5) <img src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/1eUKGlpwfr3MP5U28uM5pcSj73nRI82RX3zbwbtuTasykZHRbno5U3Y4i7TBL38avJ4wxztOfxDUrWhTIQ=s48" alt="Fancy Widget"><a title="Fancy Widget" href="http://www.appbrain.com/app/fancy-widget/com.anddoes.fancywidget" target="_blank">Fancy Widget</a> (Free &amp; Pro Version)</h1>
<p><strong>&ldquo;Fancy clock and weather widget with lots of customization options.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Fancy Widget reduces clutter by allowing you to view the date, time, and weather all in one widget. You can even click each individual part of the widget to open either a calendar, alarm clock, or weather application. While the free version is worth a download by itself, the paid version offers hundreds of customizable widget themes that you can toy with.</p>
<h1>#6) <img src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/ce52TF2X0HYdTS9DYhaoiB79ykS22f8iExohVhUxb0m0Po0LIx9bwuOVKMfCdgPGnrmSzGHAyIPYnWE8=s48" alt="PowerAMP Music Player (Trial)"><a title="PowerAMP" href="http://www.appbrain.com/app/poweramp-music-player-%28trial%29/com.maxmpz.audioplayer" target="_blank">PowerAMP Music Player</a> (Trial &amp; Pro Version)</h1>
<p><strong>&ldquo;PowerAMP is a powerful music player for Android.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>If you are like me and you like to mess around with your smartphone and customize the hell out of it to fit your own style, then PowerAMP Music Player is not only the best looking music player out there on Android, but offers some of the best features like the lock screen widget and equalizer. The trial version allows you full featured access for 15 days before asking you to purchase it, but it definitely is worth it considering you will be able to download it at no extra cost on any Android phone you own in the future as well.</p>
<h1>#7) <img src="http://lh4.ggpht.com/z90nCKfX7ClTVJu8Hccesj3KHHsCUiOJAfgMLQtYreOlXMNTpKn5gvFPNi7BUlGMQknyozailaC3yFSR=s48" alt="Dolphin Browser? Mini"><a title="Dolphin Browser Mini" href="http://www.appbrain.com/app/dolphin-browser%E2%84%A2-mini/com.dolphin.browser" target="_blank">Dolphin Browser? Mini</a> (Free)</h1>
<p><strong>&ldquo;Something powerful, something elegant, something valuable! It is Dolphin Browser HD.</strong><br><strong>Something fast, something simple, something new! It is Dolphin Browser Mini.</strong><br><strong>Browsing made wonderful.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Dolphin Browser Mini aims at providing a friendly user experience for all of you. </strong><br><strong>Enjoy this new version now and let us know how it works for you.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Both Dolphin Browser HD and Dolphin Browser Mini are <em>much </em>better than the stock Web browser that comes on most Android phones. Both offer intuitive UI design and are more efficient/faster than most of the other top browsers I have tried (Opera Mini, Firefox Mobile, MIREN Browser).</p>
<h1>#8) <img src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/B6HF4fFK-OXPCx8UQOPxYxTZyhOdfPlMiyp4OkwEfrFn0wyy3mc85perlojufE8Ju_Ui4kGkVIHYJv59bg=s48" alt="Camera360 Ultimate"><a title="Camera360" href="http://www.appbrain.com/app/camera360-ultimate/vStudio.Android.GPhotoPaid" target="_blank">Camera360</a> (Free &amp; Pro Version)</h1>
<p><strong>&ldquo;Turn your phone into a professional camera. Provides LOMO, HDR, axis shift, draft, ghost, etc. and multiple styles.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Makes your stock mobile camera 100 times better; Camera360 provides many different camera modes, effects, and enhancements that will give you a reason to leave your actual camera at home.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1>(For Rooted Android Phones)</h1>
<h1>#9) <img src="http://lh4.ggpht.com/GEwS6nzY0i6oVTqupcsrgzwdMrulHubuepVR1KfwZ6nbNgqne8H2dptn3IIV4FhMBABf-7xNWMGE32WIeA=s48" alt="Titanium Backup ? root"><a title="Titanium Backup" href="http://www.appbrain.com/app/titanium-backup-%E2%98%85-root/com.keramidas.TitaniumBackup" target="_blank">Titanium Backup</a> (Free &amp; Pro Version)</h1>
<p><strong>&ldquo;The ONLY tool that can backup, restore, freeze (with Pro) your apps +  data + Market links! Supports protected and system apps! 0-click  Batch/scheduled backups! The PRO version has 0-click batch restores,  Dropbox sync, Dalvik cleaner &amp; MORE!&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>A real lifesaver. Once you are rooted, Titanium Backup is one of the apps that you will be downloading first. It allows you to backup your existing apps and system data so that you can easily restore them.</p>
<h1>#10) <img src="http://lh4.ggpht.com/pmU8ZhLQqDYRb1OGWf6Ug_kRcRyi4qZVNXWC7eYjBZR6GkRRX_dYY0vCBpC2S35CEBdFkRx2gulBdlb0mQ=s48" alt="Root Explorer (File Manager)"><a title="Root Explorer" href="http://www.appbrain.com/app/root-explorer-%28file-manager%29/com.speedsoftware.rootexplorer" target="_blank">Root Explorer</a> (Paid Version Only)</h1>
<p><strong>&ldquo;Root Explorer is the ultimate file manager for root users. Access the  whole of android&rsquo;s file system (including the elusive data folder!).</strong></p>
<p><strong>Features  include SQLite database viewer, Text Editor, create and extract zip or  tar/gzip files, multi-select, execute scripts, search, remount,  permissions, bookmarks, send files (via email, bluetooth etc), image  thumbnails, APK binary XML viewer, change file owner and group.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>If you are rooted, Root Explorer is one of the bread-and-butter applications that you will need in order to take full advantage of the Superuser access that you are granted. Like the description says, it is the <em>ultimate</em> file manager on the Android market<strong>.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="Elixir Photo" href="http://s4.appbrain.com/screen?id=5317013346735400364&amp;i=1" target="_blank">Photo</a> by <a title="developer" href="http://www.appbrain.com/browse/dev/Tam%C3%A1s+Barta" target="_blank">Tam&aacute;s Barta</a> via <a title="AppBrain" href="http://www.appbrain.com/" target="_blank">AppBrain</a></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/05/must-have-android-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Copycat! Apple Sues Samsung</title>
		<link>/2011/04/copycat-apple-sues-samsung/</link>
		<comments>/2011/04/copycat-apple-sues-samsung/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 17:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Ahn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sued]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=2600</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[?Man is an idiot. He doesn&#8217;t know how to do anything without copying, without imitating, without plagiarizing, without aping. It might even have been that man invented generation by coitus after seeing the grasshopper copulate.? &#8211; Augusto Roa Bastos. My <a href="/2011/04/copycat-apple-sues-samsung/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/04/copycat-apple-sues-samsung/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p style="text-align: center">?Man is an idiot. He doesn&rsquo;t know how to do anything without copying,  without imitating, without plagiarizing, without aping. It might even  have been that man invented generation by coitus after seeing the  grasshopper copulate.?</p>
<p style="text-align: center">&ndash; Augusto Roa Bastos.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2011/04/11x0418b7323f.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="515"></p>
<p>My middle school Latin teacher once told me that &ldquo;if you&rsquo;re not cheating,   then you&rsquo;re not trying.&rdquo; While it was obviously meant to be a joke that  I  never took seriously, it&rsquo;s the only thing I can remember from his   class. However, in the world of trademarks, patents, and intellectual  property rights, there is only  the slightest bit of room for humor &ndash; and  Apple is clearly not in the laughing  mood.</p>
<p>On Friday afternoon, Apple filed a 38-page lawsuit against Samsung, specifically targeting Samsung&rsquo;s Galaxy line which, according to Apple, has &ldquo;slavishly&rdquo; copied the &ldquo;look and feel&rdquo; of the iPad and iPhone. Apple alleges that Samsung not only copied the look and feel of its devices, but also copied the applications and the packaging that the devices are housed in. <a title="Wall Street Journal" href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703916004576271210109389154.html" target="_blank">The Wall Street Journal</a> adds, &ldquo;Apple is also embroiled in legal battles with companies such as  HTC Corp., Motorola Mobility Holdings Inc., Amazon.com Inc., Nokia Corp.  and Eastman Kodak Co. over products such as smartphones and software,  some of whom it has sued and some of whom it has been sued by.&rdquo;</p>
<p style="text-align: left">While the South Korean company plans on defending itself against the lawsuit, the relationship between the two heavyweight consumer electronics companies may be impacted in the future as several Apple products contain computer chips manufactured by Samsung, including parts of the A4 and A5 processors which are found in iOS devices and Apple TV products.</p>
<p style="text-align: left">It would be an extremely rare case for Apple to <em>win</em> something in court based on their argument that Samsung copied the &ldquo;look and feel&rdquo; of their devices, if anything, Apple is just trying to take a stand and make sure that it doesn&rsquo;t <em>lose</em> its competitive advantage over its rivals who are taking business away. Let&rsquo;s face it though; all electronics companies imitate the latest innovative product to hit the market (that&rsquo;s just a part of what makes our economy a free market) and Apple just happens to be leading the way.</p>
<p style="text-align: left">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left"><a title="Photo" href="http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2011/04/11x0418b7323f.jpg" target="_blank">Photo</a> by <a title="Vlad Savov" href="http://www.engadget.com/editor/vlad-savov" target="_blank">Vlad Savov</a> via <a title="Engadget" href="http://www.engadget.com/" target="_blank">Engadget</a></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/04/copycat-apple-sues-samsung/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>AT&#038;T-Mobile?</title>
		<link>/2011/04/att-mobile/</link>
		<comments>/2011/04/att-mobile/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 17:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Ahn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3G]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4G]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LTE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T-Mobile]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=1842</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A GSM monopoly? A savvy business acquisition? A precursor to the end of times? Call it what you&#8217;d like, but AT&#38;T is offering Deutsche Telekom AG 39 billion reasons to sell T-Mobile. The potential mega-merger will face strict scrutiny over <a href="/2011/04/att-mobile/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/04/att-mobile/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://surfpk.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/ATT-Mobile-Engadget.jpeg" alt="" width="342" height="256">A GSM monopoly? A savvy business acquisition? A precursor to the end of times? Call it what you&rsquo;d like, but AT&amp;T is offering Deutsche Telekom AG 39 billion reasons to sell T-Mobile. The potential mega-merger will face strict scrutiny over the next year by the government, the media, and the public, but one thing is certain &ndash; current T-Mobile users have a cause for concern.</p>
<p>As a satisfied customer of T-Mobile since 2002, there are two things that I believe set this cell phone provider apart from the rest, and that is their loyalty to customer service and their great pricing strategy.</p>
<p>So what could this merger mean for us T-Mobile users? Although the networks of AT&amp;T and T-Mobile use the same underlying cellular technology, T-Mobile users who currently have 3G wireless mobile broadband service would eventually have to upgrade to AT&amp;T&rsquo;s 3G or 4G LTE (Long Term Evolution) data services. Say goodbye to $30 unlimited data plans for our beloved Smartphones, and say hello to expensive, capped data plans that charge overage fees. With a company as large as AT&amp;T, customer service is not a primary driving point for their business model and by adding an additional 33.7 million more U.S. customers, how bad could it possibly get? Look on the bright side though, fellow T-Mobilers: You would have a wider array of phones to choose from, including the coveted Apple iPhone, and a merger could lead to better network coverage throughout the States. Although we will have to wait and watch the outcome unfold, if the deal is eventually approved though, I&rsquo;ll be making sure that I&rsquo;m not one of the people left asking, &ldquo;Can you hear me now?&rdquo;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://surfpk.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/ATT-Mobile-Engadget.jpeg" target="_blank">Photo</a> by <a href="http://surfpk.com/att-mobile-att-acquires-t-mobile-usa-for-39-billion/-0346" target="_blank">djshoaib</a> via <a href="http://surfpk.com/" target="_blank">Surfpk<br></a></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/04/att-mobile/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Android Continues to Surge Past the Apple iPhone</title>
		<link>/2011/04/android-continues-to-surge-past-the-apple-iphone/</link>
		<comments>/2011/04/android-continues-to-surge-past-the-apple-iphone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 18:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Ahn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RIM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=2107</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Google continues to take a bite out of the big Apple. After dethroning both RIM (BlackBerry) and the Apple iPhone in the middle of 2010, Google&#8217;s Android mobile operating system continues to increase its grip on the smartphone market with <a href="/2011/04/android-continues-to-surge-past-the-apple-iphone/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/04/android-continues-to-surge-past-the-apple-iphone/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://static3.businessinsider.com/image/4d99f3d3ccd1d5196c0e0000/sai-chart-android-iphone-ios-market-share-ipod-touch.gif" alt="" width="610" height="457"></p>
<p>Google continues to take a bite out of the big Apple. After dethroning both RIM (BlackBerry) and the Apple iPhone in the middle of 2010, Google&rsquo;s Android mobile operating system continues to increase its grip on the smartphone market with a growth of 7% since last November. With over 1/3 of the market share, the Android platform is really growing into the vision that Google and the Open Handset Alliance sought to develop, when they collaborated to create a modified version of the Linux kernel for mobile devices. The open-source software stack has a large community of developers, both paid and those who choose to develop on their own free time, who have combined to write over 150,000 apps for the Android Market, many of which are available for free. Google even introduced a live, online Android Market that can be accessed via computer, where Android smartphone users can download apps directly to their phone from the convenience of their computer.</p>
<p>One downside to Android&rsquo;s continual growth is that the platform is still heavily fragmented, with multiple phone manufacturers running multiple different firmwares, leading to developers having issues streamlining apps and wondering whether their apps will even work on future versions of Android. In order to combat this fragmentation, Google has taken the initiative by gaining total control of the Android platform, even going as far as to create non-fragmentation clauses that would give Google final veto rights. What this means for developers and smartphone users in the future though is uncertain, after all, Google promised to keep Android open-source&hellip;but that didn&rsquo;t last for long.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://static3.businessinsider.com/image/4d99f3d3ccd1d5196c0e0000/sai-chart-android-iphone-ios-market-share-ipod-touch.gif" target="_blank">Photo</a> by <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/author/dylan-love" target="_blank">Dylan Love</a> via <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/" target="_blank">BusinessInsider</a></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/04/android-continues-to-surge-past-the-apple-iphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>HP&#8217;s cards are finally on the table, but not all of them are good.</title>
		<link>/2011/02/hps-cards-are-finally-on-the-table-but-not-all-of-them-are-good/</link>
		<comments>/2011/02/hps-cards-are-finally-on-the-table-but-not-all-of-them-are-good/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 13:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP Pre3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP Slate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP TouchPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP Veer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP WebOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm Pre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm Pre 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pre3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Think Beyond]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TouchPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WebOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WebOS 2.0]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=215</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/02/HPsCardsAreOnTheTable-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="HPsCardsAreOnTheTable" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Yesterday HP had its big announcement that had the tech world waiting on pins and needles. A lot of famous people were in the audience, including the requisite journalists and even a few minor celebrities (MC Hammer and&#160;Serena Williams). The <a href="/2011/02/hps-cards-are-finally-on-the-table-but-not-all-of-them-are-good/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/02/hps-cards-are-finally-on-the-table-but-not-all-of-them-are-good/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/02/HPsCardsAreOnTheTable-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="HPsCardsAreOnTheTable" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-240" title="HPs Cards Are On The Table" src="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/HPsCardsAreOnTheTable.jpg" alt="HPs Cards Are On The Table" width="480" height="200"></p>
<p>Yesterday HP had its big announcement that had the tech world waiting on pins and needles. A lot of famous people were in the audience, including the requisite journalists and even a few minor celebrities (MC Hammer and&nbsp;Serena Williams<em>).</em> The one thing that <a title="RIP, Palm: 1992 - 2011 -- Engadget" href="http://www.engadget.com/2011/02/09/rip-palm-1992-2011/" target="_blank">everyone</a> seemed to&nbsp;<a title="Fare thee well, Palm -- we'll miss you | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/fare-thee-well-palm-we-ll-miss-you" target="_blank">noticed</a> was suspiciously missing was the Palm logo, which is <a title="Palm's site updated with newly announced devices (but lacking Palm logo) | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/palm-s-site-updated-newly-announced-devices-but-lacking-palm-logo" target="_blank">now missing</a> from <a title="Palm USA | Mobile Products for Consumers, Professionals, and Businesses" href="http://www.palm.com/us/" target="_blank">Palm&rsquo;s website</a>. [<strong>UPDATE</strong>:&nbsp;OK, now it&rsquo;s back? Make up your mind people!]&nbsp;This was just a foreshadow of the real stab to the hearts of Palm fans that would come later in the day.<span id="more-215"></span></p>
<p>The&nbsp;announcement&nbsp;yesterday wasn&rsquo;t quite a royal flush; it was more like 3 of a kind and a couple of jokers. I know that would normally be an incredible hand, but suffice it to say that these jokers were not good ones. Let me start with the three of a kind: HP announced three new devices yesterday.</p>
<p><a href="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/veer-open-left.png"></a><a href="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/veer-open-left.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-237" title="HP Veer" src="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/veer-open-left.jpg"  alt="HP Veer" width="75" height="150"></a>The first device announced, the <a title="HP Veer Phone | Features, Details" href="http://www.palm.com/us/products/phones/veer/index.html" target="_blank">HP Veer</a>, is an incredibly small, and pretty much adorable, device that is apparently replacing the Palm Pixi line. The Veer has a 2.6 inches&nbsp;screen, which is almost exactly the same size as the Pixi. However, the Veer is a portrait slider instead of a candybar. Another differentiating factor is that in addition to being&nbsp;compatible&nbsp;with the iconic Touchstone charger it has a magnetic USB connector that it charges through and transmits data through. The Veer camera is significantly upgraded over the Pixi with a 5-megapixel camera with extended depth of field. Most of the reviewers that got their hands on it were surprised at how&nbsp;comfortable&nbsp;it was to use, despite its diminutive size. The question remains though, &ldquo;<a title="The HP Veer Gamble | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/hp-veer-gamble" target="_blank">Is there a market for a small smartphone like the Veer?</a>&rdquo; Other companies have tried and failed. Does the Veer have something that will set it apart, or will it crash and burn like the others?</p>
<p><a href="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/pre3-front-left-opened.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-full wp-image-232 alignleft" title="HP Pre3" src="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/pre3-front-left-opened.jpg"  alt="HP Pre3" width="75" height="150"></a>Their second device they announced yesterday is the one that most Palm fanboys and girls were waiting on: the next iteration of what was Palm&rsquo;s flagship phone, the&nbsp;<a title="HP Pre 3 Phone | Features, Details" href="http://www.palm.com/us/products/phones/pre3/index.html" target="_blank">HP Pre<sup>3</sup></a>. In addition to having an annoying superscripted number three at the end of its name, the Pre<sup>3</sup> also comes with a larger, 3.58 inch, 800 x 480 pixel screen and a 1.4 GHz Qualcomm Snapdragon processor. It also has a front-facing VGA camera and a rear-facing 5-megapixel auto-focus camera with LED flash, and HD 720p video recording. Some other minor upgrades include a digital compass, dual-mic noise cancellation, and a slightly larger battery. Many fans were hoping for something larger, but one of the presenters said that HP wanted to differentiate themselves from the &ldquo;bigger is better&rdquo; crowd.</p>
<p><a href="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/tp-left-front.jpg"></a><a href="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/tp-left-front.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-235" title="HP TouchPad" src="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/tp-left-front.jpg"  alt="HP TouchPad" width="100" height="160"></a>The&nbsp;pi&egrave;ce de r&eacute;sistance of the event was the <a title="Palm USA | HP TouchPad" href="http://www.palm.com/us/products/pads/touchpad/index.html" target="_blank">HP TouchPad</a>. This was the device that kept <a title="HP can't help but tease after slate leak: &quot;Think again.&quot; | PreCentral.net | The #1 Palm Pre and Pixi Community" href="http://www.precentral.net/hp-can-t-help-tease-after-slate-leak-think-again" target="_blank">sneaking out and starting rumors</a>. The TouchPad has&nbsp;a 9.7-inch XGA capacitive, multitouch, 1024&times;768 resolution display and a front-facing 1.3-megapixel webcam. One of the features of the TouchPad that HP seemed to be the proudest of was the integration of&nbsp;<a href="http://www.beatsbydre.com/">Beats Audio<sup>?</sup> by Dr. Dre</a>. Although there aren&rsquo;t any technical specifics about what makes this brand of sound equipment better, HP says that it &ldquo;reproduces the original sonic integrity of digital tracks?letting you hear the music the way recording artists intended.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Although the hardware was certainly impressive, a large portion of the event was spent talking about new apps for the devices. HP especially focused on the applications that are designed specifically for the TouchPad, such as the new Time Inc, magazines, the Kindle app, and Quickoffice. However, the highlight of the event was seeing how the new version of WebOS, verions 2.2 on the Pre<sup>3</sup> and Veer, and 3.0 on the TouchPad, work and how they work together. For example, you can &ldquo;move&rdquo; web content that you are viewing on one device to another just by taping the two devices together. Also, you can answer a phone call or receive text messages that came in on your WebOS Phone on your TouchPad instead.&nbsp;HP also gave us a sneak peak into the future. HP intends to bring WebOS to desktops and laptops, thus bridging the gap from mobile devices to our more stationary devices and extending the experience.</p>
<p>The two daggers to the hearts of Palm fans that I mentioned earlier were discovered after the bright lights had come down and had everyone started to trickle out of the Herbst Pavilion. First, even though HP CEO <a title='HP CEO Apotheker: "the [new webOS] hardware is ready" | PreCentral.net' href="http://www.precentral.net/hp-ceo-apotheker-the-hardware-ready" target="_blank">Leo Apotheker promised that the new HP WebOS hardware was ready</a> and that it&nbsp;<a title="BBC News - Can Leo Apotheker make Hewlett Packard a cool company?" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-12291529" target="_blank">would be ready to ship within weeks of the announcement</a>, the Veer is the only device shipping within the next few <em>months</em>. HP officially says on its website that the TouchPad and the Pre<sup>3</sup> are planned to be available this summer, and the Veer is planned to be available this spring. These statements have the sad, familiar ring of the line that became infamous within the WebOS community: &ldquo;in the coming months.&rdquo;&nbsp;&nbsp;This was the answer every time there was a <a title="YouTube - I said release the pre" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8Kgex9Q69lY" target="_blank">delay in releasing the Palm Pre</a>, &nbsp;<a title='Verizon and Canada to get Pre 2 in "coming months" | PreCentral.net' href="http://www.precentral.net/verizon-and-canada-get-pre-2-coming-months" target="_blank">the Pre 2,</a> <a title='webOS 2.0 will be released to "all devices" in coming months (Update: Video online) | PreCentral.net' href="http://www.precentral.net/webos-2-0-will-be-released-all-devices-coming-months-update-video-online" target="_blank">WebOS 2.0</a> and <a title="Flash Player 10.1 coming to Palm Pre (Adobe Flash Platform Blog) " href="http://blogs.adobe.com/flashplatform/2010/01/flash_player_101_coming_to_pal.html" target="_blank">Adobe Flash support</a>.&nbsp;It was also noted that neither the price of these new devices or the carriers that they would be on was disclosed.</p>
<p>The second and most painful wound for WebOS fans came when both&nbsp;<a title="Original Pre, Pre Plus, Pixi and Pixi Plus won't get updated to webOS 2.0" href="http://www.engadget.com/2011/02/09/original-pre-pre-plus-pixi-and-pixi-plus-wont-get-updated-to/" target="_blank">Engadget</a> and <a title="No major webOS OTA Updates to Pre, Pre Plus, Pixi, Pixi Plus" href="http://www.precentral.net/no-major-webos-ota-updates-pre-pre-plus-pixi-pixi-plus" target="_blank">PreCentral</a> spoke to the folks at HP behind WebOS and they confirmed to both sites that the Palm Pre, Pixi, Pre Plus, and Pixi Plus will not receive any more major over-the-air updates of WebOS. Jon Rubinstein told Engadget that the older devices simply did not have the necessary specs to support WebOS 2.0 properly. Apparently HP has &ldquo;something special&rdquo; planned for owners of the older devices when the new devices go on sale; what that means at this point is anyone&rsquo;s guess. In the midst of the resulting torch and pitchfork waving from the incited masses, HP showed its humanity and compassion towards its loyal users when <a title="Twitter / @Lisa Brewster" href="http://twitter.com/#!/Adora/status/35517969089953792" target="_blank">Lisa Brewster of Palm Developer Relations tweeted</a>: &ldquo;We&rsquo;ve broken a promise to our most faithful users, and that has my heart heavy tonight. Ppl keep asking if I&rsquo;m ok.&rdquo; <a title="Twitter / @palm" href="http://twitter.com/#!/palm/status/35490855481507840" target="_blank">Palm later tweeted</a> from their official Twitter account: &ldquo;All the feedback and questions are appreciated &mdash; will be sharing as much info as possible as soon as possible&rdquo;</p>
<p>In the end, HP may have scored a win with the general public, but they also scored an epic fail with their fiercely loyal fans that stuck with them through <a title="Crossing the webOS Desert | WebOS Roundup" href="http://www.webosroundup.com/2010/06/crossing-the-webos-desert/" target="_blank">the WebOS Desert</a>. HP needs to respond quickly to this <a title="Twitter / @Ray Hollister" href="http://twitter.com/#!/RayHollister/status/35468167048466432" target="_blank">PR nightmare</a> with something that will salve the wounds that they inflicted. Then, HP needs to get these devices out quickly before new iOS and Android hardware comes out that make the new HP devices look beige and boring again.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/02/hps-cards-are-finally-on-the-table-but-not-all-of-them-are-good/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
