<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Ask Deemable Tech: Wi-Fi Assist</title>
		<link>/2016/06/ask-deemable-tech-wi-fi-assist/</link>
		<comments>/2016/06/ask-deemable-tech-wi-fi-assist/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 18:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ask Deemable Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wi-Fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wi-Fi Assist]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10604</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/07/iphone_wi-fi-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="iphone_wi-fi" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Walter writes, &#8220;I read a story about a teenager who ran up a $2,000 phone bill because they thought they were using Wi-Fi but they were actually on the cellular network. I didn&#8217;t catch the whole story, but I know <a href="/2016/06/ask-deemable-tech-wi-fi-assist/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2016/06/ask-deemable-tech-wi-fi-assist/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/07/iphone_wi-fi-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="iphone_wi-fi" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><em><a href="/media/2016/07/iphone_wi-fi.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-10622" src="/media/2016/07/iphone_wi-fi-300x150.jpg"  alt="iphone_wi-fi" width="300" height="150"></a>Walter writes, &ldquo;I read a story about a teenager who ran up a $2,000 phone bill because they thought they were using Wi-Fi but they were actually on the cellular network. I didn&rsquo;t catch the whole story, but I know it had something to do with iPhones. Do you know what&rsquo;s going on?&rdquo;</em></p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10604-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/06/adt20160616.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/06/adt20160616.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/06/adt20160616.mp3</a></audio><p>We heard about that story too, Walter, and all we can say is, &ldquo;Yikes!&rdquo;</p>
<p>It sounds like it wasn?t entirely the kid&rsquo;s fault, though. There&rsquo;s a new feature in iOS 9 called <strong>Wi-Fi Assist</strong> that was at least partially responsible.</p>
<p>Wi-Fi Assist helps to make sure you have a solid data connection when you&rsquo;re using Wi-Fi, even if your Wi-Fi connection is really weak. For example, if you&rsquo;re in a part of your house that is far away from your wireless router, Wi-Fi Assist will automatically switch your phone over to 4G cellular data to keep you connected to the internet.</p>
<p>This is great for people who have unlimited data plans, but it could run up your bill pretty quickly if you have a data cap and you&rsquo;re not paying attention to how much you&rsquo;re using.</p>
<hr><p>For tips on keeping your data usage low, check out our other articles <a href="/2013/04/michelle-asks-how-can-i-lower-my-data-usage-on-my-iphone/" target="_blank">here</a>, <a href="/2014/09/angela-asks-can-monthly-usage-smartphone/" target="_blank">here</a> and <a href="/2015/05/ask-deemable-tech-why-am-i-using-so-much-data/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<hr><p style="text-align: left;">If you&rsquo;re worried about Wi-Fi Assist eating up your data, here&rsquo;s how to turn it off:</p>
<ul><li style="text-align: left;">Open the Settings app</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Tap Cellular</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Scroll all the to the bottom of that menu</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Tap the toggle button next to Wi-Fi Assist</li>
</ul><p>In the Cellular menu, you&rsquo;ll also see a list of all of the apps on your phone that use cellular data. Next to each one is a toggle button to turn data for it on or off. It&rsquo;s a good idea to look through this list to see if there are any using data that don&rsquo;t need to be, especially ones you rarely use anymore.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/06/ask-deemable-tech-wi-fi-assist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/06/adt20160616.mp3" length="3184244" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#106 It&#8217;s So Hard To Say Goodbye&#8230; For Now</title>
		<link>/2016/05/106-its-so-haroodbye-for-now/</link>
		<comments>/2016/05/106-its-so-haroodbye-for-now/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 16:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chromebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10579</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/05/dt_explosion-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="dt_explosion" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week Ray, Tom and Sean talk about quantum computers, Google&#8217;s new messaging apps, and the possibility of an all-glass iPhone. Plus the guys share some sad news. A special message from Ray, Tom and Sean If you&#8217;re an avid <a href="/2016/05/106-its-so-haroodbye-for-now/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2016/05/106-its-so-haroodbye-for-now/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/05/dt_explosion-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="dt_explosion" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week Ray, Tom and Sean talk about quantum computers, Google&rsquo;s new messaging apps, and the possibility of an all-glass iPhone. Plus the guys share some sad news.</p>
<p><a href="/media/2016/05/dt_explosion.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-10585 size-full" src="/media/2016/05/dt_explosion.jpg"  alt="dt_explosion" width="960" height="720"></a></p>
<p><span id="more-10579"></span></p>
<h3>A special message from Ray, Tom and Sean</h3>
<p>If you&rsquo;re an avid listener to Deemable Tech, it will probably come as no surprise that we&rsquo;ve been having some difficulty putting out shows for the past few months. The three of us have gone through some major changes in our careers and lives over the past year, and those have taken away a lot of the time we&rsquo;ve had to devote to bringing you this show every week.</p>
<p>So, after months of not recording an episode, we&rsquo;ve made the tough decision to end the Deemable Tech podcast. For now, at least.</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ve come to the realization that it is just not sustainable. We can&rsquo;t keep producing the show to the level that we did before, and it was unfair of us to leave you in the dark about it.</p>
<p>We may relaunch the show down the road, if we are able to.&nbsp;If&nbsp;you are interested in finding out when we or if we do, sign up for our newsletter on the right side of this page.&nbsp;You&rsquo;ll be the first to know.</p>
<p>We won&rsquo;t be gone completely, though. You can still catch us answering your tech questions every week on Ask Deemable Tech, so be sure to subscribe to that podcast or listen live Thursdays on 89.9 FM WJCT.</p>
<p>If you have any farewell messages for us, leave us a voicemail at 1-888-972-9868 or send an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ve truly appreciated you listening to (and sometimes even enjoying) our shenanigans for the past four years. It&rsquo;s been a blast.</p>
<p>Now let&rsquo;s take this baby for one last ride!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://i.giphy.com/mWmip2ArAPHJC.gif" alt=""></p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10579-2" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/DeemableTech_2016-05-23.mp3?_=2"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/DeemableTech_2016-05-23.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/DeemableTech_2016-05-23.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>Google releases Science Journal app</h3>
<p>For those of you who loved doing science projects as a kid, Google recently released a new app that you&rsquo;ll love.</p>
<p>The app, Science Journal, uses the sensors in your phone to measure and record data in real time, including movement, light and sound.</p>
<p><span style="letter-spacing: 0.05em; line-height: 1.6875;"><a href="https://makingscience.withgoogle.com/science-journal" target="_blank">As Google says on the Science Journal site</a>, &ldquo;See something you want to measure? How much light is in my room compared to outside? How loud is the dog&rsquo;s bark compared to my cough? Record your observations in real-time at the press of a button. Explore your environment or measure things you&rsquo;ve built yourself.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p>Among other features, Science Journal lets you record measurements as charts and graphs, and record a voice memo as you&rsquo;re doing your experiment so you can give extra details about it.</p>
<p>Google has also partnered with the Exploratorium in San Francisco to sell special little kits with materials like sensors your phone doesn&rsquo;t have to let you measure other stuff.</p>
<p>Science Journal is currently only available for Android.</p>
<h3>It&rsquo;s all about the qubits, baby</h3>
<p>Verge is reporting that IBM has made <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2016/5/4/11589656/ibm-quantum-computing-cloud" target="_blank">a working quantum computer that anyone in the world can play with</a>.</p>
<p>What does that mean? Glad you asked! Basically, as anyone who has watched any movie from the 90s that involved computers can tell you, computers work by translating ones and zeros into machine understandable language and then translating that into human language and user interfaces. Quantum computers use ones, zeros and both at the same time.</p>
<p>Now the question is, what to do with that. We&rsquo;ve built an entire industry out of a binary system, and now that we have the capability to expand it to a trinary or &ldquo;ternary&rdquo; system, the question is how to use it. So, IBM has opened it to the public for research and experimentation because basically the only people who understand what we just said are scientists.</p>
<h3>Google says hello to Allo and Duo</h3>
<p>One area where Google has long lagged behind competitors like Apple and Facebook has been in messaging. Rather than having a single, unified messaging app, Google has introduced numerous messaging systems like Gchat, Google Hangouts, and the default Android text-messaging app.</p>
<p>This week at Google&rsquo;s I/O event, the company announced <a href="http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2016/05/googles-allo-and-duo-are-2-communication-apps-based-on-your-phone-number/" target="_blank">two new messaging apps, Allo and Duo</a>. Allo is for text messaging, and includes Google bot technology which offers up auto-responses to messages based on things you usually type.</p>
<p>Duo, meanwhile, is a 1-on-1 video chat app. It is optimized to work even in low-bandwidth situations.</p>
<p>Both apps support end-to-end encryption, however, controversially, it will not be enabled be default. Some think this might be because it would impede their ability to offer features like the auto response bot.</p>
<h3>All-glass iPhone?</h3>
<p>We couldn&rsquo;t do a final episode of the podcast without Ray talking about iPhones, could we?</p>
<p>Forbes is reporting that the <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/ewanspence/2016/05/20/apple-news-digest-iphone-7-leak-ios-9-3-2-broken/#6d348b86407d" target="_blank">iPhone 8 could lose the unibody aluminium case for an all glass one</a>. No, you didn&rsquo;t read that incorrectly, the next iPhone is the presumptively going to be coined the &ldquo;7&rdquo;, but this rumor is about the iPhone 8.</p>
<p>The glass case is expected to wrap around the entire device and have no bezel as a result.</p>
<p>And apparently the entire front of the phone will be screen. The front facing camera, touch ID sensor, speaker and proximity sensor will somehow all be behind the screen.</p>
<h3>Android apps coming to Chromebooks</h3>
<p>The Google Play Store is coming to Chromebooks. Along with every single Android app!</p>
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2016/05/if-you-want-to-run-android-apps-on-chromebooks-youll-need-a-newer-model/" target="_blank">As Ars Technica puts it</a>, everything &ldquo;from Microsoft Word to Hearthstone to Firefox will be able to run on Chrome OS without noticeable performance penalties.&rdquo;</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s the pretty great stuff. Here&rsquo;s the asterisk: Google has released a compatibility list for this amazing new feature and it basically excludes any Chromebook older than two years old. This even includes Google&rsquo;s souped-up and overpriced Pixel Chromebook.</p>
<p><em>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at&nbsp;<a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/05/106-its-so-haroodbye-for-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/DeemableTech_2016-05-23.mp3" length="33498125" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ask Deemable Tech: Browser Extensions</title>
		<link>/2016/05/browser-extensions/</link>
		<comments>/2016/05/browser-extensions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 16:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[add-ons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extensions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Firefox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web browsers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10568</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/05/browser_extensions-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="browser_extensions" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Steve writes, &#8220;When I&#8217;m on the internet, I constantly see things pop up on the screen that say &#8216;Check for malware now&#8217; or &#8216;You&#8217;re missing drivers, click to update.&#8217; Should I click on it? The way things are nowadays, I&#8217;m <a href="/2016/05/browser-extensions/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2016/05/browser-extensions/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/05/browser_extensions-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="browser_extensions" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><strong><a href="/media/2016/05/browser_extensions.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-10569" src="/media/2016/05/browser_extensions-300x228.jpg"  alt="browser_extensions" width="300" height="228"></a>Steve writes, &ldquo;When I&rsquo;m on the internet, I constantly see things pop up on the screen that say &lsquo;Check for malware now&rsquo; or &lsquo;You&rsquo;re missing drivers, click to update.&rsquo; Should I click on it? The way things are nowadays, I&rsquo;m afraid to try!&rdquo;&nbsp;</strong><span id="more-10568"></span></p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10568-3" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/adt20160519.mp3?_=3"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/adt20160519.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/adt20160519.mp3</a></audio><p>Don&rsquo;t click on it, Steve! As our friend Admiral Ackbar would say:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://i.giphy.com/3ornka9rAaKRA2Rkac.gif" alt="It's a trap!"></p>
<p>What you&rsquo;re seeing is a pop-up ad designed to trick you into visiting a spam website or downloading harmful malware.</p>
<p>Internet pop-ups will disguise themselves as all kinds of stuff to get you to click on them. Spammers have gotten pretty good at making pop-ups look like legitimate error messages, so sometimes it can be hard to tell it&rsquo;s a pop-up until it?s too late. Our advice is to install a pop-up blocker extension for your browser.</p>
<p>Extensions (also known as add-ons) are little programs you can install on some web browsers which give them extra features. There are a lot of extensions for the Mozilla Firefox and Google Chrome browsers, including effective pop-up blockers.</p>
<p><a href="https://adblockplus.org/" target="_blank">Adblock Plus</a> is one of the most popular pop-up blockers, and is available for both Firefox and Chrome. It not only kills 98 percent of pop-up ads, but also removes most of the in-page ads from many websites. Try it out, and hopefully you&rsquo;ll never see another one of those pesky fake error messages again.</p>
<p>But we wouldn&rsquo;t stop there with browser extensions. You can trick out your browser in a number of cool ways. Some of our favorites include:</p>
<ul><li>Lazarus: Form Recovery &ndash; Remembers what you were typing in an online form, in case something happens while you&rsquo;re filling one out and you lose everything. (<a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/lazarus-form-recovery/loljledaigphbcpfhfmgopdkppkifgno?hl=en" target="_blank">Lazarus for Chome</a>) (<a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-uS/firefox/addon/lazarus-form-recovery/" target="_blank">Lazarus for Firefox</a>)</li>
</ul><ul><li><span style="line-height: 1.5;">Panic Button &ndash; Immediately hides all of your open browser tabs with a single click. We&rsquo;re not saying that it comes in really handy for when your boss walks by, but we&rsquo;d have to imagine it would. (<a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/panicbutton/faminaibgiklngmfpfbhmokfmnglamcm?hl=en" target="_blank">Panic Button for Chrome</a>) (<a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/panic-button/" target="_blank">Panic Button for Firefox</a>)</span></li>
</ul><ul><li>LastPass<span style="line-height: 1.5;"> &ndash; One of our favorite password managers. Stores all of your passwords, generates complex new ones, and automatically fills in login fields for you. (<a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/lastpass-free-password-ma/hdokiejnpimakedhajhdlcegeplioahd?hl=en-US" target="_blank">LastPass for Chrome</a>) (<a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/lastpass-password-manager/" target="_blank">LastPass for Firefox</a>)</span></li>
</ul><ul><li><span style="line-height: 1.5;">Honey &ndash; Automatically finds coupon codes and sales for many popular online stores. (<a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/honey/bmnlcjabgnpnenekpadlanbbkooimhnj?hl=en-US" target="_blank">Honey for Chrome</a>) (<a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/honey/" target="_blank">Honey for Firefox</a>)</span></li>
</ul><ul><li><span style="line-height: 1.5;">Google Tone &ndash; Google&rsquo;s experimental extension, only for Chrome, which lets you share links with your nearby friends through sound. (<a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/google-tone/nnckehldicaciogcbchegobnafnjkcne?hl=en" target="_blank">Google Tone for Chrome</a>)</span></li>
</ul><p><span style="line-height: 1.5;">It&rsquo;s important that you only download Firefox </span><span style="line-height: 1.5;">a</span>dd-ons<span style="line-height: 1.5;"> from the official <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/" target="_blank">Mozilla Firefox add-on site</a>, and only download Chrome extensions from the <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/category/apps" target="_blank">Google Chrome web store</a>. Downloading extensions from other locations could be dangerous. </span></p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5;">You may have noticed that we haven?t mentioned extensions for Microsoft?s Internet Explorer browser. The reason is, well, IE doesn?t really support them. That?s just one of its many, many issues. In fact, with Windows 10, Microsoft is officially killing it and replacing it with the new Edge Browser, which will support extensions soon. Until then, we recommend giving Firefox or Chrome a shot. </span></p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5;">Safe surfing!</span></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/05/browser-extensions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/adt20160519.mp3" length="3484145" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ask Deemable Tech: How Do I Block Spam Text Messages?</title>
		<link>/2016/05/ask-deemable-t-text-messages/</link>
		<comments>/2016/05/ask-deemable-t-text-messages/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 22:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Text Message]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10556</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/07/blocked_call-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image Credit: Tap Call" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Norma writes, &#8220;How do you stop receiving an automated text message? When I got my new phone I started receiving messages from a store telling me about their specials. I&#8217;ve tried visiting the website and &#8216;unsubscribing&#8217; but that didn&#8217;t work.&#8221; <a href="/2016/05/ask-deemable-t-text-messages/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2016/05/ask-deemable-t-text-messages/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/07/blocked_call-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image Credit: Tap Call" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_9070" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2014/07/blocked_call.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-9070" src="/media/2014/07/blocked_call-300x225.jpg"  alt="Image Credit: Tap Call" width="300" height="225"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image Credit: Tap Call</p></div>
<p><strong>Norma writes, &ldquo;How do you stop receiving an automated text message? When I got my new phone I started receiving messages from a store telling me about their specials. I&rsquo;ve tried visiting the website and &lsquo;unsubscribing&rsquo; but that didn&rsquo;t work.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10556-4" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/adt20160505.mp3?_=4"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/adt20160505.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/adt20160505.mp3</a></audio><p>We feel you, Norma. Like junk mail and spam email, unsolicited text messages are the bane of our existence. Luckily there are ways to stop them.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re receiving texts from a reputable company, there should be a way to unsubscribe from them through a text. Scroll back through the text messages from that number, and you&rsquo;ll probably find a message telling you to text the word &ldquo;STOP,&rdquo; &ldquo;QUIT,&rdquo; &ldquo;END,&rdquo; or &ldquo;UNSUBSCRIBE&rdquo; to stop receiving texts from them. Different companies use different keywords, but most of the time if you text the word &ldquo;HELP&rdquo; to them, they will tell you what other keywords work on their system.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re receiving genuine spam texts from a less than reputable source, the best thing you can do is to not respond. This just lets the scammers know that your number is a good one to keep spamming. Your only choice is to block the number sending you those texts.</p>
<p><strong>How to block numbers on iOS</strong></p>
<ul><li>Open the offending text message</li>
<li>Tap Details</li>
<li>Tap the &ldquo;i&rdquo; button in the top right</li>
<li>Tap &ldquo;Block this Caller&rdquo;</li>
</ul><p><strong>How to block numbers on Android</strong></p>
<ul><li>Find the text message you want to block in the Message app</li>
<li>Press and hold it until a pop up appears</li>
<li>Tap the &ldquo;Block it as spam&rdquo; option</li>
</ul><p>If you&rsquo;re using a regular cell phone, you&rsquo;ll have to block the texts through your carrier.</p>
<p><strong>AT&amp;T</strong></p>
<ul><li>To report spam text messages on AT&amp;T, forward the offending text message to 7726 (SPAM)</li>
<li>You can also call their customer service at 1-800-331-0500 to report spam</li>
</ul><p><strong>Sprint</strong></p>
<ul><li>Follow <a href="http://support.sprint.com/support/article/Block-restrict-or-allow-text-services-via-My-Sprint/case-fk158645-20100930-171711%22">these directions on Sprint&rsquo;s site</a> to block numbers</li>
<li>Or call customer service at 1-888-211-4727</li>
</ul><p><strong>Verizon</strong></p>
<ul><li>Call 1-800-922-0204 to report the spam to customer service</li>
</ul><p><strong>T-Mobile</strong></p>
<ul><li>Call customer service at 1-877-453-1304</li>
<li>Or use their <a href="https://support.t-mobile.com/community/contact-us">live chat</a> to block the number</li>
</ul></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/05/ask-deemable-t-text-messages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/adt20160505.mp3" length="3623689" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ask Deemable Tech: Do I Need To Wait To Upgrade To Windows 10?</title>
		<link>/2016/02/10527/</link>
		<comments>/2016/02/10527/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 23:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10527</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/02/windows_10_logo-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="windows_10_logo" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Joan writes, &#8220;I&#8217;m running Windows 7 on my laptop, and for the past five months I&#8217;ve had a request pending to get the upgrade to Windows 10. Am I supposed to just keep waiting patiently, or is there something else <a href="/2016/02/10527/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2016/02/10527/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/02/windows_10_logo-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="windows_10_logo" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="/media/2016/02/windows_10_logo.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10528 alignleft" src="/media/2016/02/windows_10_logo-300x247.jpg"  alt="windows_10_logo" width="300" height="247"></a>Joan writes, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m running Windows 7 on my laptop, and for the past five months I&rsquo;ve had a request pending to get the upgrade to Windows 10. Am I supposed to just keep waiting patiently, or is there something else I&rsquo;m supposed to do?&rdquo;</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10527-5" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/02/adt20160225.mp3?_=5"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/02/adt20160225.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/02/adt20160225.mp3</a></audio><p>Congratulations, Joan, on being way more patient than we are! We&rsquo;re about to lose our minds just waiting for the next season of &ldquo;Sherlock&rdquo; to air.</p>
<p>You should be able to download and upgrade to Windows 10 right now for free, if you&rsquo;re currently using Windows 7, 8 or 8.1 Most Windows users have been receiving little notifications about the update since July 2015. If you clicked on that notification and followed the directions, it should have upgraded your system as soon as Windows 10 became available.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re not getting those notifications, or that option just didn&rsquo;t work for some reason, you can go to <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/windows-10-upgrade" target="_blank">Microsoft&rsquo;s website</a> and click the Windows 10 link to manually start the download and installation.</p>
<p>But why would you want to upgrade to Windows 10? Well, it depends on which operating system you&rsquo;re currently using.</p>
<p>Windows 10 is a much smaller installation than Windows 7. It runs a lot faster, and you&rsquo;ll see a big performance boost by upgrading, even without changing any of the hardware in your computer.</p>
<p>For those readers currently running Windows 8, you absolutely have to upgrade to Windows 10 as soon as possible. Microsoft dropped support for Windows 8 in early 2016, which means there won&rsquo;t be any more security updates, software patches or bug fixes.</p>
<p>There aren&rsquo;t as many differences between Windows 8.1 and Windows 10, but we still suggest upgrading anyway. You&rsquo;ll get the latest version that should be supported for longer, and you?ll get some cool new features like Cortana, Microsoft&rsquo;s virtual assistant that is sort of like Siri for your home PC.</p>
<p>Another new feature we really like are virtual desktops, which let you set up multiple virtual workspaces on one computer and switch back and forth between them. It&rsquo;s like having multiple screens without having extra monitors.</p>
<p>So, Joan, go ahead and upgrade, and see if you like it!</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/02/10527/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/02/adt20160225.mp3" length="3353129" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ask Deemable Tech: Tech Support Scammers</title>
		<link>/2016/02/ask-deemable-tpport-scammers/</link>
		<comments>/2016/02/ask-deemable-tpport-scammers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 20:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech support]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10514</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/10/scam-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Scam Computer Keys Showing Swindles And Fraud" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Today we have not one but two related questions from different listeners. Lenny writes, &#8220;Last week I received a call from a guy who said he was from Microsoft. He said they had detected that my computer was having problems. <a href="/2016/02/ask-deemable-tpport-scammers/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2016/02/ask-deemable-tpport-scammers/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/10/scam-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Scam Computer Keys Showing Swindles And Fraud" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="/media/2014/10/scam.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-9348 alignleft" src="/media/2014/10/scam-300x225.jpg"  alt="Scam Computer Keys Showing Swindles And Fraud" width="300" height="225"></a>Today we have not one but two related questions from different listeners.</p>
<p>Lenny writes, <em>&ldquo;Last week I received a call from a guy who said he was from Microsoft. He said they had detected that my computer was having problems. To prove it, he told me how to open my Windows log file, and when I did it was full of errors. So I paid him to fix all the problems and scan for viruses. Now I&rsquo;m wondering if that was really a good idea.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Sandra sends us a similar story. She says: <em>&ldquo;I was checking my email and all of a sudden windows started giving me an error message which said it had a virus. It included a phone number. I called the number and a man connected to my computer and fixed it. But now my computer runs slowly and this guy charged me a lot of money. Have I been hacked?&rdquo;</em></p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10514-6" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/02/adt20160211.mp3?_=6"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/02/adt20160211.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/02/adt20160211.mp3</a></audio><p>Neither Sandra nor Lenny were hacked. They were, unfortunately, the victims of one of the most popular scams on the internet these days.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s how it works: crafty scammers convince people that their computer has a serious problem, and the only way to fix it is to pay the scammers money. In actuality, there is no such problem, and these people are paying for nothing.</p>
<p>This is such a major issue that Microsoft testified about it in front of Congress in the fall of 2015. These scammers love to impersonate major, legitimate companies like Microsoft, Apple, and HP, which can create problems for those organizations.</p>
<p>So, what can you do to make sure you don&rsquo;t fall for this scam? Remember one simple rule: tech support will never call you out of the blue. You call them first.</p>
<p>And just to be clear, Windows error messages do not include a number for Microsoft tech support. If you see an error message that says you need to call Microsoft or any other company immediately, there is a good chance that you are seeing a fake error message. Maybe it&rsquo;s just a clever web page, but do not call the phone number.</p>
<p>If you do talk to these scammers, they can be very convincing. They may do things like you show a Windows log file full of errors to make you think there is something wrong with your PC. The thing is, though, your computer&rsquo;s logs are always full of errors, but they are little ones that are perfectly normal.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, both Sandra and Lenny let the scammers gain access to their computers. All of these scammers, once they have you on the phone, will ask you to run or download programs that let them look at your computer remotely. Do not do this! You should never let someone who you don&rsquo;t completely trust have remote access to your computer. They can&rsquo;t get into your computer unless you let them.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re not sure if someone is from tech support, hang up on them, find the manual for your computer, and call the number in there. That&rsquo;s the real number, the one that you can trust.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/02/ask-deemable-tpport-scammers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/02/adt20160211.mp3" length="3207596" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#105 The Rumor Mill</title>
		<link>/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/</link>
		<comments>/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 20:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NetFlix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10391</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/01/Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="That rumor mill&#039;s a-churning. Image credit: Wikimedia Commons" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week, Ray, Tom and Sean delve into rumors about the next iPhone as well as Twitter&#8217;s famous 140-character limit. Plus, the latest about the Oculus Rift, and the story of a man who found more than he bargained for <a href="/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/01/Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="That rumor mill&#039;s a-churning. Image credit: Wikimedia Commons" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_10394" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2016/01/Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10394" src="/media/2016/01/Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square-300x300.jpg"  alt="That rumor mill's a-churning. Image credit: Wikimedia Commons" width="300" height="300"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">That rumor mill&rsquo;s a-churning. Image credit: Wikimedia Commons</p></div>
<p>This week, Ray, Tom and Sean delve into rumors about the next iPhone as well as Twitter&rsquo;s famous 140-character limit. Plus, the latest about the Oculus Rift, and the story of a man who found more than he bargained for in his Amazon cart.</p>
<p><span id="more-10391"></span></p>
<p>By the way, we don&rsquo;t just have a subreddit page for the fame and the glory. We have it because we want to know what you want us to talk about! We know you&rsquo;re purusing the tech news all week.&nbsp;Go to our subreddit page, <a href="/reddit" target="_blank">reddit.com/r/deemable</a>, and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down.</p>
<p>And make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show and leave a review&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at&nbsp;<a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10391-7" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/01/DeemableTech_2016-01-14.mp3?_=7"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/01/DeemableTech_2016-01-14.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/01/DeemableTech_2016-01-14.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>Apple planning to remove headphone jack on the iPhone 7</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The rumor mill about the next iPhone is churning and this time it has come up with a doozy. In order to get the next version of the iPhone even slimmer, Apple is supposedly going to ditch the headphone jack. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These rumors actually started swirling about a month ago, but now </span><a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3055208/its-true-apple-will-drop-the-headphone-jack-to-make-the-iphone-7-slimmer-and-simpler" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fast Company has a new source which has confirmed them</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, along with adding new details: that the replacement will be a lightning jack with a headphone adaptor, or completely wireless EarPods.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fast Company also says that the next iPhone will employ a new noise-cancelling technology to improve sound quality. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Oculus Rift announces release date, final price</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The product that arguably has launched the current wave of excitement about virtual-reality-tech has finally gotten a price, and a date on which you will be able to buy it. That product, of course, is the Oculus Rift. The date? Sometime in March, assuming you pre-ordered, oh, last week. The price? $599.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/01/virtually-a-reality-oculus-rift-goes-on-sale/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Ars Technica</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, that scores you a cutting-edge VR headset, a head-tracking camera, an Xbox One controller, an Oculus remote, cables, a carrying case, and two games. That sounds pretty good, but note that it doesn&rsquo;t include the beefy high-end PC you&rsquo;ll need to plug your headset into.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If all you&rsquo;ve got at home right now is Sean Birch&rsquo;s Chromebook, expect to drop $1,500 to gain access to a high resolution universe of virtual wonder.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After two dev kits, which were priced at $300 and $350 respectively, and Oculus founder Palmer Lucky stating in an interview in October that the Rift would cost &ldquo;more than $350,&rdquo; many eager fans are experiencing sticker shock. They have taken to the internets to express their anger. </span><a href="http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/01/oculus-founder-apologizes-for-messaging-poorly-on-599-rift-price/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Outrage was so great that Palmer Lucky popped up on reddit to apologize for misleading people</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. That said, if you pre-order the Rift right now, you&rsquo;ll be lucky to get it by April, so clearly the high price has not been enough to discourage everyone.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Netflix gives customers socks for the holidays</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You probably remember the Netflix-and-chill button that Netflix recently released design specs for so DIY enthusiasts could build their own. Well the company has topped themselves with their latest DIY brainstorm &ndash; Netflix socks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you regularly binge watch so much that you fall asleep, Netflix socks are for you. These socks detect when you&rsquo;ve fallen asleep and send a pause signal to Netflix, so you won&rsquo;t miss a moment of Jessica Jones! You can check them out at </span><a href="https://makeit.netflix.com/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">makeit.netflix.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. There are even multiple snazzy templates for great Netflix-themed patterns! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just to be clear, you can&rsquo;t buy these &ndash; you have to make them! So get out your darning needles and soldering iron and get to work! If any Deemable Tech listeners are planning on building this or the Netflix button, we&rsquo;d love to see your work!</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Lenovo ditching the Motorola brand name, but keeping &ldquo;Moto&rdquo;</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Motorola was once a powerhouse in mobile phones, but it has been through a lot of changes lately. First it was purchased by Google, which launched the Moto X line of phones, and then it was sold to Lenovo. </span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/goodbye-moto-rola-iconic-brand-name-to-be-phased-out/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In an interview with Cnet this month</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> while at CES, Lenovo announced that it would begin phasing out the &ldquo;Motorola&rdquo; branding on its phones and replacing it with Lenovo branding. Lenovo will, however, be keeping the &ldquo;Moto&rdquo; name and the iconic &ldquo;batwing&rdquo; logo. So you can still say, &ldquo;Hello, Moto.&rdquo; But really, it is goodbye to Motorola as we know it.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Twitter to break the 140 character limit, probably for real this time</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are always endless rumors swirling that Twitter is about to increase its famous 140 character limit. And actually right now it looks like those rumors have some substance. </span></p>
<p><a href="http://recode.net/2016/01/05/twitter-considering-10000-character-limit-for-tweets/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to re/code</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, sources within the company say that tweets will still initially appear in your Twitter feed as 140 characters, but will then feature some kind of call to action which allows them to be expanded, showing up to 10,000 characters of text. This would be a pretty significant change for a company that has built its reputation on very brief messages. The same rumors also say that Twitter is experimenting with changing its reverse chronological timeline, another core feature from early days.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since Twitter went public in 2013 it has struggled to impress investors with steady growth. CEO Jack Dorsey and other company heads are definitely looking at radical changes to keep the social media giant relevant. </span></p>
<h3>IE is Dead, Long Live Edge&hellip; and IE</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Microsoft finally </span><a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/3021789/windows/microsoft-patch-tuesday-kills-off-windows-8-and-internet-explorer-8-9-and-10.html" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">buried Internet Explorers</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 8, 9 and 10. If you have one of them installed on your computer it will still work, but just like when Microsoft pulled the plug on Windows XP back in 2013, you won&rsquo;t receive any security updates anymore. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Speaking of operating systems, Windows killed another operating system this week. No, it wasn&rsquo;t Vista, it was Windows 8! If you&rsquo;re running Windows 8, you need to upgrade to 8.1 or 10, because you will no longer get bug fixes or security updates. Why did Microsoft skip Vista? Who knows, but our guess is that there is a very small user base running 8 compared to Vista. But the reaper is coming for Vista too. Vista will swim with the fishes in April 2017.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Customer finds unexpected dildo in his shopping cart after poor customer service experience at Amazon.de</h3>
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/01/amazon-customer-complains-finds-spiteful-10-inch-dildo-in-his-shopping-basket/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ars Technica reported on an unusual customer service snafu last week</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Not that customer service screw ups are unusual, but this one came from Amazon, typically known for their top notch customer service. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An IT contractor living in Ireland had ordered a textbook from Amazon.de, the Germany-based version of the site. Unfortunately he was shipped the wrong edition. After spending a great deal of time on the phone with a customer service rep, he was informed that the company did not have the right edition and they would only be able to credit him his money back.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Upset, the contractor left a negative review on a customer satisfaction survey.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A few days later he was browsing the site at work and noticed that there was something in his shopping basket. Not having added anything to the cart, he clicked to see what it was. At this point he discovered that a dildo known as &ldquo;The Hulk&rdquo; had been added to his basket. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since the contractor was at his job and was being observed by coworkers, including a woman, he was not pleased by this. He reports that he was able to get in touch with an executive at Amazon.de and had been credited with 100 euros for the incident. The company hinted that the dildo had been added to the contractor&rsquo;s basket by the customer service rep, but would not say if any steps had been taken to discipline the rep.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Image credit: Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill.jpg: Gabor Eszes (UED77)derivative work: WVhybrid at en.wikipedia (Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill.jpg) [<a href="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/fdl.html">GFDL</a> or <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA-3.0</a>], <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File%3AGlade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square.jpg">via Wikimedia Commons</a></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/01/DeemableTech_2016-01-14.mp3" length="36476269" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#104 Lasers We Have Seen On High</title>
		<link>/2015/12/104-lasers-we-e-seen-on-high/</link>
		<comments>/2015/12/104-lasers-we-e-seen-on-high/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 17:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vtech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10375</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week, Ray, Tom and Sean look at the dangers of over-the-top Christmas decorations, wonder when a tablet is too big, and try to solve the mystery of Bitcoin&#8217;s creator. By the way, we don&#8217;t just have a subreddit page <a href="/2015/12/104-lasers-we-e-seen-on-high/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/12/104-lasers-we-e-seen-on-high/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week, Ray, Tom and Sean look at the dangers of over-the-top Christmas decorations, wonder when a tablet is too big, and try to solve the mystery of Bitcoin&rsquo;s creator.</p>
<p><span id="more-10375"></span></p>
<p>By the way, we don&rsquo;t just have a subreddit page for the fame and the glory. We have it because we want to know what you want us to talk about! We know you&rsquo;re purusing the tech news all week.&nbsp;Go to our subreddit page, <a href="/reddit" target="_blank">reddit.com/r/deemable</a>, and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down.</p>
<p>And make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show and leave a review&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at&nbsp;<a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10375-8" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/12/DeemableTech_2015-12-15.mp3?_=8"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/12/DeemableTech_2015-12-15.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/12/DeemableTech_2015-12-15.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>C130 pilots blinded by Christmas decorations</h3>
<p>Are your Christmas decorations sufficiently over-the-top this year? Apparently if you&rsquo;re not blinding low-flying planes, you aren?t really trying.</p>
<p>In mid-November, the crew of a Coast Guard C130 plane over Sacramento radioed that it was being blinded by a laser light &ndash; a distressingly common &lsquo;prank&rsquo; that has dangerous consequences for pilots. However, when Sacramento police tracked down the source of the laser, it was not a prankster, but a home Christmas light display.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.nbclosangeles.com/investigations/Warning-Issued-About-Popular-Holiday-Decoration-360986471.html" target="_blank">NBC Los Angeles reports that a Christmas light display projector called the Star Shower</a> was the culprit. The Star Shower uses hundreds of pinpoint laser lights to simulate a surface covered with lights. It comes with a warning to point it only at solid surfaces, not the sky, and not to use it within ten miles of an airport. However, it appears that it is easy for someone attempting to project it up onto the wall of their home to allow the projector to accidentally beam lights into the sky, and the cockpit of passing planes. Homeowners using this product are advised to exercise caution.</p>
<h3>Google ProjectFi gives customers the gift of Lego</h3>
<p>You guys will remember we had long time listener Ardis on a few episodes ago to talk about <a href="/2015/11/102-we-dont-need-no-stinkin-producer/" target="_blank">his experience using Google?s ProjectFi cellular service</a>. Well Ardis informed us last week that Google had sent him an interesting gift in the mail: a Lego kit that could be assembled into a charging stand for his Nexus device.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/11/26/9804216/google-project-fi-lego-kit" target="_blank">The Verge</a> reports that a number of ProjectFi subscribers have been reporting receiving the kits, along with a note that says ?Thank you for your support, let?s build on this.? It is not known if the kit will go out to all ProjectFi subscribers or not.</p>
<h3>Samsung unveils new giant tablet</h3>
<p>It seems like the giant tablet arms race has officially begun. Apple has released the 12.9 inch iPad Pro to compete with Microsoft?s Surface Pro, which is a measly 12.3 inches. So they&rsquo;re the winner, right? Not even close.</p>
<p>Samsung has jumped into the game with the Samsung Galaxy View, a &ldquo;tablet&rdquo; with a massive 18.5 inch screen. The only problem is, no one knows quite what to do with this monstrosity. In an Engadget piece entitled <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2015/11/19/samsung-galaxy-view-wtf/" target="_blank">I just don&rsquo;t understand why Samsung?s Galaxy View exists</a>, tech writer Nathan Ingraham says that &ldquo;Because it&rsquo;s a giant tablet, you need to be close to get your videos playing, but because it&rsquo;s so giant you naturally want to be a little farther away than your arm&rsquo;s reach.&rdquo; Samsung seems to want to position the tablet as a media playing device, but if this is a portable TV, it is one without a remote.</p>
<p>$599 is not a bad price for an elephantine tablet, but it?s very pricey for a small flatscreen. And when your screen is over 18 inches, you are definitely getting into flatscreen territory.</p>
<h3>When drones are outlawed, only outlaws will have drones</h3>
<p>A warning to drone enthusiasts: get in the way of the police, and they may take away your toys. According to<a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2015/11/man-whose-drone-got-too-close-to-lapd-helicopter-given-three-years-probation/" target="_blank"> a report by Ars Technica</a>, Martin Sheldon of Los Angeles was caught after allegedly buzzing a police helicopter with his drone over Sunset Boulevard. He was charged with interfering with a police investigation. He has now been sentenced. In addition to community service and probation, Sheldon must turn over his drone and is banned from owning or operating a remote-controlled airplane, helicopter, or drone for a period of three years.</p>
<h3>Hackers steal massive trove of children&rsquo;s data from Vtech</h3>
<p>Another major data breach is in the news lately. In November high tech toymaker Vtech reported that hackers got into its servers and stole the personal information of over ten million users, half of whom were children. The rest are parents.</p>
<p><a href="http://gizmodo.com/the-horrifying-vtech-hack-let-someone-download-thousand-1745321580" target="_blank">Gizmodo reports that the data includes first names, genders, and birthdays of over six million children.</a> But if that wasn?t scary enough, the cache of leaked data also contains 190 gigabytes of photos from Vtech?s kid connect service, most likely containing headshots of kids who used the video chat service to talk with their parents.</p>
<p>The hack has been catastrophically damaging to Vtech, which has suspended of their stock on the Hong Kong stock exchange after word got out that they had been transmitting customer data completely unencrypted.</p>
<h3>Is Australian entrepreneur actually the creator of Bitcoin? Eh, probably not.</h3>
<p>Bitcoin fascinates people for at least two reasons: one is the digital cryptocurrency itself, but two is because nobody knows the true identity of the person who really invented it. The inventor was known on online listservs as Satoshi Nakamoto, but this is undoubtedly just an alias. Last year a major Newsweek investigation featured a California man named Dorian Nakamoto as Satoshi, but this was later proven false.</p>
<p>Well this month the media is at it again, as both <a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/12/bitcoins-creator-satoshi-nakamoto-is-probably-this-unknown-australian-genius/" target="_blank">Wired</a> and <a href="http://gizmodo.com/this-australian-says-he-and-his-dead-friend-invented-bi-1746958692" target="_blank">Gizmodo</a> published stories claiming that an Australian entrepreneur named Craig Wright, in partnership with a Florida man named Dave Kleiman, was probably the secretive inventory of Bitcoin. The stories were based on documents leaked to the outlets by an anonymous source including unsent emails in which Wright admitted to being Nakamoto.</p>
<p>However, since the media have been burnt by false leads before, so both outlets hedged their bets, with Wired writing, ?Either Wright invented bitcoin, or he?s a brilliant hoaxer who very badly wants us to believe he did.?<br>
That was a smart thing to say, because things got weird in a hurry. The day after the stories were published, the Australian Federal Police raided Wright?s home and office, <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/dec/09/bitcoin-founder-craig-wrights-home-raided-by-australian-police" target="_blank">according to the Guardian</a>, executing a warrant on tax issues unrelated to the Bitcoin story.</p>
<p>Since then, <a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/12/new-clues-suggest-satoshi-suspect-craig-wright-may-be-a-hoaxer/" target="_blank">Wired reports</a>, more holes have appeared in the story, casting doubt on whether or not Craig Wright really has two PhDs or whether his company in fact owns one of the world?s most powerful privately-owned supercomputers. Wright does, however, appear to own millions in Bitcoin, a point in his favor that is hard to explain away.</p>
<p>A post on a listserv supposedly from Satoshi Nakamoto denied that Craig Wright was him the day after the original stories ran, however there was no way to verify.</p>
<p>The full story is still unfolding and appears to involve either an extortion scheme or a hoaxer pretending to extort himself.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/12/104-lasers-we-e-seen-on-high/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/12/DeemableTech_2015-12-15.mp3" length="28883674" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ask Deemable Tech: What Can I Do With An Old Hard Drive?</title>
		<link>/2015/12/what-can-i-do-with-old-hard-drive/</link>
		<comments>/2015/12/what-can-i-do-with-old-hard-drive/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 21:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[external hard drive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hard drive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10565</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/05/external_hard_drive-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Credit: Misbehave / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Thurman writes, &#8220;I have a hard drive that was removed from my old computer before I got rid of it. It has some pictures on it that I don&#8217;t have stored anywhere else and some of my old tax returns. <a href="/2015/12/what-can-i-do-with-old-hard-drive/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/12/what-can-i-do-with-old-hard-drive/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/05/external_hard_drive-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Credit: Misbehave / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_10566" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2016/05/external_hard_drive.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10566" src="/media/2016/05/external_hard_drive-300x171.jpg"  alt="Credit: Misbehave / Flickr" width="300" height="171"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Credit: Misbehave / Flickr</p></div>
<p><strong>Thurman writes, &ldquo;I have a hard drive that was removed from my old computer before I got rid of it. It has some pictures on it that I don&rsquo;t have stored anywhere else and some of my old tax returns. Is there anything I can do with it, or is it just a hunk of junk? And, should I be concerned about other people getting into it if I throw it out?&rdquo;&nbsp;</strong></p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10565-9" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/ad20151217.mp3?_=9"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/ad20151217.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/ad20151217.mp3</a></audio><p>You can definitely make use of that old hard drive, and you can get those pictures and tax returns off of it too!</p>
<p>No matter how old your hard drive is, it will still probably work with the latest and greatest computers. If you have a new desktop computer, it might even be as simple as opening up your computer case and just plugging that hard drive in. This can be hit-or-miss since a lot of new desktop computers are so small that there&rsquo;s no room for a second hard drive.</p>
<p>However, almost all computers have a USB port. All you need is a special adapter to change your internal hard drive into an external one, and then you can plug that hard drive into the computer&rsquo;s USB port.</p>
<p>External hard drive adapters are available almost anywhere you can purchase computers, and vary in price from $5 to $30. If you&rsquo;re only going to use it once, or you don?t care if it looks fancy, the lower priced ones will work just fine.</p>
<p>Now, Thurman, you asked if you should be concerned about your data if you just throw that hard drive away. The answer is a resounding YES. You should definitely be concerned about your privacy, as it&rsquo;s just as easy for someone else to put that hard drive into their computer as it is for you. Even if you delete your sensitive files, they pretty easy to retrieve.</p>
<p>Your computer doesn&rsquo;t really erase files when you delete them, it just pretends that the space is no longer written on. To make sure that your hard drive is secure and completely erased, the U.S Department of Defense recommends that you write over every sector with new data at least three times (or even up to 35 times, if you really want to be safe). Each single bit of the hard drive needs to be written over with all ones and zeroes.</p>
<p>We know that sounds daunting, but there are a few easy ways to accomplish this. If you have a PC, you can use a program like <a href="http://eraser.heidi.ie/" target="_blank">Eraser</a> or the &ldquo;Drive Wiper&rdquo; feature in <a href="https://www.piriform.com/ccleaner/download" target="_blank">C Cleaner</a>. If you&rsquo;re a Mac person, try using a program called <a href="http://www.edenwaith.com/products/permanent%20eraser/" target="_blank">Permanent Eraser</a>.</p>
<p>Just plug in your hard drive to your new computer using the USB adapter, run one of the programs to wipe it, and you&rsquo;re good to go. Just make sure you wipe the right hard drive.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/12/what-can-i-do-with-old-hard-drive/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/05/ad20151217.mp3" length="3353129" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#103 Guess Who’s Back, Back Again, Sean Is Back, Tell A Friend</title>
		<link>/2015/11/103-guess-whos-back-back-sean-back-tell-friend/</link>
		<comments>/2015/11/103-guess-whos-back-back-sean-back-tell-friend/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chromestick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Safety Check]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Trek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USB-C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zune]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10356</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/11/IMG_6671-e1448040095891-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="We were left with nothing to remember Sean Birch except dozens of his high school graduation pictures." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Producer Sean Birch is back. So, Ray is under control, no more&#160;innuendos and inappropriate jokes. In this episode Ray, Tom and Sean tackle how Facebook helped France but forgot about Lebanon and talk about crappy USB-C cables, Microsoft putting the <a href="/2015/11/103-guess-whos-back-back-sean-back-tell-friend/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/11/103-guess-whos-back-back-sean-back-tell-friend/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/11/IMG_6671-e1448040095891-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="We were left with nothing to remember Sean Birch except dozens of his high school graduation pictures." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_10365" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2015/11/IMG_6671-e1448040095891.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10365" src="/media/2015/11/IMG_6671-e1448040095891-300x300.jpg"  alt="We were left with nothing to remember Sean Birch except dozens of his high school graduation pictures." width="300" height="300"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">We were left with nothing to remember Sean Birch except dozens of his high school graduation pictures.</p></div>
<p>Producer Sean Birch is back. So, Ray is under control, no more&nbsp;innuendos and inappropriate jokes. In this episode Ray, Tom and Sean tackle how Facebook helped France but forgot about Lebanon and talk about crappy USB-C cables, Microsoft putting the Zune out to pasture, the new Star Trek TV show and the Chromestick.</p>
<p>By the way, we don&rsquo;t just have a subreddit page for the fame and the glory. We have it because we want to know what you want us to talk about! We know you&rsquo;re purusing the tech news all week.&nbsp;Go to our subreddit page, <a href="/reddit" target="_blank">reddit.com/r/deemable</a>, and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down.</p>
<p>And make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show and leave a review&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at&nbsp;<a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10356-10" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/11/DeemableTech_2015-11-19.mp3?_=10"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/11/DeemableTech_2015-11-19.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/11/DeemableTech_2015-11-19.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>Facebook Safety Check Helps France, Ignores Beirut</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2015/11/16/facebooks-paris-safety-check-by-the-numbers/">The Washington Post reports</a>&nbsp;that Facebook turned on its ?Safety Check? feature for a man-made disaster last weekend for the first time, for the attacks in Paris. With Safety Check, users who are in an area affected by a disaster who login to Facebook are greeted by a message asking them if they are safe. If they indicate that they are, a status update is then posted to their wall letting their friends and family know.</p>
<p>Facebook said that about 4.1 million users checked in within 24 hours after the attack, about one-third of metropolitan Paris?s population. Safety check has been deployed on five previous occasions, including the earthquake in Nepal in April, Tropical Cyclone Pam in the South Pacific, and Typhoon Ruby in the Philippines. It was originally inspired by the aftermath of the 2011 Japanese tsunami.</p>
<p>Facebook has drawn criticism because it has not deployed the feature for several recent disasters in the Middle East, including for the double suicide bombings in Beirut just a day earlier. Facebook says that it plans to deploy the tool more frequently in the future.</p>
<h3>Crappy Cables Be Crappy</h3>
<p>One of the dangers of buying something online is that it could be a dud. This is especially a problem if you buy things from some random website. But sometimes even products from Amazon can be lemons, and the reviews ? which are often written by less-than-tech-savvy customers ? don&rsquo;t always save the day. Well, one very tech savvy customer is doing everything he can to change that.</p>
<p>Gizmodo reports that a <a href="http://gizmodo.com/a-google-engineer-is-publicly-shaming-crappy-usb-c-cabl-1742719818" target="_blank">Google engineer is buying USB-C cables off&nbsp;Amazon, testing them and reviewing them</a>. Benson Leung is a Chromebook engineer, specifically an engineer on the Chromebook Pixel team, which, no surprise, has a USB-C port on it.</p>
<p>From Benson&rsquo;s experience, good USB-C cables are hit-or-miss. And unfortunately, it doesn&rsquo;t seem to matter if they name brand or not. He&rsquo;s found some cables with the wrong wiring, the wrong resisters, or will just completely burn out your charger, USB hubs or your mobile device.</p>
<p>You can follow him and read <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.amazon.com/gp/pdp/profile/A25GROL6KJV3QG/ref%3Dcm_cr_rdp_pdp?tag%3Dgizmodoamzn-20%26ascsubtag%3D4b5fdaedf94712829705e9d1007f02b1026f337e%26rawdata%3D%255Br%257Chttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.reddit.com%252Fr%252Fdeemable%255Bt%257Clink%255Bp%257C1742719818%255Bau%257C5836322932740811680&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNG7xIr3LursnKBKoXbrGltN_z0kcA">his reviews on Amazon</a>&nbsp;or on <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://plus.google.com/u/0/%2BBensonLeung&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNFV2BSvCMc-1tZOxfkAVxTRFrBArA">his Google+ page</a>, because? he works for Google? so of course he has a Google+ page.</p>
<h3>Microsoft Finally Puts Zune Out of Its Misery</h3>
<p>This week marks a sad time for those who love Microsoft?s Zune audio players (don?t laugh, there may be some out there).</p>
<p>PCWorld reports that <a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/3004965/data-center-cloud/microsoft-turns-off-the-lights-on-zune-services.html" target="_blank">Microsoft officially shut down all Zune-related services</a> this week, including the Zune Music Pass streaming subscription service, and the Zune marketplace where users could buy MP3s.</p>
<p>Anyone still subscribed to Zune Music Pass was automatically switched to Microsoft?s new Groove Music service. As for the MP3s, if any of them had DRM they sadly might not work after a while because the license can?t be renewed.</p>
<p>It has taken a surprisingly long time for Microsoft to both stop the services and stop using the Zune name. The company stopped making Zune hardware all the way back in 2011. They kept using the brand name for a few years before they switched to using ?Xbox? branding for a lot of things.</p>
<h3>Google Answers</h3>
<p>Shout out to redditor BHK123 for suggesting our next story.&nbsp;Google?s search app is about to get better at understanding complex questions. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://venturebeat.com/2015/11/16/googles-app-for-android-and-ios-can-now-answer-complex-questions-with-superlatives-ordered-items-and-dates/&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNF75bz5b_T4ClNolD_-kOV7G1NK4g">According to VentureBeat</a>, a new update to the Google search app allows it to better understand superlatives, ordered items, and dates. As an example, Google suggests the question ?Who was president when the Angels won the world series?? Google will figure out that you?re talking about US Presidents and baseball and combine the two to return the correct answer: George W. Bush.</p>
<h3>Chromestick</h3>
<p>Fans of ChromeOS rejoice, you are that much closer to being able to have Chrome on almost everything. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2015/11/asus-and-googles-chromebit-turns-any-monitor-into-a-chrome-os-device/&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNG5PvwFNfH3P0wHKZEIrHGU8t-tkw">Ars Technica says that Google and Asus have partnered up to create a 2.6 oz HDMI stick with ChromeOS</a>&nbsp;that can be plugged into any monitor or screen, instantly turning it into a Chromebook. The stick contains 2GB of RAM and 16GB of storage, supports 802.11ac Wi-Fi and Bluetooth 4.0. It also has a single USB port. The stick will reportedly retail for $85.</p>
<h3>Star Trekkin&rsquo; Across The Universe</h3>
<p>You are all no doubt very excited about the new Star Trek television show that has recently been announced. I know I am. Well <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/live-feed/star-trek-tv-series-works-828638&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNG0UvpuosKoUo96NwBT6EFvCKNdYw">The Hollywood Reporter claims</a>&nbsp;that the show will not, as you might expect, be airing regularly on network TV. While the pilot episode will indeed air on CBS, the regular episodes will stream on CBS All Access and will require a $5.99 monthly subscription to view. CBS All Access includes CBS feed, which as of right now includes 85 shows, <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.itworld.com/article/3001017/consumer-electronics/hands-on-with-cbs-all-access-the-future-home-of-star-trek.html&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNHuVaJs4f9HLln2krP3uKWHrYBInw">according to IT World</a>. Some shows do appear to include commercials.</p>
<p>The new Trek show is slated to appear in January 2017.</p>
<p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://deemable.com/reddit&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNEydTeHrQvmDcf3CbTGWjMzWOruOw">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/11/103-guess-whos-back-back-sean-back-tell-friend/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/11/DeemableTech_2015-11-19.mp3" length="42478665" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#102 We Don’t Need No Stinkin’ Producer</title>
		<link>/2015/11/102-we-dont-need-no-stinkin-producer/</link>
		<comments>/2015/11/102-we-dont-need-no-stinkin-producer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2015 22:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hackers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tsu.co]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10340</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/11/IMG_6602-e1446948765227-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Ardis loves his new Nexus 6P on Google Project Fi." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />It&#8217;s Sean Birch&#8217;s turn to venture through&#160;the Pacific Northwest, so he is out of the studio for this&#160;week and next. (When&#8217;s Ray&#8217;s turn? #justsayin.) But Ray and Tom press on none-the-less. The Deemable Duo&#160;were joined by long-time listener Ardis Meade <a href="/2015/11/102-we-dont-need-no-stinkin-producer/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/11/102-we-dont-need-no-stinkin-producer/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/11/IMG_6602-e1446948765227-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Ardis loves his new Nexus 6P on Google Project Fi." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_10345" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2015/11/IMG_6602-e1446948765227.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10345" src="/media/2015/11/IMG_6602-e1446948765227-300x300.jpg"  alt="Ardis loves his new Nexus 6P on Google Project Fi." width="300" height="300"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ardis loves his new Nexus 6P on Google Project Fi.</p></div>
<p>It&rsquo;s Sean Birch&rsquo;s turn to venture through&nbsp;the Pacific Northwest, so he is out of the studio for this&nbsp;week and next. (When&rsquo;s Ray&rsquo;s turn? #justsayin.) But Ray and Tom press on none-the-less. The <a href="/2013/02/episode-29-the-deemable-duo-rises/" target="_blank">Deemable Duo</a>&nbsp;were joined by long-time listener Ardis Meade who showed us his new phone, the Nexus 6P and told us all about his phone carrier, Google Project Fi. Very interesting stuff if you&rsquo;re in the market for a new phone or a new carrier. Stick around after the news for that.</p>
<p>By the way, we don&rsquo;t just have a subreddit page for the fame and the glory. We have it because we want to know what you want us to talk about! We know you&rsquo;re purusing the tech news all week.&nbsp;Go to our subreddit page, <a href="/reddit" target="_blank">reddit.com/r/deemable</a>, and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down.</p>
<p>And make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show and leave a review&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at&nbsp;<a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10340-11" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wjct/files/201511/DeemableTech_2015-11-06.mp3?_=11"></source><a href="http://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wjct/files/201511/DeemableTech_2015-11-06.mp3">http://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wjct/files/201511/DeemableTech_2015-11-06.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>Turns Out Disney Isn&rsquo;t That Bad After All</h3>
<p><a href="http://gawker.com/teen-stoner-who-reportedly-hacked-cia-head-i-am-pre-1737375743?utm_expid=66866090-62._DVNDEZYQh2S4K00ZSnKcw.0&amp;utm_referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com%2F#_ga=1.120775688.1425775626.1429542769"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CNN reports that one Star Wars superfan with terminal cancer got to screen the film early</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Daniel Fleetwood is a 32-year-old who lives in Spring, Texas and a Star Wars enthusiast who camped out to see new releases of the films and collected Star Wars paraphernalia. He is also dying of spindle cell sarcoma and is not expected to live to see the official release date of the new Star Wars film Episode VII: The Force Awakens. Hashtag &nbsp;ForceForDaniel promoted by actors Mark Hamill and John Boyega persuaded director J.J. Abrams and Disney studio execs to let Fleetwood view an early edit of the film according to a spokesperson from Disney Studios. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The film will be released to the public on December 18th.</span></p>
<h3>Chrome OS And Android OS To&nbsp;Become One</h3>
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2015/10/wsj-google-to-merge-chrome-os-into-android-unveil-unified-os-next-year/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Wall Street Journal reports</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that Google is planning to merge ChromeOS and Android OS starting in 2017, with a beta appearing next year. The first Chromebooks came out back in 2011. At the time, the idea that Google would release an OS that wasn?t Android created quite a stir. However Chromebooks soon made inroads thanks to their super-cheap, basic, and lightweight SKUs. Chromebooks have an OS that is essentially the Chrome browser plus a couple of simple add-ons. The Chrome app store has never really taken off, but the OS has delivered on its promises of being lightweight and receiving constant, invisible updates. While Android is also a relatively lightweight OS it works entirely differently from ChromeOS, and its update process is much more laborious. How the two operating systems will merge remains to be seen.</span></p>
<h3>Facebook Kicks More Competition To The Curb</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Facebook, and practically all companies on the web, stay in business from ad revenue. The more you are on the website, the more money they make. Yep, that&rsquo;s right, Facebook is making bank from all those pictures of your kids and stupid quizzes you fill out. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, another social media network, Tsu.co, decided to share its revenue with the users. The more that people view your content, the more money you make. And you make money off of inviting people to join Tsu.co. You make money off of the posts that the people you invited posted. If that sounds like a pyramid scheme, it&rsquo;s because it basically is.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And much like any other new social network that has started since Facebook took dominance, (Instagram, Pinterest, Vine, etc.) Tsu.co is trying to grow by letting its users share posts on Facebook. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This worked, right up until Facebook blocked them. Unlike how Facebook made YouTube videos look like crap on Facebook to make its own video platform stand out, Mashable is reporting that </span><a href="http://mashable.com/2015/11/06/facebook-blocks-tsu-co/#8CtVa4h.3uq6"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Facebook went with the nuclear option</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Users cannot even mention the website on Facebook. If you type Tsu.co into a post or comment, Facebook will not allowed it to be posted.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Facebook says it&rsquo;s because users posting links to Tsu.co are engaging in spammy behavior and Tsu.co encourages it. I will say after checking out Tsu.co, it doesn&rsquo;t seem very spammy. It&rsquo;s mostly the same type of posts I see on almost every social network: cats, muscle-heads, news, cats ? you get it. </span></p>
<h3>Don&rsquo;t Buy Things From The Guy In The Back Alley</h3>
<p><a href="http://gizmodo.com/newly-discovered-breed-of-android-malware-is-almost-imp-1740938991"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gizmodo reports</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that a security research blog claims that in third-party Android stores, popular apps like Candy Crush, Facebook, Google Now, Twitter, WhatsApp, and more are infected with adware that gives itself root access to a user?s device. It appears that hackers are taking popular apps and repacking them with their own malicious Trojans and uploading them to these other stores. Right now the Trojans do nothing but serve up ads, but with root access much nastier things are possible. So far, no Trojanized apps have been found in the official Google Play store. So as always, people, you sideload apps at your own risk. Playing outside the official sandbox is still the #1 way to get your device infected with malware. Be very certain that you trust an app?s maker before you sideload it.</span></p>
<h3>One More Reason To Hate Comcast</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you live in Little Rock, Arkansas; Houma, LaPlace and Shreveport, Louisiana; Chattanooga, Greenville, Johnson City/Gray, Tennessee; or Galax, Virginia you&rsquo;re about to have one more reason to hate Comcast. DSLReports says that the lucky customers in those cities will </span><a href="http://www.dslreports.com/shownews/Comcast-Dramatically-Expanding-Usage-Cap-Areas-December-1-135551"><span style="font-weight: 400;">no longer have unlimited Internet on Comcast</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, but instead will have a cap of 300 GB per month starting in December. If you go over, you will be hit with $10 per 50 GB over the limit. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why is Comcast doing this, you ask? They say it is for ?fairness and providing a more flexible policy to our customers? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the email DSLReports obtained, Comcast believes &ldquo;that 300 GB is more than enough to meet your Internet usage needs.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All hope is not lost though. You can still get unlimited Internet from Comcast in those markets. All you have to do is pay $35 more each month for unlimited Internet than you were already paying for unlimited Internet.</span></p>
<h3>Teen Stoners Hack CIA Director&rsquo;s Email. Yeah, It&rsquo;s That Easy</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A pair of teenage hackers who enjoy ?recreational pot smoking? are apparently on a hacking roll, </span><a href="http://gizmodo.com/teen-hackers-strike-again-leak-info-of-government-em-1740871626"><span style="font-weight: 400;">according to Gizmodo</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Calling themselves CWA, short for ?Crackas With Attitude,? they </span><a href="http://gawker.com/teen-stoner-who-reportedly-hacked-cia-head-i-am-pre-1737375743?utm_expid=66866090-62._DVNDEZYQh2S4K00ZSnKcw.0&amp;utm_referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com%2F#_ga=1.120775688.1425775626.1429542769"><span style="font-weight: 400;">hacked CIA director John Brennan?s AOL email account last month</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This week they did one better, posting the contact information of 34,000 government employees online, including the phone numbers of FBI agents. So far it appears that all the data leaked is legitimate. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The hackers have been communicating at times with the press, often via disposable Twitter accounts. Asked how he felt about hacking the government, one of them told Gawker, ?since only 13 i am pretty hype about it.? He also said he had no problem with being labeled a ?teen stoner?, saying that he felt that ?it just kinda describes us in away.?</span></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/11/102-we-dont-need-no-stinkin-producer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wjct/files/201511/DeemableTech_2015-11-06.mp3" length="57158140" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#101 The Episode Where We Don&#8217;t Talk About &#8216;Back To The Future&#8217;</title>
		<link>/2015/10/101-the-episode-where-we-dont-talk-about-back-to-the-future/</link>
		<comments>/2015/10/101-the-episode-where-we-dont-talk-about-back-to-the-future/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 02:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTTF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LastPass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LogMeIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube Red]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10329</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/10/NoBTTF-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Just don&#039;t bring it up." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Last week was Back To The Future Day, but the Internet went and ruined it, so we&#8217;re not going to talk about it. But we are going to talk about YouTube Red, Amazon taking on reviews for hire, laser razors, <a href="/2015/10/101-the-episode-where-we-dont-talk-about-back-to-the-future/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/10/101-the-episode-where-we-dont-talk-about-back-to-the-future/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/10/NoBTTF-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Just don&#039;t bring it up." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_10334" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2015/10/NoBTTF.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10334" src="/media/2015/10/NoBTTF-300x300.jpg"  alt="Just don't bring it up." width="300" height="300"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Just don&rsquo;t bring it up.</p></div>
<p>Last week was Back To The Future Day, but the Internet went and ruined it, so we&rsquo;re not going to talk about it. But we are going to talk about YouTube Red, Amazon taking on reviews for hire, laser razors, and LogMeIn buying LastPass.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://deemable.com/reddit&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNEydTeHrQvmDcf3CbTGWjMzWOruOw">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on the&nbsp;website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you&rsquo;re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>What do you think about comics on television? If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at&nbsp;<a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10329-12" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/10/DeemableTech_2015-10-26.mp3?_=12"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/10/DeemableTech_2015-10-26.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/10/DeemableTech_2015-10-26.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3><a href="http://gizmodo.com/dont-buy-your-youtube-red-subscription-on-ios-1737961156"><b>Don&rsquo;t buy YouTube Red on your iPhone</b></a></h3>
<p>YouTube has decided to launch a premium service. For $10 a month, you can watch YouTube videos without any ads, plus you get streaming music from YouTube Music and access to exclusive original content.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If that does sound like something you&rsquo;re interested in, don&rsquo;t buy your subscription on your iOS device. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That might sound crazy, but as you may know, Apple takes 30 percent of in-app purchases. Most companies just bite the bullet and eat that loss because the convenience of being able to pay right on your Apple device, and some companies, like Amazon, decided they weren&rsquo;t going to pay, and pushed the checkout page to a website. Google is trying something different. Instead of eating the cost of Apple&rsquo;s commission, or potentially losing a sale by sending the customer to a website, Google is passing the cost on to you! If you buy a subscription to YouTube Red on an iOS device, you will pay $13 instead of $10. So, come October 28th when YouTube Red launches, make sure to go to YouTube.com to sign up to save yourself $3.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2015/10/15/amid-the-adblockalypse-advertisers-apologize-for-messing-up-the-web/"><b>Advertisers say they broke the Web</b></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Washington Post reports that the online advertising industry is saying, ?We?re sorry.? Or at least, the part of it which is represented by the Interactive Advertising Bureau. In a recent blog post, Scott Cunningham, a high level exec for the Bureau wrote, ?We messed up.? He said that</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the systems that allowed marketers to track and target advertisements &ldquo;have slowed down the public internet and drained more than a few batteries.? He attributed this to plumbing that was, quote, over-engineered.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In case you are wondering why the online advertising is suddenly waking up to the fact that they have been annoying users and slowing down web pages after all this time, the answer is two little words: ad blockers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ad blockers have become hugely popular on desktop browsers and now are beginning to come to mobile as well. The latest version of iOS opens the iPhone up to adblocking. Advertisers are, well, concerned.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Cunningham?s blog post, he announced that the IAB is developing a new ad system called LEAN, which stands for Light, Non-invasive, Ad-choice supported and Non-invasive. If its ads really are all those things that will be a welcome change.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://mashable.com/2015/10/18/amazon-fake-review-lawsuit/?utm_cid=mash-com-fb-main-link#NdRX7W2OqZqB"><b>Amazon goes after fake reviewers</b></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amazon has filed a lawsuit against more than a thousand people they say have offered to write fake reviews for money.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Mashable reports, Amazon is going after people on Fiverr.com, a website that lets people do tasks for as little as $5, who offered to write and post five-star reviews for products in exchange for payment from the sellers or manufacturers of said products.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This follows a similar lawsuit Amazon filed in April of this year against a group of sites that offered to write Amazon reviews, including buy-amazon-reviews.com and buy-reviews-now.com.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Amazon says in the claim, &ldquo;While small in number, these reviews threaten to undermine the trust that customers, and the vast majority of sellers and manufacturers, place in Amazon, thereby tarnishing Amazon?s brand.?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fortunately, Amazon is not going after </span><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/feature.html?docId=1001250201"><span style="font-weight: 400;">funny reviews</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><b><a href="http://gizmodo.com/kickstarter-bans-product-for-not-existing-1736179452">A razor with &ldquo;frickin&rsquo; lasers attached to its frickin&rsquo; head&rdquo;</a></b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crowdfunding can often be like a bug zapper drawing people into something that they </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">probably</span></i> <span style="font-weight: 400;">should be staying away from and definitely shouldn&rsquo;t be investing in. There have been quite a few Kickstarter and Indiegogo projects that have been successfully funded but never materialized. Kickstarter and Indiegogo have been fighting this since their inceptions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, Kickstarter took some action recently to prevent it from happening again. The Skarp Laser Razor got the boot from Kickstarter after having raised just over $4 million from backers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, as the name of the product specifically states, the Skarp Laser Razor has a &ldquo;frickin laser attached to its frickin&rsquo; head.&rdquo; In other words, you can shave your face with a laser beam.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why did Kickstarter kick them off their site? Well, Kickstarter says it&rsquo;s because of one pesky little fact. Kickstarter says Skarp doesn&rsquo;t have a working prototype. Kickstarter said, that the laser razor was ?in violation of our rule requiring working prototypes of physical products that are offered as rewards.?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you watch the promotional video you will see a &ldquo;prototype.&rdquo; I don&rsquo;t know about you, but I wouldn&rsquo;t use that thing on my face, and not just because I have a long, luxurious beard, but because I want to keep my face.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not surprisingly, Skarp has setup shop over at Indiegogo&nbsp;and has raised a measly $400,000.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2015/10/logmein-buys-lastpass-password-manager-for-110-million/"><b>LogMeIn Bought LastPass</b></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Arstechnica reports that LastPass is being acquired by LogMeIn, which makes remote desktop management and support software for individuals and businesses. LogMeIn will pay $110 million for LastPass.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you?ve never heard of LastPass (and really, how could you listen to this show and not have heard about it? We talk about it all the time) it?s a password manager that generates strong passwords and stores them in an encrypted vault. It offers extensions and apps for desktop and mobile browsers that will automatically fill in password fields once you?ve logged in with your master password &ndash; the LAST PASSword you?ll ever have to remember. They currently offer free, premium and enterprise versions of the software.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">LogMeIn actually bought another company last year called Meldium, which makes a password manager for teams and businesses. It looks like those features will be integrated into LastPass once the deal goes through.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://fossbytes.com/google-just-bought-abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz-com/"><b>Google buys entire alphabet</b></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As you probably remember, last month Google restructured itself under a new parent company called Alphabet. Jazzed about their new name, Google ran to snap up Alphabet.com but &ndash; whoops! It was already owned by BMW, and they weren?t selling. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, Google decided that if it couldn?t own Alphabet, it would buy THE alphabet. It has officially purchased abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz.com. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Right now the domain name leads to an inactive website. You can still learn all about Google/Alphabet at abc.xyz. </span></p>
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2015/10/nexus-5x-and-nexus-6p-review-the-true-flagships-of-the-android-ecosystem/"><b>Google?s New Flagship Phones</b></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We promised our listeners last time we would talk about the new Nexus phone, which is of course Google?s flagship. Well, actually there are two of them as it turns out: they are called the 5X and the 6P, respectively. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 5X is the smaller, cheaper phone, and it is made by LG. It has a 5.2? 1080p screen, a 12.3 MP rear camera with laser autofocus, and a 2700 mAh battery. The phone starts at an affordable $379 for the 16 GB version.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 6P is made by Huwai and supposedly the ?P? stands for premium. It does feature an anodized aluminum case whereas the 5X is pure plastic. It has a 5.7? screen that has some sort of super ultra mega high density Samsung display. It also rocks a 12.3 MP camera but the battery is a whopping 3450 mAh. This phablet is a little pricier, starting at $499 for the 32 GB version.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Both phones ship with Android Marshmallow on them and have fingerprint sensors. </span></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/10/101-the-episode-where-we-dont-talk-about-back-to-the-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/10/DeemableTech_2015-10-26.mp3" length="46974885" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#100 The Deemable Decade</title>
		<link>/2015/10/100-the-deemable-decade/</link>
		<comments>/2015/10/100-the-deemable-decade/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 00:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chromecast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peeple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlayStation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roku]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snopes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XBox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yelp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10303</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/10/anniversary-500967_1920-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="We still don&#039;t make any money doing this, so... you know... this is the best graphic we could find in the public domain." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />It&#8217;s the 100th episode of Deemable Tech. It only took us three years to get here!&#160;Jessica Palombo, co-host of the mystical, never aired &#8220;Deemable Tech Pilot Episode,&#8221; and current WJCT News Director, joined Ray, Tom and Sean for the big <a href="/2015/10/100-the-deemable-decade/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/10/100-the-deemable-decade/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/10/anniversary-500967_1920-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="We still don&#039;t make any money doing this, so... you know... this is the best graphic we could find in the public domain." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_10308" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="/media/2015/10/anniversary-500967_1920.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10308" src="/media/2015/10/anniversary-500967_1920-300x211.jpg"  alt="We still don't make any money doing this, so... you know... this is the best graphic we could find in the public domain." width="300" height="211"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">We still don&rsquo;t make any money doing this, so&hellip; you know&hellip; this is the best graphic we could find in the public domain.</p></div>
<p>It&rsquo;s the 100th episode of Deemable Tech. It only took us three years to get here!&nbsp;Jessica Palombo, co-host of the mystical, never aired &ldquo;Deemable Tech Pilot Episode,&rdquo; and current WJCT News Director, joined Ray, Tom and Sean for the big celebration. The foursome talked about Facebook&rsquo;s new &ldquo;dislike&rdquo; button, a new service that promises to be &ldquo;Yelp for humans,&rdquo; Amazon cuts out the competition and some guy who managed to buy the domain&nbsp;&ldquo;Google.com&rdquo; from &mdash; get this &mdash; Google!<span id="more-10303"></span></p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://deemable.com/reddit&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNEydTeHrQvmDcf3CbTGWjMzWOruOw">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on the&nbsp;website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you&rsquo;re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>What do you think about comics on television? If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at&nbsp;<a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10303-13" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/10/DeemableTech_2015-10-09.mp3?_=13"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/10/DeemableTech_2015-10-09.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/10/DeemableTech_2015-10-09.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>Facebook ?Likes&rsquo; rumors of a ?Dislike&rsquo; button</h3>
<p>Pretty much ever since Facebook introduced its ubiquitous ?like&rsquo; button, users have been clamoring for a ?dislike&rsquo; button. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.businessinsider.com/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-is-working-on-a-disklike-button-2015-9&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNESLWUmoJTSDf2YlombZDDSLHvrEg">Well last month, Business Insider reported that Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg had announced that the company was working on one</a>. Only, it isn&rsquo;t quite what you think.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t worry, the world&rsquo;s most dominant social media site isn&rsquo;t about to turn into a den of passive-aggressive backstabbing &ndash; anymore than it already is. Zuck says he wants to give users a way to express sympathy or empathy when someone posts that they are having a bad day or going through a difficult time.</p>
<p>While Facebook&rsquo;s CEO promised that the ?dislike&rsquo; button would appear in the not-too-distant future, as of this recording it is not available. And you should be wary of scams. Gizmodo reports that <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://factually.gizmodo.com/dont-fall-for-the-facebook-dislike-button-scam-1732352168&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNGBMDi-u-SLQOrXd3yHLTFDe5Y_9Q">ads have started appearing promising that people that take a survey can get early access to the ?dislike&rsquo; button</a>. You can&rsquo;t and you won&rsquo;t. Although you may ?dislike&rsquo; what happens to you if you try.</p>
<h3>The internet gives ?Yelp for Humans&rsquo; a one star rating</h3>
<p>Ever app developer hopes that their app will go viral and gain massive media attention. Last week, one soon-to-be-released app did, although probably not in the way its creators wanted. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-intersect/wp/2015/09/30/everyone-you-know-will-be-able-to-rate-you-on-the-terrifying-yelp-for-people-whether-you-want-them-to-or-not/&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNG7yS9IfdLogqgONJkV9u7RSiAIHg">The Washington Post ran a story about an app called Peeple</a>, which founder Julia Cordray billed as ?Yelp for Humans&rsquo;. Supposedly the app would allow you to rate anyone you had a phone # on a 1-5 scale. The people you were rating did not have to be signed up for the app.</p>
<p>Although Cordray promised that there would be controls in place to prevent cyber-bullying and that those who received negative ratings would have 48 hours to respond to them before they were posted, the internet backlash was swift and massive. Within hours, #Peeple was a trending topic on Twitter, with the Tweets about it almost uniformly negative. Peeple&rsquo;s Facebook page was flooded with angry comments. Ironically, Peeple began to delete negative feedback from their Facebook page before taking both it and their Twitter feed offline entirely.</p>
<p>Over the weekend, <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://m.snopes.com/2015/10/01/peeple/&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNFkmBDPXjHBSVr6ewJ_mOFVVD_LQg">Snopes.com speculated that Peeple was actually just a hoax</a>&nbsp;intended to rile everyone up. However, there has been no confirmation that it is in fact a hoax at this time.</p>
<p>As of this morning, <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/julia-cordray-ceo-peeple-creating-worlds-largest-app-julia-cordray&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNFqHOZ-BYwSxqCZOtmk-ONuTn1-lg">Peeple founder Julia Cordray has posted a lengthy ?clarification&rsquo; on LinkedIn</a>. In her article, she claims that the purpose of the app has been misunderstood, that it is a ?positivity&rsquo; app, and that it will NOT in fact allow negative reviews or allow reviews of people who have not signed up for the app. This seems directly contradictory to what has been stated about the app before, including in a handful of ?webisodes&rsquo; that the team had posted on YouTube.</p>
<p>A further wrinkle in this crazy only-on-the-internet story: Peeple is also the name of another startup, this one a company which has developed an electronic, wifi-enabled peephole for your front-door. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.wired.com/2015/10/peeple-the-thing-versus-peeple-the-app/&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNEPayX-_WOeKBTXppsfcnYARZwssQ">Wired reports that the other Peeple is less-than-pleased about the unwanted publicity</a>. Since the other Peeple owns the trademark to the name in the US, it is not clear how the app makers will proceed. Should they choose to, their stated release date is in November.</p>
<h2>Random guy buys Google.com from Google for $12</h2>
<p>Mashable reports <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://mashable.com/2015/10/01/buys-google-com-for-12/?utm_cid%3Dmash-com-fb-main-link%236tNOquWWjqq1&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNHzZ2yglbX9reJn1UDSYCMOu2z6Iw">that last week a random guy was able to buy Google.com </a><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://mashable.com/2015/10/01/buys-google-com-for-12/?utm_cid%3Dmash-com-fb-main-link%236tNOquWWjqq1&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNHzZ2yglbX9reJn1UDSYCMOu2z6Iw">from Google</a><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://mashable.com/2015/10/01/buys-google-com-for-12/?utm_cid%3Dmash-com-fb-main-link%236tNOquWWjqq1&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNHzZ2yglbX9reJn1UDSYCMOu2z6Iw">&nbsp;for the massive price of $12</a>. Sanmay Ved, a student at Babson University, was playing around with Google Domains when he noticed that the site said that &ldquo;Google.com&rdquo; was unclaimed. He added it to his cart, checked out, and a few minutes later had an email informing him of his successful purchase of &ldquo;Google.com.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Just a few minutes after that, however, his purchase was mysteriously cancelled. Ved reports that he did notify Google of the glitch after the fact. No word on why Google had its own domain up for sale in the first place.</p>
<p>Mashable notes that Microsoft lost Hotmail.co.uk in a similar glitch in 2003, but had more trouble getting it back.</p>
<h2>Amazon.com to stop carrying competing streaming devices Chromecast and Apple TV</h2>
<p>Competition in the world of streaming TV and movies continues to heat up. Several different companies now offer low-cost solutions that allow users to stream high quality video from several different services on the cheap. The leaders are Google&rsquo;s Chromecast, Apple&rsquo;s Apple TV, and Amazon&rsquo;s Fire TV Stick. Well <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2015-10-01/amazon-will-ban-sale-of-apple-google-video-streaming-devices&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNEkxlNaEuhFqa8g2WgV67q9_QKZvw">Bloomberg reports that Amazon.com has decided that that is a few competitors too many</a>. It has announced that starting on October 29th it will no longer carry either the Chromecast or the AppleTV in its online store. Just in time for the Christmas season!</p>
<p>Amazon states that the reason for this move is that its competitor&rsquo;s devices don&rsquo;t &ldquo;interact well&rdquo; with Amazon Prime Video. Of course it would appear that it is up to Amazon to develop software for the devices, not the companies that make them.</p>
<p>Other streaming devices, including Roku&rsquo;s set top device and Microsoft&rsquo;s XBox One and Sony&rsquo;s Playstation 4 are not affected</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/10/100-the-deemable-decade/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/10/DeemableTech_2015-10-09.mp3" length="39339509" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#99 Live Photos Are Not Videos, They&#8217;re MOVING PICTURES!</title>
		<link>/2015/09/99-live-photos-are-not-videos-theyre-moving-pictures/</link>
		<comments>/2015/09/99-live-photos-are-not-videos-theyre-moving-pictures/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 21:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Pencil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple watch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad Pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 6S]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 6S Plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone Upgrade Program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One Republic]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10280</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/09/AppleLivePhotos-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Apple Live Photos" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Tom is out of town, and there was an Apple Special Event Wednesday, so Ray and Sean&#160;get to talk about Apple without Tom&#8217;s skeptical cynicism. Don&#8217;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, <a href="/2015/09/99-live-photos-are-not-videos-theyre-moving-pictures/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/09/99-live-photos-are-not-videos-theyre-moving-pictures/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/09/AppleLivePhotos-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Apple Live Photos" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-10282" src="/media/2015/09/AppleLivePhotos-300x300.png" alt="Apple Live Photos" width="300" height="300">Tom is out of town, and there was an Apple Special Event Wednesday, so Ray and Sean&nbsp;get to talk about Apple without Tom&rsquo;s skeptical cynicism.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://deemable.com/reddit&amp;sa=D&amp;usg=AFQjCNEydTeHrQvmDcf3CbTGWjMzWOruOw">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on the&nbsp;website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you&rsquo;re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>What do you think about comics on television? If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at&nbsp;<a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10280-14" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wjct/files/201509/DeemableTech_2015-09-11.mp3?_=14"></source><a href="http://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wjct/files/201509/DeemableTech_2015-09-11.mp3">http://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wjct/files/201509/DeemableTech_2015-09-11.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>Apple Watch</h3>
<p>Tim Cook opened Wednesday&rsquo;s announcement by touting the huge success of the Apple Watch, and then didn&rsquo;t tell us any real numbers, and then touted the new Watch OS 2. There wasn&rsquo;t much to talk about here, other than there are now 10,000 apps on the Apple Watch.</p>
<p>Apple also figured out that people who don&rsquo;t have $10,000 to spare still like the color gold. Apple announced two new finishes: gold&nbsp;and rose&nbsp;gold in annonized aluminium. They also announced new leather watch straps from Hermes&nbsp;and a new Product Red&nbsp;model.</p>
<h3>Apple TV</h3>
<p>Apple also announced their first update to the Apple TV since 2012 at the event. The 4th generation Apple TV will feature major hardware and software updates, a new remote, new apps, and something called Siri (not sure what that is).</p>
<p>While the Apple TV box mostly looks the same as the old one from the outside (besides being a tad bit taller), the inside contains a lot of the same hardware as the iPhone 6 so it looks like it will be much faster than the previous generation.</p>
<p>It will need this extra speed for all of the new apps that are coming from the new Apple TV App Store. For the first time in the device?s history, Apple is letting developers create apps for the Apple TV and what they?re calling the new ?TV OS? operating system. They said these will include universal apps that will work and sync across devices. They made a particularly big deal about games on the Apple TV.</p>
<p>And it looks like those games will utilize a lot of the features of the new Apple TV remote. The new design includes a glass touch surface across the top that you?ll be able to swipe left and right, and up and down, to navigate menus and control game characters and the like. The remote also has a built-in gyroscope and accelerometer.</p>
<p>The biggest thing about the remote, though, is the Siri button.</p>
<p>Yes, in a greatly anticipated move, Apple has added Siri to Apple TV. Press that button, and you?ll be able to ask Siri to search for content across platforms like Netflix, Hulu and iTunes. You can even get really specific &ndash; the demo included a search for ?the episode of Modern Family with Edward Norton? that resulted in Siri pulling up the exact episode of that show in which the actor guest starred.</p>
<p>You?ll also be able to use Siri to search for information while watching content without pausing. A Siri special bar will pop up at the bottom of the screen with the results, which you can then swipe up for more details.</p>
<p>There was no release date for the new Apple TV, but Apple did reveal some prices. A 64 gigabyte version will be 199 dollars, a 32 gig one will be 149 dollars.</p>
<h3>iPad Pro</h3>
<p>The biggest news of the event (see what I did there?) was the iPad Pro. Coming in with a 12.9&Prime; display, it is the biggest iOS device ever made. There were rumors forever that there would be a pro version of the iPad, and that it would have OS X, the operating system that runs Mac computers. Not surprising, that rumor turned out to be a dud.</p>
<p>Apple announced two accessories for the iPad Pro: the Smart Keyboard and ? the Apple Pencil.</p>
<p>I can tell you everything you need to know about the Smart Keyboard in five words: it&rsquo;s not a Surface Keyboard. It looks pretty much exactly like a Surface Keyboard. It connects to the iPad very similarly to a Surface Keyboard. It&rsquo;s a little more expensive than a Surface Keyboard at $169 instead of the Surface Pro Keyboard&rsquo;s $129.99</p>
<p>Then there&rsquo;s the Apple Pencil. It&rsquo;s magical, it&rsquo;s revolutionary? it&rsquo;s a freakin&rsquo; stylus. Steve Jobs is rolling in his grave. Again, Apple Pencil, $99, Surface Pen, $49. #imjustsayin</p>
<p>In all seriousness though, Apple has a habit of &ldquo;inventing&rdquo; products that have been around forever, only to make them worlds better than the ones that are already out there on the market. The Apple Pencil does look really incredible, for a stylus. &nbsp;It detects pressure and angle so it gives you a lot of variation. It&rsquo;s supposed to last for 12 hours between charges, and it charges by plugging into the lighting connection on the iPad. Time will tell if it lives up to the hype.</p>
<p>Just like the original iPad announcement though, there was not a lot of &ldquo;Wow this is amazing!&rdquo; moments in the iPad Pro announcement. It does have a four speaker stereo sound system. So, that should help with how awful sound always is on every tablet device. The huge screen boasts 2732-by-2048 pixels across its 12.9 inches on the diagonal, and it&rsquo;s the fastest, most powerful Apple product that runs iOS. In fact, Apple claims it is faster than 90% of portable PCs. So, there&rsquo;s that.</p>
<h3>iPhone 6S and 6S Plus</h3>
<p>No surprise, Apple announced the iPhone 6S and 6S Plus. Since we are on the &ldquo;S&rdquo; cycle, there wasn&rsquo;t much new in the outward facing hardware department.</p>
<p>Other than the addition of a new rose gold finish, one of the biggest change was the addition of 3D Touch. This is one of the hardest features to explain. Basically, instead of just tapping, dragging and double tapping, you can tap deeper. And, if you tap deeper, on some menu items you&rsquo;ll find additional options.</p>
<p>3D Touch is going to be the least used feature of the iPhone 6S.</p>
<p>Another big change to the iPhone 6Ses was the camera. The iPhone 6S has a 12 megapixel camera and can shoot 4K video.</p>
<p>The front-facing camera, known as the FaceTime camera, also got an upgrade. The FaceTime Camera is now a 5 megapixel camera, and it can shoot video in 1080. Also, the FaceTime camera now has TrueTone Flash, by using the screen as a flash bulb. Instead of adding LEDs to the front of the phone, Apple engineered the screen to flash brighter.</p>
<p>And, now you can have moving&nbsp;pictures! with sound! Apple is calling them: Live Photos. when you are looking at a picture that was taken with the Live Photo option turned on, you&rsquo;ll be able to pressed the photo and it will start moving. Basically, it captures seconds before the photo was taken and afterward so you can be more in the moment. These are not movies according to Apple.</p>
<h3>iPhone Upgrade Program</h3>
<p>But, I hope you can afford to pay for a new iPhone with cash, because&nbsp;AT&amp;T is the only carrier left that sells iPhones on a two-year contract.</p>
<p>But, Apple did announce a new payment plan to buy an iPhone. Starting at $27 a month, you can buy an iPhone directly from Apple. This works out to 24 payments, so starting out at a total of $649, the same price as buying an iPhone outright.</p>
<p>This would be great, if you could theoretically get a lower priced service plan from the carriers, but we really haven&rsquo;t seen much of a difference in prices since Sprint and Verizon announced that they were no longer selling iPhones at the two-year contract price.</p>
<h3>One Republic Apologizes</h3>
<p>And finally, Apple, as it often does, closed out the announcement with a performance from a big name band. Fortunately this time they did not also force feed a new album into our phones. One Republic played a few ditties. They also apologized for all the times you&rsquo;ve had to listen to &ldquo;Good Life&rdquo; while you were shopping at Whole Foods.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/09/99-live-photos-are-not-videos-theyre-moving-pictures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wjct/files/201509/DeemableTech_2015-09-11.mp3" length="41768424" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ask Deemable Tech: The Tech To Help You Get Through The Storm</title>
		<link>/2015/09/ask-deemable-tech-the-tech-to-help-you-get-through-the-storm/</link>
		<comments>/2015/09/ask-deemable-tech-the-tech-to-help-you-get-through-the-storm/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 12:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ask Deemable Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hurricane preparedness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10274</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/09/RedCrossEtonFRX3-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="The Red Cross FRX3 Eton Emergency Radio contains a solar panel and hand turbine charger, rechargeable battery, AM/FM radio, NOAA weather band radio, LED red flashing beacon and LED flashlight. Image credit: Eton" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />As you prepare for hurricane season, don&#8217;t forget about your technology. Make sure to download apps now that can make it easier to get through the storm, and make sure to have what you need to keep your devices running <a href="/2015/09/ask-deemable-tech-the-tech-to-help-you-get-through-the-storm/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/09/ask-deemable-tech-the-tech-to-help-you-get-through-the-storm/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/09/RedCrossEtonFRX3-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="The Red Cross FRX3 Eton Emergency Radio contains a solar panel and hand turbine charger, rechargeable battery, AM/FM radio, NOAA weather band radio, LED red flashing beacon and LED flashlight. Image credit: Eton" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>As you prepare for hurricane season, don&rsquo;t forget about your technology. Make sure to download apps now that can make it easier to get through the storm, and make sure to have what you need to keep your devices running during and after the storm.</p>
<p><span id="more-10274"></span></p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10274-15" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/09/adt_20150910_storm_tech.mp3?_=15"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/09/adt_20150910_storm_tech.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/09/adt_20150910_storm_tech.mp3</a></audio><div id="attachment_10275" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2015/09/RedCrossEtonFRX3.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-10275 size-medium" src="/media/2015/09/RedCrossEtonFRX3-300x169.jpg"  alt="The Red Cross FRX3 Eton Emergency Radio contains a solar panel and hand turbine charger, rechargeable battery, AM/FM radio, NOAA weather band radio, LED red flashing beacon and LED flashlight. Image credit: Eton" width="300" height="169"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Red Cross FRX3 Eton Emergency Radio contains a solar panel and hand turbine charger, rechargeable battery, AM/FM radio, NOAA weather band radio, LED red flashing beacon and LED flashlight. Image credit: Eton</p></div>
<p><strong>Apps</strong></p>
<p>There are countless weather apps on the Apple App Store and the Google Play Store. &nbsp;<a href="https://mobile.yahoo.com/weather/" data-cke-saved-href="https://mobile.yahoo.com/weather/">Yahoo Weather</a>, <a href="http://downloads.accuweather.com/" data-cke-saved-href="http://downloads.accuweather.com/"><span data-scaytid="1" data-scayt_word="Accuweather">Accuweather</span></a>, <a href="http://www.weather.com/apps" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.weather.com/apps">The Weather Channel</a>, <a href="http://getweatherbug.com/" data-cke-saved-href="http://getweatherbug.com/"><span data-scaytid="2" data-scayt_word="WeatherBug">WeatherBug</span></a> and <a href="http://www.wunderground.com/weather-app" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.wunderground.com/weather-app">Weather Underground</a> all do a fine job of providing up-to-date weather alerts and information.</p>
<p><span data-scaytid="3" data-scayt_word="News4Jax?s">News4Jax&rsquo;s</span> <a href="http://www.news4jax.com/22092112" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.news4jax.com/22092112"><span data-scaytid="4" data-scayt_word="WJXT">WJXT</span>: The Weather Authority</a> app provides weather alerts and forecasts specifically for Northeast Florida. The <a href="http://www.coj.net/mobile-apps/mobile-apps-list/jaxready.aspx" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.coj.net/mobile-apps/mobile-apps-list/jaxready.aspx"><span data-scaytid="5" data-scayt_word="JaxReady">JaxReady</span> app</a> provides evacuation information for Jacksonville residents. The Florida Public Radio Emergency Network&rsquo;s new app,&nbsp;<a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/florida-storms/id1011397030?mt=8" data-cke-saved-href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/florida-storms/id1011397030?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Florida Storms</a>, provides weather and storm tracking and forecasting information, preparedness checklists, evacuation routes and a live audio stream from 89.9 FM or your local Florida public radio station.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.redcross.org/mobile-apps/hurricane-app" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.redcross.org/mobile-apps/hurricane-app">The Red Cross Hurricane App</a> helps you plan before the storm, gives updates during the storm and provides information on how to recover after the storm has passed. <a href="http://www.redcross.org/mobile-apps/first-aid-app" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.redcross.org/mobile-apps/first-aid-app">The Red Cross First Aid App</a> has information and videos to help you handle common first aid emergencies that might arise during a disaster.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re stuck in a precarious position, you may need to get information out fast to someone who can help. <a href="http://www.redpanicbutton.com/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.redpanicbutton.com/">Red Panic Button</a> is an app that can send out an urgent text message, tweet, Facebook message and email with a link to your location on Google Maps.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.fema.gov/mobile-app" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.fema.gov/mobile-app">FEMA&rsquo;s mobile app</a> can help you find shelters and disaster recovery centers. It also provides tips to survive a disaster and can be used to apply for aid after the storm.</p>
<p><strong>External Batteries</strong></p>
<p>An external battery with a USB port will keep your devices working for a while until the power comes back on.</p>
<p>When shopping for a USB battery backup, look for the mAh, or milliAmpere-hour, rating. The mAh is a measurement of how much energy the battery can store. The more mAh, the better. Choose a battery backup that has more mAh than the device that needs to be charged.</p>
<p>The iPhone 6 has a 1,810 mAh battery and the iPad&rsquo;s battery has 8,827 mAh. A quick search on the web will usually tell you how much mAh your device&rsquo;s battery has in it. For a list of recommendations, Lifehacker has put together a list of <a href="http://lifehacker.com/five-best-external-battery-packs-509802431" data-cke-saved-href="http://lifehacker.com/five-best-external-battery-packs-509802431">five of the best battery packs</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Battery Chargers</strong></p>
<p>There are a few options that can keep those external batteries and devices charged if the power is out for more than a few hours. Hand crank chargers are devices that turn your arm energy into battery power. There are also <a href="https://www.k-tor.com/pedal-powered-generator/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.k-tor.com/pedal-powered-generator/">pedal-powered generators</a> that use your feet to make energy, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Best-Sellers-Electronics-Cell-Phone-Solar-Chargers/zgbs/electronics/2407762011" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.amazon.com/Best-Sellers-Electronics-Cell-Phone-Solar-Chargers/zgbs/electronics/2407762011">solar chargers</a> that use energy from the sun to charge your phone, <a href="http://www.macworld.com/article/2086548/review-seven-off-the-grid-chargers-for-your-portable-devices.html" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.macworld.com/article/2086548/review-seven-off-the-grid-chargers-for-your-portable-devices.html">fuel cells that turn water into electricity</a> and <a href="http://powerpractical.com/products/powerpot5-thermoelectric-generator" data-cke-saved-href="http://powerpractical.com/products/powerpot5-thermoelectric-generator">heat-powered generators</a> that use the thermal energy from cooking to charge a battery.</p>
<p><strong>Radios, Flashlights</strong></p>
<p>Of course, if the Internet and cell phone service goes out your apps won&rsquo;t much provide information. In case that happens, make sure you have a working, battery-powered radio. Tune your radio to WJCT 89.9 FM, the official emergency weather station for Northeast Florida and extreme Southeast Georgia.</p>
<p>Also, make sure to have battery-powered flashlights. Newer LED flashlights provide more light and last much longer than the older incandescent flashlights.</p>
<p><strong>All-In-One</strong></p>
<p>The ideal solution would be one device that had it all: a flashlight, radio, external battery and a way to charge the battery or an electronic device if the power goes out. Fortunately, Eton and the Red Cross have made that device. <a href="http://www.redcrossstore.org/item/FRX3" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.redcrossstore.org/item/FRX3">The Red Cross FRX3 Eton Emergency Radio</a> contains a solar panel and hand turbine charger, rechargeable battery, AM/FM radio, NOAA weather band radio, LED red flashing beacon and LED flashlight. Eton has <a href="http://www.etoncorp.com/en/products?f%5B0%5D=field_product_category%3A18" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.etoncorp.com/en/products?f%5B0%5D=field_product_category%3A18">other survival devices</a> of greater and lesser complexity as well.</p>
<p><em>Note: This article originally appeared on <a href="http://news.wjct.org/post/tech-help-you-get-through-storm" target="_blank">WJCTNews.org</a>.</em></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/09/ask-deemable-tech-the-tech-to-help-you-get-through-the-storm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/09/adt_20150910_storm_tech.mp3" length="3353129" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple Special Event Live Blog</title>
		<link>/2015/09/live-blog-apple-special-event/</link>
		<comments>/2015/09/live-blog-apple-special-event/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 16:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10264</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-09-at-1.02.28-PM-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2015-09-09 at 1.02.28 PM" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Read Deemable Tech&#8217;s live blog from the Apple special press event discussing the announcements of the iPad Pro, new Apple TV and the iPhone 6S and iPhone 6S Plus, and the new accessories, Apple Pencil and Keyboard.<p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/09/live-blog-apple-special-event/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-09-at-1.02.28-PM-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2015-09-09 at 1.02.28 PM" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>Read Deemable Tech&rsquo;s live blog from the Apple special press event discussing the announcements of the iPad Pro, new Apple TV and the iPhone 6S and iPhone 6S Plus, and the new accessories, Apple Pencil and Keyboard.</p>
<div id="24lb_thread" class="lb_1302064"></div>
<p><script type="text/javascript">// <![CDATA[
(function() {
var lb24 = document.createElement('script'); lb24.type = 'text/javascript'; lb24.id = '24lbScript'; lb24.async = true; lb24.charset="utf-8";
lb24.src = '//v.24liveblog.com/embed/24.js?id=1302064';
(document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(lb24);})();
// ]]&gt;</script></p>
<p><img class="size-large wp-image-10268 alignnone" src="/media/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-09-at-1.02.28-PM-1024x640.png" alt="Screen Shot 2015-09-09 at 1.02.28 PM" width="659" height="412"></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/09/live-blog-apple-special-event/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#98 Don’t Tase Me, Drone!</title>
		<link>/2015/08/98-dont-tase-me-drone/</link>
		<comments>/2015/08/98-dont-tase-me-drone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 19:40:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ashley Madison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10250</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/08/DontTaseMeDrone-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Don&#039;t Tase Me, Drone!" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Weaponized drones, Ashley Madison, Facebook&#8217;s new virtual assistant and artificial intelligence are all in the news this week. If you?re listening to Deemable Tech on the&#160;website, make sure to&#160;subscribe to the show on iTunes&#160;or&#160;on Stitcher.&#160;And, while you?re there, leave a <a href="/2015/08/98-dont-tase-me-drone/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/08/98-dont-tase-me-drone/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/08/DontTaseMeDrone-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Don&#039;t Tase Me, Drone!" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><h1></h1>
<p>Weaponized drones, Ashley Madison, Facebook&rsquo;s new virtual assistant and artificial intelligence are all in the news this week.</p>
<p>If you?re listening to Deemable Tech on the&nbsp;website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you?re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-10253" src="/media/2015/08/DontTaseMeDrone-300x200.jpg" alt="Don't Tase Me, Drone!" width="300" height="200">If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at&nbsp;<a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10250-16" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-31.mp3?_=16"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-31.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-31.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>Ashley Madison was nothing but a honeypot</h3>
<p>Ashley Madison is still in the news. Gizmodo is reporting that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fgizmodo.com%2Falmost-none-of-the-women-in-the-ashley-madison-database-1725558944&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGP-jb1kD96rjNvXLZ-Jx6ndKzbGA">hardly any of the real women on Ashley Madison actually used the site</a>. Salon says that the number of <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.salon.com%2F2015%2F08%2F20%2Fmy_fake_ashley_madison_affair_someone_else_used_my_email_address_to_create_an_account_so_why_do_i_feel_so_guilty%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGs3cacD8DTOweLV_4lJtYjDW6sTA">fake female accounts is close to 95%</a>&nbsp;which sounds about right from my experience. Like I&rsquo;ve mentioned on the show a few times most of the women on the site are bots. By most, I mean, I don&rsquo;t think I ever spoke to a single real person the entire time I was on the site. So, there were only about 5.5 million female accounts, meaning that there were only about 250 thousand real women on the website.</p>
<p>To make things even worse for Avid Life Media, of those 250 thousand women, a very small number of them actually used the site. Only about 2400 used the chat system and 1,400 used the messaging system. Considering the site also had 31.3 million men, and the site billed itself as a place to find women who wanted to have an affair, that is pretty rough for the company. It looks like they didn&rsquo;t have the product to sell, so they built bots. Lots of the accounts have email addresses like 100@ashleymadison.com.</p>
<h3>Ashley Madison CEO gets the &ldquo;mutual agreement&rdquo; boot</h3>
<p>So, it shouldn&rsquo;t come as much surprise that Avid Life Media CEO <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.engadget.com%2F2015%2F08%2F28%2Favid-life-media-ceo-quits%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNF371bDd4GVhDg1SXlEgqybgZ0_dw">Noel Biderman, has quit his job as CEO</a>&nbsp;? &ldquo;in mutual agreement with the company.&rdquo;</p>
<p>A company that sold a service so crappy that women barely signed up for it, so the company had to make bots, and the site was so insecure that all of its data was dumped on the Internet. Yeah, I don&rsquo;t know why they didn&rsquo;t want to keep him around.</p>
<p>That being said, we are happy to say, this is the last time we are going to talk about Ashley Madison, Established Gentlemen or Avid Life Media, hopefully for a long time.</p>
<h3>Facebook launches new virtual assistant &ldquo;M&rdquo;</h3>
<p>Following in the footsteps of Apple?s Siri, Google Now and Microsoft?s Cortana, Facebook unveiled a new virtual assistant this week that they?re calling ?M.?</p>
<p>M will be built into the Facebook Messenger app. Unlike its competitors, M is &ndash; at least for the time being &ndash; is entirely text based.</p>
<p>As Wired reports, there is another huge difference between M and the other virtual assistants: <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wired.com%2F2015%2F08%2Ffacebook-launches-m-new-kind-virtual-assistant%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGJ2slpblmZeE07SudFdH0liP5GGA">M will use a hybrid of artificial intelligence and </a><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wired.com%2F2015%2F08%2Ffacebook-launches-m-new-kind-virtual-assistant%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGJ2slpblmZeE07SudFdH0liP5GGA">real people</a><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wired.com%2F2015%2F08%2Ffacebook-launches-m-new-kind-virtual-assistant%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGJ2slpblmZeE07SudFdH0liP5GGA">&nbsp;to complete tasks.</a></p>
<p>A team of employees called ?M trainers? will work alongside the software to make sure every question and request is answered. Facebook says M will offer a true personal assistant experience by helping users book restaurants, pick out and deliver gifts and more.</p>
<p>During internal employee testing, one of the most popular requests for M was to call the user?s cable company so they wouldn?t have sit through long wait lines and automated messages.</p>
<p>David Marcus, vice president of messaging products at Facebook, says they are also looking for a way to partner with businesses that get a lot of requests through M.</p>
<p>Facebook is currently doing a trial run for M with a few hundred users in the San Francisco Bay Area.</p>
<h3>Facebook Hits 1 Billion Visitors A Day</h3>
<p>Speaking of The Facebook, the Associated Press reported this week that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.ibnlive.com%2Fnews%2Ftech%2Ffacebook-hits-milestone-1-billion-people-used-site-on-a-single-day-1056653.html&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGuRe4rF-Sz6b9IPo2x4381-yak1w">the social media behemoth hit a major milestone as one billion users visited the site in a single day</a>. Facebook hit a billion users back in 2012, but there is a significant difference between having a billion users and having a billion people actually logging onto your site and using it every day. Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg celebrated the milestone in a Facebook post, stating that this meant that 1 out of every 7 people on earth had logged onto the site that day.</p>
<h3>North Dakota legalizes armed police drones</h3>
<p>NPR reports that North Dakota has passed a law legalizing use of drones armed with ?less than lethal? weapons by law enforcement. Less than lethal weapons apparently include &nbsp;tear gas, rubber bullets, beanbags, pepper spray and Tasers. The bill?s sponsor, Republican State Senator Becker said that the bill was actually intended to require police to get warrants before using drones for surveillance. In order to pass the bill, however, compromises had to be included. Becker says that he hopes to get the weaponization part of the bill overturned in a future session.</p>
<h3>Arrrrrrr-tificial Intelligence Predicts Pirate Attacks</h3>
<p>Our next story is about the rapidly growing field of Arrrrrr-tificial intelligence. David Nield at Science Alert reports that the Navy has filed a patent for a computerized system that can predict pirate attacks based on previous intelligence, weather, and other factors. Modern day piracy is a real problem, costing the US maritime industry an estimated $16 billion per year. The Navy?s pirate attack computer model would be able to simulate attacks by large numbers of ?virtual pirates? and generate probability estimates of when and where pirate attacks are most likely to take place.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Uber hires Jeep hackers</h3>
<p>Regular listeners will remember that not long ago we talked about the two hackers who were able to take control of a Jeep?s engine and brakes through its uConnect system. The hack made such big headlines that it caused Fiat Chrysler to issue a recall. Well <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.engadget.com%2F2015%2F08%2F28%2Fuber-jeep-hackers%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHXzv0tZQMUxwEhIRXXgRp8FULpaw">Engadget reports that this week Uber announced that it had hired the men behind the hack</a>, Charlie Miller and Chris Valacek, to work at its Advanced Technology Center in Pennsylvania. Like other tech companies, Uber is known to be exploring the possibilities of autonomous cars. Making sure that your driverless car has robust security to keep it from being remotely controlled by a hacker is probably a smart move.</p>
<h3>BEM Twitter Account</h3>
<p>Just wanted to share a great Twitter account I just discovered: <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2FBoredElonMusk&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGtt8i9VudISSztTYJH1G37f9E7gg">Bored Elon Musk</a>. This parody account purports to be the downtime thoughts of Musk, the inventor, entrepreneur and cofounder of Paypal, Tesla and SpaceX.</p>
<p><em>Photo credit: &ldquo;<a href="/?attachment_id=10253" target="_blank">Don&rsquo;t Taze Me, Drone!</a>&rdquo; by <a href="/author/rayhollister/" target="_blank">Ray Hollister</a> is a derivative work of &ldquo;<a href="https://flic.kr/p/s7SFv9" target="_blank">Project 365 #121: 010515 Attack Of The Drones!</a>&rdquo; by <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/comedynose/" target="_blank">Pete</a> used under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/" target="_blank">CC BY 2.0</a>.</em></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/08/98-dont-tase-me-drone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-31.mp3" length="20405510" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#97 Ashley Madison Just Got Dumped</title>
		<link>/2015/08/97-ashley-madison-just-got-dumped/</link>
		<comments>/2015/08/97-ashley-madison-just-got-dumped/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 22:41:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ashley Madison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sprint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10241</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/ashleymadison-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Ashley Madison" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />If you&#8217;re listening to Deemable Tech on the&#160;website, make sure to&#160;subscribe to the show on iTunes&#160;or&#160;on Stitcher.&#160;And, while you&#8217;re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show. If <a href="/2015/08/97-ashley-madison-just-got-dumped/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/08/97-ashley-madison-just-got-dumped/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/ashleymadison-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Ashley Madison" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_10170" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2015/07/ashleymadison.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10170" src="/media/2015/07/ashleymadison-300x169.jpg"  alt="Image credit: Ashley Madison" width="300" height="169"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: Ashley Madison</p></div>
<p>If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on the&nbsp;website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you&rsquo;re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10241-17" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-24.mp3?_=17"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-24.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-24.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3><b></b><b>Google Launches New Router</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Google announced this week that is partnering with networking manufacturer TP-Link to make a new a Wi-Fi router called the OnHub. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In </span><a href="http://mashable.com/2015/08/18/google-launches-onhub-router/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the announcement on their official blog</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Google says they want to alleviate the setup headaches and connection problems that many people experience with their wireless routers by introducing a simple, user-friendly device.&nbsp;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The OnHub, which looks like a large cylinder with a single light on top, is filled with 13 antennas &ndash; 12 for signal, and one that checks the airwaves to make sure there is no wireless congestion in the area. This supposedly will make sure that you?ll always have the fastest connection.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You set up and manage the OnHub by using the Google On Android and iOS app, which Google says will let you prioritize connections for specific devices, and give you easy access to your router password so you can copy and text it to your friends. In a really cool twist, you connect your phone with the router at first by using SOUND.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As for the clean design, Google had this to say: ?Many of us keep our router on the floor and out of sight, where it doesn?t work as well. We replaced unruly cords and blinking lights with internal antennas and subtle, useful lighting, so you?ll be happy placing OnHub out in the open, where your router performs its best.?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The OnHub is available for preorder now (though it apparently is completely sold out). It?s a little pricey for a router at $199.</span></p>
<h3><b>Google Project Sunroof Tool</b></h3>
<p><a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/8/17/9166485/google-sunroof-solar"><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to an article on Vox</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Google is working on a new tool called Project Sunroof that will help you figure out if solar power is right for your home. The Project Sunroof tool allows you to enter your address and then uses aerial imagery to calculate how much sunlight your rooftop receives. The tool then uses other information such as your monthly electric bill and whether you want to buy or lease the panels to determine how much going solar could save you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The tool is still in its early stages. Right now, it doesn?t work for North Florida, where we are located, but </span><a href="https://www.google.com/get/sunroof#p=0"><span style="font-weight: 400;">you can have fun playing with it for Google?s stomping grounds in California</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><b>And then there was one. Sprint stops offering two-year contracts.</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Verizon announced in early August that it would not be offering subsidized phones with two-year contracts to new customers. Existing customers could still get a new phone at a cheaper price, as long as they didn&rsquo;t change phone plans. This made Verizon the second company to drop the ol&rsquo; two year routine. T-Mobile, the company Siri thinks I&rsquo;m talking about everytime I say &ldquo;Deemable,&rdquo; started this trend in 2013 when they became the so-called &ldquo;unCarrier.&rdquo; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now according to the Wall Street Journal, Sprint has jumped on the bandwagon. </span><a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/sprint-to-abandon-two-year-contracts-1439837235"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sprint is no longer offering subsidized smartphones on two-year contracts</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, leaving poor old AT&amp;T as the only major carrier that offers subsidized phones.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, if you can&rsquo;t afford to drop $650 for a new iPhone Sprint, Verizon and T-Mobile offer a payment plan to buy a phone. At Verizon and T-Mobile, if you have good enough credit, you can pay for the phone in 24 monthly installments. Sprint doesn&rsquo;t have &nbsp;a similar purchase plan, but it will let you </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">lease </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">an iPhone starting at $22 per month. No word yet if they will offer the same deal with Android phones.</span></p>
<h3><b>Google Reveals Real Name Of ?Android M? Version of OS</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Okay guys, so as you know Google likes to name each version of its Android operating system out of something sweet, in alphabetical order. The last three versions have been Jellybean, KitKat, and Lollipop, and the next one up is Android M. This week, Google revealed what the ?M? would stand for. Any guesses?</span></p>
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2015/08/android-ms-official-name-is-marshmallow/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">And the answer is?</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Google says the new version will be 6.0. Android Lollipop is currently on version 5.1.1.</span></p>
<h3><b> iPhone 6 Plus Camera-gate</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you have an iPhone 6 Plus, you may have bought it for its significantly better camera. Well, jokes on you! Engadget is reporting that </span><a href="http://www.engadget.com/2015/08/21/psa-apple-will-replace-your-iphone-6-plus-wonky-camera/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the camera on several of the iPhone 6 Pluses are defective</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, making the image blurry. If you think you are a victim of this atrocity, you can go to </span><a href="https://www.apple.com/support/iphone6plus-isightcamera/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a page on Apple&rsquo;s website and enter your serial number</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to find out. If you don&rsquo;t have an iPhone 6 Plus and your camera lens is blurry, for instance if you have an iPhone 6, 5S, Samsung Galaxy, Nokia 3390, you&rsquo;re OK, it&rsquo;s not a defect. Just wipe the lens off</span></p>
<p><b>A Dog Joined Twitter</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Ray was worried about robot civil rights last week, a dog joined Twitter!&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Computer science student Henry Conklin thought that his dog, Oliver, was so outspoken that his thoughts needed to be shared with the world. So he created the account </span><a href="https://twitter.com/OliverBarkBark"><span style="font-weight: 400;">@OliverBarkBark</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&nbsp;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Conklin says </span><a href="http://henrywconklin.github.io/projects/2015/08/17/oliver-twitter.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">on his blog</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">: rather than transcribe every bark out of his dog?s mouth, he set up a system that ?automatically detected, filtered and published each one of Oliver?s deafening vocalizations.?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Conklin?s system consists of a Raspberry Pi &ndash; a type of microcomputer that is promoted for teaching basic computer science in schools &ndash; a microphone, and a Wi-Fi dongle. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The computer starts recording when it hears a loud sound that matches a library of barks Conklin created. The system then tweets out a random string of ?barks,? ?woofs? and ?ruffs.?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Conklin says he hopes to replace this with a bark-to-text translator he says will be ?more accurate to Oliver?s actual voice.?</span></p>
<h3><b>Boston Dynamics Unleashes Walking Robots</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Robots: threat or menace? No matter what you think about our future robotic overlords, one thing is clear: they are getting better all the time. </span><a href="http://gizmodo.com/watch-boston-dynamics-robots-run-outside-oh-god-theyre-1724630556"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gizmodo reports</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that cutting edge robotics company Boston Dynamics released a video this week showing off two of its robots. Spot, a quadrupedal robot, features a robotic arm that allows it to open doors. A bipedal robot named Atlas is shown walking over uneven surfaces, including a bed of rocks. Atlas is also shown navigating through a forest outdoors. Essentially, the only thing stopping it from running the Boston Marathon is the fact that the model is not yet wireless and must remain hooked up to a power source at all times.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company reports that they are working on this.</span></p>
<h3><b>Ashley Madison, Established Men</b></h3>
<p>Hacker group, Impact Team, announced last month that it had gained access to Avid Life Media&rsquo;s user database. ALM is the parent company of Ashley Madison, the dating website for married people who want to have an affair, and Established Men, the dating website for rich men to find young, beautiful women.</p>
<p>Impact Team demanded that Avid Life Media take down AshleyMadison.com and EstablishedMen.com, and last week, one month later, Impact Team published the data on the deepweb.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is the second major hack of a dating website of ill repute. Back in May, AdultFriendFinder was hacked. CNN Money says that customers&rsquo; email addresses, usernames, passwords, birthdays and zip codes, were included in that hack. </span></p>
<p>The data in this hack is just as extensive, and more so. The data includes most recent communications, last four digits of member credit card numbers, and more.</p>
<p>Roughly 10 GB of data in the dump. Almost 23 GB uncompressed. It&rsquo;s not available on the &ldquo;regular&rdquo; web; it was posted to the deepweb. If you don&rsquo;t know what that is, or how to get on it? educate yourself, we are not going to get into that. We have the data, but we haven&rsquo;t had enough time to dig into it before this episode was recorded.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CNN Money is reporting that </span><a href="http://money.cnn.com/2015/08/19/technology/ashley-madison-search/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">almost 7,000 email American and Canadian government email addresses are in the data dump</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Obviously, this is causing a lot of marital fall outs. The Daily Mail is reporting that lawyers are saying this is going to be &ldquo;</span><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3206003/Wife-starts-Ashley-Madison-divorce-proceedings-lawyers-call-hack-Black-Friday-say-s-like-Christmas-September.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Christmas in September</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rdquo; as spouses find out that their partner was registered or paying to be on the site in the next few weeks. Other lawyers are calling it &ldquo;Legal Black Friday.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p>CNN Money also pointed out one disturbing fact: &ldquo;The website&rsquo;s users were worldwide, and there are 79 countries where homosexuality is illegal. In Afghanistan, Iran, Mauritania, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates, the punishment is death.&rdquo;</p>
<h3><b>Josh Duggar Had Paid Account</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the first widely known names to be exposed in the Ashley Madison data dump is reality TV star and conservative value promoter Josh Duggar, of TLC?s 19 Kids and Counting fame. </span><a href="http://gawker.com/family-values-activist-josh-duggar-had-a-paid-ashley-ma-1725132091"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gawker reports that Duggar had not just one AshMad account but two</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, one linked to his home in Fayetteville, Arkansas, and the other to an address in Oxon Hill, Maryland. Both accounts were ?paid accounts?, which included the $250 purchase of an ?affair guarantee? from the website.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Duggar drew controversy in May when it was reported that he had molested several girls as a teenager, including his own sisters. His family claimed that he had since reformed. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Josh Duggar has been married to his wife Anna for seven years and they have four children.</span></p>
<h3><b>Ritch Workman</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Closer to home, FloridaPolitics.com confirmed that </span><a href="http://floridapolitics.com/archives/188733-first-hes-an-uber-driver-now-state-rep-ritch-workman-is-on-ashleymadison-com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Florida State Representative Ritch Workman was a paying Ashley Madison member</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Workman did admit that he had an account on the site, and regretted it. He said it was when he was single, but he still wishes he had never joined the site.</span></p>
<h3><b>Disney Unveils Plans for Star Wars Lands</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ever since Disney bought Star Wars, speculation has been rampant that the company would introduce Star Wars-themed attractions to its famous theme parks. Well this week Ars Technica reported that </span><a href="http://arstechnica.com/the-multiverse/2015/08/two-massive-star-wars-themed-lands-will-be-built-at-disneyland-and-disney-world/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the company made it official, announcing massive, fourteen acre Star Wars expansions to California?s Disneyland and Florida?s Disney World</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. There are few details yet but Disney says guests will be able to fly around in the Millennium Falcon and visit the Mos Eisley space cantina. The attractions will reportedly be staffed by ?local inhabitants? of the Star Wars universe.</span></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/08/97-ashley-madison-just-got-dumped/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-24.mp3" length="39485762" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#96 I need to Alphabet that</title>
		<link>/2015/08/96-i-need-to-alphabet-that/</link>
		<comments>/2015/08/96-i-need-to-alphabet-that/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 20:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[abc.xyx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eSports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hard drive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Larry Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sergei Brin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solid state drive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sundar Pichai]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10222</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/08/AlphabetSoup-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Alphabet Soup" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />If you&#8217;re listening to Deemable Tech on the&#160;website, make sure to&#160;subscribe to the show on iTunes&#160;or&#160;on Stitcher.&#160;And, while you&#8217;re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show. If <a href="/2015/08/96-i-need-to-alphabet-that/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/08/96-i-need-to-alphabet-that/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/08/AlphabetSoup-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Alphabet Soup" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-10224" src="/media/2015/08/AlphabetSoup.jpg" alt="Alphabet Soup" width="350" height="350">If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on the&nbsp;website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you&rsquo;re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10222-18" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-14.mp3?_=18"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-14.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-14.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>A is for Alphabet, G is for Google</h3>
<p>In our top story this week, tech giant Google announced a major corporate restructuring which included, to everyone&rsquo;s surprise, a name change. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fabc.xyz%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHXep9B5Ns8_XYn4ukdwSNPWU8OLQ">A new holding company has been created called Alphabet</a>. Alphabet is made up of a collection of companies including Google. Google itself is being slimmed down so that just the products and services traditionally associated with it, such as Google Search, Gmail, and Chrome, are part of it. Unrelated projects such as Google&rsquo;s famous &ldquo;moonshot&rdquo; projects, Google Fiber, and its research into self-driving cars will be spun off into their own companies, all under the Alphabet umbrella.</p>
<p>As part of the restructuring, Google&rsquo;s Senior Vice President Sundar Pichai has been made CEO of the new, slimmer Google, while Larry Page and Sergei Brin are taking control of Alphabet.</p>
<p>For the moment, no branding is changing, so if you want to search something you don&rsquo;t suddenly have to &ldquo;Alphabet&rdquo; it and you won&rsquo;t be checking &ldquo;Alphabet Mail&rdquo; anytime soon on your &ldquo;Alphabet Phone.&rdquo; At least, we sure hope not.</p>
<p>You can check out the new company&rsquo;s website and a letter from its founders at <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fabc.xyz&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFA5do-Hgq6YpPtjla53IsO7UTFow">abc.xyz</a>.</p>
<h3>Why not Alphabet.com?</h3>
<p>You might be asking yourself, why didn&rsquo;t Google just go with Alphabet.com? Well, it turns out, even the mighty Google can&rsquo;t just have any domain name they want. The New York Times is reporting that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.nytimes.com%2F2015%2F08%2F12%2Ftechnology%2Fgoogle-creates-alphabet-but-runs-into-bmw.html&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGNuAzRhhD1Ngm7mX8Q5KzjMQwANQ">car manufacturer BMW already owns Alphabet.com</a>&nbsp;and they are not interested in selling it.</p>
<p>Alphabet is a subsidiary of BMW that provides vehicle fleet services. Micaela Sandstede, a BMW spokeswoman in Munich. She described the website as a &ldquo;very active&rdquo; part of Alphabet?s business. Which is ironic, because the website has been inaccessible ever since the Google Alphabet (or is it Alphabet Google?) announcement, presumably because of the increase in traffic. It makes us feel better knowing that even mega-companies like BMW have issues keeping their website running when they get hit with a ton of traffic.</p>
<p>The article points out that it would only be trademark infringement if it creates confusion with customers&hellip; which wouldn&rsquo;t be an issue if Google and BMW were in entirely different industries, which they were, right up until Google entered the automobile industry with self-driving cars and Android for automobiles.</p>
<h3>Android flaw that got patched actually not patched</h3>
<p>You may recall that a couple of weeks ago we talked about a major security flaw in Android that allowed a remote attacker to execute code using a vulnerability in Hangouts. Google rushed out a patch for the vulnerability, which has now been codenamed &ldquo;Stagefright,&rdquo; and it was just a matter of getting it out to the phones for all the different carriers. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.bbc.com%2Fnews%2Ftechnology-33914826&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFyNAmdZ7qKlCEW9nycKeGHFF49rA">Except, according to the BBC, it turns out that the patch doesn&rsquo;t work &ndash; or at least, that it is easy to bypass</a>. Better keep Hangouts disabled for the time being.</p>
<h3>How to lose an internship at Facebook</h3>
<p>If you figure out a huge flaw in the company you are going to start an internship at, perhaps it&rsquo;s a good idea to keep it to yourself. According to Boston.com, Aran Khanna created a web-app demonstrating a <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.boston.com%2Fnews%2Fnation%2F2015%2F08%2F12%2Fharvard-student-loses-facebook-internship-after-pointing-out-privacy-flaws%2FzASZFdUjn6PoliUiR9kVHJ%2Fstory.html&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHRamxJO6tv_zofZD5NQjuEt94ChA">huge privacy flaw in Facebook Messenger</a>&nbsp;shortly before he was to begin his highly coveted internship at Facebook. Facebook Messenger stored your location automatically and shared it with anyone you chatted with on the app. Khanna&rsquo;s web-app took that information and placed it onto a map showing where everyone you had chatted with was when they sent the message.</p>
<p>He tweeted about his app and posted it on Reddit and Medium, and a few days later, Facebook asked him to disable it, and then let him know that his internship was also disabled.</p>
<p>According to Khanna, he wasn&rsquo;t fired from his internship because of the app, but because of the way he described Facebook?s user data collection. Khanna says the Medium post wasn&rsquo;t in line with the high ethical standards expected of interns.</p>
<h3>Drones make bears nervous</h3>
<p>Drones seem like an ideal method for wildlife biologists to study the habits of wild animals such as bears, but it appears that there is a catch. NPR reports that a&nbsp;new study shows that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fnews.wjct.org%2Fpost%2Fdrones-increase-heart-rates-wild-bears-too-much-stress&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGg9ueEd_jKKcBMlu7XPsDxl0VJzA">the presence of drones make bears nervous, elevating their heart rates by as much as 400%</a>. Mark Ditmer, a biologist at the University of Minnesota, St. Paul, flew a drone near bears that had been previously implanted with heart rate monitors to study their hibernation states. Although the bears appeared outwardly unphased, all of them showed elevated heart rates when buzzed by the drone.</p>
<h3>Meet the world?s biggest hard drive</h3>
<p>Samsung has unveiled a new device with the catchy name of PM1633a. According to The Verge, it&rsquo;s a 2.5 inch solid state drive, and it packs a whopping 16 terabytes of storage space, making it essentially <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2015%2F8%2F14%2F9153083%2Fsamsung-worlds-largest-hard-drive-16tb&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHgNTyAaD04c7pGArfntuH5F2nUaw">the biggest hard drive </a>ever. Samsung has not announced a price tag, but they plan to sell servers with up to 48 of these drives installed, which they are calling JBOF. One JBOF should hold about 768 TB. JBOF stands for Just a Bunch Of Flash.&nbsp;Before you ask, the next step up after terabyte is petabyte.</p>
<h3>Still No Apple TV</h3>
<p>Apple TV, the long delayed, rumored, mystical device and service is further delayed. Bloomberg is reporting that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.bloomberg.com%2Fnews%2Farticles%2F2015-08-13%2Fapple-said-to-delay-tv-service-to-2016-as-negotiations-stall&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEGeYwAhP1_D9GOzno1kbmFjkS4kw">negotiations between Apple and the big TV networks are holding up the works</a>. According to Bloomberg, Apple was to announce a new live &nbsp;streaming TV service at its Sept. 9 press event, but instead Buzzfeed News says <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.buzzfeed.com%2Fjohnpaczkowski%2Fapple-will-debut-new-apple-tv-in-september%23.raEzRlaNe&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEy3coy8AaLbXsb6FxenUSNmfnkIw">Apple is only announcing a beefed up Apple TV set-top box</a>.</p>
<h3>eSports Drug Testing</h3>
<p>Top-ranked Counter Strike: Global Offensive player Cory &ldquo;Semphis&rdquo; Friesen admitted in an interview last month that he and his competitive eSports team &ldquo;were all on Adderall&rdquo; during a recent tournament. According to NPR news, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fnews.wjct.org%2Fpost%2Fvideo-game-league-announces-random-drug-tests-competitors&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHYnOgNnD_uKIYc4_FoZK3htuwAmQ">at least one eSports league has decided that it is not okay with that</a>. The Electronic Sports League, which sponsored the $250,000 tournament Friesen and his team took part in, has announced a ban on drugs and alcohol during its tournaments and will be instituting random drug testing during its tournaments going forward. The League says the substances banned include those prohibited by the World Anti-Doping Agency. The first random drug testing at a League event will occur at ESL One in Cologne later this month.</p>
<h3>LOL is OOS (Out of Style)</h3>
<p>You may have seen an article from the New Yorker back in April about <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fculture%2Fcultural-comment%2Fhahaha-vs-hehehe&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGT6rqMpHqHc8PxweQLu0iN7cNApA">how we express laughter online</a>&nbsp;&ndash; appropriately known as e-laughter &ndash; and the increase in the use of &ldquo;hehe.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This piqued the interest of the he research team at Facebook, who decided to <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fresearch.facebook.com%2Fblog%2F1605690073053884%2Fthe-not-so-universal-language-of-laughter&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGJXlm_qj74ayt6m0xIkOIw66f6fQ">look into how users showed amusement</a>. They did so by analyzing posts and comments from last week of May. Don&rsquo;t worry &ndash; they only looked at ones that had &ldquo;at least one string of characters that matched laughter&rdquo; and they left out private messages.</p>
<p>So what did their study find? Well, among other things, the form of e-laughter that is used more than any other is &ldquo;haha&rdquo; &ndash; which they found is used over 50% of the time. In second place are emoji, followed by &ldquo;hehe&rdquo; in third. And it last place&hellip; our dear friend &ldquo;LOL.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The first text speak that many of us learned is now used only about 2 percent of the time.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fmic.com%2Farticles%2F123648%2Fhaha-lol-or-emoji-facebook-knows-how-you-laugh&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNE3y7VntKNYrYhphfVeXxJUQmT42g">Mic.com has a great breakdown</a>&nbsp;of all of Facebook&rsquo;s findings, including which phrases are most popular among different age groups and states.</p>
<hr><p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/08/96-i-need-to-alphabet-that/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-14.mp3" length="27316451" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#95 Murder, She Robot</title>
		<link>/2015/08/95-murder-she-robot/</link>
		<comments>/2015/08/95-murder-she-robot/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 20:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Dott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firmware worm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fujifilm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Glass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HitchBot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kentucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MacBook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philadelphia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thunderstrike 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VLC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows Media Player]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wired]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10195</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/08/MurderSheRobot-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Murder She Robot" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Murdered robots, silent video chat, drones being shot out of the sky, X-ray vision cameras and more Windows 10 news. All the tech news worth talking about this week on Deemable Tech. If you&#8217;re listening to Deemable Tech on the&#160;website, <a href="/2015/08/95-murder-she-robot/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/08/95-murder-she-robot/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/08/MurderSheRobot-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Murder She Robot" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="/media/2015/08/MurderSheRobot.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright wp-image-10206 size-medium" src="/media/2015/08/MurderSheRobot-300x225.jpg"  alt="Murder She Robot" width="300" height="225"></a>Murdered robots, silent video chat, drones being shot out of the sky, X-ray vision cameras and more Windows 10 news. All the tech news worth talking about this week on Deemable Tech.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on the&nbsp;website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you&rsquo;re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10195-19" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-07.mp3?_=19"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-07.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-07.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S RUNDOWN</h1>
<h3>Yahoo released Yahoo LiveText. No one is sure why.</h3>
<p>Yahoo announced a new app this week called Yahoo Livetext on <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/yahoo-livetext-video-messenger/id995121875?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yahoo.arrow&amp;hl=en" target="_blank">Android</a>. With the new app you can chat with people you know, while you look at them on a live video. What makes Livetext different than any other video chat app out there like Skype, Facetime or Google Hangouts is that you cannot hear the person on the other end. Don&rsquo;t worry, it&rsquo;s not your phone. Yahoo designed it like that? for some reason. We tried it out.</p>
<h3>Windows 10 Updates</h3>
<p>Windows 10 has been out for a week now and we&rsquo;ve learned a few more things about it.</p>
<p>Among other things, it turns out that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Finformation-technology%2F2015%2F08%2Fwindows-10-doesnt-offer-much-privacy-by-default-heres-how-to-fix-it%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFNt9WQE9YVYd_TzjZRUFFsmnVLWw">Windows 10 collects a </a><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Finformation-technology%2F2015%2F08%2Fwindows-10-doesnt-offer-much-privacy-by-default-heres-how-to-fix-it%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFNt9WQE9YVYd_TzjZRUFFsmnVLWw">lot</a><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Finformation-technology%2F2015%2F08%2Fwindows-10-doesnt-offer-much-privacy-by-default-heres-how-to-fix-it%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFNt9WQE9YVYd_TzjZRUFFsmnVLWw">&nbsp;more data on its users than previous version of the operating system did</a>. The main reason for this appears to be Cortana: the nifty digital personal assistant needs a lot more personal data to power her search results and voice recognition. Of course, that isn&rsquo;t to say that Microsoft isn&rsquo;t just taking a page from Google and Facebook here.</p>
<p>If you want to stop Windows 10 from&nbsp;gathering up your contacts, calendar details, text and touch input, location data, and a whole lot more and sending it off into the cloud, you will need to let Windows know. This can be done at installation: you&rsquo;ll need to select &lsquo;custom settings&rsquo; instead of &lsquo;express&rsquo; and then you will see the personalized settings for what data Windows will collect on you. If you&rsquo;ve already installed Windows 10, you can also limit the data it is phoning home by signing in with a strictly local account rather than a Microsoft one.</p>
<p>Cortana herself also has settings that you will need to adjust.</p>
<p>Needless to say, you may find Cortana to be less functional if you disable all of these options.</p>
<p>Another surprise in store for those upgrading to Windows 10: Windows Media Center, Microsoft&rsquo;s free media player which has for years allowed DVD playback in Windows, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.co.uk%2Fgadgets%2F2015%2F08%2Fmicrosoft-wants-you-to-pay-12-for-dvd-playback-in-windows-10%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGC5ZriS3JrOPrORaN7R8k4VcH_DA">will disappear</a>. Its replacement is an app in the Windows Store called Windows DVD Player, but this new app isn&rsquo;t free &ndash; it will cost you $14.99. Which is too bad, considering that it doesn&rsquo;t do any of the cool stuff Media Center used to do, like DVR, image slideshows, and media organization.</p>
<p>DVD playback isn&rsquo;t the only formerly free feature is holding its hand out for your credit card in Windows 10. Minesweeper and Solitaire, those old Windows standbys, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsweek.com%2Fsolitaire-microsoft-windows-10-pay-freemium-358366&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNG7YuZ0qsu9H-shQrfSe2N6LRCHUQ">are now full of intrusive ads unless you pay a $9.99 annual fee</a>. That&rsquo;s not so great.</p>
<p>You know what IS great? VLC media player! It&rsquo;s still free, it still plays DVDs, and it still works with Windows 10. We&rsquo;re just saying.</p>
<h3>More fun drone news</h3>
<p>The Daily Dot is reporting that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.dailydot.com%2Ftechnology%2Fkentucky-drone-shooting%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGjOlEq-0UIwu5nIrHki0Rnw55hBA">a Kentucky man blew a drone out of the sky with a shotgun</a>. He claims that his kids told him the drone had passed over the house multiple times before, and he claims that the drone dropped down to close to the ground and was hovering over his back deck where his 16-year-old daughter was sun bathing. He had enough at that point and fired duck shot knocking it out of the sky. When the drone pilot and three of his buddies showed up to collect the drone, the father told them,&nbsp;&ldquo;If you cross that sidewalk onto my property, there&rsquo;s going to be another shooting.&rdquo; Instead of doing that, they waited for the police to arrive and the father was arrested and charged with wanton endangerment and criminal mischief related to his firing the gun.</p>
<p>The drone owner has since released video to WDRB in Louisville showing <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wdrb.com%2Fstory%2F29670583%2Fupdate-drone-owner-disputes-shooters-story-produces-video-he-claims-shows-flight-path&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNH6Be_M9SpDhcvdKCB_mNz-QiUxdA">the drone was almost 200 feet above the ground</a>&nbsp;and it moving when it was shot. The drone operator says he was heading to his friends house to shoot pictures for him at his request and was only passing by.</p>
<h3>When you shut down the newsstand, you don&rsquo;t sell newspapers</h3>
<p>Back in October 2014, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Ftech-policy%2F2014%2F10%2Fcountry-by-country-europe-falls-in-and-out-of-love-with-a-google-tax%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNE20zuj9MGEQ-Bm-lZSguRO7nfIDA">Spain decided to impose a levy on Google for using snippets of Spanish news articles</a>&nbsp;and linking to news articles in Google News. Google responded by almost immediately <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Ftech-policy%2F2014%2F12%2Fthe-predictable-result-of-spains-google-tax-no-more-google-news%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHyZZXOUa9yAL7EvaqU_zGriVZQ6w">removing all Spanish news outlets from Google News</a>.</p>
<p>A report commissioned by the Asociacio?n Espan?ola de Editoriales de Publicaciones Perio?dicas (Spanish Association of Publishers of Periodicals) came out last week showing that Spains little experiment is working? for no one.</p>
<p>The study showed that in the short term, the law will cost publishers about ?10 million or about $10.9 million. The cost will fall especially on smaller news outlets who disproportionately are getting less traffic since Google News went dark in Spain.</p>
<h2>Fujifilm camera sees through clothes</h2>
<p>Fujifilm has announced a new camera called the X-T1 IR which boasts a 16 megapixel sensor, high speed autofocus, and wifi connectivity. Oh yeah, and <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wired.com%2F2015%2F08%2Ffujifilm-x-t1-infrared%2F%3Fmbid%3Dsocial_twitter&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGytZDHQFzB7hfzooshAYk37R-lcw">according to a new Wired report, it may be able to see through some clothes</a>. That&rsquo;s right, the &ldquo;IR&rdquo; in X-T1 IR stands for &lsquo;infrared&rsquo;. Infrared photography allows would-be shutterbugs to capture some trippy and dreamlike images and helps specialists like crime-scene techs locate blood spatter. But it can also allow pervs with cameras to get an eyeful, given the right conditions. Specifically, the clothing in question would have to be pretty thin in the first place for these cameras to see through it.</p>
<p>Hopefully dweebs hanging around the girls&rsquo; locker room will be priced out of the market: the cameras will start at $1700 when they go on sale in October.</p>
<p><span style="overflow: hidden; display: inline-block; margin: 0.00px 0.00px; border: 0.00px solid #000000; transform: rotate(0.00rad) translateZ(0px); -webkit-transform: rotate(0.00rad) translateZ(0px);"><img style="margin-left: 0.00px; margin-top: 0.00px; transform: rotate(0.00rad) translateZ(0px); -webkit-transform: rotate(0.00rad) translateZ(0px);" title="" src="/media/2015/08/Script-08-07-2015-95-.jpg" alt=""></span></p>
<h3>Macs get malware too</h3>
<p>Wired is reporting that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wired.com%2F2015%2F08%2Fresearchers-create-first-firmware-worm-attacks-macs%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFrxxSQq7hhSMoXNqtt_Sc0GmlTQw">the first firmware worm for Mac</a>&nbsp;has been developed. The worm dubbed &ldquo;Thunderstrike 2&rdquo; is a proof-of-concept. (The original Thunderstrike did the same thing, but required physical access to the computer) The worm can spread from Mac to Mac without it needing to be networked. Even air-gapped Apple computers would be vulnerable to the attack. Since it is a firmware worm, the processor chip would have to be reflashed to eliminate the worm, and since these are Macs we are talking about, this basically means they would have to be thrown away, because who can work on Macs, amirite?</p>
<p>Fortunately, the worm was created by hackers who are discussing their findings at the Black Hat Conference this week in Las Vegas, so manufacturers like Apple will be able to use their research to improve the security of firmware.</p>
<h3>The mysterious murder of HitchBot in the city of brotherly love</h3>
<p>Our next story is something of an unfolding saga.</p>
<p>A year ago, a team of Canadian researchers created a small robot which they dubbed HitchBot. HitchBot was completely immobile, but it could interact with people. It&rsquo;s mission was to hitchhike from place to place. In 2014 it successfully hitched all the way across Canada. Later it made a similar journey through Germany and the Netherlands. On July 17th of this year, HitchBot set out for its biggest road trip yet: crossing the US, starting in Massachusetts and hopefully winding up in San Francisco&rsquo;s Exploratorium. Sadly, the little bot that could had only made it to the city of Philadelphia <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Fthe-multiverse%2F2015%2F08%2Frobot-depending-on-kindness-of-strangers-meets-its-demise-in-philadelphia%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEa1ajU5izrdTqNMgedD4S1ALBs9w">when tragedy struck</a>.</p>
<p>The precise details aren&rsquo;t known, but HitchBot was found dismembered, its limbs strewn across the street and its internal wiring damaged or scooped out. Although HitchBot reportedly takes a picture every ten minutes or so of its currently location, no picture was taken of its assailant.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.crossingbroad.com%2F2015%2F08%2Fhitchbot-was-actually-destroyed-but-surveillance-video-was-dumb-youtube-prank.html&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFzmmF_VQeqoCONKkbdvA-Zwpw7vw">This is where things get a little weird</a>: two Philly-based YouTubers were reportedly the last people who the bot &lsquo;hitched&rsquo; a ride with before it was destroyed. They then came forward claiming to have obtained surveillance footage from a nearby camera showing the attacker. The footage they delivered appeared to show one of the YouTubers kicking and stomping on an obscured object and waving what looked like HitchBot&rsquo;s limbs around. After some initial confusion, the YouTubers said this was a prank and that they in fact had nothing to do with HitchBot&rsquo;s demise.</p>
<p>There are still some good Samaritans in the City of Brotherly Love. Hackers from a local makerspace <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Fthe-multiverse%2F2015%2F08%2Fwe-can-rebuild-him-philadelphia-hackers-offer-brotherly-love-to-fallen-robot%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFq41VBrFc4VLE5sHarrsmnXrWiDg">offered to rebuild HitchBot</a>. However, the bot&rsquo;s original creators intend to rebuild it themselves better than before, so that it will be ready for its next big trip. The predicted starting point? Philadelphia.</p>
<hr><p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/08/95-murder-she-robot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-07.mp3" length="30825089" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#94 Windows 10 Is Out But We’re Still Sticking With Windows 9</title>
		<link>/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/</link>
		<comments>/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 22:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiat Chrysler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Firefox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet.org]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smart Guns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stephen Hawking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Wozniak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10183</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/Windows10cropped-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="So much for Windows 10 fun. Now Ray has to reinstall Windows 8.1 just so he can upgrade it to 10, so he can reinstall Windows 10!" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Killer robots, self-aware robots, cars, guns and Android phones getting hacked into and the death of another Google product? Yeah, that sounds like a typical Deemable Tech episode. If you?re listening to Deemable Tech on the&#160;website, make sure to&#160;subscribe to <a href="/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/Windows10cropped-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="So much for Windows 10 fun. Now Ray has to reinstall Windows 8.1 just so he can upgrade it to 10, so he can reinstall Windows 10!" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_10185" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10185" src="/media/2015/07/Windows10cropped-300x212.jpg" alt="So much for Windows 10 fun. Now Ray has to reinstall Windows 8.1 just so he can upgrade it to 10, so he can reinstall Windows 10!" width="300" height="212"><p class="wp-caption-text">So much for Windows 10 fun. Now Ray has to reinstall Windows 8.1 just so he can upgrade it to 10, so he can reinstall Windows 10!</p></div>
<p>Killer robots, self-aware robots, cars, guns and Android phones getting hacked into and the death of another Google product? Yeah, that sounds like a typical Deemable Tech episode.</p>
<p>If you?re listening to Deemable Tech on the&nbsp;website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you?re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there. We?re also looking for a new admin to help manage and moderate our subreddit page. Submit a text post to our subreddit explaining why you would make a great admin.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10183-20" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-31.mp3?_=20"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-31.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-31.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK?S RUNDOWN</h1>
<h3><strong>Windows 10 is released.</strong></h3>
<p>Our top story this week is the long-awaited release of Microsoft?s Windows 10. In an unprecedented move, Microsoft has made the new Windows available as a free upgrade to anyone who had Windows 7, 8 or 8.1. The upgrade became available to download for most of those folks starting on Wednesday.</p>
<p>With Windows 10, Microsoft hopes to reunite its fractured userbase, many of whom are still stuck way back on Windows XP. Windows 10 will feature continuous upgrades and may be the last major windows version for the foreseeable future. To lure back customers scared off by the controversial Windows 8, Windows 10 brings back the Start Button and does away with the charms menu.</p>
<p>Other new features include the integration of Microsoft?s Siri-like virtual assistant Cortana, the brand new Edge web browser, virtual desktops, and Mission Control, which gives you an overview of all the apps you have running.</p>
<p>Ray Hollister has bravely volunteered to install Windows the 10th on the dual boot partition of his MacBook, so let?s dive right in.</p>
<p>The beauty of Windows 10 is that you can&rsquo;t install Windows 10 as a fresh, clean install. Except you can. But you can&rsquo;t.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/antonyleather/2015/07/30/windows-10-updating-reinstalling-and-activation-guide-essential-advice-to-avoid-problems/">Forbes &ndash; Windows 10 Updating, Reinstalling And Activation Guide: Essential Advice To Avoid Problems</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/29/9058825/windows-10-macbook-how-to-install-osx">The Verge &ndash; How to get Windows 10 on your Mac</a></p>
<h3><strong>CEO of Mozilla Firefox complains in an open letter that Windows 10 upgrade resets default web browser</strong></h3>
<p>Mozilla CEO Chris Beard is one person who is less than pleased with Windows 10. It appears that when you do an upgrade with ?Express Settings? that <a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2015/07/windows-10-upgrade-resets-your-default-browser-to-edge-mozilla-is-very-unhappy/">it will default your browser to Microsoft?s Edge browser</a>, even if you had Firefox selected by default before. Even worse, in Windows 10 the default browser is now buried down in the settings control panel, meaning that it is difficult to find for non-technical users. Microsoft defends the changes as making the upgrade ?simple and cohesive? for users and says that they may make ?improvements? in the future.</p>
<h3><strong>Facebook builds an Internet drone</strong></h3>
<p>The BBC is reporting that <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-33728704">Facebook has built a drone</a>, with the wingspan of a Boeing 737 that will fly as high as 90,000 feet and for up to 90 days at a time to provide wireless Internet access at up to 10 Gigabits per second.</p>
<p>The drone will communicate via a laser beam that can hit a target the size of a dime more than 10 miles away. The lasers will connect the drones together and to the ground.</p>
<p>This is part of Facebook&rsquo;s Internet.org project to bring Internet access to the developing world. No word on whether this will be like Internet.org&rsquo;s last launch which only included access to a few sites, which caused a bit of a backlash since the access gave an unfair advantage to those sites.</p>
<p>Facebook will be testing the drones later this year in the United States.</p>
<h3><strong>Google+ dies a slow and painful death</strong></h3>
<p>Google?s ill-fated Facebook competitor, Google+, courted a lot of controversy in 2013 when Google started requiring users to create a Google+ profile to comment on YouTube. This week on the official Google blog, <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2015/07/everything-in-its-right-place.html">the search giant announced that they would be hitting the ?undo? button on that policy</a>. They said that a Google account would be all you need to share content, create contacts, comment on YouTube, and more, across all of Google. This change will reportedly be rolled out ?in the coming months.? This announcement comes on the heels of Google splitting Google+ in two, with Google Photos becoming its own stand-alone service and app.</p>
<h3><strong>Killer Robots</strong></h3>
<p>I posted this on our Facebook page, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Deemable">facebook.com/Deemable</a>, but it bears repeating. As a general rule, everyone here at Deemable Tech is anti-killer robots.</p>
<p>Unless, as I said, the uprising has already happened, in which case, let me rephrase that: How may we serve you, robot masters?</p>
<p>I bring this all up because Elon Musk (you know, Iron Man, the guy who brought you PayPal, Tesla, SpaceX, the Hyperloop, and who plans to die on Mars) and Steve Wozniak, (the reason why you have a computer at your desk, smartphone in your pocket and ultimately why you&rsquo;re listening to this podcast) and Stephen Hawking (who you&rsquo;ll know as the guy who played poker with Data, Albert Einstein and Isaac Newton.) and have joined a letter calling for the banning of autonomous weapons.</p>
<p>We talked about a weaponized drone last week that had a gun attached to it, well imagine an autonomous drone with a gun. The icons aren&rsquo;t as concerned about them throwing a revolution and killing humanity as they are concerned about another cold war arms race where every country tries to build bigger, better faster killing machines. But considering a <a href="http://www.slashgear.com/nao-robot-becomes-self-aware-very-briefly-20393569/">robot recently demonstrated self awareness</a>, perhaps they should be concerned about a robot uprising too.</p>
<h3><strong>Hacking Smart Rifles</strong></h3>
<p>Speaking of things that shouldn&rsquo;t be connected to the Internet, like killer robots. As much as I love my connected light bulbs, switches and thermostat, The Internet of things is not necessarily a good thing. Not everything should be connected to the Internet. Case in point, smart guns. In case you didn&rsquo;t know, <a href="http://tracking-point.com/">TrackingPoint makes an smart rifle</a> that almost anyone can use to hit a bullseye up to a mile away. The gun, which sells for $13,000, has a computer screen for a scope where you can enter wind speed, ammunition weight and distance. The computer calculates the correct aim and after you pull the trigger, it waits until you have the shot lined up perfectly before firing the gun.</p>
<p>The Mirror is reporting that a couple of <a href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/technology-science/technology/hackers-force-gun-blast-wrong-6171684">married hackers have hacked the gun wirelessly to shoot 2.5 feet away from the intended target</a>. They also managed to get it to disable the firing pin, making the gun unable to fire.</p>
<h3><strong>Android hack</strong></h3>
<p>Speaking of hacks, <a href="http://news.wjct.org/post/major-flaw-android-phones-would-let-hackers-just-text">NPR is reporting that the security firm Zimperium says there&rsquo;s a &ldquo;gaping hole&rdquo; in Android</a> that would allow hackers to take over your phone, and all they need is your phone number.</p>
<p>The app Hangouts automatically processes videos when they are received by text message. So, all a hacker has to do is send a video with malware inside it and send it to your phone. Since Hangouts instantly processes the videos, there&rsquo;s nothing you can do to stop it.</p>
<p>Google has released a patch and manufacturers have been notified, but we&rsquo;ll see how long it takes for them to get the update sent out to users.</p>
<h3><strong>Fiat Chrysler follow-up</strong></h3>
<p>Last week we reported that if you had a Jeep Cherokee with Fiat Chrysler?s ?uConnect? system, hackers could remotely take control of your vehicle and destroy everyone that you hold dear. It turns out that this was a source of some concern to Chrysler Fiat, as they have issued an official recall for 1.4 million vehicles to patch the issue. Affected models include certain Dodge Rams, Dodge Vipers, Dodge Chargers, Dodge Challengers, Chrysler 200s and 300s, and of course Jeep Grand Cherokees, all model year 2013 or later. If you are driving one of those vehicles you should check to see if your specific model is affected. The recall does not actually require the vehicles to be taken to the dealer: affected owners will receive a USB device which can be used to load the patch into their uConnect systems.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/07/gadget-hacks-gm-cars-locate-unlock-start/"><strong>Wired &ndash; This Gadget Hacks GM Cars to Locate, Unlock, and Start Them</strong></a></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-31.mp3" length="38005829" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ask Deemable Tech: Keyboard Shortcuts</title>
		<link>/2015/07/ask-deemable-tech-keyboard-shortcuts/</link>
		<comments>/2015/07/ask-deemable-tech-keyboard-shortcuts/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hotkeys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keyboard Shortcuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shortcuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10174</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/02/Logitech_K750-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Logitech Wireless Solar Keyboard K750" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Dale writes, &#8220;My son-in-law was helping me with some computer stuff and he showed me a trick where I could see all the windows I have open on my computer at once and switch between them. The problem is, I <a href="/2015/07/ask-deemable-tech-keyboard-shortcuts/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/07/ask-deemable-tech-keyboard-shortcuts/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/02/Logitech_K750-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Logitech Wireless Solar Keyboard K750" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><em><strong>Dale writes, &ldquo;My son-in-law was helping me with some computer stuff and he showed me a trick where I could see all the windows I have open on my computer at once and switch between them. The problem is, I have forgotten how he did it, and I don?t want to keep bothering him. So I thought I&rsquo;d bother you guys instead!&rdquo;</strong></em></p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10174-21" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/adt_20150730_keyboard_shortcuts.mp3?_=21"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/adt_20150730_keyboard_shortcuts.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/adt_20150730_keyboard_shortcuts.mp3</a></audio><p><span id="more-10174"></span></p>
<p>No problem, Dale, that&rsquo;s what we&rsquo;re here for!</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-4956" src="/media/2012/02/Logitech_K750-300x165.jpg" alt="Logitech Wireless Solar Keyboard K750" width="300" height="165">As far as your question goes, we&rsquo;re pretty sure that the &ldquo;trick&rdquo; you are looking for is holding down the ALT and TAB keys on your keyboard at the same time. In Windows 8, that brings up a view of all the windows you currently have open. If you keep holding ALT and start pressing TAB, you can switch from window to window. When you get to the one you want to select, just let go of the ALT key and boom, there you go.</p>
<p>ALT-TAB is one of many keyboard shortcuts that we think are essential to know when using Windows. A shortcut &mdash; or hotkey, as they are sometimes called &mdash; is a combination of key presses that triggers a command. They unusually involve holding down two keys at once, like pressing CTRL and C to copy, or&nbsp;CTRL and V to paste. Shortcuts can save you a lot of time by condensing everyday tasks that usually require several clicks of the mouse into one press of the keys.</p>
<p>Here are some of our favorite keyboard shortcuts for Windows and Mac.</p>
<p><strong>Windows</strong></p>
<ul><li>Alt + Tab &ndash; Cycle through open windows/programs</li>
<li>Windows key + D &ndash; Display desktop</li>
<li>Windows key + E &ndash; Open new Windows Explorer window</li>
<li>Windows key + F &ndash; Open Windows search window</li>
<li>Windows key + down arrow &ndash; Minimize window</li>
<li>Windows key + up arrow &ndash; Maximize window</li>
<li>Windows key + X &ndash; Open Quick Access Menu</li>
<li>Windows key + plus or minus sign &ndash; Zoom in or zoom out</li>
<li>Windows key + L &ndash; Lock computer or switch user</li>
<li>Ctrl + Shift + Esc &ndash; Open Task Manager</li>
<li>Ctrl + W &ndash; Close window</li>
<li>Ctrl + C &ndash; Copy selected item or text</li>
<li>Ctrl + X &ndash; Cut selected item or text</li>
<li>Ctr l+ V &ndash; Paste selected copied item or text</li>
<li>Ctrl + P &ndash; Print</li>
<li>Ctrl + A &ndash; Select everything</li>
<li>Ctrl + Z &ndash; Undo</li>
<li>Ctrl + Y &ndash; Redo</li>
</ul><p><strong>Mac</strong></p>
<ul><li>Command + Tab &ndash; Cycle through open windows/applications</li>
<li>Command + Q &ndash; Quit open application</li>
<li>Command + W &ndash; Close active window</li>
<li>Command + C &ndash; Copy selected item or text</li>
<li>Command + X &ndash; Cut Selected item or text</li>
<li>Command + V &ndash; Paste copie item or text</li>
<li>Command + F3 &ndash; Show desktop</li>
<li>Command + Alt + Esc &ndash; Force quit application</li>
<li>Command + Option + Control + Esc &ndash; Shut down computer</li>
<li>Command + Alt + Eject button &ndash; Put computer to sleep</li>
<li>Ctrl + D &ndash; Delete</li>
</ul><p>&nbsp;</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/07/ask-deemable-tech-keyboard-shortcuts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/adt_20150730_keyboard_shortcuts.mp3" length="3297251" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#93 Bro, You&#8217;ve Been Hacked</title>
		<link>/2015/07/93-bro-youve-been-hacked/</link>
		<comments>/2015/07/93-bro-youve-been-hacked/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 20:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ashley Madison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hackers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nest Thermostat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10169</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/ashleymadison-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Ashley Madison" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week Ray, Tom and Sean discuss the hacking of the adultery-centric site Ashley Madison, drones causing problems for California firefighters, and security flaws in Jeep Cherokees. That and more on this episode of the Deemable Tech podcast. If you&#8217;re <a href="/2015/07/93-bro-youve-been-hacked/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/07/93-bro-youve-been-hacked/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/ashleymadison-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Ashley Madison" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week Ray, Tom and Sean discuss the hacking of the adultery-centric site Ashley Madison, drones causing problems for California firefighters, and security flaws in Jeep Cherokees. That and more on this episode of the Deemable Tech podcast.<span id="more-10169"></span></p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on our website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you&rsquo;re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there. We&rsquo;re also looking for a new admin to help manage and moderate our subreddit page. Submit a text post to our subreddit explaining why you would make a great admin.</p>
<p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable&nbsp;dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10169-22" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-24.mp3?_=22"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-24.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-24.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S RUNDOWN</h1>
<h3></h3>
<h3><b>Ashley Madison gets hacked</b></h3>
<p>Last week, hackers targeted AshleyMadison.com, an online dating site for married people looking to have an affair, and&nbsp;<a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2015/07/cheaters-hook-up-site-ashley-madison-makes-account-deletion-confusing/" target="_blank">claimed to have&nbsp;downloaded its complete database of 37 million user profiles</a>. The hackers, who call themselves The Impact Team, are threatening to release all the profiles publicly unless Avid Life Media, the company that owns Ashley Madison, shutters the site permanently along with sister site EstablishedMen.com.</p>
<div id="attachment_10170" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/media/2015/07/ashleymadison.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10170" src="/media/2015/07/ashleymadison-300x169.jpg"  alt="Image credit: Ashley Madison" width="300" height="169"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: Ashley Madison</p></div>
<p>The hackers also take issue with Ashley Madison&rsquo;s paid &ldquo;full delete,&rdquo; where the site charges users $19 to full erase their profile. The hackers claim that Ashley Madison does not in fact purge all of their records from their database, even after a full delete has been paid for.</p>
<p>Strangely, as of this podcast, the hackers have released only two of the 37 million profiles. One belongs to a man in Brockton, Massachusetts, the other to a man in Mississauga, Ontario, in Canada.</p>
<h3><b>Stupid, stupid drones</b></h3>
<p><a href="http://gizmodo.com/firefighters-cant-save-people-burning-in-cars-because-o-1718675039?rev=1437224396454" target="_blank">Drones prevent firefighters from putting out a fire on the 15 Freeway in Southern California&rsquo;s Cajon Pass</a>. Cars were stopped on the 15 because of a wildfire and several caught fire. Firefighters were unable to get water to the cars because five drones were hovering over the site. Apparently this has been an ongoing issue with the wildfire that is so bad it&rsquo;s been given a name, North Fire.</p>
<p>Drone operators have been flying around while firefighter helicopters have been trying to do their job. This particular incident was so bad, several people were severely burned, and twenty vehicles were completely destroyed. Two of the drones even pursued the helicopter.</p>
<p>In equally stupid drone news, an 18-year-old decided to attach a gun to a drone and fire the gun. He probably would have been fine if he hadn&rsquo;t also decided to <a href="http://gizmodo.com/the-feds-are-investigating-a-teen-who-weaponized-a-quad-1719265092" target="_blank">video record it and post the video to YouTube</a>. The FAA is investigating the case to see if any federal laws were broken.</p>
<p>This isn&rsquo;t the first time someone has weaponized a drone. In 2013 a company that creates screen protection built a drone, attached a gun to the gimble and shot some video of the <a href="http://io9.com/this-video-of-a-drone-with-a-gun-will-freak-you-the-hel-513442074" target="_blank">Skynet-esque monstrosity shooting soda bottles</a> and cans, and a Samsung Galaxy.</p>
<h3><b>Hackers demonstrate exploit that allows them to remotely control Jeep Cherokee</b></h3>
<p>Wired reports that white hat hackers Charlie Miller and Chris Valasek <a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/07/hackers-remotely-kill-jeep-highway/">were able to take control of a Jeep Cherokee using the Chrysler Uconnect system installed in the vehicle</a>. The hackers performed their exploit remotely while Wired&rsquo;s journalist was inside. The hacker&rsquo;s code reportedly allows them to control the AC, change the volume of the stereo, control the transmission, disable the brakes, and kill the engine.</p>
<p>The hack comes just as senators Ed Markey and Richard Blumenthal are introducing new legislation that will mandate digital security standards for cars and trucks.</p>
<h3><b>Apple kicks Nest out of bed</b></h3>
<p>Re/Code is reporting that the <a href="http://recode.net/2015/07/23/apple-kicks-nest-thermostats-from-its-shelves-for-now/">Apple Store no longer carries the Nest Thermostat, Nest Protect or Nest Cam</a> online or in its retail stores.</p>
<p>This all happens of course after Google bought Nest last year, and Apple is about to launch the first of its HomeKit automation enabled products. No surprise, around the same time as the Nest Thermostat was taken off the shelves, the Ecobee 3, a wireless thermostat that does work with HomeKit quickly took its place.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, none of this is terribly surprising. Apple sold tons of fitness bands like the Jawbone Up and the Nike FuelBand&hellip; right up until they launched the Apple Watch when they quickly dumped the products off their shelves.</p>
<p>This could be a sign that Nest won&rsquo;t support HomeKit. Which is sad for iPhone users who were looking forward to the day when we could tell Siri to turn the temperature down, like their&nbsp;Android friends can do with Google Now.</p>
<p>&mdash;</p>
<p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable&nbsp;dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/07/93-bro-youve-been-hacked/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-24.mp3" length="30463550" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#92 Still A Better Deal Than Amazon Prime Day</title>
		<link>/2015/07/92-still-a-better-deal-than-amazon-prime-day/</link>
		<comments>/2015/07/92-still-a-better-deal-than-amazon-prime-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 23:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe Flash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Black Friday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hacking Team]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Horizons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pluto]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10150</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/PrimeDayFail-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="#PrimeDayFail" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week Ray, Tom and Sean discuss the train wreck that was Amazon&#8217;s Prime Day, the loss of Nintendo&#8217;s Saturo Iwata and New Horizon&#8217;s historic visit to Pluto. If you&#8217;re listening to Deemable Tech on our website, make sure to&#160;subscribe <a href="/2015/07/92-still-a-better-deal-than-amazon-prime-day/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/07/92-still-a-better-deal-than-amazon-prime-day/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/PrimeDayFail-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="#PrimeDayFail" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-10152" src="/media/2015/07/PrimeDayFail-300x300.jpg" alt="#PrimeDayFail" width="300" height="300">This week Ray, Tom and Sean discuss the train wreck that was Amazon&rsquo;s Prime Day, the loss of Nintendo&rsquo;s Saturo Iwata and New Horizon&rsquo;s historic visit to Pluto.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on our website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you&rsquo;re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there. We&rsquo;re also looking for a new admin to help manage and moderate our subreddit page. Submit a text post to our subreddit explaining why you would make a great admin.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10150-23" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-17.mp3?_=23"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-17.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-17.mp3</a></audio><p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable&nbsp;dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there.</p>
<h3>New Horizons flies by Pluto</h3>
<p>Space has been in the news this week. The spacecraft New Horizons, which launched in 2006, ventured closer to the dwarf planet Pluto than any other man-made object has ever been, 7,800 miles from the surface of Pluto. And the best part is, it took pictures! New Horizons has already sent back a handful of high resolution images of Pluto and its moons and more are expected to follow. New Horizons? journey is not over yet, as it is scheduled to continue on out into the largely unexplored Kuiper Belt.</p>
<h3>#PrimeDayFail</h3>
<p>Amazon held their much-hyped Prime Day event this week to celebrate their 20th anniversary.</p>
<p>Described as a summertime Black Friday for customers with Amazon Prime accounts, the company promised great deals on hot items all throughout the day on Wednesday. And depending on who you are and what you were looking to buy, this was true.</p>
<p>It was certainly a success for Amazon, who reported that sales were up 80 percent on Prime Day. They also most likely saw a jump in Amazon Prime subscriptions, since you had to be a member to get the deals.</p>
<p>The overwhelming reaction on social media, though, was ?meh.? Disgruntled shoppers quickly took to Twitter and Facebook with the hashtag #primedayfail to voice their complaints about what they saw as Amazon?s failure to deliver on all of their hype. Reactions ranged from disappoint with the selection of sale items (some described it as being like a bad garage sale full of weird stuff), underwhelming prices, and frustration over limited quantities for items they actually wanted.</p>
<p><a href="http://gizmodo.com/the-shittiest-deals-of-amazon-prime-day-1717984690">Gizmodo&rsquo;s List of Prime Day Fails</a></p>
<h3><b>Nintendo President &amp; CEO Saturo Iwata</b></h3>
<p>Nintendo president Satoru Iwata passed Saturday July 11th at the age of 55 after an almost year-long struggle with cancer.</p>
<p>For those of you who aren&rsquo;t familiar with Iwata-san, early in his career he helped develop or worked on the Mario, Legend of Zelda, Pok&eacute;mon, Super Smash Bros., Animal Crossing and Kirby series.</p>
<p>Iwata was promoted to president of Nintendo in 2003 and became CEO of Nintendo of America in 2013. Iwata took over Nintendo when it was struggling from poor sales of the GameCube, and brought the highly successful Wii and Nintendo DS to market. He was uniquely the first Nintendo president that was not related to the Yamauchi family since its founding.</p>
<p>Iwata was a very charismatic business leader that reached out to the community. He started an interview series on the Nintendo website called &ldquo;<a href="http://iwataasks.nintendo.com/">Iwata Asks</a>&rdquo; where he discussed games with the developers and gave gamers a behind-the-scene view of the process.</p>
<p>He famously said at the Game Developers Conference in 2005, &ldquo;On my business card, I am a corporate president. In my mind, I am a game developer. But in my heart, I am a gamer.&rdquo;</p>
<p>There have been tons of memorials to Iwata on the Internet since his passing, one of my favorites was Mashable&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="http://mashable.com/2015/07/13/games-iwata-memorial/">5 games you can play to honor late Nintendo President Satoru Iwata</a>&rdquo;</p>
<h3>Hacking Team Gets Hacked</h3>
<p>Secretive cybersecurity firm Hacking Team has long courted controversy for selling advanced cyber surveillance tools to governments with a less-than-spotless record on human rights. Well, two weeks ago they were&nbsp;hacked. Massively. An unknown hacker going by the pseudonym of Phineas Fisher <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2015/07/09/how-spyware-peddler-hacking-team-was-publicly-dismantled/">broke into the company?s systems and dumped over 400 GB of the company?s data</a>, including invoices, code for software, and software exploits it had paid for known as ?zero day exploits?, and posted it using the company?s own Twitter feed. Most controversially, the documents show that Hacking Team was doing business with Azerbaijan, Kazakhstan, Uzbekistan, Russia, Bahrain, Saudi Arabia, Ethiopia, and the UAE, many of whom have been criticized by international human rights organizations for their aggressive surveillance of citizens, activists and journalists both domestically and overseas. Even Sudan, with whom Hacking Team had denied connections, was shown to be a recent client. These countries didn?t just use Hacking Team?s software, they often called upon Hacking Team?s specialized services to go after specific ?high value targets?, including journalists.</p>
<p>At this time Hacking Team has officially requested that its clients <a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/read/hacking-team-asks-customers-to-stop-using-its-software-after-hack">immediately cease use of all of its tools and software</a>. This is slightly odd as leaked documents show that the company claims to have the ability to shut its own software down remotely.</p>
<p>The Hacking Team dump has also had some consequences for the larger software industry. The company had purchased a number of what are called ?zero-day exploits?, which are unpatched, undiscovered software vulnerabilities that can be used by hackers to infiltrate software or systems. Three major zero-day exploits were discovered for Flash, which Adobe had not known about and has been scrambling to patch. The fact that this company had access to loopholes in such a major, widespread piece of software is reason for concern.</p>
<p>Also, it is just one more reason that everyone should stop using Flash.</p>
<h3>Firefox Axes Flash</h3>
<p>Speaking of Flash. Computerworld is reporting that partly as a result of these new and really bad vulnerabilities, <a href="http://www.computerworld.com/article/2948012/security/adobe-flash-must-die-firefox-facebook-itbwcw.html">Mozilla Firefox has taken the unusual step of blocking Flash</a> until it is completely patched. Alex Stamos, the chief of security for Facebook, has called on Adobe to announce an end-of-life date for Flash.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/07/92-still-a-better-deal-than-amazon-prime-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-17.mp3" length="23655608" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ask Deemable Tech: How Can I Safely Shop Online?</title>
		<link>/2015/07/ask-deemable-tech-how-can-i-safely-shop-online/</link>
		<comments>/2015/07/ask-deemable-tech-how-can-i-safely-shop-online/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 12:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Credit Cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hackers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passwords]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10146</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/credit_cards_flickr-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Sean MacEntee / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Andrew writes, &#8220;It seems like every week there&#8217;s another scary news story about a big bank or a major company getting hacked. Is there any way to safely shop online, or should I just stay off the internet altogether?&#8221; You&#8217;re <a href="/2015/07/ask-deemable-tech-how-can-i-safely-shop-online/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/07/ask-deemable-tech-how-can-i-safely-shop-online/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/credit_cards_flickr-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Sean MacEntee / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><em><strong>Andrew writes, &ldquo;It seems like every week there&rsquo;s another scary news story about a big bank or a major company getting hacked. Is there any way to safely shop online, or should I just stay off the internet altogether?&rdquo;</strong></em></p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10146-24" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/adt_20150716_shop_safely_online.mp3?_=24"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/adt_20150716_shop_safely_online.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/adt_20150716_shop_safely_online.mp3</a></audio><p><span id="more-10146"></span></p>
<p>You&rsquo;re right, Andrew, there have been a few pretty severe hacks of some large corporations recently. Unfortunately, we probably haven&rsquo;t seen the last of them. But here&rsquo;s the thing: staying off the internet probably won&rsquo;t help you at all.</p>
<div id="attachment_10159" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2015/07/credit_cards_flickr.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10159" src="/media/2015/07/credit_cards_flickr-300x169.jpg"  alt="Image credit: Sean MacEntee / Flickr" width="300" height="169"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: Sean MacEntee / Flickr</p></div>
<p>Most of the businesses that have been hacked lately were retail stores, and the people affected were those who had shopped in the stores&rsquo; brick and mortar locations, not online. Hackers found their way into the companies&rsquo; servers, and were able to skim credit card numbers as they were scanned into the database.</p>
<p>Banks similarly store your information in databases that are connected to the internet. While they take security precautions, those defenses are sometimes compromised by hacking groups that have become more organized and sophisticated.</p>
<p>You see, Andrew, you don&rsquo;t even have to be online for businesses or banks to store your information online.</p>
<p>All of this can understandably seem pretty scary. Luckily there are systems in place to protect you if your information is stolen. The Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or FDIC, says that customers can only be held responsible for a maximum of $50 for a fraudulent transaction, provided they report it to their bank or credit card company quickly. In fact, most credit card companies will rarely hold someone responsible for any fraudulent charges on their card, as long as they report those charges in a timely manner.</p>
<p>The trick is to keep an eye on your bank account and credit card statements. Be on the lookout for transactions you don&rsquo;t remember making. Remember, the sooner your report a fraudulent transaction, the more likely you are to get all of your money back.</p>
<p>It really is okay to shop online, just as long as you use some common sense. For example, only give your credit card information to reputable online retailers. And make sure you use good, unique passwords.&nbsp;<a href="/2013/05/greg-asks-how-can-i-have-strong-secure-passwords/" target="_blank">Like we&rsquo;ve said before</a>, long passwords of 15 characters or more are best. You should also avoid using easily guessable names or words for passwords. Have&nbsp;different passwords for different websites, especially the important ones like your bank, your favorite online store and your primary email account. We also recommend using a password manager like LastPass or DashLane.</p>
<p>Stay safe, and happy shopping!</p>
<p><em>Photo Credit: &ldquo;<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/smemon/12696032183" target="_blank">Credit Cards</a>&rdquo;&nbsp;by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/smemon/" target="_blank">Sean MacEntee</a>&nbsp;is used under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/" target="_blank">CC BY 2.0.</a></em></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/07/ask-deemable-tech-how-can-i-safely-shop-online/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/adt_20150716_shop_safely_online.mp3" length="3353129" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
