<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Motorola</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/motorola/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#105 The Rumor Mill</title>
		<link>/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/</link>
		<comments>/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 20:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NetFlix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10391</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/01/Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="That rumor mill&#039;s a-churning. Image credit: Wikimedia Commons" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week, Ray, Tom and Sean delve into rumors about the next iPhone as well as Twitter&#8217;s famous 140-character limit. Plus, the latest about the Oculus Rift, and the story of a man who found more than he bargained for <a href="/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/01/Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="That rumor mill&#039;s a-churning. Image credit: Wikimedia Commons" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_10394" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2016/01/Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10394" src="//media/2016/01/Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square-300x300.jpg"  alt="That rumor mill's a-churning. Image credit: Wikimedia Commons" width="300" height="300"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">That rumor mill&rsquo;s a-churning. Image credit: Wikimedia Commons</p></div>
<p>This week, Ray, Tom and Sean delve into rumors about the next iPhone as well as Twitter&rsquo;s famous 140-character limit. Plus, the latest about the Oculus Rift, and the story of a man who found more than he bargained for in his Amazon cart.</p>
<p><span id="more-10391"></span></p>
<p>By the way, we don&rsquo;t just have a subreddit page for the fame and the glory. We have it because we want to know what you want us to talk about! We know you&rsquo;re purusing the tech news all week.&nbsp;Go to our subreddit page, <a href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">reddit.com/r/deemable</a>, and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down.</p>
<p>And make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show and leave a review&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at&nbsp;<a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10391-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/01/DeemableTech_2016-01-14.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/01/DeemableTech_2016-01-14.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/01/DeemableTech_2016-01-14.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>Apple planning to remove headphone jack on the iPhone 7</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The rumor mill about the next iPhone is churning and this time it has come up with a doozy. In order to get the next version of the iPhone even slimmer, Apple is supposedly going to ditch the headphone jack. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These rumors actually started swirling about a month ago, but now </span><a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3055208/its-true-apple-will-drop-the-headphone-jack-to-make-the-iphone-7-slimmer-and-simpler" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fast Company has a new source which has confirmed them</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, along with adding new details: that the replacement will be a lightning jack with a headphone adaptor, or completely wireless EarPods.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fast Company also says that the next iPhone will employ a new noise-cancelling technology to improve sound quality. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Oculus Rift announces release date, final price</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The product that arguably has launched the current wave of excitement about virtual-reality-tech has finally gotten a price, and a date on which you will be able to buy it. That product, of course, is the Oculus Rift. The date? Sometime in March, assuming you pre-ordered, oh, last week. The price? $599.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/01/virtually-a-reality-oculus-rift-goes-on-sale/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Ars Technica</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, that scores you a cutting-edge VR headset, a head-tracking camera, an Xbox One controller, an Oculus remote, cables, a carrying case, and two games. That sounds pretty good, but note that it doesn&rsquo;t include the beefy high-end PC you&rsquo;ll need to plug your headset into.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If all you&rsquo;ve got at home right now is Sean Birch&rsquo;s Chromebook, expect to drop $1,500 to gain access to a high resolution universe of virtual wonder.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After two dev kits, which were priced at $300 and $350 respectively, and Oculus founder Palmer Lucky stating in an interview in October that the Rift would cost &ldquo;more than $350,&rdquo; many eager fans are experiencing sticker shock. They have taken to the internets to express their anger. </span><a href="http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/01/oculus-founder-apologizes-for-messaging-poorly-on-599-rift-price/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Outrage was so great that Palmer Lucky popped up on reddit to apologize for misleading people</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. That said, if you pre-order the Rift right now, you&rsquo;ll be lucky to get it by April, so clearly the high price has not been enough to discourage everyone.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Netflix gives customers socks for the holidays</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You probably remember the Netflix-and-chill button that Netflix recently released design specs for so DIY enthusiasts could build their own. Well the company has topped themselves with their latest DIY brainstorm &ndash; Netflix socks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you regularly binge watch so much that you fall asleep, Netflix socks are for you. These socks detect when you&rsquo;ve fallen asleep and send a pause signal to Netflix, so you won&rsquo;t miss a moment of Jessica Jones! You can check them out at </span><a href="https://makeit.netflix.com/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">makeit.netflix.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. There are even multiple snazzy templates for great Netflix-themed patterns! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just to be clear, you can&rsquo;t buy these &ndash; you have to make them! So get out your darning needles and soldering iron and get to work! If any Deemable Tech listeners are planning on building this or the Netflix button, we&rsquo;d love to see your work!</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Lenovo ditching the Motorola brand name, but keeping &ldquo;Moto&rdquo;</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Motorola was once a powerhouse in mobile phones, but it has been through a lot of changes lately. First it was purchased by Google, which launched the Moto X line of phones, and then it was sold to Lenovo. </span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/goodbye-moto-rola-iconic-brand-name-to-be-phased-out/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In an interview with Cnet this month</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> while at CES, Lenovo announced that it would begin phasing out the &ldquo;Motorola&rdquo; branding on its phones and replacing it with Lenovo branding. Lenovo will, however, be keeping the &ldquo;Moto&rdquo; name and the iconic &ldquo;batwing&rdquo; logo. So you can still say, &ldquo;Hello, Moto.&rdquo; But really, it is goodbye to Motorola as we know it.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Twitter to break the 140 character limit, probably for real this time</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are always endless rumors swirling that Twitter is about to increase its famous 140 character limit. And actually right now it looks like those rumors have some substance. </span></p>
<p><a href="http://recode.net/2016/01/05/twitter-considering-10000-character-limit-for-tweets/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to re/code</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, sources within the company say that tweets will still initially appear in your Twitter feed as 140 characters, but will then feature some kind of call to action which allows them to be expanded, showing up to 10,000 characters of text. This would be a pretty significant change for a company that has built its reputation on very brief messages. The same rumors also say that Twitter is experimenting with changing its reverse chronological timeline, another core feature from early days.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since Twitter went public in 2013 it has struggled to impress investors with steady growth. CEO Jack Dorsey and other company heads are definitely looking at radical changes to keep the social media giant relevant. </span></p>
<h3>IE is Dead, Long Live Edge&hellip; and IE</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Microsoft finally </span><a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/3021789/windows/microsoft-patch-tuesday-kills-off-windows-8-and-internet-explorer-8-9-and-10.html" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">buried Internet Explorers</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 8, 9 and 10. If you have one of them installed on your computer it will still work, but just like when Microsoft pulled the plug on Windows XP back in 2013, you won&rsquo;t receive any security updates anymore. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Speaking of operating systems, Windows killed another operating system this week. No, it wasn&rsquo;t Vista, it was Windows 8! If you&rsquo;re running Windows 8, you need to upgrade to 8.1 or 10, because you will no longer get bug fixes or security updates. Why did Microsoft skip Vista? Who knows, but our guess is that there is a very small user base running 8 compared to Vista. But the reaper is coming for Vista too. Vista will swim with the fishes in April 2017.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Customer finds unexpected dildo in his shopping cart after poor customer service experience at Amazon.de</h3>
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/01/amazon-customer-complains-finds-spiteful-10-inch-dildo-in-his-shopping-basket/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ars Technica reported on an unusual customer service snafu last week</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Not that customer service screw ups are unusual, but this one came from Amazon, typically known for their top notch customer service. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An IT contractor living in Ireland had ordered a textbook from Amazon.de, the Germany-based version of the site. Unfortunately he was shipped the wrong edition. After spending a great deal of time on the phone with a customer service rep, he was informed that the company did not have the right edition and they would only be able to credit him his money back.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Upset, the contractor left a negative review on a customer satisfaction survey.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A few days later he was browsing the site at work and noticed that there was something in his shopping basket. Not having added anything to the cart, he clicked to see what it was. At this point he discovered that a dildo known as &ldquo;The Hulk&rdquo; had been added to his basket. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since the contractor was at his job and was being observed by coworkers, including a woman, he was not pleased by this. He reports that he was able to get in touch with an executive at Amazon.de and had been credited with 100 euros for the incident. The company hinted that the dildo had been added to the contractor&rsquo;s basket by the customer service rep, but would not say if any steps had been taken to discipline the rep.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Image credit: Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill.jpg: Gabor Eszes (UED77)derivative work: WVhybrid at en.wikipedia (Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill.jpg) [<a href="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/fdl.html">GFDL</a> or <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA-3.0</a>], <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File%3AGlade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square.jpg">via Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#105 The Rumor Mill" data-link="/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#105 The Rumor Mill" data-link="/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/01/DeemableTech_2016-01-14.mp3" length="36476269" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Please stop announcing products that aren&#8217;t ready to launch. &#8211; Ray&#8217;s Rants</title>
		<link>/2012/09/please-stop-announcing-products-that-arent-ready-to-launch-rays-rants/</link>
		<comments>/2012/09/please-stop-announcing-products-that-arent-ready-to-launch-rays-rants/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 15:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ray's Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Droid RAZR HD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kobo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lumia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nokia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RAZR]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=5439</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/09/YUNOLaunchDate-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="MOTOROLA AND NOKIA Y U NO GIVE US LAUNCH DATE AND PRICES?" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Yesterday, both Nokia and Motorola announced their latest flagship phones, the Lumia 920 and the&#160;Droid RAZR HD&#160;respectively. Both of them seem like they will be quite impressive phones when they come out. The question that wasn&#8217;t answered at either of <a href="/2012/09/please-stop-announcing-products-that-arent-ready-to-launch-rays-rants/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2012/09/please-stop-announcing-products-that-arent-ready-to-launch-rays-rants/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/09/YUNOLaunchDate-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="MOTOROLA AND NOKIA Y U NO GIVE US LAUNCH DATE AND PRICES?" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2012/09/YUNOLaunchDate.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-5442 alignleft" title="MOTOROLA AND NOKIA Y U NO GIVE US LAUNCH DATE AND PRICES?" src="//media/2012/09/YUNOLaunchDate-300x225.jpg"  alt="" width="300" height="225"></a>Yesterday, both Nokia and Motorola announced their latest flagship phones, the <a title="Nokia unveils flagship Windows 8 smartphone Lumia 920 | Deemable Tech" href="http://deemable.com/2012/09/nokia-unveils-flagship-windows-8-smartphone/" target="_blank">Lumia 920</a> and the&nbsp;<a title="Motorola and Verizon announce the Droid RAZR HD | Android Central" href="http://www.androidcentral.com/motorola-and-verizon-announce-droid-razr-hd" target="_blank">Droid RAZR HD</a>&nbsp;respectively. Both of them seem like they will be quite impressive phones when they come out. The question that wasn&rsquo;t answered at either of these press conferences is, when are they being released?</p>
<p><a title="Kobo announces 7-inch Android tablet and two new e-readers ahead of Amazon's Kindle event" href="http://www.theverge.com/2012/9/6/3296243/kobo-arc-glo-mini-tablet-e-reader-announcement" target="_blank">Kobo did the same thing</a> today. They beat Amazon to the punch by announcing two new e-readers and a new 7-inch Android tablet hours before <a title="Live from Amazon's Kindle event at 1:30PM EDT / 6:30PM BST | The Verge" href="http://live.theverge.com/amazon-kindle-fire-paperwhite-reader-event-live/" target="_blank">Amazon&rsquo;s event scheduled for later today</a>. They didn&rsquo;t provide a specific launch date for the Arc, the Android tablet, but at least they gave us prices and told us what month it was&nbsp;coming out.</p>
<p>Why is it that Apple and Amazon seem to be&nbsp;the only companies able to wait until a product is ready to be sold before they announce it? Nothing, and I mean, <strong><em>NOTHING</em></strong>, is more excruciatingly frustrating as a consumer and a tech enthusiast than to listen to an entire announcement about an amazing product, only to be&nbsp;left hanging, waiting for the two most important details: when can I buy it, and how much does it cost?&nbsp;Does announcing a product before the company has even decided how much they are going to charge for it actually help to increase sales? I know that beating Apple out of the gate has to be&nbsp;good idea, but announcing a phone or tablet without a price or a launch date is like jumping the gun and then tripping and falling on your face. You&rsquo;re not going to win the race, even if you are a better runner.&nbsp;In my humble&nbsp;opinion, announcing a product before it is ready to be launched screams insecurity. Your company is saying that you really don&rsquo;t think you can compete head-to-head with another company&rsquo;s product, so you have to announce yours first, or you&rsquo;ll lose in the long run. That doesn&rsquo;t make me want to buy your product. That makes me want to kick you in the shins.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m done.</p>
<p>End rant.</p>
<p>###</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Please stop announcing products that aren't ready to launch. - Ray's Rants" data-link="/2012/09/please-stop-announcing-products-that-arent-ready-to-launch-rays-rants/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Please stop announcing products that aren't ready to launch. - Ray's Rants" data-link="/2012/09/please-stop-announcing-products-that-arent-ready-to-launch-rays-rants/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2012/09/please-stop-announcing-products-that-arent-ready-to-launch-rays-rants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
