<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; JaxComputerChic</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/jaxcomputerchic/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#56 Deemable Tech Meets Marie &#8220;Hot Lips&#8221; Curie</title>
		<link>/2013/12/56-deemable-tech-meets-marie-hot-lips-curie/</link>
		<comments>/2013/12/56-deemable-tech-meets-marie-hot-lips-curie/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 15:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Does Not Compute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JaxComputerChic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8480</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/12/Pierre_and_Marie_Curie-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Pierre_and_Marie_Curie" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week Tom and guest co-host Jax Computer Chic&#8217;s Elizabeth Pampalone are joined by producer Sean Birch to congratulate Ray on his new child! Then they discuss what you can do if you&#8217;re being bullied on Facebook, play a round <a href="/2013/12/56-deemable-tech-meets-marie-hot-lips-curie/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/12/56-deemable-tech-meets-marie-hot-lips-curie/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/12/Pierre_and_Marie_Curie-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Pierre_and_Marie_Curie" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="/media/2013/12/does-not-compute.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-8492" alt="does not compute" src="/media/2013/12/does-not-compute-300x295.jpg"  width="300" height="295"></a>This week Tom and guest co-host <a href="http://elizabethpampalone.com/">Jax Computer Chic&rsquo;s Elizabeth Pampalone</a> are joined by producer Sean Birch to congratulate Ray on his new child! Then they discuss what you can do if you&rsquo;re being bullied on Facebook, play a round of our new tech and geek trivia segment &ldquo;DOES NOT COMPUTE&rdquo; and answer a question about saving photos from your iPhone. Are all of your photos being saved to your iCloud? Find out how you can make sure they are.</p>
<p>Remember, we are also prepping for the first Deemable Tech hour-long radio episode. Get your calls in at 1-888-972-9868 to &ldquo;audition&rdquo; for the show!</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-8480-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-12-08.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-12-08.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-12-08.mp3</a></audio><p><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-12-08.mp3">#56 Deemable Tech Meets Marie &ldquo;Hot Lips&rdquo; Curie</a></p>
<span class="embed-youtube" style="text-align:center; display: block;"><iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="752" height="453" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tb_krKO4A1I?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
<p>TRANSCRIPT</p>
<p>TOM: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, in for Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>ELIZABETH: I&rsquo;m Elizabeth Pampalone, in for Tom Braun</p>
<p>TOM: and this is Deemable Tech. This week&rsquo;s episode is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p>ELIZABETH: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? You can give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at questions@deemable.com.</p>
<p>TOM: Well, as you can tell, Ray is not here again this week. Thankfully this time it&rsquo;s not because he&rsquo;s having an appendectomy like a few weeks ago. This time it&rsquo;s actually because of something great: Ray and his wife just had their second child!</p>
<p>So congratulations to Ray! He&rsquo;ll be back soon. And thank you Elizabeth for stepping in to help us out this week.</p>
<p>ELIZABETH: Happy to be here!</p>
<p>TOM: And also back again this week is our producer Sean Birch.</p>
<p>SEAN: Hello there!</p>
<p>TOM: And as we said on last week&rsquo;s show, we&rsquo;re changing things up a little bit here on the podcast. We realized that the people who listen to this and the people who listen to our segments on public radio aren&rsquo;t necessarily the same.</p>
<p>We don&rsquo;t have a specific plan just yet, but we do know that we won&rsquo;t be spending as much time answering questions on the podcast. We&rsquo;re still going to answer them, it just won&rsquo;t be as many. Instead we&rsquo;re going to try different things. And if you have suggestions for things you?d like to hear us try, let us know. Questions@deemable.com.</p>
<p>Before we dive into questions and other stuff, I got a call from a friend today with an interesting problem. Interesting to me, anyway, not so good for her.</p>
<p>She followed a page that had posted a story about a cat who had gotten lost and finally come home to its owners after six months. And she had posted a comment along the lines of &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s right to let cats outside.&rdquo; Now that&rsquo;s a statement that you can agree or disagree with, but she posted it in a really non-confrontational way. Just a statement of opinion.</p>
<p>But some people who she didn&rsquo;t know who were not Facebook friends of hers started replying to this comment and saying really mean things. They were calling her names, saying she should be neutered, that she shouldn&rsquo;t be allowed out of the house, etc. And she was getting notifications about these comments. So she called me in a real tizzy wanting to make the notifications stop.</p>
<p>Basically, this is Facebook bullying. What are some steps my friend could take to stop it?</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/12/56-deemable-tech-meets-marie-hot-lips-curie/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-12-08.mp3" length="29575426" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#54 Teenage Mutant Ninja Deemable</title>
		<link>/2013/11/54-teenage-mutant-ninja-deemable/</link>
		<comments>/2013/11/54-teenage-mutant-ninja-deemable/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 17:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer support]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GAAM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Games Art and Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Support]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JaxComputerChic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech support]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TMNT]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8418</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week Ray and Elizabeth were joined in the studio&#160;by Ryan Paul Thompson, the founder and president of GAAM, Games Art and Music, to talk to us about the upcoming GAAM event, Teenage Mutant Ninja GAAM, Saturday, December 7, 2013 <a href="/2013/11/54-teenage-mutant-ninja-deemable/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/11/54-teenage-mutant-ninja-deemable/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week Ray and Elizabeth were joined in the studio&nbsp;by Ryan Paul Thompson, the founder and president of <a onclick="javascript:_gaq.push(['_trackEvent','outbound-article','http://gaamshow.com/']);" href="http://gaamshow.com/">GAAM, Games Art and Music</a>, to talk to us about the upcoming GAAM event, <a href="http://gaam.eventbrite.com/">Teenage Mutant Ninja GAAM</a>, Saturday, December 7, 2013 starting at 6:00 PM. There&rsquo;s going to be&nbsp;video game art exhibit, video game competition, cosplay competition and free beer! Ray, Tom and Sean went to the <a href="//2013/06/41-the-legend-of-gaam-is-extreme-but-its-not-free-99/">last GAAM show</a>, and it was a blast. If you love video games, you should definitely check it out. Head over to <a href="http://gaam.eventbrite.com/">gaam.eventbrite.com</a> to get your tickets.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://gaam.eventbrite.com/"><img class="aligncenter" alt="Teenage Mutant Ninja GAAM" src="/media/2013/11/TMNG.jpg" width="600" height="222"></a></p>
<p>After the break, Ray and Elizabeth answered listeners questions about&nbsp;&nbsp;transferring an iTunes collection from a dead computer, which antivirus software is the best, and how to restore an iPhone from an older backup.</p>
<p>And remember, we are prepping for the first Deemable Tech hour-long radio episode. Get your calls in at 1-888-972-9868 to &ldquo;audition&rdquo; for the show!&nbsp;</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-8418-2" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-11-03.mp3?_=2"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-11-03.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-11-03.mp3</a></audio><p><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-11-03.mp3">#54 Teenage Mutant Ninja Deemable</a></p>
<p>TRANSCRIPT</p>
<p>RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>ELIZABETH: I&rsquo;m Elizabeth Pampalone, in for Tom Braun</p>
<p>RAY: and this is Deemable Tech. This week&rsquo;s episode is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p>ELIZABETH: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? You can give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at questions@deemable.com.</p>
<p>RAY: We mentioned this last week, but once Tom get&rsquo;s back, we are going to be&nbsp;working on our first, hour-long Deemable Tech radio special, and we need your help. We need some live callers to be&nbsp;on the show. So, we want you to call and leave a voicemail. We will be using them to pick our callers for the show. Make sure to leave your phone number so we can schedule a time for you to be on the show.</p>
<p>Now, before we get to your questions, we have a guest back in the studio again, Ryan Thompson, creator and President of GAAM, Games, Art and Music is here! Welcome to the show, Ryan!</p>
<p>You were on the show back in June before your last event and you guys have another awesome event coming up really soon.</p>
<p>Questions for Ryan Paul Thompson</p>
<ul><li>What is GAAM? What is the purpose of GAAM?</li>
<li>Where did you get the idea for GAAM?</li>
<li>Ask about the last GAAM&nbsp;event, The Legend of GAAM</li>
<li>Tell us about Teenage Mutant Ninja GAAM</li>
</ul><p>Ryan, thanks so much for coming in. Where can our listeners find out more about GAAM and get tickets for the event?</p>
<p>BREAK</p>
<p>Well, we have to take a quick break, after the break Elizabeth and I will answer a few questions from you guys about antivirus software, moving your iTunes account to a new computer.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech.</p>
<p>OUTRO</p>
<p><b>Name: </b>Phil</p>
<p><b>Question:</b>&nbsp;How do I switch my iTunes account from an old computer which no longer turns on to my new computer? I&rsquo;ve downloaded iTunes onto&nbsp;the new computer but, needless to say, it doesn&rsquo;t recognize my account. The last time I changed computers with the same problem I had to start a new account on the new computer and reenter music into my library. I have all my music on my iPod but now am not able to add to it.</p>
<p><b>Answer: </b>Before Switching computers, go into My Music (Music), Itunes, Save the iTunes Library.itl and iTunes Library.xml files to a flash drive or external drive. Install itunes&nbsp;on the new computer. Go into the same location (Music/iTunes) and replace those files with your library files from the older computer. Make sure to move your music files to the same place as they lived on the old computer. (ie Music)</p>
<p>If it&rsquo;s too late, and you&rsquo;ve already gotten rid of your old computer, try <a href="http://www.digidna.net/diskaid">DiskAid</a> or <a href="http://www.macroplant.com/iexplorer/">iExplorer</a> to take music, movies, etc. off of your iPad, iPod, iPhone and get it into your computer.</p>
<p><b>Name: </b>Danielle</p>
<p>&nbsp;<b>Question: </b>Is paying for antivirus software more safer that the free versions? What are some recommendations for antivirus?</p>
<p><b>Answer: </b>We answered this once before on our <a href="//2013/01/jo-el-asks-which-antivirus-software-is-the-best/">radio segment</a>. If you are using a Windows: XP, Vista, Win 7 use MS Security Essentials. It is FREE and works seamlessly with Windows Firewall and Windows Defender. Windows 8 has MS Security Essentials built in. It is really the best antivirus software on the market, especially for the price. Word of caution: you can only use ONE antivirus at a time. You can not have TWO running, they will cancel each other out!</p>
<p>If you are using Mac, antivirus protection is built&nbsp;in. Check System Preferences, Security &amp; Privacy. There are some settings you might want to check out the settings there. Some of the items on General and Privacy tabs are good to go through based on what your personal preferences happen to be.</p>
<p><b>Name:</b> Valerie</p>
<p><b>Question:</b> Can I retrieve an iPhone backup from maybe 5 backups ago?</p>
<p>iPhoto&nbsp;apparently failed on one of my loads from image capture, and of course I had the &ldquo;delete&nbsp;after import&rdquo; option checked. I saw some warning about iPhoto&nbsp;being full (although not an issue since) after my Macbook Pro had been working&nbsp;for awhile. I didn&rsquo;t have time to deal with it and later re-backed up my phone. When I went looking for the 3 months of photos/videos, I couldn&rsquo;t find them anywhere on my computer &mdash; it is a mess. Also my time machine (to my external hard drive) apparently hadn&rsquo;t been working during that time period either. I just can&rsquo;t imagine that the photos/video from the whole&nbsp;upload don&rsquo;t exist in some cache somewhere.</p>
<p><b>Answer:</b> Plug in your iPhone, click the Summary button, and under Backups click Restore Backup. If you have multiple backups saved, you should have a drop down menu appear. Choose one of the options.</p>
<p><a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1766">http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1766</a></p>
<p>Thanks for all your questions, and keep them coming. Call us at our toll-free number, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com. Also, subscribe to the show! Search for Deemable Tech on iTunes, YouTube, Facebook and Twitter and follow us or subscribe.</p>
<p>Our producer is Sean Birch. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Elizabeth Pampalone, and this is Deemable Tech. Thanks for listening. Have a great week.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/11/54-teenage-mutant-ninja-deemable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-11-03.mp3" length="31698039" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#50 The Ginger Episode</title>
		<link>/2013/09/50-ginger-episode/</link>
		<comments>/2013/09/50-ginger-episode/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 16:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer support]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Support]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JaxComputerChic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech support]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8320</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/09-29-2013-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Elizabeth Pampalone, Blue Screen of Death, Busted iPad, Critical Updates, Air Print, Clearwire" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week on Deemable Tech, Tom is out-of-town, but Elizabeth Pampalone stepped in to keep the show rolling. And, she gave Tom a run for his money. Ray and Elizabeth answered lots of questions, including questions about Blue Screens of <a href="/2013/09/50-ginger-episode/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/09/50-ginger-episode/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/09-29-2013-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Elizabeth Pampalone, Blue Screen of Death, Busted iPad, Critical Updates, Air Print, Clearwire" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img src="/media/2013/09/09-29-2013-1024x576.png" alt="Elizabeth Pampalone, Blue Screen of Death, Busted iPad, Critical Updates, Air Print, Clearwire" width="659" height="370" class="alignright size-large wp-image-8324">This week on Deemable Tech, Tom is out-of-town, but Elizabeth Pampalone stepped in to keep the show rolling. And, she gave Tom a run for his money. Ray and Elizabeth answered lots of questions, including questions about Blue Screens of Death, whether you can change your internet provider without changing your email provider, Facebook photo syncing, how to print from your iPad, and Critical Updates that break things!</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-8320-3" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-09-29.mp3?_=3"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-09-29.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-09-29.mp3</a></audio><p><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-09-29.mp3">#50 The Ginger Episode</a></p>
<span class="embed-youtube" style="text-align:center; display: block;"><iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="752" height="453" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_qQWifjPIMY?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
<p>RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>LIZ: I&rsquo;m Elizabeth Pampalone in for Tom Braun,</p>
<p>RAY: and this is Deemable Tech, tech help worth listening to.</p>
<p>RAY: This week&rsquo;s episode of the Deemable Tech podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p>So, Tom is out&hellip;again. This time he gave some notice, so I asked our friend Elizabeth Pampalone to give us a hand, and she was gracious enough to help. Thanks for coming in, Elizabeth.</p>
<p>LIZ: *vamp response*</p>
<p>RAY:</p>
<p>Actually, you did almost all of the work getting ready for this show, you&rsquo;re giving Tom a run for his money. I tell you what, I&rsquo;ll hire you for half of what I pay Tom.</p>
<p>&ndash; I gonna be the brains, and I guess that leaves me to be the beauty. This is not going to go well for me.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s the ginger episode. If you&rsquo;re watching the video stream &hellip;</p>
<p>Before we jump into the show, could I ask a favor? OK, thanks. Would you take a second and tell your friends about Deemable Tech? Especially if you know someone who is interested&nbsp;in learning more about technology, whether they currently know nothing about technology, or you think they already know everything about technology. Tell them to check out Deemable Tech. We&rsquo;d really appreciate it!</p>
<p>Also, if you haven&rsquo;t done so already, make sure you are subscribed&nbsp;to Deemable Tech. Just go to iTunes and search for Deemable Tech, or go to deemable.com/itunes to take you directly to our iTunes page. You can also subscribe to our YouTube page. And we&rsquo;re on the Facebook and the Twitter, just search for Deemable Tech.</p>
<p>LIZ: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? You can give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email to questions@deemable.com.</p>
<p>RAY: Hey folks, time is dwindling down to the end of our Amazon Gift Card contest. All you have to do is answer a few questions about the Deemable Tech podcast. Just go to Deemable.com and click the link to take the survey. You can&rsquo;t miss it, it is the first or second article at the top of the page, but it is ends September 30th, so don&rsquo;t wait, go submit&nbsp;your survey answers right now. Even if you&rsquo;re listening live, go pull up the survey now, because you won&rsquo;t have much time after we finish recording this episode.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t worry, it&rsquo;s not a trivia contest. We just need your opinion on a few questions. If you could take a few minutes and answer our survey it will really help us out a lot. And, just for doing so, you&rsquo;ll be entered to win a $20 Amazon Gift Card.</p>
<p>Speaking of questions, Elizabeth, what kind of questions do we have today?</p>
<p>LIZ: Well, we have questions about Blue Screens of Death, whether you can change your internet provider without changing your email provider, Facebook photo syncing, how to print from your iPad, and Critical Updates that break things!</p>
<p>RAY: Awesome, let&rsquo;s start with Blue Screens of Death.</p>
<p>JUDY<br>
Hi, Saw article in Folio about BSOD. Am getting a lot of unexpected shutdowns &ndash; 4 in last week-&nbsp;and service hang ups &ndash; 15 last week. Microsoft-speak about drivers, etc. might as well be Greek given how little I know about computers. What should I do to address it? How serious is it? Thanks so much!!</p>
<p>ANSWER: I would call a tech ASAP!</p>
<p>WALTER</p>
<p>Switch Email Service Providers and not lose emails. forwarding emails to another account for a short time.</p>
<p>ANSWER:<br>
I do not recommend using ANY of the ISP accounts email addresses. You can use something like a GMAIL&nbsp;account and BEFORE you switch start having your emails forwarded. this will eliminate&nbsp;the need to go cold turkey with your account when you switch. a gmail&nbsp;account is like your cell phone. no matter where you live it travels with you. your ISP email address (bellsouth/comcast) is like a landline, when you move it stays behind. Switching to gmail&nbsp;and fwding&nbsp;your accounts before you switch ISPs is like when the post office fwds&nbsp;your mail. you don&rsquo;t have to worry about the missed&nbsp;messages or people not knowing your email address because you will see all of them come in and you will be able to tell if that person or company is using your gmail&nbsp;address or your old ISP address. this gives you a chance to gradually switch all of your addresses over for daily use rather than having to switch all at once.</p>
<p>&hellip; this is marvin&nbsp;here in jacksonville&nbsp;3670124 I&rsquo;ve asked this question before but I&rsquo;m not quite getting the answer you gave me I wanna print out my address book I&rsquo;m on on&nbsp;h. p. computer per sorry &hellip; s. sorry 1930 annex and I&rsquo;m using windows x. p. progress and hi&nbsp;address book his obscured died on the right have bye &hellip; part of the address book proper left I can print out name is but hello information is sitting behind the they&rsquo;ll have for the page hello if I explained that well or not 3670124 thanks.</p>
<p>ANSWER: When printing anything online you want to make sure you are not printing the web page but printing the email or in this case, the addressbook you actually want to print.</p>
<p>I always look for a Printer icon that is ON the page. The word print or the printer icon to print the items you want to print without printing all those annoying ads etc that are normally on webpages.</p>
<p>KATHERINE I have an iPhone 5 and every time I take a photo and try to upload it to Facebook, it keeps adding it to a stream of old photos and the comments from friends are from all the old photos. How do I get this to stop and just upload 1 photo at a time in a post?</p>
<p>ANSWER: Open Facebook app on your phone, Go to the Photos Section, Go to Synched. If you have set it up to sync you can scroll to the bottom and turn that off. If you have not set it up to synch&nbsp;it will ask you if you want to. I say NO, don&rsquo;t do it. Every photo you post to Facebook becomes property of facebook&nbsp;and they can use them however they wish. also, sometimes i take photos of stupid stuff and I don&rsquo;t want my mom and everybody seeing them.</p>
<p>ROBERT<br>
Recently, as I use the &lsquo;back arrow&rsquo; on my Internet Explorer browser to return to a previous page, something strange has happened. Even if I continue to click on the back arrow, I still do not return to the previous web page. After waiting a few moments, I click on the down arrow next to the back arrow and all that I see are a bunch of web page links that I have never visited. Usually, there is a portion of the links that has something like: ad.doubleclick.<br>
In order to get back to the web page that I want, I have to either open a new web browser page; or, I can click on the Home link (alt +M) and then type in the URL address all over again. What is going on; and, more importantly, how can I block this from happening again?</p>
<p>Bob: Installed Adblock and its working fine, however I still get<br>
random audio ads (sometimes playing over audio coming from<br>
a U-tube I&rsquo;m watching) and other times while reading an e-mail.</p>
<p>Is there a solution to block unwanted audio?</p>
<p>ANSWER:This is not a browser hack but some sites open multiple windows of ads that can appear in your browser as if you had visited the site multiple times. this often happens on ad heavy sites like sites where you can watch tv online etc. TO ROBERT&nbsp;If I am going to open a link like this, I try to Right click on the Link before going to it and ?open in a new tab? this helps to keep your original spot if you decide the link wasn?t worth it and want to go back to your original page. TO BOB If you are using Google Chrome as your browser, which you should be,whenever&nbsp;there is a pop up a box will appear near the Bookmark star. It will have a red X on it. If you click it you will see a list of all the pop ups that did NOT pop up. in order to&nbsp;stop the audio, you must open each hidden pop up and close it using the normal means, the red X. This can happen with Audio and Non Audio pop ups and can be&nbsp;very annoying as they often start playing the audio after a few min. If the audio ad is on the page you are viewing you can click the MUTE symbol on the ad. this usually works, but some ads have taken to makeing&nbsp;the mute button look like it is muted and it is playing really loudly. click the mute button anyway, this will stop the audio.</p>
<p>JULIE<br>
Using Clearwire, Not giving her the speeds she needs</p>
<p>ANSWER: Might have someone come out and look at it BEFORE you switch providers. Clearwire only allows you to have up to 8 devices on at a time depending on your service you pay for.</p>
<p>SCOTT<br>
Wants to print from ipad to printer.</p>
<p>ANSWER:<br>
Need a printer with Airprint :</p>
<p>All of the models sold by apple are airprint&nbsp;compatible. you don&rsquo;t have to buy it from apple, but most wireless HP models have airprint&nbsp;that were made within the last year.</p>
<p>Also, there is an app called Collobos&nbsp;printer that you can buy for $20. if you have a computer that is on and connected to a printer and connected to the same network your wifi&nbsp;is on, you can print via that printer. essentially Collobos is a patch to make any printer that is connected&nbsp;to a computer that is connected&nbsp;to your wifi&nbsp;network your ipad&nbsp;or iphone&nbsp;is on an airprint compatible printer.</p>
<p>https://www.collobos.com/</p>
<p>Joe</p>
<p>Guys,</p>
<p>I am at my wits end&nbsp;regarding&nbsp;a Microsoft Critical Update that just won&rsquo;t install. It has failed over and over again&nbsp;on my Windows 7 laptop. I have tried everything mentioned in the Microsoft Knowledgebase&nbsp;and on Tech Net. Nothing works! This includes downloading the critical update separately and trying to install it, using the MS Fixit&nbsp;tool, using a Hot Fix utility to fix Windows Update, use the SFC&nbsp;command to find/repair missing files, etc. I have shut down my firewall and turned off my A/V program and even tried to install the critical update in Safe Mode! The update is apparently critical to security as it updates the kernel to remove some vulnerability. What I don&rsquo;t understand is why Microsoft gives you a cryptic error message on the fail that doesn&rsquo;t really tell you anything! The update is KB2850851&nbsp;and error I get is 800736B3.</p>
<p>The laptop is an HP DV7&nbsp;with Windows 7 64 bit. It&rsquo;s about 18 months old and I haven&rsquo;t had any problems with it until now. I run Webroot Secure Anywhere for A/V and the built-in Security Essentials from Microsoft.</p>
<p>Thanks.</p>
<p>http://answers.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/forum/windows_7-windows_update/unable-to-install-update-kb2850851-error-8007045d/a1bcef56-687b-4afc-af00-428a96c6c1c3</p>
<p>RAY<br>
Randomly and occasionally the computer will not wake from sleep state. I have looked at the event log for this. Results: Event log. Critical error. Message: The last sleep transition was unsuccessful. This error could be caused if the system stopped responding, failed, or lost power during the sleep transition. Windows Vista Home Premium.<br>
Going to event log online help reveals nothing useful: Results for: Microsoft Product: Windows Operating System; Version: 6.0.6002.18005; Event ID: 41; Event Source: Microsoft-Windows-Kernel-Power.<br>
This is not helpful. This failure occurs less than once a month. The solution is a hard reboot, using the power switch to turn off and turn on the computer. Then it works fine for several months. The hardware diagnostic tools scan shows that all the hardware is working. Since it happens rarely and randomly, it would be difficult to troubleshoot. Any suggestions? The computer is up to date regarding&nbsp;service packs and other updates and updating the bios did not help. The mouse and none of the buttons on the keyboard do not wake the computer. Hibernation is not enabled for this computer, only sleep state. Since this is an infrequent and random error, perhaps the only solution is to give the computer a hard boot when necessary. Thank you for your assistance.</p>
<p>ANSWER:<br>
The problem was solved on several message boards by going back to an older version of the motherboard BIOS Or you are overclocking their ATI cards</p>
<p>ANDREA I was wondering if you know of any places in Jacksonville, FL that buys and/or recycles old outdated electronics such as: computers, cell phones, keyboards, hard drives, etc.?<br>
ANSWER<br>
http://www.scrapcomputers.com/</p>
<p>MARY Apple told me they would sell me a refurbished ipad for $220<br>
I would like to find a reputable repair service (preferably locally) who can repair or replace the damaged screen without going broke in the process. Is that possible? I know that in doing so, I would void my Apple warranty and would be SOL in the event that something else goes wrong, but honestly, since Apple&rsquo;s &ldquo;technicians&rdquo; are now just fulltime warranty specialists, I would probably have to replace the device anyway(at which point, the mini would go into a drawer somewhere and I&rsquo;d dedicate myself full time to my Android devices). I called a couple of local fix it places and most charge close to $200 to replace the screen (almost as much as Apple charges for a replacement). I&rsquo;m also concerned that some of these technicians may damage the device in the process of replacing the screen. Do you know of a reputable company that can help me out without cleaning me out?<br>
Time: 09/20/2013 at 3:52 PM<br>
ANSWER: iphone911.com reasonable prices, good hours and fast service.</p>
<p>http://www.theiphone911.com/<br>
http://www.jaxiphonerepair.com/<br>
http://www.ubreakifix.com/</p>
<p>Thanks for all your questions, and keep them coming. Call us at our toll-free number, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com. Also, subscribe to the show! Search for Deemable Tech on iTunes or point your favorite podcast app to dmbl.co/pod.</p>
<p>Our producer is Sean Birch. Thanks to Robert Snyder for Video Production Assistance. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Elizabeth Pampalone, and this is Deemable Tech. Thanks for listening. Have a great week.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/09/50-ginger-episode/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-09-29.mp3" length="0" type="" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Episode 38 &#8211; The Lightning Round</title>
		<link>/2013/05/episode-38-the-lightning-round/</link>
		<comments>/2013/05/episode-38-the-lightning-round/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 03:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackBerry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DMCA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DRM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eureka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JaxComputerChic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lightning Round]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XBMC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7340</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week on Deemable Tech, Ray and Tom have so many questions they decide to have the first ever &#8220;Deemable Tech: Lightning Round.&#8221; In the Lightning Round, Ray, Tom and guest host Elizabeth Pampalone try to answer as many questions <a href="/2013/05/episode-38-the-lightning-round/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/05/episode-38-the-lightning-round/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="/media/2013/05/LightningRound.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright  wp-image-7345" title="Page 1 of the mystic Lightning Round scoresheet, the only real evidence that the Lightning Round even happened." alt="" src="/media/2013/05/LightningRound-1024x768.jpg"  width="395" height="296"></a>This week on Deemable Tech, Ray and Tom have so many questions they decide to have the first ever &ldquo;Deemable Tech: Lightning Round.&rdquo; In the Lightning Round, Ray, Tom and guest host Elizabeth Pampalone try to answer as many questions as they can off the top of their head. Sean Birch is the judge, and whoever gets the most questions right gets the grand prize of absolutely nothing!</p>
<p><audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-7340-4" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-05-19.mp3?_=4"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-05-19.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-05-19.mp3</a></audio><br><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-05-19.mp3">Episode 38 &ndash; The Lightning Round</a></p>
<p>DRAFT TRANSCRIPT</p>
<p>RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>TOM: I&rsquo;m Tom Braun,</p>
<p>RAY: and this is Deemable Tech, tech help worth listening to.</p>
<p>TOM: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? Give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at questions@deemable.com.</p>
<p>RAY: This week&rsquo;s episode of the Deemable Tech podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p>And, by audible.com &ndash; Deemable Tech listeners can get a FREE audiobook download at audibletrial.com/Deemable Over 100,000 titles to choose from for your iPhone, Android, Kindle or mp3 player.</p>
<p>And, from All Florida Insurance Options, an authorized Progressive agency, helping people shop for insurance at 904-757-3288 or at their office in Highland Square on Dunn Avenue in North Jacksonville.</p>
<p>RAY: This week, back in the studio once again, we have a special guest, Elizabeth Pampalone, owner of <a href="JaxComputerChic.com">JaxComputerChic.com</a>, a small business computer consulting and computer training company. Welcome back to the show Elizabeth!</p>
<p>ELIZABETH: *vamp response*</p>
<p>RAY: Today we are going to do something a little different. We have a backlog of older questions to get through.</p>
<p>TOM: Why didn&rsquo;t we answer those questions?</p>
<p>RAY: Laziness? Stupidity? A lack of organization?</p>
<p>TOM: Yeah, that sounds about right. So what are we going to do about them?</p>
<p>RAY: I thought we should just run through them, as fast as we can, answering them off the cuff, gameshow style. In fact, I thought we could call it.</p>
<p>*THE LIGHTNING ROUND*</p>
<p>TOM: Wow, what are we calling it again?</p>
<p>RAY: *THE LIGHTNING ROUND*</p>
<p>TOM: Awesome! But before we dive into The Lightning Round &ndash;</p>
<p>RAY: You mean, *THE LIGHTNING ROUND*</p>
<p>TOM: Yeah, that. Before we do that, we have a couple of ordinary questions to answer. And, Elizabeth, feel free to dive in on these at any point.</p>
<p>ELIZABETH: OK. Looks like the first question is from a guy named Ryan.</p>
<p>RAY: Cool, can you read it for us?</p>
<p>ELIZABETH: Ryan writes, For some reason, I can&rsquo;t find 1channel or icefilms as add on options on my XBMCHub on my Windows 7 laptop. They are amazing on the unlocked Apple TV, and I want to put them on my laptop. Any thoughts?<br>
TOM: *laughs*<br>
Now I know how listeners to our show must feel when we start going on and on about things they&rsquo;ve never heard about.<br>
Before I yell at those pesky kids to get off my lawn, does anybody know what a 1channel or an icefilm is? And what is an XBM-whatever and what does it have to do with unlocking an Apple TV? I didn&rsquo;t even know you could unlock an Apple TV.<br>
RAY: Well, in the Apple world we call it jailbreaking. And yes, you definitely can jailbreak your Apple TV. Just like Jailbreaking an iPhone or iPad, you are simply taking off or breaking the code that keeps iOS shackled.<br>
TOM: Why would you want to?<br>
RAY: Well, normally your Apple TV can do two things: mirror the desktop of your Mac, iPhone or iPad, and stream media from iTunes, Hulu, Netflix, YouTube or one of the other authorized Apple TV channels, to your television. If you want to play any other kind of media through it, you&rsquo;re out of luck. But an Apple TV is actually a powerful little LINUX-based computer in its own right, and by losing it from its shackles, you can use it to stream just about anything you want to your television.<br>
TOM: OK, what is XB-whatever?<br>
RAY: XBMC. It used to stand for Xbox Media Center because that&rsquo;s what it started out as, but now it is a free, open source media player which can be run on a variety of devices.<br>
TOM: Including, let me guess, a jailbroken Apple TV or a Windows 7 laptop.<br>
RAY: You got it. The XBMC platform support third-party add-ons which allow you to do things like stream movies through it and watch ripped DVDs.<br>
TOM: So if I jailbreak my Apple TV, I can install XBMC and watch my ripped DVDs on it?<br>
RAY: Yep.<br>
TOM: Cool. But Ryan didn&rsquo;t just say XBMC, did he? He said XBMCHub.<br>
RAY: OK, so despite the fact that it was originally designed to be installed on hacked XBoxes and jailbroken Apple TV&rsquo;s, XBMC is supposed to only access legal content. But since it&rsquo;s open source, someone has created a separate version called XBMC Hub which is a little more &ndash; open &ndash; about what content you access through it.<br>
TOM: I&rsquo;m guessing 1channel and icefilms are ways to get free content that you&rsquo;d normally have to pay for.<br>
RAY: Well basically they are free services that host links to all kinds of TV and movies&hellip; some of which you should technically be paying for. But they don&rsquo;t actually host the content themselves, so they&rsquo;re in a legal grey area. There&rsquo;s no law that specifically says what they are doing is illegal, but that&rsquo;s never stopped a copyright lawyer before.<br>
TOM: Riiight. So, just to recap, Ryan has jailbroken his Apple TV and installed XBMC Hub on it so he can stream free TV shows and movies to his TV. And now he wants to do the same thing on his Windows laptop, but he&rsquo;s running into problems.<br>
RAY: I think that sums up it up.<br>
TOM: And&hellip; we&rsquo;re not going to help him, are we?<br>
RAY: No.<br>
TOM: Here&rsquo;s the deal Ryan, and all our other podcast listeners. Here at Deemable Tech we have a policy of trying to stay neutral on the topic of copyright, piracy, DRM and that sort of thing.<br>
On the one hand, it&rsquo;s your laptop, it&rsquo;s your Apple TV, you are welcome to try and do whatever you want with it. And we&rsquo;re not going to pretend that there aren&rsquo;t lots of ways to get, say, pretty much any movie or television program for free and stream it to your television.<br>
RAY: But we&rsquo;re also not going to tell you how to do it. At least in the US, distributing copyrighted content for free without the author&rsquo;s permission is technically illegal. Do people do it all the time? Yes. Should the laws about this stuff be different? Maybe. Are movie and TV studios technological dinosaurs with their heads stuck in the sand? Probably. But right now the law is the law and we can&rsquo;t be in the position of encouraging our listeners to break it.<br>
TOM: If you decide to stick it to the man and circumvent the official channels for this kind of stuff, well, that&rsquo;s your business. I mean, we&rsquo;re geeks, we get it. It&rsquo;s like rooting or jailbreaking your smartphone &ndash; it&rsquo;s your device, we think you should be able to do what you want with it. Fortunately, rooting and jailbreaking smartphones is legal. We&rsquo;re glad to answer questions about that on this podcast. But with other devices you&rsquo;re getting into a gray area and we can&rsquo;t help you. And as far as copyrighted content goes, well, we&rsquo;re not even going to touch that issue with a ten foot pole.<br>
Ryan, I&rsquo;m sure with a little technical know-how, Google-fu and maybe asking some questions on the right messageboards you can get your questions answered. But it&rsquo;s up to you to face the legal or technical consequences. So you&rsquo;re on your own with this one!</p>
<p>TOM: Fabio writes &ndash; Hi Tom and Ray,</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m Fabio and I&rsquo;m writing you from Italy. I&rsquo;m Italian so please forgive me if I make any mistakes. Here&rsquo;s my problem: I have a desktop computer with windows 7 and sometimes while I surf the web, (I use the latest version of firefox) the screen freezes for a couple of seconds and then on the system tray this message appears: ?Display driver stopped responding and has recovered?. I tried to update the video card driver (I have an ATI Radeon 5700) but the problem continues. I hope you can help me with this because it is really annoying. I really love your show, it&rsquo;s useful and entertaining and I&rsquo;ve downloaded every podcast of the program on Itunes.</p>
<p>Thank you in advance</p>
<p>RAY: Awesome! Thanks for your question Fabio. That&rsquo;s a hard one. *PAUSE* Did you ever watch Eureka, Tom?</p>
<p>TOM: Like, one time. For five minutes. And then I changed the channel.</p>
<p>RAY: *Explain what Eureka is.*</p>
<p>TOM: OK, did you just completely change the subject? Aren&rsquo;t we going to answer Fabio&rsquo;s question?</p>
<p>RAY: Of course we are&hellip;</p>
<p>TOM: So what does this have to do with Fabio&rsquo;s question?</p>
<p>RAY: Explain how every episode of Eureka works.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s the formula for a perfect Eureka episode:<br>
They&rsquo;re having a normal day, *example*<br>
then something wacky happens, *example*<br>
Then, they find out that that wacky thing has gotten worse, *example*<br>
Then they find out that the wacky thing was caused by some experiment, except the experiment wasn&rsquo;t suppose to work like that, *example*<br>
Then, they find out that the wacky thing happened because the first experiment interacted with a second experiment *example* and the interference of the two experiments caused the wacky thing.<br>
Then, they find out the wacky thing is going to (A) kill someone, (B) destroy the entire town, (C) kill everyone in the country, or (D) destroy the entire world, and they only have five minutes or less to fix it.<br>
So, then they come up with some ridiculously complicated method of changing the wacky thing described with technobabble by the geeks, and the sheriff describes it with an simple analogy, and it will probably result in an amazing new achievement in science if it works.<br>
And then, they do it. It almost always works, unless it&rsquo;s a ?very special episode? in which case the worst case scenario does happen, but even then there is a twist that makes it a good thing that it happened. *example*</p>
<p>So that&rsquo;s how it works. And Colin Ferguson, if you&rsquo;re listening, when you guys decide to make the Eureka movie, I am totally ready to write the script.</p>
<p>TOM: OK, Ray, while that was *vamps*, what does that have to do with Fabio&rsquo;s question?</p>
<p>RAY: I don&rsquo;t know? What was Fabio&rsquo;s question?</p>
<p>TOM: Remember, his display driver stopped responding? I knew it, you were just changing the subject!</p>
<p>RAY: *Explain how PCs are like Eureka. Everything should work together well, but they sometimes don&rsquo;t and it&rsquo;s really complicated to explain why.</p>
<p>TOM: Anyway, this one&rsquo;s pretty easy, you just</p>
<p>Open Catalyst Control Center and switch to ATI Overdrive<br>
Unlock and enable Overdrive<br>
Go to Options/Profiles/Profile Manager and create a new profile called, let&rsquo;s say, STABLE.<br>
Save the new profile. But DO NOT ACTIVATE the profile.<br>
Now go to C:\Users\{YourUserName}\AppData\Local\ATI\ACE\Profiles folder ( I assume C: is your system drive )<br>
Note: You should have &rdquo; show hidden files &rdquo; turned on to see the folder.<br>
Open the .xml file named STABLE with notepad.<br>
Change the values of the idle Core clock and Memory clock speeds below</p>
<p>Feature name=&rdquo;CoreClockTarget_0&Prime;<br>
Property name=&rdquo;Want_0&Prime; value=&rdquo;40000&Prime; note: previous value should be &ldquo;15700&rdquo;</p>
<p>Feature name=&rdquo;MemoryClockTarget_0&Prime;<br>
Property name=&rdquo;Want_0&Prime; value=&rdquo;90000&Prime; note: previous value should be &ldquo;30000&rdquo;<br>
Save the file and close it.<br>
Go back to CCC and activate the profile. This will make the card idle at 400 MHz core clock and 900 MHz memory clock.</p>
<p>Boom! You&rsquo;re good. Hopefully.</p>
<p>RAY: So&hellip; Yeah there is a possible solution, but it is very complicated and no one else in the world will get any benefit out of it. So, Fabio we are going to send you an email with a link to the information. So you can try it out for yourself, and let us know how it works out.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.tomshardware.com/forum/276896-33-radeon-5750-display-driver-stopped-responding">http://www.tomshardware.com/forum/276896-33-radeon-5750-display-driver-stopped-responding</a></p>
<p>RAY: OKay guys, we&rsquo;ve gotten through the regular questions, so do you know what time it is?</p>
<p>TOM: I think it&rsquo;s time for *THE LIGHTNING ROUND*</p>
<p>RAY: Yes!</p>
<p>ELIZABETH: So how&rsquo;s it going to work?</p>
<p>RAY: *explains*</p>
<p><strong>Question 1:</strong></p>
<p>Anonymous &ndash; I LOVE my Windows Phone. I just don&rsquo;t know why the business world doesn&rsquo;t use them more often. The OS is better than the ?cutesy? Android system that seems more teenager/unprofessional like. It has Office (word, PowerPoint, Excel), and more over Outlook ?.everything we may use in the business world. I just don&rsquo;t know why I can&rsquo;t sync my Outlook calendar at the office with my Samsung Smartphone Windows OS? I have an &ldquo;Microsoft Exchange server&rdquo; &ndash; the Phone asks for this but it always asks for a &ldquo;domain name&rdquo;? What are these and what do I type into make this work?</p>
<p><strong>Question 2:</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Hey guys,</p>
<p dir="ltr">I have my laptop hooked up to my LCD tv via HDMI so that I can watch &nbsp;Netflix. However, recently I have noticed that if I&rsquo;m watching a show that&rsquo;s longer than 30 minutes the audio and video will suddenly stop being sent to the tv via HDMI, and instead it starts playing directly from the laptop, almost as if the HDMI itself went into sleep mode. If I move the mouse, then the HDMI audio and video goes back to the tv.</p>
<p dir="ltr">What gives?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Also, after trying to hook my laptop up to my tv via the VGA connection,&nbsp;now it doesn&rsquo;t recognize my tv as an LCD, but thinks its an analog CRT and won&rsquo;t allow me to set the proper resolution!</p>
<p dir="ltr">Arrrrrrrgh!</p>
<p>-Joel</p>
<p><strong>Question 3:</strong></p>
<p>Melody &ndash; I recently heard a piece where you all recommended the Find My iPhone app and was wondering about something. I keep my Location Services off unless I need them, since they seem to be a huge battery suck. Will the Find My iPhone features still work if the Location Services are off?</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>Question 4:</b></p>
<p>Voicemail transcript: Dan this jacksonville beach florida&hellip; I&rsquo;m calling to see if you do house calls &hellip; and if you do &hellip; please call me back and let me know otherwise I guess I maybe have to call &hellip; I&rsquo;m making some call again but thank you very much I appreciate hearing from you and enjoy your programs on &hellip; on the radio thank you bye bye.</p>
<p><b>Question 5:</b></p>
<p>Scott &ndash; Dear Ray &amp; Tom,<br>
I have windows internet explorer version 8 and everytime I bring it up, it gives me the error message, ?A program on your computer has corrupted your browser preferences? and then I have click on ?OK? or change my preferences. I can&rsquo;t seem to get rid of it. I have re-enabled Google as my default browser and I still get the error message. I tried picking another browser and I still get the error message.<br>
Is there any way I can stop the error message?<br>
Thank you.</p>
<p><b>Question 6:</b></p>
<p>Jennifer writes, I listened to your show this morning on WJCT about protecting the iPad &amp; iPhone. I have the Blackberry Bold 9900 &amp; Blackberry Playbook 64gb tablet. I would like a recommendation for apps to protect, lock down &amp; secure the Blackberry Bold &amp; Blackberry Playbook tablet.<br>
Thanks for all your help!</p>
<p><b>Question 7:</b></p>
<p>Alan &ndash; Hi Ray/Tom,<br>
My iphone sends my incoming mail to the trash. The messages appear briefly in the in box, then go to trash. ATT says it is a problem with my computer settings, Apple says it is a problem with Yahoo. I have cleared and reset the account information to no avail.</p>
<p>I went online and spoke with some guy in India who said he could fix it for $50.00. I was irritated and did not take him up on it. I would rather pay you or someone local.</p>
<p>Please advise.</p>
<p><b>Question 8:</b></p>
<p>Mel &ndash; Hi I am using an HP laptop with Vista. My account is with AT&amp;T (bellsouth.net) for my email. Yahoo is only my choice as my search engine. I would like to use Google as a choice. How can I do that with out messing up my email?</p>
<p>Love your spot on NPR&rsquo;s morning edition.</p>
<p><b>Question 9:</b></p>
<p>Michelle &ndash; I have an LG Thrill from AT&amp;T that has been unlocked. I&rsquo;m using it on T-Mobile, but I can&rsquo;t get the data to work on it. What do I need to do to get the data working?</p>
<p>Thanks for all your questions, and keep them coming. Call us at our toll-free number, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com. Also, subscribe to the show! Search for Deemable Tech on iTunes or point your favorite podcast app to dmbl.co/pod.</p>
<p>Our producer is Sean Birch. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, I&rsquo;m Elizabeth Pampalone, and this is Deemable Tech.<br>
Thanks for listening. Have a great week.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/05/episode-38-the-lightning-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-05-19.mp3" length="54294988" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Episode 18 &#8211; Lots and Lots of Questions</title>
		<link>/2012/10/episode-18-lots-and-lots-of-questions/</link>
		<comments>/2012/10/episode-18-lots-and-lots-of-questions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 14:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JaxComputerChic]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=5898</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/10/LotsOfQuestions-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Lots and Lots of Questions" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week, we had a special guest in the studio, Elizabeth Pampalone, a small business computer consultant and repair technician and continuing education instructor at UNF. Since WJCT had its pledge drive last week, and we had to cut last <a href="/2012/10/episode-18-lots-and-lots-of-questions/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2012/10/episode-18-lots-and-lots-of-questions/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/10/LotsOfQuestions-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Lots and Lots of Questions" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="/media/2012/10/LotsOfQuestions.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-5900" title="Lots and Lots of Questions" src="/media/2012/10/LotsOfQuestions-300x300.jpg"  alt="" width="300" height="300"></a>This week, we had a special guest in the studio, <a href="http://elizabethpampalone.com/">Elizabeth Pampalone</a>, a small business computer consultant and repair technician and continuing education instructor at UNF.</p>
<p>Since WJCT had its pledge drive last week, and we had to cut last week&rsquo;s episode short, we had tons of questions this week. So, all we did is answer a bunch of your great questions. &nbsp;If <em>you</em> have a tech question for Deemable Tech call us, leave us a voice-mail at 904-372-3336.</p>
<p><a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="pcast://feeds.feedburner.com/DeemableTech">Subscribe to the show in iTunes by clicking here.</a></p>
<p><a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech Podcast!" href="http://dmbl.co/pod">Subscribe to the show in another podcast reader by clicking here</a>.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-5898-5" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-10-21.mp3?_=5"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-10-21.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-10-21.mp3</a></audio><p><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-10-21.mp3">Deemable Tech &ndash; Episode 18 </a></p>
<h3><strong>Today&rsquo;s Questions:</strong></h3>
<div>
<ul><li>What do I need for my new iPad?</li>
<li>What is a print screen, and how do I take a print screen and send it to someone else?</li>
<li>Which is better Gmail or Outlook.com?</li>
<li>How can I find out if my kid was recommended to friend someone on Facebook by one of her friends or by Facebook?</li>
<li>How can I tell if my kid has more than one Facebook account?</li>
<li>How do I get Facebook to stop sending me text messages when I have 2 step authentication turned on?</li>
<li>Dropbox vs Google Drive vs SkyDrive. Which is the best and why?</li>
<li>How can I control multiple computers with one keyboard and mouse?</li>
<li>I deleted a file, but it&rsquo;s not in the Recycle Bin. Where did it go?</li>
<li>What is a permalink?</li>
<li>What is Steam? Should I buy games on Steam, and will I be able to download them again if my hard drive crashes?</li>
</ul></div>
<p>Need tech help? Got a problem or tech question about your computer, phone or tablet? Give us a call and leave us a voice mail at 904-372-DEEM (3336), or send us an email to questions at deemable dot com. We&rsquo;ll take the best questions and answer them on the show.</p>
<h3>Links we mentioned on today&rsquo;s show:</h3>
<ul><li><a href="http://ElizabethPampalone.com/">ElizabethPampalone.com</a></li>
<li><a title="iMore.com | The #1 Site for iPhone, iPad, iPod touch and Apple TV owners." href="http://www.imore.com/" target="_blank">iMore.com</a></li>
<li><a title="Podcasts" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/podcasts/id525463029" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Apple Podcasts</a></li>
<li><a title="Chrome for iPhone, iPod touch, and iPad on the iTunes App Store" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/chrome/id535886823" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Google Chrome</a></li>
<li><a title="Google Drive for iPhone, iPod touch, and iPad on the iTunes App" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/google-drive/id507874739" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Google Drive</a></li>
<li><a title="Vtok: Google talk video and text chat on your mobiles" href="http://www.vtokapp.com/" target="_blank">Vtok &ndash; Google Chat</a></li>
<li><a title="Talkatone - free calls and text via WiFi or 3G" href="http://www.talkatone.com/" target="_blank">Talkatone</a></li>
<li><a title="Sparrow - Get mail done" href="http://sparrowmailapp.com/" target="_blank">Sparrow</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/apps/pages/" target="_blank">Pages</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.apple.com/apps/numbers/" target="_blank">Numbers</a> and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.apple.com/apps/keynote/" target="_blank">Keynote</a></li>
<li><a title="Netflix for iPhone, iPod touch, and iPad on the iTunes App Store" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/netflix/id363590051" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Netflix</a>, <a title="Hulu Plus for iPhone, iPod touch, and iPad on the iTunes App Store" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hulu-plus/id376510438" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Hulu</a>, <a title="HBO GO for iPhone 3GS, iPhone 4, iPhone 4S, iPhone 5, iPod touch" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hbo-go/id429775439" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">HBO GO</a>, <a title="PBS for iPhone, iPod touch, and iPad on the iTunes App Store" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pbs/id410053365" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">PBS</a>, <a href="http://to.pbs.org/pbskidsapps" target="_blank">PBS Kids</a>, and <a title="WATCH Disney Channel for iPhone, iPod touch, and iPad" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/watch-disney-channel/id529997671" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Disney Channel</a></li>
<li><a href="http://gmail.com/" target="_blank">Gmail</a> and <a href="http://Outlook.com/" target="_blank">Outlook.com</a></li>
<li><a href="http://steampowered.com/">SteamPowered.com</a></li>
<li><a title="Deemable Tech ? Episode 10 ? The Two Step Verification, Baby" href="//2012/08/deemable-tech-episode-10-the-two-step-verification-baby/" target="_blank">Deemable Tech ? Episode 10 ? The Two Step Verification, Baby</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.keyboard-and-mouse-sharing.com/">ShareMouse</a></li>
<li><a href="http://synergy-foss.org/">Synergy</a></li>
<li><a title="How to Control Multiple Computers with a Single Keyboard and Mouse - Lifehacker" href="http://lifehacker.com/254648/how-to-control-multiple-computers-with-a-single-keyboard-and-mouse" target="_blank">Lifehacker &ndash; Synergy</a></li>
<li><a href="http://mobilemouse.com/">Mobile Mouse Pro</a></li>
</ul></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2012/10/episode-18-lots-and-lots-of-questions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-10-21.mp3" length="50400862" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
