<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; data monitoring</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/data-monitoring/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Michelle asks, How can I lower my data usage on my iPhone?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2013/04/michelle-asks-how-can-i-lower-my-data-usage-on-my-iphone/</link>
		<comments>/2013/04/michelle-asks-how-can-i-lower-my-data-usage-on-my-iphone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3G]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4G]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cellular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data caps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data monitoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data usage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7300</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Smart phones put the Internet at your fingertips, allowing you to check your email and surf the web from anywhere with the power of 3G and 4G. However, if you don&#8217;t have an unlimited data plan, you can be charged <a href="/2013/04/michelle-asks-how-can-i-lower-my-data-usage-on-my-iphone/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/04/michelle-asks-how-can-i-lower-my-data-usage-on-my-iphone/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>Smart phones put the Internet at your fingertips, allowing you to check your email and surf the web from anywhere with the power of 3G and 4G. However, if you don&rsquo;t have an unlimited data plan, you can be charged more if you use it too much. Ray and Tom have some tips to make sure you&rsquo;re not going over your data limit on this week&rsquo;s Ask Deemable Tech.</p>
<p>And if you like our radio segments, make sure to check out <a href="//category/podcast/">Deemable Tech&rsquo;s weekly hour-long podcast.</a> You can subscribe to the show by clicking the following links or by searching for <a href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">Deemable Tech in iTunes</a> or <a href="http://youtube.com/deemabletech">YouTube</a>.</p>
<p><script id="prx-p96321-embed" src="http://www.prx.org/p/96321/embed.js?size=full"></script></p>
<p>RAY: Hi, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>TOM: I&rsquo;m Tom Braun,</p>
<p>RAY: and we&rsquo;re the hosts of Deemable Tech. On the show, we answer your questions about computers, tablets, mobile phones and the Internet, like this question:</p>
<p>TOM: Michelle asks, I was wondering about ways to lower my data usage on my iPhone. I always seem to go over my limit, and then I am slapped with another monthly charge. What things can I turn &ldquo;off&rdquo; or put away unless I need them, and how do I do it?</p>
<p>RAY: Thanks for your question, Michelle. iPhones and Android phones can eat up a data plan like a 5 year old with an unattended candy bowl. Unless you&rsquo;re on an unlimited data plan, you have to keep an eye on what your phone is downloading and sending, or it&rsquo;ll end up taking a bite out of your wallet.<br>
Periodically check your cellular data usage on your iPhone by opening your Settings app, and tapping General, Usage and then Cellular Usage at the bottom. On that screen you can see how much data your phone has sent and received. Each month, at the end of your billing cycle, tap the Reset Statistics button to clear out the counters and start over.</p>
<p>TOM: Well, Ray, that&rsquo;s good information about how to keep track of how much data you&rsquo;re using on an iPhone, but Michelle wanted to know how to reduce the amount of data she&rsquo;s using on an iPhone. Come on man, stay focused!</p>
<p>RAY: Well, you&rsquo;re right, but the first step to any diet is keeping track of how much you&rsquo;re consuming, or so I&rsquo;ve heard. Knowing how much data you&rsquo;re using in the first place will help to stay you on track. Now, here&rsquo;s a few tips to keep your cellular data usage low. First of all, don&rsquo;t download or stream any video or audio unless you are connected to a Wi-Fi network. Those NPR, Netflix, Hulu and PBS Kids apps will devour your cellular data. I&rsquo;m not saying don&rsquo;t use them! They&rsquo;re great apps. Just make sure to use them when you are connected to a Wi-Fi network if you&rsquo;re trying to save your cellular data.</p>
<p>TOM: And, if you have streaming video or music that you just have to watch or listen to over 3G or 4G, go for the Non-HD version or the lower quality version. That will save you a bunch of data, too. If you use Spotify, make your playlists Available Offline so that the next time you&rsquo;re away from home they&rsquo;ll play from your phone instead of over the Internet.</p>
<p>RAY: The same thing is true for Amazon Cloud Player and the Podcast app; make sure to download your songs and new podcast episodes to your device before you leave the house. Also, and it&rsquo;s probably obvious, but make sure to only download new apps and updates when you are on a Wi-Fi network too.</p>
<p>TOM: Also, try reducing the number of times that your phone downloads new email. On the iPhone, open your Settings app and tap &ldquo;Mail, Contacts, Calendars&rdquo; and then, Fetch New Data. Turn off Push, and change Fetch to Manually or, at most, Hourly.</p>
<p>RAY: Finally, If you see that you&rsquo;re getting close to your limit, or you just want to save your data plan for later in the month, turn your cellular data off. On the iPhone go to the General menu under Settings, tap Cellular and then tap the Cellular Data on/off switch. You&rsquo;ll still get phone calls and text messages, but you won&rsquo;t be able to browse the web and none of your apps will access the Internet either unless you are connected to a Wi-Fi network. You can also turn off Cellular data for specific built-in functions like iTunes, FaceTime, and Personal Hotspot in that same menu.</p>
<p>TOM: Follow all of these tips, and you should have a thinner waistline &ndash; oops, cellular bill &ndash; within a month or two!</p>
<p>RAY: To hear more answers to questions like this one, listen to our show at Deemable dot com, that&rsquo;s D-E E-M A-B-L-E dot com. There you can listen to all of our previous episodes and subscribe to our podcast.</p>
<p>TOM: If you have a question for Deemable Tech give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or you can send us an email at questions at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>RAY: For Deemable Tech, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>TOM: And I&rsquo;m Tom Braun.</p>
<p><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/production.mediajoint.prx.org/public/piece_images/226950/hand_holding_iphone_medium.jpg" title="iPhone"></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/04/michelle-asks-how-can-i-lower-my-data-usage-on-my-iphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
