<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; travel</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/travel/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Pam asks, &#8220;What electronics do I need while traveling the world?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2014/10/pam-asks-electronics-need-traveling-world/</link>
		<comments>/2014/10/pam-asks-electronics-need-traveling-world/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 16:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world phones]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9244</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/10/passport_adapters-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Phil Long / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Q: My husband and I are retiring in two years. We plan on selling our house and becoming international vagabonds. What kind of things do I need to do so we can use technology to our best advantage during our <a href="/2014/10/pam-asks-electronics-need-traveling-world/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2014/10/pam-asks-electronics-need-traveling-world/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/10/passport_adapters-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Phil Long / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><strong>Q</strong>: My husband and I are retiring in two years. We plan on selling our house and becoming international vagabonds. What kind of things do I need to do so we can use technology to our best advantage during our travels. We use Apple because it seems simple. Should I take a laptop or will a tablet work?<span id="more-9244"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_9257" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2014/10/passport_adapters.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-9257" src="/media/2014/10/passport_adapters-300x200.jpg"  alt="Image credit: Phil Long / Flickr" width="300" height="200"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: Phil Long / Flickr</p></div>
<p><strong>A:</strong> Sounds like you&rsquo;ll be living the dream, Pam! If you have both a laptop and a tablet, we say take them both. But if you have to pick one, take a laptop. You&rsquo;re going to get tired of typing emails and messages on a tablet before too long. There is a whole class of ultra-thin and lightweight laptops called &ldquo;ultrabooks&rdquo; which would work great for traveling.</p>
<p>The great news is that either one will work &ndash; just as long as you have the right adapter plugs, which you can get a set of at just about any big box store.</p>
<p>The great thing about electronics in the last couple of decades is that the power bricks dangling off them are designed to take from 100 to 240 watts of power, which basically covers all the power levels you are likely to encounter. Most electronic devices can handle all the standard voltages as well, so you just need the right adapter for the power sockets of the country you&rsquo;re in.</p>
<p>Once you have power, you&rsquo;ll want internet access. Getting online with your laptop or tablet can be easy if you&rsquo;re in a place where you have Wi-Fi. Wi-Fi is a world-wide standard, so your device can connect to Japanese or Italian Wi-Fi just as easily as American Wi-Fi.</p>
<p>Smart phones are trickier, though. Basically you have two options: you can buy cheap, disposable phones and SIM cards in every country you travel to, or you can invest in a &ldquo;world phone&rdquo;. These are smart phones that operate on almost every carrier, which when paired with world-roaming data plans can be used basically anywhere. However, this can get pretty expensive fast. Our advice is to stick to Wi-Fi when you can, and try calling land-lines using Skype. You can read more about using your phone in a different country <a title="Ric asks, ?Can I use my cell phone in another country??" href="http://deemable.com/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/" target="_blank">in this article</a>.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title='Pam asks, "What electronics do I need while traveling the world?"' data-link="/2014/10/pam-asks-electronics-need-traveling-world/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title='Pam asks, "What electronics do I need while traveling the world?"' data-link="/2014/10/pam-asks-electronics-need-traveling-world/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/10/pam-asks-electronics-need-traveling-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ric asks, &#8220;Can I use my cell phone in another country?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/</link>
		<comments>/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 17:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cell Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8115</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/08/cell_phone_passport-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Andrew Catellier / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />&#160; Q:&#160;I&#8217;m taking a trip to Costa Rica soon, and I need a simple phone to use while I&#8217;m there. I know very little about cell phones. What sort of phone should I buy for international travel, and what do <a href="/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/08/cell_phone_passport-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Andrew Catellier / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Q:&nbsp;</strong>I&rsquo;m taking a trip to Costa Rica soon, and I need a simple phone to use while I&rsquo;m there. I know very little about cell phones. What sort of phone should I buy for international travel, and what do I need to know to make sure it will work before the trip?</p>
<p><strong>A:&nbsp;</strong>Finding the right phone for international travel can get complicated and expensive in a hurry. Whatever you do, don&rsquo;t just take your normal phone to Central America and start racking up roaming charges. They start at ridiculous and go up from there. If your phone even works there, that is.</p>
<div id="attachment_8116" style="width: 316px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/08/cell_phone_passport.png" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class=" wp-image-8116     " alt="Phone and passport. Image credit: Andrew Catellier / Flickr" src="/media/2013/08/cell_phone_passport.png"  width="306" height="257"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">You&rsquo;ve got your passport and your traveler&rsquo;s cheques packed, but what about your phone?Image credit: Andrew Catellier / Flickr</p>
<p></p></div>
<p>You see, there are two main types of cell networks worldwide: GSM and CDMA. GSM is the worldwide standard while CDMA is most common in the US. So you really want a GSM phone, specifically a &ldquo;quad band&rdquo; GSM phone. A &ldquo;quad band&rdquo; GSM phone will work on just about any cell network in any country. One such phone is the iPhone 4S. The iPhone 5 also supports quad band&hellip; providing you bought yours in Europe.</p>
<p>The type of network your phone is compatible with is determined by the carrier you bought it for. The US carriers that use GSM are AT&amp;T and T-Mobile. Sprint and Verizon use CDMA. LTE networks are basically all completely incompatible with each other (which is why American iPhone 5&rsquo;s will most likely not work in another country). Once you have a quad-band GSM phone, you will need to buy an international SIM card so you can make calls without racking up astronomical roaming charges.</p>
<p>Now, if this all sounds complicated, that&rsquo;s because it is. Don&rsquo;t fret, though, because there&rsquo;s a simple trick to finding a phone that is guaranteed to work cheaply in the country you are visiting: wait until you get to Costa Rica, and buy a phone there. When you arrive in Costa Rica, go to the local mobile store and buy the cheapest prepaid cell phone you can find. We be there will be one you can buy for under $30 (US dollars). Whatever you do, don&rsquo;t buy a phone or SIM card at or near the airport, because prices are almost always much higher there. Once you get out of the airport, ask a local to point you to a good, cheap store.</p>
<p>Of course, you won&rsquo;t be able to call your folks in Sarasota on your el cheapo Costa Rican prepaid phone, Ric. But there&rsquo;s an easy solution for that, too. You can use the popular Internet telephony software Skype to call real phone numbers, anywhere in the world. It&rsquo;s not free, but it&rsquo;s very cheap. Before you leave, buy some Skype credit, download the Skype app for your smartphone, and take it with you to Costa Rica. Then when you&rsquo;re on Wi-Fi, just log in to Skype and call home like normal!</p>
<p>In general, buying a cheap phone in the country you will be visiting is a good plan, and pretty foolproof. However if you expect to be traveling to multiple countries, or you need to call other countries while you&rsquo;re there and you won&rsquo;t have consistent access to Wi-Fi, you need an unlocked, quad-band GSM phone and an international SIM card. You can buy prepaid international SIM cards from companies like <a href="http://www.telestial.com/">Telestial</a> and <a href="http://www.onesimcard.com/">OneSimCard</a> for under $50. Just remember, you&rsquo;ll need a phone to match.</p>
<p>To sum up, if you absolutely have to make a lot of international calls while you&rsquo;re there, you&rsquo;ll need an unlocked, quad-band GSM phone such as the iPhone 4S and an international SIM card. If not, you can just buy a cheap prepaid phone once you land.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title='Ric asks, "Can I use my cell phone in another country?"' data-link="/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title='Ric asks, "Can I use my cell phone in another country?"' data-link="/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
