<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; violent</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/violent/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Supreme Court: Violent Video Games = Free Speech</title>
		<link>/2011/06/supreme-court-violent-video-games-free-speech/</link>
		<comments>/2011/06/supreme-court-violent-video-games-free-speech/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 19:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Ahn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[California]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Supreme Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video Game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[violent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=3735</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On Monday, the U.S.&#160;Supreme Court ruled&#160;in a 7-to-2 majority opinion against a California law that banned the sale of violent video games to children in the case&#160;Brown v. Entertainment Merchants Association.&#160;The majority opinion, written by Justice Antonin Scalia, says that&#160;video <a href="/2011/06/supreme-court-violent-video-games-free-speech/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/06/supreme-court-violent-video-games-free-speech/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://fc00.deviantart.net/fs71/i/2010/337/1/8/call_of_duty_nazi_zombies_by_blackspider_man-d3442df.jpg" alt="" width="437" height="276"></p>
<p>On Monday, the U.S.&nbsp;Supreme Court ruled&nbsp;in a 7-to-2 <a title="Majority Opinion" href="http://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/10pdf/08-1448.pdf" target="_blank">majority opinion</a> against a California law that banned the sale of violent video games to children in the case&nbsp;<em>Brown v. Entertainment Merchants Association</em>.&nbsp;The majority opinion, written by Justice Antonin Scalia, says that&nbsp;video games &ldquo;qualify for First Amendment protection. Like protected books, plays, and movies, they communicate ideas through familiar literary devices and features distinctive to the medium.&rdquo; The First Amendment essentially provides those protected by the U.S. Constitution with the right to freedom of expression, and in this instance, video games are a way to communicate ideas.</p>
<p>The California law would have prohibited the sale or rental of violent video games to minors under the age of 18, with violent video games defined as &ldquo;killing, maiming, dismembering, or sexually assaulting an image of a human being.&rdquo; Retailers who violated the act would have been fined up to $1,000 per infraction. The video game law was originally signed by then-California Gov. Arnold Schwarzenegger in October of 2005 but was <a title="blocked" href="http://news.cnet.com/Judge-blocks-California-video-game-law/2100-1043_3-6005835.html" target="_blank">blocked by a federal judge</a>, whose decision was upheld by the U.S. Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals. The state of California appealed to the Supreme Court to overturn those decisions in May of 2009.</p>
<p>Justices Clarence Thomas and Stephen Breyer dissented from the Supreme Court&rsquo;s ruling. Thomas said that the view at the time when the Bill of Rights was originally amended&nbsp;&ldquo;does not include a right to speak to minors (or a right of minors to access speech) without going through the minors&rsquo; parents or guardians,&rdquo; and Breyer wrote,&nbsp;&ldquo;California&rsquo;s law imposes no more than a modest restriction on expression. The statute prevents no one from playing a video game, it prevents no adult from buying a video game, and it prevents no child or adolescent from obtaining a game provided a parent is willing to help.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The Supreme Court ruling, however, is a huge win for the video game industry which makes $10.5 billion in domestic annual sales. The computer and video game industry are represented by the Entertainment Software Association (ESA) in the United States, with&nbsp;members including Disney Interactive Studios, Electronic Arts, Microsoft Corp, and Sony Computer Entertainment America.&nbsp;Michael D. Gallagher, the president and CEO of the ESA stated,&nbsp;&ldquo;Today, the Supreme Court affirmed what we have always known&ndash;that free speech protections apply every bit as much to video games as they do to other forms of creative expression like books, movies and music&hellip; The Court declared forcefully that content-based restrictions on games are unconstitutional; and that parents, not government bureaucrats, have the right to decide what is appropriate for their children.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The Supreme Court&rsquo;s decision will most likely put an end to all the expensive litigation by individual states to ban the sale of violent video games to minors, and undoubtedly put a smile on the faces of children who have been patiently waiting to kill some nazi zombies.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://fc00.deviantart.net/fs71/i/2010/337/1/8/call_of_duty_nazi_zombies_by_blackspider_man-d3442df.jpg" target="_blank">Photo</a> by <a title="BlackSpider-Man" href="http://blackspider-man.deviantart.com/" target="_blank">BlackSpider-Man</a> via <a title="DeviantArt" href="http://www.deviantart.com/" target="_blank">DeviantArt</a></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/06/supreme-court-violent-video-games-free-speech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
