<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Lumia 920</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/lumia-920/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Nokia unveils flagship Windows 8 smartphone Lumia 920</title>
		<link>/2012/09/nokia-unveils-flagship-windows-8-smartphone/</link>
		<comments>/2012/09/nokia-unveils-flagship-windows-8-smartphone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 15:43:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tom Braun]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lumia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lumia 920]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nokia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows Phone 8]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=5450</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/09/nokia-lumia-920-color-range-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Nokia Lumia 920 - All of the colors" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Wednesday at a New York City press event, Nokia unveiled two new Windows 8 phones: the Nokia Lumia 920 and the Nokia Lumia 820. A Microsoft representative was present at the event to show off some of the phone&#8217;s Windows <a href="/2012/09/nokia-unveils-flagship-windows-8-smartphone/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2012/09/nokia-unveils-flagship-windows-8-smartphone/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/09/nokia-lumia-920-color-range-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Nokia Lumia 920 - All of the colors" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2012/09/nokia-lumia-920-color-range.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-5458" src="/media/2012/09/nokia-lumia-920-color-range-300x300.jpg"  alt="" width="300" height="300"></a>Wednesday at a New York City press event, Nokia unveiled two new Windows 8 phones: the <a title="Nokia Lumia 920 specs" href="http://www.nokia.com/global/products/phone/lumia920/specifications/" target="_blank">Nokia Lumia 920</a> and the <a title="Nokia Lumia 820 specs" href="http://www.nokia.com/global/products/phone/lumia820/specifications/" target="_blank">Nokia Lumia 820</a>.</p>
<p>A Microsoft representative was present at the event to show off some of the phone&rsquo;s Windows 8-specific features. The company has apparently taken a page from the Google playbook and decided that Windows 8 phones need a flagship, similar to Android&rsquo;s Samsung Galaxy Nexus phone. It would appear that the Nokia Lumia 920 is that flagship.</p>
<p>Nokia is an interesting choice as Microsoft&rsquo;s primary partner for Windows Phone 8 as the company has been hemorrhaging market share to Samsung and HTC in the last couple years, while posting billion dollar losses.</p>
<p>The Lumia 920 that Nokia showed off at Wednesday&rsquo;s event looked impressive, however, with a major focus on a powerful camera that uses ?floating lens&rsquo; technology to stabilize video and take high-quality photographs in low-light situations. Another camera-based integrated feature is ?City Lens&rsquo;, an augmented reality app that tags the environment around the user with information about businesses and restaurants. Nokia is marketing the screen on the phone as ?HD+&rsquo; and claims that it shows up well even in direct sunlight.</p>
<p>The phone also boasts native support for the Qi wireless charging standard.</p>
<p>Nokia has not neglected its new phones&rsquo; styling: the 920 comes in a variety of bright, vibrant colors including ?spectacular yellow, stunning lipstick red and seductive gray.? The 820 features easily swappable snap-on backs in a variety of colors. Both phones boast a rounded form-factor, including curved Gorilla Glass screens. Customers are certainly unlikely to confuse the new Nokia Lumia phones with any other smartphone.</p>
<p>There were a couple small flies in the ointment after the unveiling. Nokia admitted that its impressive side-by-side image stabilization comparisons were not shot with the actual phone. They have now <a title="Nokia's apology and updated demo" href="http://conversations.nokia.com/2012/09/06/an-apology-is-due/" target="_blank">posted a new demo video</a>&nbsp;using the actual phone. While the Lumia 920&rsquo;s stabilized video certainly compares favorably against the iPhone 4s, it&rsquo;s not as effortlessly smooth as the original demo video. Some bloggers are also <a href="http://sefsar.com/nokia-faked-the-still-photos-too" target="_blank">calling some of the demo images of the phone&rsquo;s low-light photo capabilities into question</a>, but we&rsquo;ll probably have to wait until the phone is out in the wild to see how its night-shot camera really stacks up.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s no word yet on the official release date although it will probably coincide closely with the official release of Windows 8. The final&nbsp;phone is expected&nbsp;to boast a 1.5GHz dual-core Snapdragon S4&nbsp;processor and 32 mb of on-board memory (no expandable SD slot, though). Pricing and carriers have yet to be announced.</p>
<p>Both Microsoft and Nokia have a lot riding on the new Lumia phones. Microsoft needs to get a ?must-have&rsquo; Windows 8 phone into the marketplace in order to&nbsp;seriously compete with iOS and Android. And Nokia desperately needs a big hit to help it regain its old position as a major phone maker, or at least put it back in the black.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Nokia unveils flagship Windows 8 smartphone Lumia 920" data-link="/2012/09/nokia-unveils-flagship-windows-8-smartphone/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Nokia unveils flagship Windows 8 smartphone Lumia 920" data-link="/2012/09/nokia-unveils-flagship-windows-8-smartphone/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2012/09/nokia-unveils-flagship-windows-8-smartphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
