<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Chrissy Das</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/chrissydas/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Can a LinkedIn Profile Help New Professionals Get Jobs?</title>
		<link>/2014/01/can-linkedin-profile-help-new-professionals/</link>
		<comments>/2014/01/can-linkedin-profile-help-new-professionals/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 12:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chrissy Das]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[job applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resume]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web 2.0]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8552</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/01/LinkedIn_sq-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="New Professional LinkedIn" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Spring semester is in full swing for college students around the world and the Class of 2014 will be entering the job market in mere months. Unemployment rates are still scary at 6.7%&#160;but there are ways to improve the likelihood <a href="/2014/01/can-linkedin-profile-help-new-professionals/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2014/01/can-linkedin-profile-help-new-professionals/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/01/LinkedIn_sq-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="New Professional LinkedIn" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>Spring semester is in full swing for college students around the world and the Class of 2014 will be entering the job market in mere months. Unemployment rates are still scary at <a title="Bureau of Labor Statistics" href="http://data.bls.gov/timeseries/LNS14000000" target="_blank">6.7%</a>&nbsp;but there are ways to improve the likelihood of landing an interview. If you are planning to enter the job market in the coming months, here&rsquo;s how to position yourself on <a title="LinkedIn" href="http://www.linkedin.com/" target="_blank">LinkedIn</a>:</p>
<p><a href="/media/2014/01/LinkedIn_sq.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox" rel="attachment wp-att-8554"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-8554" style="margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 25px;" alt="New Professional LinkedIn" src="/media/2014/01/LinkedIn_sq-300x300.jpg"  width="300" height="300"></a></p>
<h4><strong>Create a profile.</strong></h4>
<p><strong></strong>Use a permanent personal email account. You can add your work or school email after you&rsquo;ve set up your profile. LinkedIn will suggest you import your email contacts each time you add an email address. Be aware if you do import your contacts, LinkedIn may send them a connection request. This can be a problem if you do not update your contact list. It&rsquo;s better to connect with people on an individual basis rather than en masse.</p>
<h4><strong>Upload a headshot.</strong></h4>
<p>A picture is worth a thousand words and yours should express your personality while appealing to employers in your industry. You can improve your personal brand by using the same picture across your social media accounts. Your Twitter account with thoughtful posts about industry trends can confirm to potential employers that they&rsquo;ve found the right person.</p>
<h4><strong>Craft an SEO-approved headline.&nbsp;</strong></h4>
<p>LinkedIn gives you 120 characters to sell yourself. Use that space to squeeze in some industry keywords. Are you actively seeking employment? Consider starting your headline with &ldquo;Seeking Employment As [Insert Job Title].&rdquo;Now that you have started setting up your LinkedIn profile, adjust your privacy settings. Turn off broadcast of your activity while making frequent changes to your profile. You can turn this feature on again when you are ready to announce new positions or skills.</p>
<h4><strong>Explain your personal brand in the Summary.</strong></h4>
<p>Use this space to introduce yourself to future employers or clients. You have 2,000 characters to present your story. Keep it professional and remember to use keywords common to your desired profession.</p>
<h4><strong>Add current and previous positions.</strong></h4>
<p>LinkedIn allows you to add as much of your work history as you desire. Focus on the jobs you enjoyed most and the ones that showcase skills you want to utilize in the future.</p>
<p>Now you&rsquo;re ready to start adding connections. Not sure how to build a strong network? Check back for Part 2: Building a Solid LinkedIn Network.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/01/can-linkedin-profile-help-new-professionals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Launching a Bakery in a Tech World</title>
		<link>/2013/01/launching_bakery_in_a_tech_world/</link>
		<comments>/2013/01/launching_bakery_in_a_tech_world/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 10:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chrissy Das]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kickstarter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=6733</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/01/seven-wonders-bakery-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Bonnie is using Kickstarter to raise money for cleaning, remodeling and opening costs." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Bonnie Kilgore-Conde is a grandmother of 8 with the energy of a 20-something. She&#8217;s going to need that energy to launch Seven Wonders Bakery in Jacksonville, Florida.&#160;Bonnie is using&#160;Kickstarter&#160;to raise money for cleaning, remodeling and opening costs. Seven Wonders Bakery <a href="/2013/01/launching_bakery_in_a_tech_world/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/01/launching_bakery_in_a_tech_world/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/01/seven-wonders-bakery-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Bonnie is using Kickstarter to raise money for cleaning, remodeling and opening costs." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>Bonnie Kilgore-Conde is a grandmother of 8 with the energy of a 20-something. She&rsquo;s going to need that energy to launch Seven Wonders Bakery in Jacksonville, Florida.&nbsp;Bonnie is using&nbsp;<a title="Bonnie's Kickstarter Page" href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1970953054/seven-wonders-bakery-serving-a-diverse-community" target="_blank">Kickstarter</a>&nbsp;to raise money for cleaning, remodeling and opening costs. Seven Wonders Bakery has been dormant since 2008 and Bonnie contacted the original owners through access to public records.</p>
<div id="attachment_6772" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="/media/2013/01/seven-wonders-bakery.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox" rel="attachment wp-att-6772"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6772   " style="margin: 0px" alt="Bonnie is using Kickstarter to raise money for cleaning, remodeling and opening costs." src="/media/2013/01/seven-wonders-bakery-300x224.jpg"  width="300" height="224"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Bonnie is using <a title="Bonnie's Kickstarter Page" href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1970953054/seven-wonders-bakery-serving-a-diverse-community" target="_blank">Kickstarter</a> to raise money for cleaning, remodeling and opening costs.</p></div>
<p>Bonnie envisions the bakery as a place where college students will come from nearby Jacksonville University and University of Florida and enjoy the cafe and free access to Wifi. Community members will come for birthday cakes, graduation cakes, and pastries for parties. She values the diversity of Jacksonville and the bakery will highlight desserts from around the globe.</p>
<p>A north Georgia native, Bonnie grew up in Lookout Mountain with limited access to the latest technology. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s two mountains and a valley; you&rsquo;ll pass it in 30 minutes. In high school we had two computers each the size of a coffee table and seniors were the only ones who could sign up to use them.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Now, Bonnie uses her smart phone, laptop, desktop and a digital camera almost daily. Bonnie created the <a href="http://kck.st/11y3jkl" target="_blank">Kickstarter video</a> advertising her campaign by using her digital camera and adding a voiceover using the built-in microphone on her laptop. She&rsquo;s planning to use a ipad with a Square attachment to accept credit cards when she opens the bakery sometime in late March or early April.</p>
<p>Bonnie&rsquo;s been around the world since growing up in Georgia. A few years ago, she relocated from Los Angeles&nbsp;to Jacksonville. Kickstarter caught her attention when a friend&rsquo;s son explained that many of the movies featured in Sundance receive their funding through the website.</p>
<p>Since launching her Kickstarter campaign on January 15, Bonnie has received attention from online backers and offline donations. She&rsquo;s also gained Basha Staub as a business partner.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Basha and I come from medical administration backgrounds and we have both been baking for decades. She saw my Kickstarter page and contacted me. We hit it off right away and were bouncing ideas off of each other as quick as anything,&rdquo; gushes Bonnie.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s a lot to be done before the bakery can open for business. These instant collaborators are using their resources to update the inside of the bakery and market their wares. They have access to two contractors (Basha&rsquo;a husband and Bonnie&rsquo;s father) and a wealth of family members vowing to help them launch on time.</p>
<p>The original&nbsp;<a href="www.sevenwondersbakery.com/" target="_blank">bakery website</a>&nbsp;will keep its URL but is scheduled for a facelift before the grand opening. For now, you can visit them on&nbsp;<a title="Seven Wonders Bakery Facebook Page" href="www.facebook.com/SevenWondersInternationalBakery" target="_blank">Facebook</a>.</p>
<p>You can donate to Bonnie&rsquo;s campaign by visiting her Kickstarter page <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1970953054/seven-wonders-bakery-serving-a-diverse-community" target="_blank">here</a>. Contributions will be accepted through Valentine&rsquo;s Day.</p>
<p>Bonnie&rsquo;s Buttery Citrus Cake recipe is below.</p>
<p><strong>Buttery Citrus Cake</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_6770" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2013/01/Buttery-Citrus-Cake.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox" rel="attachment wp-att-6770"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6770" alt="Photo provided by Bonnie Kilgore-Conde" src="/media/2013/01/Buttery-Citrus-Cake-300x200.jpg"  width="300" height="200"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo provided by Bonnie Kilgore-Conde</p></div>
<p>Ingredients</p>
<p>&frac34; cup of butter</p>
<p>6 egg yolks or 3 whole eggs</p>
<p>2 2/3 Cups of all purpose flour (I find you make a lighter cake if the flour is sifted</p>
<p>2 teaspoons of baking powder</p>
<p>&frac12; teaspoon of salt</p>
<p>&frac14; teaspoon of baking soda</p>
<p>1 2/3 cups of sugar</p>
<p>1 cup of milk</p>
<p>2 teaspoons of finely shredded lemon or lime peel</p>
<p>1 teaspoon finely shredded orange peel</p>
<p>2 tablespoons of lemon or lime juice</p>
<p>2 tablespoons of orange juice</p>
<p>Preheat oven to 375 degrees</p>
<p>Combine flour, baking powder, salt, and baking soda. Set aside. (If possible use a whisk to really combine these dry ingredients together)</p>
<p>In another bowl beat the butter until fluffy, then beat in the sugar, then add the yolks in one at a time and beat.</p>
<p>Add the flour mixture and milk alternately and beat into the butter, sugar, and egg mixture. Begin and end with flour mixture. (This may seem silly to start and end with the flour mixture, but if you don&rsquo;t you will notice that your cake will not bake at the consistency that you desire)</p>
<p>Last stir in the peels and juices. Bake 20 to 25 minutes.</p>
<p><strong>Lemon, Lime, or Orange Whipped Cream Frosting</strong></p>
<p>In a chilled bowl (glass or metal in the freezer for a few minutes will work great) beat 2 cups of heavy whipping cream, 2 tablespoons of powdered sugar, and 1 tablespoon of instant vanilla pudding. Beat until stiff peaks form. Fold in 1 tablespoon on shredded lemon, lime, or orange peelings.</p>
<p>I find if I double the frosting recipe I have a prettier and more well covered layer cake.</p>
<p>This cake makes 12 servings.</p>
<p>Thin slices of Meyers lemons, limes, or oranges make a very nice garnish.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/01/launching_bakery_in_a_tech_world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Ways to Keep in Touch After the Holidays</title>
		<link>/2013/01/5-ways-to-keep-in-touch/</link>
		<comments>/2013/01/5-ways-to-keep-in-touch/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 13:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chrissy Das]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video Calls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video Chat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VOIP]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=6555</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/01/Sisters-at-Christmas-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Sisters at Christmas" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />&#8220;Fish and visitors smell after three days.&#8221; &#8211; Benjamin Franklin You&#8217;ve survived and (dare I say, enjoyed) the 2012 Holidays with your distant relatives. It&#8217;s nice getting the family together for a few days. The hustle and bustle of the <a href="/2013/01/5-ways-to-keep-in-touch/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/01/5-ways-to-keep-in-touch/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/01/Sisters-at-Christmas-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Sisters at Christmas" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>&ldquo;Fish and visitors smell after three days.&rdquo; &ndash; Benjamin Franklin</p>
<p>You&rsquo;ve survived and (dare I say, enjoyed) the 2012 Holidays with your distant relatives. It&rsquo;s nice getting the family together for a few days. The hustle and bustle of the holidays can be overwhelming and the sudden silence after guests leave can be gloomy. &nbsp;Technology can make the transition back to everyday life a lot easier.</p>
<p><a href="/media/2013/01/Sisters-at-Christmas.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox" rel="attachment wp-att-6582"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-6582" alt="Sisters at Christmas" src="/media/2013/01/Sisters-at-Christmas-300x225.jpg"  width="300" height="225"></a></p>
<p>If your brother and his family live in Seattle, Washington and you live in Jacksonville, Florida, chances are you won&rsquo;t be able to afford to see him or your cute nieces and nephews more than a few times a year. You don&rsquo;t have to rack up thousands of frequent flier miles to be a good aunt or uncle; use these five ways to keep in touch:</p>
<ol><ol><li><a title="Skype's Website" href="www.skype.com" target="_blank">Skype</a><br>
If everyone has a webcam and fast enough wifi, Skype provides an inexpensive way to sing &ldquo;Happy Birthday&rdquo; to any friend or family member anywhere on the globe. It works on Android and iOS, allowing it to work on most smartphones and computers. The video quality isn&rsquo;t always the best but the price is free if both people have Skype. If you want to do a group video call, there is a premium option explained <a title="Skype Premium" href="http://beta.skype.com/en/premium/" target="_blank">here</a>.</li>
<li><a title="Apple's FaceTime" href="http://www.apple.com/ios/facetime/" target="_blank">FaceTime</a><br>
iMac, iPhone, iPod, iPad. These will all come pre-installed with FaceTime. This application uses the built-in webcam &nbsp;to connect people across the city and around the world. The video quality tends to be a little better than Skype but it only works if everyone owns an Apple product.</li>
<li><a title="Google Chat" href="https://www.google.com/chat/video" target="_blank">Google Chat<br></a>With a free Google or Gmail account, you can instant message or video chat with friends around the globe. The account is free and with <a title="Google + Hangouts" href="http://www.google.com/+/learnmore/hangouts/" target="_blank">Google+</a> you can create a Hangout that allows group video chat.</li>
<li><a title="Facebook" href="www.facebook.com" target="_blank">Facebook</a><br>
Privacy concerns may be an issue for some people but if enough of your friends and family are on Facebook, it can be worthwhile for you to be as well. Facebook events and private group messages can make Grandma&rsquo;s Surprise Birthday Party the event of the year. Remember to make the event Private and Invite Only otherwise it won&rsquo;t be a surprise from Grandma.</li>
<li>Cellphone or Landline<br>
If you can&rsquo;t touch or see someone, sometime&rsquo;s voice is the next best thing. Check your cellphone plan to see when it&rsquo;s the cheapest to call. Free nights and weekends, mobile-to-mobile, and unlimited texting are possible perks of a contract cellphone.</li>
</ol></ol><p>Did I miss your favorite way to contact your family long distance? Tell me in the comments!</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/01/5-ways-to-keep-in-touch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>2013 Tech Resolutions</title>
		<link>/2013/01/2013-tech-resolutions/</link>
		<comments>/2013/01/2013-tech-resolutions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 17:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chrissy Das]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Year's Resolutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Years]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=6543</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/01/technology-fireworks-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="technology fireworks" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Happy New Year! If you are reading this post, we at Deemable Tech will assume you made it home safely last night. Ready to make 2013 New Year&#8217;s Resolutions? Instead of swearing of chocolate and bread for the year, why <a href="/2013/01/2013-tech-resolutions/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/01/2013-tech-resolutions/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/01/technology-fireworks-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="technology fireworks" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>Happy New Year! If you are reading this post, we at Deemable Tech will assume you made it home safely last night.</p>
<p><a href="/media/2013/01/technology-fireworks.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox" rel="attachment wp-att-6545"><img class=" wp-image-6545 alignleft" style="border: 0px;margin-left: 25px;margin-right: 25px" alt="technology fireworks" src="/media/2013/01/technology-fireworks-300x261.jpg"  width="231" height="201"></a></p>
<p>Ready to make 2013 New Year&rsquo;s Resolutions? Instead of swearing of chocolate and bread for the year, why not make some improvements in your use of technology?</p>
<p>Here are a few resolutions to get you started:</p>
<ul><li><strong>I will protect and upkeep my electronics.<br></strong>Did you make out like a bandit and get lots of cool stuff for Christmas? Now is the time to buy a screen protector and a case, my friend.</li>
</ul><ul><li><strong>I will do my research before buying a new gadget.<br></strong>It&rsquo;s the&nbsp;best/shiniest/biggest/smallest version ever! Do you need it at the midnight release or can it wait six months for the price to drop? Stay tuned to our site and we&rsquo;ll keep you in the loop.</li>
</ul><ul><li><strong>I will put down my cellphone / tablet / e-reader when interacting with friends and family.<br></strong>Work on building personal relationships instead of beating their high score on Words with Friends.</li>
</ul><ul><li><strong>I will set up automated banking so I can save up for the next gadget and pay my bills on time.<br></strong>In the age of online banking and virtual billing statements, it is easier than ever to set up a firm financial foundation. Services such as <a href="http://www.smartypig.com/">SmartyPig</a>&nbsp;can provide a seamless way to automatically take $10 or $15 and sock it away until you save enough for a bigger television or the next laptop.</li>
</ul><ul><li><strong>I will organize my email inbox.<br></strong>Do you have hundreds of emails in your inbox? Start the year off by eliminating some of the digital clutter you&rsquo;ve accrued. You can delete the newsletter from March 2012, &nbsp;we promise.</li>
</ul><ul><li><strong>I will change my passwords monthly.<br></strong>Want to make it easy for a stranger to access your email, banking information, and social media accounts? Use a different password for each one and change it every month or two. It will make it more difficult for you to remember your passwords but it will also provide a deterrent to unauthorized users hacking your accounts.</li>
</ul><p>What are your New Year&rsquo;s Resolutions? Let us know in the comments.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/01/2013-tech-resolutions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Technology and the Small Business</title>
		<link>/2012/12/technology-and-the-small-business/</link>
		<comments>/2012/12/technology-and-the-small-business/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 03:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chrissy Das]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art Walk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Small Business]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=6403</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/12/Optimized-IMG_0576-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Nicole and her ipad" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Nicole Butler is a self-described geek. She is also the owner of Nicole Made This, a small business specializing in handcrafted items such as soaps, lotions, scrubs and other spa items. She was kind enough to sit down with Deemable <a href="/2012/12/technology-and-the-small-business/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2012/12/technology-and-the-small-business/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/12/Optimized-IMG_0576-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Nicole and her ipad" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>Nicole Butler is a self-described geek. She is also the owner of <a title="Nicole Made This" href="www.nicolemadethis.com" target="_blank">Nicole Made This</a>, a small business specializing in handcrafted items such as soaps, lotions, scrubs and other spa items. She was kind enough to sit down with Deemable for an interview while setting up for <a title="Jacksonville Art Walk" href="http://www.downtownjacksonville.org/Marketing/First_Wednesday_Artwalk.aspx" target="_blank">Art Walk</a>. Art Walk is a fun-filled event held the first Wednesday of every month in downtown Jacksonville that features local artists and vendors. It&rsquo;s a great place to pick up one-of-a-kind items and visit Nicole. She&rsquo;s in the Visitors&rsquo; Center on Laura Street across from Chamblin&rsquo;s&nbsp;Bookmine.</p>
<p><a href="/media/2012/12/Optimized-IMG_0576.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox" rel="attachment wp-att-6406"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6406 alignleft" style="margin-left: 10px; margin-right: 10px;" src="/media/2012/12/Optimized-IMG_0576-300x225.jpg"  alt="" width="300" height="225"></a></p>
<div><strong>DT: As a small business, how does technology help you compete with bigger</strong>&nbsp;<strong>businesses?</strong></div>
<p>NB: A larger business is typically a less efficient &ldquo;machine.&rdquo; &nbsp;As a very&nbsp;small organization, I can implement changes and improvements almost&nbsp;immediately. &nbsp;Because I control all aspects of my electronic presence,&nbsp;I can carry those changes through my entire business within a matter&nbsp;of moments. &nbsp;I have often joked that the ability to change with the&nbsp;times is imperative to growth and success &ndash; &ldquo;adapt or die&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Technology enables me to improve and evolve with the rapid pace of&nbsp;today&rsquo;s market.</p>
<p><strong>DT: What&rsquo;s your favorite business app for the iPad?</strong></p>
<p>NB: Square Register. &nbsp;I can process payments and control my inventory and&nbsp;purchasing with the touch of a few buttons.</p>
<div><a href="/media/2012/12/Optimized-IMG_0575.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox" rel="attachment wp-att-6407"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-6407" style="margin-left: 10px; margin-right: 10px;" src="/media/2012/12/Optimized-IMG_0575-300x225.jpg"  alt="" width="300" height="225"></a></div>
<div><strong>DT: How do you keep track of which products are most popular?</strong></div>
<p>NB: I utilize&nbsp;the inventory controls in Square for in-person purchases, as&nbsp;well as the in-depth status tools available to me on Etsy.</p>
<div><strong>DT: Do you connect with clients on Facebook, Twitter, Google+, or Pinterest?</strong></div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>NB: All of the above. Check out my links here:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Nicole-Made-This-Purveyor-of-the-Best-Bath-Goodies-on-the-Planet/189212491107373?fref=ts" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://plus.google.com/111252612243743379492/posts" target="_blank">Google+</a>, Pinterest, and <a href="http://www.etsy.com/shop/nicolemadethisinc?ref=seller_info" target="_blank">Etsy</a>. I would love to connect with you.&nbsp;I prefer Etsy&nbsp;and Pinterest although Facebook and Google+ are great online&nbsp;tools!</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>I find as an artisan of specialty/niche products that I am&nbsp;better able to target my demographic market via Etsy&nbsp;and Pinterest&nbsp;whereas&nbsp;Facebook and Google+ tend to reach a much broader market.&nbsp;It&rsquo;s a lot easier for me to get lost in the shuffle on Facebook or Google+ so I focus my energy on where I have the most success.</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div><strong>DT: What is the piece of technology you can&rsquo;t live without?</strong></div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>NB: iPhone/iPad!</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>Know of a small business using technology in a super cool way? Have them email chrissydas (at) deemable (dot) com and she may feature them in a future post.</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>What piece of technology helps you get the job done? Tell us in the comments!</div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2012/12/technology-and-the-small-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;The Creationists&#8221; at Players by the Sea</title>
		<link>/2011/02/the-creationists-at-players-by-the-sea/</link>
		<comments>/2011/02/the-creationists-at-players-by-the-sea/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 06:03:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chrissy Das]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joshua Kreis McTiernan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Players by the Sea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Creationists]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=510</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Sometimes when it comes to art you have to be the one to initiate,&#8221; states Joshua Kreis McTiernan, writer and director of The Creationists. On a minimalist stage, his characters learn to initiate art for themselves.&#160;The play is loosely structured <a href="/2011/02/the-creationists-at-players-by-the-sea/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/02/the-creationists-at-players-by-the-sea/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>&ldquo;Sometimes when it comes to art you have to be the one to initiate,&rdquo; states <a title="Interview with Joshua Kreis McTiernan" href="//2011/02/entertainment/interview-with-joshua-kreis-mctiernan/" target="_blank">Joshua Kreis McTiernan</a>, writer and director of <em>The Creationists</em>.</p>
<p>On a minimalist stage, his characters learn to initiate art for themselves.&nbsp;The play is loosely structured around a narrator leading three characters through a story. A scene replays as the narrator directs the evolving characters.&rdquo;I know your character is suffering from amnesia right now,&rdquo; the Narrator says to Cameron. &ldquo;Can you try to be a little less convincing with that?&rdquo;</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s something for everyone in this whimsical comedy. References to Austen, Dickens, and Wilde will delight&nbsp;English majors and casual readers. Physical humor eases the audience into the deeper waters of the search for identity.</p>
<p>The Narrator (Brian Fullfod) takes a break from creating the story of Cameron (Cameron Lee Henderson), Kai (Philip Harville), and Tyler (Tyler Christian Ramirez), never to return. The audience tensed in collective disbelief when the Erasers come to eliminate the story at hand. Kai&rsquo;s shrieks jolt the audience, &ldquo;There are characters and there are narrators. There&rsquo;s a huge difference between them!&rdquo;</p>
<p>The second act is laden with intertextual relationships. Scenes and characters from well-loved classics are adapted for interaction with Cameron, Kai, and Tyler. The audience laughs freely at Mrs. Bennet&rsquo;s antics and cheers Tyler as he wrestles Jack from <em>Lord of the Flies</em>.</p>
<p>McTiernan&rsquo;s aptly named show, &ldquo;The Creationists&rdquo; induces the audience to an imaginative state where men play women, guns aren&rsquo;t loaded, and characters are encouraged to be their own narrators.</p>
<p>The cast received a standing ovation from a full house. Don&rsquo;t miss the two final performances at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.playersbythesea.org/Home.aspx" target="_blank">Players by the Sea</a> on February 25 or 26 at 8:00 p.m.&nbsp;<a title="Purchase tickets" href="http://www.playersbythesea.org/Tickets.aspx" target="_blank">Tickets</a> are $12 for students and $15 for adults.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/02/the-creationists-at-players-by-the-sea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 iPhone Apps to Keep Business Running as Usual</title>
		<link>/2011/02/5-iphone-apps-to-keep-business-running-as-usual/</link>
		<comments>/2011/02/5-iphone-apps-to-keep-business-running-as-usual/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 13:10:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chrissy Das]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer separation anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dropbox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GoDocs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iCal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MacBook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pulse]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=413</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/02/iphone41-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="iphone4" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />I have a confession to make. I am attached to my laptop. I fall asleep with it running near my bed. When I wake up, I check my email before I brush my teeth. As a freelance writer, my livelihood <a href="/2011/02/5-iphone-apps-to-keep-business-running-as-usual/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/02/5-iphone-apps-to-keep-business-running-as-usual/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/02/iphone41-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="iphone4" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>I have a confession to make. I am attached to my laptop. I fall asleep with it running near my bed. When I wake up, I check my email before I brush my teeth. As a freelance writer, my livelihood depends on a steady connection and speedy applications. Last week I reluctantly put my MacBook in the hands of a computer repair friend and he noted, &ldquo;You have computer separation anxiety.&rdquo; While CSA is not (yet) recognized by any psychology journals, there are some options to lessen the fear that comes from being away from your computer.<br>
These apps can keep your business running whether you are sneaking your iPhone with you on a family vacation* or working through lunch.</p>
<div class="apps"><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/iphoneapp"><img class="logos" src="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/dropbox-small.png" alt="Dropbox App Logo" width="48" height="48"></a><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/iphoneapp" target="_blank">Dropbox</a> It&rsquo;s easy to work across multiple computers when I put my work in progress in Dropbox. It&rsquo;s secure and syncs quickly.</div>
<div class="apps"><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pulse-news-mini/id377594176?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow"><img class="logos" src="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/pulse-logo-e1298430988102.png" alt="Pulse App Logo" width="48" height="48"></a><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pulse-news-mini/id377594176?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Pulse</a> I like the interface for this app. I can stay on top of news and keep up-to-date on all my favorite sites with the swipe of a finger. It&rsquo;s easy to scroll back for archives and share favorite articles.</div>
<div class="apps"><a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/what-is-macosx/mail-ical-address-book.html"><img class="logos" src="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/ical-small-e1298429658149.png" alt="iCal App Logo" width="48" height="48"></a><a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/what-is-macosx/mail-ical-address-book.html" target="_blank">iCal</a> Keeping track of meeting times with clients in different time zones can be tricky. I like setting email reminders of important events. This app is also cool because I can import my <a href="http://calendar.google.com/" target="_blank">Google calendars</a> as well.</div>
<div class="apps"><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/godocs-for-ipad-iphone-google/id348792440?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow"><img class="logos" src="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/GoDocs-logo-e1298429994369.jpg" alt="GoDocs App Logo" width="48" height="48"></a><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/godocs-for-ipad-iphone-google/id348792440?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">GoDocs</a> Continuing my Google obsession, my workday would not be complete without <a href="http://www.google.com/apps/" target="_blank">Google Docs</a>. &nbsp;I use the spreadsheets to keep track of mileage and expenses.</div>
<div class="apps"><a href="https://personal.paypal.com/us/cgi-bin/?cmd=_render-content&amp;content_ID=marketing_us/mobile_iphone"> <img class="logos" src="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/paypal-e1298433164113.png" alt="PayPal App Logo" width="48" height="48"></a><a href="https://www.paypal.com/" target="_blank">PayPal</a> I like knowing when a client makes a payment. Through Paypal, I can send invoices for unpaid bills.</div>
<p>*Please note that I do not advocate sneaking an iPhone on family vacations. I hear it is healthy to unplug and bond with those who still love you.</p>
<p>How do you remain productive away from the office? Let me know in the comments if I missed any awesome apps.</p>
<p><em>iPhone 4 image courtesy of Apple.</em></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/02/5-iphone-apps-to-keep-business-running-as-usual/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interview with Joshua Kreis McTiernan, writer and director of &#8220;The Creationists,&#8221; a new play.</title>
		<link>/2011/02/interview-with-joshua-kreis-mctiernan/</link>
		<comments>/2011/02/interview-with-joshua-kreis-mctiernan/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 03:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chrissy Das]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Players by the Sea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playwright]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Creationists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theatre]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=365</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/02/IMG_1460-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="IMG_1460" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />High-brow. Low-brow. Pop culture and classical literature. There&#8217;s something for everyone in the debut of Joshua Kreis McTiernan&#8217;s comedy&#160;The Creationists. He took time from the busy play schedule to speak with me about the show and about his upcoming plans. <a href="/2011/02/interview-with-joshua-kreis-mctiernan/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/02/interview-with-joshua-kreis-mctiernan/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/02/IMG_1460-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="IMG_1460" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/IMG_1462.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignleft" style="margin-top: 0px; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 5px;" title="Joshua Kreis McTiernan directing his cast" src="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/IMG_1462-180x300.jpg"  alt="Joshua Kreis McTiernan directing his cast" width="180" height="300"></a>High-brow. Low-brow. Pop culture and classical literature. There&rsquo;s something for everyone in the debut of Joshua Kreis McTiernan&rsquo;s comedy&nbsp;<em><a title="Players by the Sea: The Creationists" href="http://www.playersbythesea.org/Performances.aspx" target="_blank">The Creationists</a></em>. He took time from the busy play schedule to speak with me about the show and about his upcoming plans.<span id="more-365"></span></p>
<p><strong><em>The Creationists</em> opened on February 18. Can you give us a quick taste of the show?</strong></p>
<p>The theme of the show is rooted in identity. That in itself is nothing new and groundbreaking, but the way you say it can be new. The show acknowledges all levels of humor and silliness. We talk about Postmodernism and men dressing as women. It&rsquo;s not just a play for intellectuals. I wanted to appeal to a broader audience.</p>
<p><strong>This is the first play you have written and produced that will be easily accessible to the public. Can you tell me a little bit about the process?</strong></p>
<p>I took &nbsp;playwriting classes in high school and was pretty good at it. I wrote a high school one act that was produced on one night. I&nbsp;trained as an actor at&nbsp;<a title="Douglas Anderson School of the Arts" href="http://www.da-arts.org/" target="_blank">Douglas Anderson School of the Arts</a> and went back to teach English for two years.&nbsp;Also, I have been involved in community theater since I was in middle school. Being an actor definitely helps in becoming a playwright.</p>
<p><strong>Any plans for the future?</strong></p>
<p>I already have ideas for the next show or two. Writers&rsquo; lives trickle into their art.&nbsp;In a few weeks I will take control of my own story and leave for the <a title="Peace Corps" href="http://www.peacecorps.gov/" target="_blank">Peace Corps</a>. &nbsp;I&rsquo;ll still be teaching in the Peace Corps. I&rsquo;ll be teaching English as a language instead of as literature.</p>
<div class="mceTemp">
<dl><dt> </dt>
</dl></div>
<p>Catch a performance of&nbsp;<em>The Creationists </em>at <a href="http://www.playersbythesea.org/Home.aspx" target="_blank">Players by the Sea</a> on February 19, 24, 25 or 26 at 8:00 p.m. <a title="Purchase tickets" href="http://www.playersbythesea.org/Tickets.aspx" target="_blank">Tickets</a> are $12 for students and $15 for adults.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/IMG_1453.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-368" title="A train station outside the town of Malbork with Joshua Kreis McTiernan while cast member Tyler Ramirez and crew member P.J. Milla goof off." src="//wp-content/uploads/2011/02/IMG_1453-300x225.jpg"  alt="A train station outside the town of Malbork with Joshua Kreis McTiernan while cast member Tyler Ramirez and crew member P.J. Milla goof off." width="300" height="225"></a></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/02/interview-with-joshua-kreis-mctiernan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
