<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; legislative</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/legislative/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Driving distracted affects health and changes lives</title>
		<link>/2011/03/driving-distracted-affects-health-and-changes-lives/</link>
		<comments>/2011/03/driving-distracted-affects-health-and-changes-lives/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 12:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bethany Harris]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cellphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distracted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hand-held]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laws]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legislative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teenagers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=855</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[At some point while driving you may have become distracted when a passenger was talking, a favorite song was playing or while trying to make sure you did not end up wearing your lunch. Driving distracted is not a new <a href="/2011/03/driving-distracted-affects-health-and-changes-lives/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/03/driving-distracted-affects-health-and-changes-lives/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/drvngcell.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-856" style="padding: 0 10px 10px 0" src="http://deemable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/drvngcell-300x229.jpg"  alt="A woman in the driver's seat of a car looking down at her cell phone" width="251" height="190"></a></p>
<p>At some point while driving you may have become distracted when a passenger was talking, a favorite song was playing or while trying to make sure you did not end up wearing your lunch. Driving distracted is not a new issue. In recent times it has come into greater focus because of the increasing use of hand-held technology and other electronic devices. Because of the number of injuries and fatal crashes in recent times, driving while distracted has become a health hazard.</p>
<p>Lives were changed on December 1, 2010 when a <a title="Pedestrian Injured In Car Accident Speaks Out Distracted Drivers  - News Story - KTVU San Francisco" href="http://www.ktvu.com/news/26992292/detail.html" target="_blank">California mother and her two-year daughter were hit by a distracted driver</a> as they crossed the street just a few blocks from home. Ling Murray has no memory of what happened. Both of her legs were shattered with other serious injuries and her daughter Calli was killed. Walking for the first time in three months, Ling remains in a rehabilitation medical facility. The teen that caused the accident admits to using her cell phone at the time the accident occurred.</p>
<p>In 2009 out of 1,517,000 injury crashes reported, about 20 percent involved distracted driving, according to the <a title="Driving Distracted | Stats and Facts | Driving and Texting" href="http://www.distraction.gov/stats-and-facts/index.html" target="_blank">Official U.S. Government Website for Distracted Driving</a>. This included each type of driving distraction: audible, visual, physical and cognitive. One or a combination of distractions can contribute to a crash depending on the driving behavior.</p>
<p>Audible distractions can occur when focusing on music or talking from a passenger or cell phone. Visual distractions occur when the focus is on something or someone outside the car or when reading. Physical distractions happen when removing a hand from the wheel for eating, tending to children, applying cosmetics, making a call or texting. Cognitive distractions are when your mind is not focused such as when you are emotional or daydreaming</p>
<p>So if these <a title="Distracted While Driving | World of Psychology" href="http://psychcentral.com/blog/archives/2008/06/20/distracted-while-driving/" target="_blank">types of driving behaviors</a> have existed for so long, why so much hype now? For nearly 10 years there has been a significant increase in cell phone use. It has become common to see an individual with a cell phone attached to his or her ear while in traffic. While there has been considerable focus on teenagers and texting, adults are not exempt from this behavior. A&nbsp;cell phone or PDA is a&nbsp;lifeline for business communications among many professionals, and the increasing use of Smartphones and small PC tablets does not improve the situation.</p>
<p>Distracted driving has also become a legislative issue. <a title="Traffic Safety Facts Research Note | Summary of Statistical Findings | Driver Electronic Device Use in 2009 | September 2010" href="http://www.distraction.gov/research/PDF-Files/Driver-Electronic-Device-Use-2009.pdf" target="_blank">In 2010, nearly 30 states established primary and secondary laws on texting and use hand-held devices</a>. With the objective to end distracted driving, goals also include increasing public awareness, expand law enforcement initiatives to reduce injuries and save lives.</p>
<p>Will banning cell phones while driving solve the problem? Should other distracted driving behaviors receive the same legislative treatment as cell phones and other hand-held devices? Why should teenagers be held just as accountable as adults?or should they?&nbsp; Share your views.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Driving distracted affects health and changes lives" data-link="/2011/03/driving-distracted-affects-health-and-changes-lives/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Driving distracted affects health and changes lives" data-link="/2011/03/driving-distracted-affects-health-and-changes-lives/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/03/driving-distracted-affects-health-and-changes-lives/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
