<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; PSN</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/psn/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Missing May</title>
		<link>/2011/05/missing-may/</link>
		<comments>/2011/05/missing-may/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 22:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Ahn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Osama bin Laden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlayStation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PSN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rapture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=3359</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From deadly tornadoes ripping through Missouri to the faulty claims of judgment day&#8217;s arrival, this has been quite a hectic month. After being granted a week-long hiatus from writing to enjoy a mini-vacation (thanks again Ray), I return to close <a href="/2011/05/missing-may/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/05/missing-may/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://cravesomethingmore.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/0114-Thoughts-Convicted-On-Judgment-Day-2011-05-24.jpg" alt="" width="360" height="270"></p>
<p>From deadly tornadoes ripping through Missouri to the faulty claims of judgment day&rsquo;s arrival, this has been quite a hectic month. After being granted a week-long hiatus from writing to enjoy a mini-vacation (thanks again Ray), I return to close out the end of May by revisiting some of the trending topics in the tech world and&hellip; well, I might as well throw this out there &ndash; Go Mavericks!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="Osama" href="http://deemable.com/stuff/2011/05/the-worlds-most-wanted-osama-bin-laden/" target="_blank">The World&rsquo;s Most Wanted: Osama bin Laden</a></p>
<p><a title="Puppy" href="http://www.fastcompany.com/1753360/the-tech-that-outfits-the-dogs-of-war" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://images.fastcompany.com/upload/robodog-620.jpg" alt="" width="377" height="182"></a></p>
<p>Meet Cairo, a member of the Navy SEAL team who helped take out Osama bin Laden with the help of high tech doggie body armor, called the <em>Intruder</em>. Costing up to $30,000, the ultralight vest is not only bulletproof, but the <em>Intruder</em> also has a high-definition camera that is mounted on the war dog&rsquo;s back so that its handlers can see his every movement. Now that&rsquo;s one badass puppy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="PSN" href="http://deemable.com/tech/2011/05/reconnected-playstation-network-back-online/" target="_blank">Reconnected: PlayStation Network Back Online</a></p>
<p>What a complete nightmare the PSN outage has become for Sony, but it looks like they have finally gotten things under control as their latest&nbsp;<a title="Press Release" href="http://blog.us.playstation.com/2011/05/30/full-psn-services-including-playstation-store-return-this-week/" target="_blank">Press Release</a> may suggest. However, Sony won&rsquo;t come out unscathed as the company has reportedly lost <a title="Sony losses" href="http://cnn.com/video/?/video/business/2011/05/26/lah.japan.sony.woes.cnn" target="_blank">billions of dollars</a> over the security breach, which has shaken consumer confidence in the PlayStation Network.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="Matt &amp; Ginny" href="http://deemable.com/stuff/2011/05/greatest-marriage-proposal-ever/" target="_blank">Greatest Marriage Proposal Ever?</a></p>
<p>3 million views in 3 days. 15 million views in 2 weeks. That means millions of women saw this marriage proposal video on YouTube throughout the world, leaving millions of women expecting a similar grand gesture of love. F.M.L.? More like &ldquo;F.O.L.&rdquo; for all the guys out there. But hey, at least Matt &amp; Ginny appreciate all the responses you all have given them. Sigh&hellip;</p>
<span class="embed-youtube" style="text-align:center; display: block;"><iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="560" height="349" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GcFB07zyy2E?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="Apple iCloud" href="http://deemable.com/tech/2011/05/apple-gearing-up-for-cloud-music-service/" target="_blank">Apple Gearing Up for Cloud Music Service</a></p>
<p>While Steve Jobs is currently on medical leave due to health-related issues, it&rsquo;s not stopping him from delivering the keynote address at Apple&rsquo;s annual Worldwide Developers Conference next Monday. As for Apple&rsquo;s cloud-based music service, it looks like iCloud (or whatever they name it) will allow users to <a title="Mirror" href="http://arstechnica.com/apple/news/2011/05/report-apple-music-cloud-service-to-auto-add-itunes-store-tracks.ars" target="_blank">mirror their iTunes library</a> as anticipated.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="Press Release" href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2011/05/31wwdc.html" target="_blank">Official Press Release</a><strong>: Apple to Unveil Next Generation Software at Keynote Address on Monday, June 6</strong></p>
<p>CUPERTINO, California?May 31, 2011?Apple&reg; CEO Steve Jobs and a team of  Apple executives will kick off the company&rsquo;s annual Worldwide Developers  Conference (WWDC) with a keynote address on Monday, June 6 at 10:00  a.m. At the keynote, Apple will unveil its next generation software &ndash;  Lion, the eighth major release of Mac OS&reg; X; iOS 5, the next version of  Apple&rsquo;s advanced mobile operating system which powers the iPad&reg;, iPhone&reg;  and iPod touch&reg;; and iCloud&reg;, Apple&rsquo;s upcoming cloud services offering.</p>
<p>WWDC will feature more than 100 technical sessions presented by Apple  engineers. Mac&reg; developers will see and learn how to develop world-class  Mac OS X Lion applications using its latest technologies and  capabilities. Mobile developers will be able to explore the latest  innovations and capabilities of iOS and learn how to greatly enhance the  functionality, performance and design of their apps. All developers can  bring their code to the labs and work with Apple engineers.</p>
<p>For more details, visit the Apple Worldwide Developers Conference 2011 website at <a href="http://developer.apple.com/wwdc">developer.apple.com/wwdc</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="Photo" href="http://cravesomethingmore.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/0114-Thoughts-Convicted-On-Judgment-Day-2011-05-24.jpg" target="_blank">Photo</a> by <a title="CT" href="http://cravesomethingmore.org/author/ctomlinson/" target="_blank">CT</a> via <a title="Crave" href="http://cravesomethingmore.org/" target="_blank">CraveSomethingMore</a></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Missing May" data-link="/2011/05/missing-may/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Missing May" data-link="/2011/05/missing-may/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/05/missing-may/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reconnected: PlayStation Network Back Online</title>
		<link>/2011/05/reconnected-playstation-network-back-online/</link>
		<comments>/2011/05/reconnected-playstation-network-back-online/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 19:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Ahn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyperattack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MLB.tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NetFlix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlayStation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlayStation Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PSN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PSP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qriocity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=3158</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After 22 grueling days of outage, gamers and users throughout the world can finally reconnect to the PlayStation Network after Sony carried out a phased restoration process. Although PlayStation store access won&#8217;t be restored until later, PSN&#8217;s reactivation restores online <a href="/2011/05/reconnected-playstation-network-back-online/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/05/reconnected-playstation-network-back-online/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://blog.us.playstation.com/files/2011/05/Firmware-Lead-440x247.jpg" alt="" width="440" height="247"></p>
<p>After 22 grueling days of outage, gamers and users throughout the world can finally reconnect to the PlayStation Network after Sony carried out a phased restoration process. Although PlayStation store access won&rsquo;t be restored until later, PSN&rsquo;s reactivation restores online multiplayer and chat functions, friends list   and trophy comparison functionality, PlayStation Home, and services like Hulu, Netflix, and MLB.tv. Once logging in, PSN users will be required to update to the latest 3.61 firmware and change their account passwords. Details about changing your password are provided below from the <a title="Password change" href="http://blog.us.playstation.com/2011/05/14/ps3-system-software-update/" target="_blank">PlayStation Blog</a>:</p>
<p>&ldquo;If using a PS3, your password can only be changed on your own PS3 (or a  PS3 on which your PSN account was activated), as an added layer of  security. If you have never downloaded any content using your account on  the system, an email will be sent to the registered sign-in ID (email  address) associated with your account when you first attempt to sign-in  to PSN. This e-mail will contain a link that will enable you to change  your password. In this email, click on the link and follow the  instructions to change your password. Once you have changed your  password you can sign-in to your account using your new password.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Down for over 3 weeks after hackers breached the network&rsquo;s security, Sony had to rebuild the entire PlayStation Network with more advanced security technology, encryption, firewalls, and early-warning systems. The outage affected over 77 million users worldwide and, even worse, the security breach may have allowed for the hackers to <a title="stolen information" href="http://mashable.com/2011/05/03/sony-another-hacker-attack/" target="_blank">steal</a> personal credit and debit card information from over 24 million user accounts.</p>
<p>Kazuo Hirai, Sony Corporation&rsquo;s Executive Deputy President, released a <a title="video" href="http://blog.us.playstation.com/2011/05/14/kazuo-hirai-playstation-network-relaunch-announcement/" target="_blank">video statement</a> on the PlayStation Blog providing more detailed information on the restoration of the PlayStation Network and the new security features being implemented.</p>
<p>To compensate for the long outage and compromise of account information, Sony is offering 30 days free membership in the PlayStation Plus service, which provides exclusive access to certain games and beta trials. To those users who are already subscribed to the PlayStation Plus service, an additional 30 days will be added for free. Sony Online Entertainment subscribers will also receive a special <a title="Welcome Back" href="http://www.soe.com/securityupdate/welcomeback/" target="_blank">Welcome Back Program</a> upon return.</p>
<p>At this point though, how many PSN users will even want to return to the network after the massive failure that Sony just dealt with?</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Reconnected: PlayStation Network Back Online" data-link="/2011/05/reconnected-playstation-network-back-online/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Reconnected: PlayStation Network Back Online" data-link="/2011/05/reconnected-playstation-network-back-online/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/05/reconnected-playstation-network-back-online/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PlayStation Network Goes Down</title>
		<link>/2011/04/playstation-network-goes-down/</link>
		<comments>/2011/04/playstation-network-goes-down/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Ahn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Call of Duty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NetFlix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Outage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlayStation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlayStation 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PSN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zombies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=2695</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nazi Zombies, you are free to roam the earth for a little while longer as Sony&#8217;s PlayStation Network has been out of service since 4/20. The PlayStation Network is Sony&#8217;s equivalent to Xbox LIVE, which allows for PlayStation 3 users <a href="/2011/04/playstation-network-goes-down/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/04/playstation-network-goes-down/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p style="text-align: left"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/gadgetlab/2010/03/psn.jpg" alt="" width="660" height="309"></p>
<p style="text-align: left">Nazi Zombies, you are free to roam the earth for a little while longer  as Sony&rsquo;s PlayStation Network has been out of service since 4/20.</p>
<p>The PlayStation Network is Sony&rsquo;s equivalent to Xbox LIVE, which allows for PlayStation 3 users to download games, download or stream movies and music, and have access to other services. More importantly, the network serves as the infrastructure for people to connect and play each other in multiplayer games such as Call of Duty. Oddly enough, the  network failure happened to coincide with the release of several  brand  new games including Mortal Kombat, Portal 2, SOCOM 4, and  inFAMOUS 2&rsquo;s beta release. While access to the network is free, content such as Netflix must be paid for by users, leaving them wondering whether they will be reimbursed if the outage lasts any longer.</p>
<p>A little over a year ago, Sony users of the non-slim PS3 had a <a title="similar outage" href="http://blog.us.playstation.com/2010/03/01/latest-info-on-playstation-network-status/" target="_blank">similar outage</a> on their PlayStation Network that was &ldquo;caused by a bug in the clock functionality incorporated in the system.&rdquo; Patrick Seybold, the Senior Director of Corporate Communications &amp; Social Media, posted a message yesterday on Sony&rsquo;s <a title="PSN Blog" href="http://blog.us.playstation.com/2011/04/21/latest-update-on-psn-outage/" target="_blank">PlayStation Blog</a> that said, &ldquo;While we are investigating the cause of the Network outage, we wanted to  alert you that it may be a full day or two before we&rsquo;re able to get  the&nbsp;service completely back up and running. Thank you very much for your  patience while we work to resolve this matter. Please stay tuned  to&nbsp;this space for more details, and we&rsquo;ll update you again as soon as we  can.&rdquo;</p>
<p>While there are an estimated 70 million users on the network worldwide, Sony is unable to clarify how many people are currently affected by the outage. However, players from all over the world have taken their Zombie rage to  popular social media sites like Twitter and Facebook to express their  displeasure with Sony. Got some spare time since you can&rsquo;t own some newbs? Check out some of the tweets found by a quick search of <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/%23PSN" target="_blank">#PSN on Twitter.</a></p>
<p>&ndash; Update 4/23 &ndash;</p>
<p>Patrick Seybold has made <a title="post" href="http://blog.us.playstation.com/2011/04/22/update-on-playstation-network-qriocity-services/" target="_blank">another post</a> on the PlayStation Blog regarding the ongoing issue:</p>
<p>&ldquo;An external intrusion on our system has affected our PlayStation Network  and Qriocity services. In order to conduct a thorough investigation and  to verify the smooth and secure operation of our network services going  forward, we turned off PlayStation Network &amp; Qriocity services on  the evening of Wednesday, April 20th. Providing quality entertainment  services to our customers and partners is our utmost priority. We are  doing all we can to resolve this situation quickly, and we once again  thank you for your patience. We will continue to update you promptly as  we have additional information to share.&rdquo;<a title="Photo" href="http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/gadgetlab/2010/03/psn.jpg" target="_blank"></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="Photo" href="http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/gadgetlab/2010/03/psn.jpg" target="_blank">Photo</a> by <a title="Charlie Sorrel" href="http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/author/mistercharlie/" target="_blank">Charlie Sorrel</a> via <a title="Wired" href="http://www.wired.com/" target="_blank">Wired</a></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="PlayStation Network Goes Down" data-link="/2011/04/playstation-network-goes-down/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="PlayStation Network Goes Down" data-link="/2011/04/playstation-network-goes-down/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/04/playstation-network-goes-down/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
