<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; URI</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/uri/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#43 How Tom Met Ray&#8217;s Mother</title>
		<link>/2013/07/43-how-tom-met-rays-mother/</link>
		<comments>/2013/07/43-how-tom-met-rays-mother/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 03:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackBerry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Domain names]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eBay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Etsy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Googling Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[searching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[URI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[URL]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7512</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/07/Screenshot-2013-07-14-at-11.27.47-PM-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Ray" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />On this week&#8217;s episode Ray and Tom take their first live call in the studio, and it&#8217;s Ray&#8217;s mom! (Why does everyone try a Your Mom joke? What is this the 90s?) Also, Tom and Ray help Dean find a <a href="/2013/07/43-how-tom-met-rays-mother/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/07/43-how-tom-met-rays-mother/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/07/Screenshot-2013-07-14-at-11.27.47-PM-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Ray" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>On this week&rsquo;s episode Ray and Tom take their first live call in the studio, and it&rsquo;s Ray&rsquo;s mom! (Why does everyone try a Your Mom joke? What is this the 90s?) Also, Tom and Ray help Dean find a new laptop battery, Jennifer find her lost BlackBerry Bold 9900 and Playbook, and help Kevin figure out how to get to his email.</p>
<span class="embed-youtube" style="text-align:center; display: block;"><iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="752" height="453" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N0UKYGqpP1M?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
<p><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-7512-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-14.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-14.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-14.mp3</a></audio><br><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-14.mp3">#43 How Tom Met Ray&rsquo;s Mother</a></p>
<p>DRAFT TRANSCRIPT</p>
<p>RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>TOM: I&rsquo;m Tom Braun,</p>
<p>RAY: and this is Deemable Tech, tech help worth listening to.</p>
<p>RAY: This week&rsquo;s episode of the Deemable Tech podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p>And, by audible.com &ndash; Deemable Tech listeners can get a FREE audiobook download at <a title="Audible Trial" href="http://audibletrial.com/Deemable" target="_blank">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a> Over 100,000 titles to choose from for your iPhone, Android, Kindle or mp3 player.</p>
<p>TOM: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? Give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at questions@deemable.com.</p>
<p>RAY: Today on Deemable Tech, we&rsquo;re answering your questions about replacing a laptop battery</p>
<p>TOM: finding a lost BlackBerry,</p>
<p>RAY: And, Angel&rsquo;s not here tonight!</p>
<p>TOM: But first, we have a call coming in, Ray.</p>
<p>RAY: From who, Tom?</p>
<p>TOM: It&rsquo;s from YOUR MOM.</p>
<p>RAY: OK, seriously, Tom, that&rsquo;s not funny. And we&rsquo;ve already done that joke on the show before. Jeez!</p>
<p>TOM: No really! It is you&rsquo;re mom! She&rsquo;s waiting on hold.</p>
<p>RAY: Oh Hey Mom! You&rsquo;re on Deemable Tech, what&rsquo;s your question?</p>
<p>RAY&rsquo;S MOM: &ldquo;I&rsquo;m starting a business making jewelry like necklaces and earrings. I want to sell them online. Will you make me a website?&rdquo;</p>
<p>RAY: Nope. We don&rsquo;t do website development, even for you Mom.</p>
<p>RAY&rsquo;S MOM: OK, well if you won&rsquo;t make a website for me, what should I do? How can I sell them online?</p>
<p>RAY: There&rsquo;s a few options: eBay, Craigslist, Etsy, ArtFire and a bunch of other Etsy knock offs.</p>
<p>Craigslist- Free, but expectation is to only do business locally so you have to meet people in person.</p>
<p>Ebay, don&rsquo;t pay until you buy, auction style often drives prices low because it&rsquo;s a buyers market.</p>
<p>Etsy. Go where the shoppers are.</p>
<p>Remember you can get a URL and direct it to your Etsy page, so you could get SerenityNook.com and direct it to your Etsy Page.</p>
<p>Dean asked: Where&rsquo;s a good place to get a replacement battery for my Dell laptop? It&rsquo;s Model number PP31L.</p>
<p>RAY: OK, so that&rsquo;s a Dell Studio 1735/1737.</p>
<p>Generally, I would start with the manufacturer to get a baseline price, and then I would check out a couple of other sites for comparison.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/" target="_blank">http://www.amazon.com/</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.newegg.com/" target="_blank">http://www.newegg.com/</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.tigerdirect.com/" target="_blank">http://www.tigerdirect.com/</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.batteriesplus.com/" target="_blank">http://www.batteriesplus.com/</a></p>
<p>I looked on Dell&rsquo;s website, and they had two different batteries for that model, one was about $110, the other was about $150. Obviously, the more expensive one was the better one that lasts longer.</p>
<p>Online I found them going for anywhere between $40 -120.</p>
<p>If you just want to find the cheapest replacement battery that you can fine, go to Google and just type in Dell studio 1735 battery and look at the shopping results. That will give you a breakdown of pretty much every battery that&rsquo;s out there for the Dell studio 1735 or 1737. And then you can sort it by cheapest to most expensive or most relevant or any way you want to.</p>
<p>What you want to keep in mind though is quality and customer service. If you buy a battery from some website in some foreign country that has no customer service number, but you get a cheap deal on the battery, you can expect that you&rsquo;re probably not going to get any service if the battery breaks down a month after you buy it. Sometimes it&rsquo;s worth buying something that&rsquo;s more expensive, but you know it&rsquo;s going to last, or if it doesn&rsquo;t you know the company that sold to you is going to replace it for you.</p>
<p>Jennifer wrote in: I listened to your segment this morning on WJCT about protecting the iPad &amp; iPhone. I have the Blackberry Bold 9900 &amp; Blackberry Playbook 64gb tablet. I would like a recommendation for apps to protect, lock down &amp; secure the Blackberry Bold &amp; Blackberry Playbook tablet. Thanks for all your help!</p>
<p>RAY: Well first of all thanks for email Jennifer. Second of all, sorry it took so long to get back to you. Looks like it&rsquo;s in this email back in April, and it looks like We must&rsquo;ve missed placed your email. So, sorry about that!</p>
<p>I had to go back and find out which radio segment you were talking about, and I found out it was the one about finding a lost iPhone.</p>
<p>Unfortunately BlackBerry did not have a built-in feature like Find my iPhone until BlackBerry 10. BlackBerry does make an app though that you can download for the BlackBerry Bold 9900 called BlackBerry Protect. It&rsquo;s free, and it lets you do basically everything that Find my iPhone does. It will let you locate it, lock it, make it ring loud, put a message on the screen, and wipe it if you need to. You can even back up your data remotely before you wipe it.</p>
<p>Now, for your BlackBerry playbook, Oh! You&rsquo;re the one who bought a BlackBerry playbook. I was wondering who that was.</p>
<p>The BlackBerry Playbook is an odd duck because it is the only device that runs the operating system it runs. And when blackberry puts out new tablets (whenever that is) they probably are not going to run that version of the operating system either. They&rsquo;re probably going to run BlackBerry 10.</p>
<p>And that is why BlackBerry Protect does not work on the BlackBerry Playbook, even though it is built into BlackBerry 10.</p>
<p>Thanks for all your questions, and keep them coming. Call us at our toll-free number, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com. Also, subscribe to the show! Search for <a href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">Deemable Tech on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or point your favorite podcast app to <a href="http://dmbl.co/pod">dmbl.co/pod</a>.</p>
<p>Our producer is Sean Birch. Thanks to Robert Snyder for Video Production Assistance, and to Jo El Snyder for helping us out with the phones. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, and this is Deemable Tech. Thanks for listening. Have a great week.</p>
<p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/07/Screenshot-2013-07-14-at-11.27.47-PM.png" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-7522" alt="Ray" src="/media/2013/07/Screenshot-2013-07-14-at-11.27.47-PM-300x182.png"  width="300" height="182"></a></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#43 How Tom Met Ray's Mother" data-link="/2013/07/43-how-tom-met-rays-mother/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#43 How Tom Met Ray's Mother" data-link="/2013/07/43-how-tom-met-rays-mother/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/07/43-how-tom-met-rays-mother/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-14.mp3" length="31212774" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
