<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Cell Phone</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/cell-phone/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Ric asks, &#8220;Can I use my cell phone in another country?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/</link>
		<comments>/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 17:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cell Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8115</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/08/cell_phone_passport-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Andrew Catellier / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />&#160; Q:&#160;I&#8217;m taking a trip to Costa Rica soon, and I need a simple phone to use while I&#8217;m there. I know very little about cell phones. What sort of phone should I buy for international travel, and what do <a href="/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/08/cell_phone_passport-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Andrew Catellier / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Q:&nbsp;</strong>I&rsquo;m taking a trip to Costa Rica soon, and I need a simple phone to use while I&rsquo;m there. I know very little about cell phones. What sort of phone should I buy for international travel, and what do I need to know to make sure it will work before the trip?</p>
<p><strong>A:&nbsp;</strong>Finding the right phone for international travel can get complicated and expensive in a hurry. Whatever you do, don&rsquo;t just take your normal phone to Central America and start racking up roaming charges. They start at ridiculous and go up from there. If your phone even works there, that is.</p>
<div id="attachment_8116" style="width: 316px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2013/08/cell_phone_passport.png" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class=" wp-image-8116     " alt="Phone and passport. Image credit: Andrew Catellier / Flickr" src="/media/2013/08/cell_phone_passport.png"  width="306" height="257"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">You&rsquo;ve got your passport and your traveler&rsquo;s cheques packed, but what about your phone?Image credit: Andrew Catellier / Flickr</p>
<p></p></div>
<p>You see, there are two main types of cell networks worldwide: GSM and CDMA. GSM is the worldwide standard while CDMA is most common in the US. So you really want a GSM phone, specifically a &ldquo;quad band&rdquo; GSM phone. A &ldquo;quad band&rdquo; GSM phone will work on just about any cell network in any country. One such phone is the iPhone 4S. The iPhone 5 also supports quad band&hellip; providing you bought yours in Europe.</p>
<p>The type of network your phone is compatible with is determined by the carrier you bought it for. The US carriers that use GSM are AT&amp;T and T-Mobile. Sprint and Verizon use CDMA. LTE networks are basically all completely incompatible with each other (which is why American iPhone 5&rsquo;s will most likely not work in another country). Once you have a quad-band GSM phone, you will need to buy an international SIM card so you can make calls without racking up astronomical roaming charges.</p>
<p>Now, if this all sounds complicated, that&rsquo;s because it is. Don&rsquo;t fret, though, because there&rsquo;s a simple trick to finding a phone that is guaranteed to work cheaply in the country you are visiting: wait until you get to Costa Rica, and buy a phone there. When you arrive in Costa Rica, go to the local mobile store and buy the cheapest prepaid cell phone you can find. We be there will be one you can buy for under $30 (US dollars). Whatever you do, don&rsquo;t buy a phone or SIM card at or near the airport, because prices are almost always much higher there. Once you get out of the airport, ask a local to point you to a good, cheap store.</p>
<p>Of course, you won&rsquo;t be able to call your folks in Sarasota on your el cheapo Costa Rican prepaid phone, Ric. But there&rsquo;s an easy solution for that, too. You can use the popular Internet telephony software Skype to call real phone numbers, anywhere in the world. It&rsquo;s not free, but it&rsquo;s very cheap. Before you leave, buy some Skype credit, download the Skype app for your smartphone, and take it with you to Costa Rica. Then when you&rsquo;re on Wi-Fi, just log in to Skype and call home like normal!</p>
<p>In general, buying a cheap phone in the country you will be visiting is a good plan, and pretty foolproof. However if you expect to be traveling to multiple countries, or you need to call other countries while you&rsquo;re there and you won&rsquo;t have consistent access to Wi-Fi, you need an unlocked, quad-band GSM phone and an international SIM card. You can buy prepaid international SIM cards from companies like <a href="http://www.telestial.com/">Telestial</a> and <a href="http://www.onesimcard.com/">OneSimCard</a> for under $50. Just remember, you&rsquo;ll need a phone to match.</p>
<p>To sum up, if you absolutely have to make a lot of international calls while you&rsquo;re there, you&rsquo;ll need an unlocked, quad-band GSM phone such as the iPhone 4S and an international SIM card. If not, you can just buy a cheap prepaid phone once you land.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title='Ric asks, "Can I use my cell phone in another country?"' data-link="/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title='Ric asks, "Can I use my cell phone in another country?"' data-link="/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/08/ric-asks-can-use-cell-phone-another-country/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cell Phone Addiction</title>
		<link>/2011/04/cell-phone-addiction/</link>
		<comments>/2011/04/cell-phone-addiction/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2011 23:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Ahn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Addiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cell Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=2174</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I wake up to the buzzing of my cell phone alarm, check one of my widgets for weather updates, check for new e-mails and text messages, stick my earphones in for some tunes and start my day. This all seems <a href="/2011/04/cell-phone-addiction/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/04/cell-phone-addiction/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Hwc9jFH-UVg/TZ5s9VNUCOI/AAAAAAAAElM/F3pS1J4P1Kg/s200/cell+phone+addiction.gif" class="gallery_colorbox" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/optimist/vbH49vOp20KNTIS9sEAm1HTbls2nm2h85FwDjeNTkJpd6WKyyJREYfi8msVE/imgname--korea_to_combat_mobil.gif"  alt="" width="257" height="316"></a>I wake up to the buzzing of my cell phone alarm, check one of my widgets for weather updates, check for new e-mails and text messages, stick my earphones in for some tunes and start my day. This all seems perfectly normal, some might even go as far as to say that it is being responsible, but there&rsquo;s a catch; I am a cell phone addict.</p>
<p>Addiction is defined as being abnormally tolerant to and dependent on something that is psychologically or physically habit-forming. The continual use of devices as easily accessible as mobile cell phones creates chemical responses that are similar to that of compulsive gambling. Apple iPhones, Blackberrys, Samsungs, HTCs, LGs&hellip; and the list goes on, but they all have one common link &ndash; they consume parts of our life. My cell phone has become an extension of myself, an extension of myself that I am afraid to lose sight of and am constantly reaching for.</p>
<p>Do you remember how simple life was without being bombarbed by constant text messages, social networking updates, e-mails, and phone calls? While advanced technological improvements have drastically made life easier and more efficient for the most part, the same technological advancements can be the cause of increased stress, anxiety, and in the most extreme cases &ndash; death.</p>
<p>So where do we draw the line between healthy cell phone usage and addictive cell phone dependence? If you are using your phone to avoid social interaction, to compulsively check things, to message someone sitting within arms reach, or you begin to feel empty without its presence, then it may be time to begin detoxing from the cell phone monkey.</p>
<p>Personally, I quit smoking cigarettes cold turkey in August of 2010&hellip; but I don&rsquo;t think I can let go of my cell phone as easily.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Hwc9jFH-UVg/TZ5s9VNUCOI/AAAAAAAAElM/F3pS1J4P1Kg/s200/cell+phone+addiction.gif" target="_blank">Photo</a> by <a href="http://www.blogger.com/profile/14985143085882983821" target="_blank">Elizabeth Downie </a>via <a href="http://elizabethdownie.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">Blogspot</a></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Cell Phone Addiction" data-link="/2011/04/cell-phone-addiction/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Cell Phone Addiction" data-link="/2011/04/cell-phone-addiction/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/04/cell-phone-addiction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
