<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; podcatcher</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/podcatcher/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Anonymous asks &#8220;What is a podcast, and how do I subscribe to one?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2012/12/anonymous-asks-what-is-a-podcast-and-how-do-i-subscribe-to-one/</link>
		<comments>/2012/12/anonymous-asks-what-is-a-podcast-and-how-do-i-subscribe-to-one/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcatcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscribe to a podcast]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7184</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Many public radio shows offer podcasts of their episodes. But what is a podcast, and what does it mean to &#8220;subscribe&#8221; to one? The hosts of Deemable Tech, Ray Hollister and Tom Braun, break it down in this week&#8217;s Ask <a href="/2012/12/anonymous-asks-what-is-a-podcast-and-how-do-i-subscribe-to-one/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2012/12/anonymous-asks-what-is-a-podcast-and-how-do-i-subscribe-to-one/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>Many public radio shows offer podcasts of their episodes. But what is a podcast, and what does it mean to &ldquo;subscribe&rdquo; to one? The hosts of Deemable Tech, Ray Hollister and Tom Braun, break it down in this week&rsquo;s Ask Deemable Tech.</p>
<p><script id="prx-p91007-embed" src="http://www.prx.org/p/91007/embed.js?size=full"></script></p>
<p>RAY: Hi, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, </p>
<p>TOM: I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, </p>
<p>RAY: and we&rsquo;re the hosts of Deemable Tech. On the show, we answer your questions about computers, tablets, mobile phones and the Internet, like this question we received from a listener:</p>
<p>TOM: Hey Ray &amp; Tom,</p>
<p>I have a question. What is a podcast? I listen to your show all the time on the website, and you keep saying to subscribe to the podcast. I hear other public radio shows talk about getting their podcast on the web too, but what is a podcast, and how do I &ldquo;subscribe&rdquo; to it? Are you going to mail it to my house or drop it off next to the newspaper? Forgive me for sounding stupid, but I don&rsquo;t understand.</p>
<p>Thanks!</p>
<p>Subscribe me confused</p>
<p>RAY: Hey Subscribe me! Thanks for your email. Ooh, this is our first anonymous writer! Well, &ldquo;Subscribe me confused&rdquo;, you don&rsquo;t need to be anonymous if you are embarrassed for not knowing what a podcast is, and you&rsquo;re certainly not stupid for not knowing that. In fact, even your hosts here didn&rsquo;t know what a podcast was only a few years ago.</p>
<p>TOM: In fact, podcasts didn&rsquo;t even exist until as recently as 2005. A podcast is simply a broadcast to your media player. The term podcast is derived from the brand name, iPod, Apple&rsquo;s MP3 player, but that doesn&rsquo;t really matter now. Almost any device that can play music and/or videos can receive a podcast including most MP3 players, smartphones, and tablets.</p>
<p>RAY: Subscribing to a podcast means that you will automatically get the latest episode of the show that you listen to without you having to do anything. It works like On Demand works on your TV. You can listen or watch the podcast when and where you want to, and because it happens automatically, you don&rsquo;t have to remember to check the website to see if a new episode has been posted.</p>
<p>To subscribe to a podcast you need a program or app called a podcatcher; the most popular one is iTunes. To subscribe to a podcast in iTunes you can either search for the name of the podcast you are looking for like &ldquo;Deemable Tech,&rdquo; or you can click a special link that takes you right to the podcast in iTunes, like <a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech in iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" target="_blank">Deemable Tech&rsquo;s iTunes link</a>.. Then, iTunes will pull up the podcast listing and you can click &ldquo;Subscribe&rdquo; to have the podcast automatically downloaded to your computer or your iPhone, iPad or iPod touch.</p>
<p>TOM: If you have an Android phone or a media player that isn&rsquo;t made by Apple, you can either use a program like <a title="Enjoy your Music, Video, Radio and iTunes on your Android" href="http://doubletwist.com/" target="_blank">DoubleTwist</a> to sync your device with iTunes, or you can use a different podcatcher like <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=au.com.shiftyjelly.pocketcasts" target="_blank">Pocket Casts</a> or <a title="Talk radio, podcasts and live radio on demand | Stitcher Smart Radio" href="http://stitcher.com/" target="_blank">Stitcher</a> for Android or <a title="Juice, the cross-platform podcast receiver." href="http://juicereceiver.sourceforge.net/" target="_blank">Juice</a> for Windows, Mac or Linux. Other podcatcher apps may not have directories like iTunes does. In that case, you may need to know the RSS feed address of the show that you are looking for. Ours is <a href="http://dmbl.co/pod">http://dmbl.co/pod</a>.</p>
<p>RAY: If you love listening to public radio or talk radio, you will love podcasts. Almost all of your favorite radio shows on <a title="NPR podcasts" href="www.npr.org/rss/podcast/podcast_directory.php" target="_blank">NPR</a>, <a title="PRI: Public Radio International - PRI Podcasts" href="http://www.pri.org/pri-podcasts.html" target="_blank">PRI</a> and <a title="American Public Media: Podcasts" href="http://americanpublicmedia.publicradio.org/podcasts/" target="_blank">APM</a> and most <a title="Fox News Radio" href="http://radio.foxnews.com/podcast/" target="_blank">talk radio shows</a> have podcasts, and there are a plethora of shows, like Deemable Tech, that you might not find on your local radio station. Also, subscribing to the shows that you love helps support those shows. The more subscribers that a show has, the higher up that show will be listed in the iTunes podcast directory, which means that more listeners will find the show and start listening! So, go <a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech in iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" target="_blank">subscribe to Deemable Tech&rsquo;s podcast</a>, and then check out all of the other shows out there.</p>
<p>RAY: To hear more answers to questions like this one, listen to our show at Deemable dot com, that&rsquo;s D-E E-M A-B-L-E dot com. There you can listen to all of our previous episodes and, of course, subscribe to our podcast.</p>
<p>TOM: If you have a question for Deemable Tech give us a call us at 1-888-972-9868, or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com.</p>
<p>RAY: For Deemable Tech I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>TOM: and I&rsquo;m Tom Braun.</p>
<p><img class="wp-image-6298 alignnone" title="What Is A Podcast?" alt="" src="//media/2012/11/WhatIsAPodcast.png" width="200" height="200"></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title='Anonymous asks "What is a podcast, and how do I subscribe to one?"' data-link="/2012/12/anonymous-asks-what-is-a-podcast-and-how-do-i-subscribe-to-one/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title='Anonymous asks "What is a podcast, and how do I subscribe to one?"' data-link="/2012/12/anonymous-asks-what-is-a-podcast-and-how-do-i-subscribe-to-one/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2012/12/anonymous-asks-what-is-a-podcast-and-how-do-i-subscribe-to-one/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
