<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; dual-boot</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/dual-boot/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Clare asks, &#8220;How can I have both a Mac and a PC?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2014/05/clare-asks-can-mac-pc/</link>
		<comments>/2014/05/clare-asks-can-mac-pc/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boot Camp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dual-boot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac OS X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parallels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8824</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/05/windows_on_mac-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="windows_on_mac" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Q: I&#8217;ve started getting into editing videos. I&#8217;ve heard Macs are the best computers for this, but I need to have a PC for my job. We have some programs for our company that only work on Windows. Do you <a href="/2014/05/clare-asks-can-mac-pc/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2014/05/clare-asks-can-mac-pc/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/05/windows_on_mac-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="windows_on_mac" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><script id="prx-p119765-embed" src="http://www.prx.org/p/119765/embed.js?size=small"></script></p>
<p><strong>Q: </strong>I&rsquo;ve started getting into editing videos. I&rsquo;ve heard Macs are the best computers for this, but I need to have a PC for my job. We have some programs for our company that only work on Windows. Do you have any suggestions?<span id="more-8824"></span></p>
<p><strong>A: </strong>We sure do, Clare. We would definitely recommend getting a Mac if you are seriously interested in video editing, but if the software you need for your job will only work on Windows, you&rsquo;ll need to have Windows. Unfortunately, it can be frustrating to have to run two computers at the same time. But what if you could have the best of both worlds on one computer? It can be done by installing Windows on a Mac.<br></p><div id="attachment_8826" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2014/05/windows_on_mac.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-8826 size-medium" src="/media/2014/05/windows_on_mac-300x223.jpg"  alt="windows_on_mac" width="300" height="223"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Windows 8 running on a MacBook Pro.</p></div>
<p>Yes, you read that correctly. You can actually install Windows on any Mac with an Intel processor, which all current Mac models have. This will create what is called a dual-boot system with both Mac OS and Windows. Setting this up isn&rsquo;t hard to do, but you&rsquo;ll need to make sure that you purchase a full version installation disc or download of Windows first (an upgrade version cannot be used). Of course, you&rsquo;ll need to buy a Mac as well.</p>
<p>To install Windows on a Mac, you will use one of two programs: Boot Camp or Parallels. Boot Camp comes free with your Apple computer, while Parallels is a separate program that costs around $80. The major difference between the two programs is how your computer will run the different operating systems in relation to each other. Boot Camp allows you to run Windows <em>or</em> Mac OS, and you decide which one you want to use when you boot your computer. If you want to switch to the other operating system, you have restart your machine.</p>
<p>Parallels, on the other hand, lets you use Windows <em>and</em> Mac OS at the same time and switch back and forth while both are running. You can even launch Windows applications right from your Mac dock, and it will switch over to Windows automatically. The downside to this program (apart from the price tag) is that your computer can become really bogged down since you&rsquo;re running two operating systems at the same time.</p>
<p>Of the two, we prefer Boot Camp. To install Windows using it, just open your Launchpad, go to the Boot Camp Assistant and follow the instructions. As with any major change to your computer, we recommend that you back up all of your important files and documents before you install Windows.</p>
<p>With a little time and energy, Clare, you&rsquo;ll be doing everything you want and need to with two computers in one!</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title='Clare asks, "How can I have both a Mac and a PC?"' data-link="/2014/05/clare-asks-can-mac-pc/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title='Clare asks, "How can I have both a Mac and a PC?"' data-link="/2014/05/clare-asks-can-mac-pc/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/05/clare-asks-can-mac-pc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
