<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; GAAM</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/gaam/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#54 Teenage Mutant Ninja Deemable</title>
		<link>/2013/11/54-teenage-mutant-ninja-deemable/</link>
		<comments>/2013/11/54-teenage-mutant-ninja-deemable/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 17:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer support]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GAAM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Games Art and Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Support]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JaxComputerChic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech support]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TMNT]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8418</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week Ray and Elizabeth were joined in the studio&#160;by Ryan Paul Thompson, the founder and president of GAAM, Games Art and Music, to talk to us about the upcoming GAAM event, Teenage Mutant Ninja GAAM, Saturday, December 7, 2013 <a href="/2013/11/54-teenage-mutant-ninja-deemable/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/11/54-teenage-mutant-ninja-deemable/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week Ray and Elizabeth were joined in the studio&nbsp;by Ryan Paul Thompson, the founder and president of <a onclick="javascript:_gaq.push(['_trackEvent','outbound-article','http://gaamshow.com/']);" href="http://gaamshow.com/">GAAM, Games Art and Music</a>, to talk to us about the upcoming GAAM event, <a href="http://gaam.eventbrite.com/">Teenage Mutant Ninja GAAM</a>, Saturday, December 7, 2013 starting at 6:00 PM. There&rsquo;s going to be&nbsp;video game art exhibit, video game competition, cosplay competition and free beer! Ray, Tom and Sean went to the <a href="http://deemable.com/2013/06/41-the-legend-of-gaam-is-extreme-but-its-not-free-99/">last GAAM show</a>, and it was a blast. If you love video games, you should definitely check it out. Head over to <a href="http://gaam.eventbrite.com/">gaam.eventbrite.com</a> to get your tickets.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://gaam.eventbrite.com/"><img class="aligncenter" alt="Teenage Mutant Ninja GAAM" src="//media/2013/11/TMNG.jpg" width="600" height="222"></a></p>
<p>After the break, Ray and Elizabeth answered listeners questions about&nbsp;&nbsp;transferring an iTunes collection from a dead computer, which antivirus software is the best, and how to restore an iPhone from an older backup.</p>
<p>And remember, we are prepping for the first Deemable Tech hour-long radio episode. Get your calls in at 1-888-972-9868 to &ldquo;audition&rdquo; for the show!&nbsp;</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-8418-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-11-03.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-11-03.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-11-03.mp3</a></audio><p><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-11-03.mp3">#54 Teenage Mutant Ninja Deemable</a></p>
<p>TRANSCRIPT</p>
<p>RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>ELIZABETH: I&rsquo;m Elizabeth Pampalone, in for Tom Braun</p>
<p>RAY: and this is Deemable Tech. This week&rsquo;s episode is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p>ELIZABETH: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? You can give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at questions@deemable.com.</p>
<p>RAY: We mentioned this last week, but once Tom get&rsquo;s back, we are going to be&nbsp;working on our first, hour-long Deemable Tech radio special, and we need your help. We need some live callers to be&nbsp;on the show. So, we want you to call and leave a voicemail. We will be using them to pick our callers for the show. Make sure to leave your phone number so we can schedule a time for you to be on the show.</p>
<p>Now, before we get to your questions, we have a guest back in the studio again, Ryan Thompson, creator and President of GAAM, Games, Art and Music is here! Welcome to the show, Ryan!</p>
<p>You were on the show back in June before your last event and you guys have another awesome event coming up really soon.</p>
<p>Questions for Ryan Paul Thompson</p>
<ul><li>What is GAAM? What is the purpose of GAAM?</li>
<li>Where did you get the idea for GAAM?</li>
<li>Ask about the last GAAM&nbsp;event, The Legend of GAAM</li>
<li>Tell us about Teenage Mutant Ninja GAAM</li>
</ul><p>Ryan, thanks so much for coming in. Where can our listeners find out more about GAAM and get tickets for the event?</p>
<p>BREAK</p>
<p>Well, we have to take a quick break, after the break Elizabeth and I will answer a few questions from you guys about antivirus software, moving your iTunes account to a new computer.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech.</p>
<p>OUTRO</p>
<p><b>Name: </b>Phil</p>
<p><b>Question:</b>&nbsp;How do I switch my iTunes account from an old computer which no longer turns on to my new computer? I&rsquo;ve downloaded iTunes onto&nbsp;the new computer but, needless to say, it doesn&rsquo;t recognize my account. The last time I changed computers with the same problem I had to start a new account on the new computer and reenter music into my library. I have all my music on my iPod but now am not able to add to it.</p>
<p><b>Answer: </b>Before Switching computers, go into My Music (Music), Itunes, Save the iTunes Library.itl and iTunes Library.xml files to a flash drive or external drive. Install itunes&nbsp;on the new computer. Go into the same location (Music/iTunes) and replace those files with your library files from the older computer. Make sure to move your music files to the same place as they lived on the old computer. (ie Music)</p>
<p>If it&rsquo;s too late, and you&rsquo;ve already gotten rid of your old computer, try <a href="http://www.digidna.net/diskaid">DiskAid</a> or <a href="http://www.macroplant.com/iexplorer/">iExplorer</a> to take music, movies, etc. off of your iPad, iPod, iPhone and get it into your computer.</p>
<p><b>Name: </b>Danielle</p>
<p>&nbsp;<b>Question: </b>Is paying for antivirus software more safer that the free versions? What are some recommendations for antivirus?</p>
<p><b>Answer: </b>We answered this once before on our <a href="http://deemable.com/2013/01/jo-el-asks-which-antivirus-software-is-the-best/">radio segment</a>. If you are using a Windows: XP, Vista, Win 7 use MS Security Essentials. It is FREE and works seamlessly with Windows Firewall and Windows Defender. Windows 8 has MS Security Essentials built in. It is really the best antivirus software on the market, especially for the price. Word of caution: you can only use ONE antivirus at a time. You can not have TWO running, they will cancel each other out!</p>
<p>If you are using Mac, antivirus protection is built&nbsp;in. Check System Preferences, Security &amp; Privacy. There are some settings you might want to check out the settings there. Some of the items on General and Privacy tabs are good to go through based on what your personal preferences happen to be.</p>
<p><b>Name:</b> Valerie</p>
<p><b>Question:</b> Can I retrieve an iPhone backup from maybe 5 backups ago?</p>
<p>iPhoto&nbsp;apparently failed on one of my loads from image capture, and of course I had the &ldquo;delete&nbsp;after import&rdquo; option checked. I saw some warning about iPhoto&nbsp;being full (although not an issue since) after my Macbook Pro had been working&nbsp;for awhile. I didn&rsquo;t have time to deal with it and later re-backed up my phone. When I went looking for the 3 months of photos/videos, I couldn&rsquo;t find them anywhere on my computer &mdash; it is a mess. Also my time machine (to my external hard drive) apparently hadn&rsquo;t been working during that time period either. I just can&rsquo;t imagine that the photos/video from the whole&nbsp;upload don&rsquo;t exist in some cache somewhere.</p>
<p><b>Answer:</b> Plug in your iPhone, click the Summary button, and under Backups click Restore Backup. If you have multiple backups saved, you should have a drop down menu appear. Choose one of the options.</p>
<p><a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1766">http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1766</a></p>
<p>Thanks for all your questions, and keep them coming. Call us at our toll-free number, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com. Also, subscribe to the show! Search for Deemable Tech on iTunes, YouTube, Facebook and Twitter and follow us or subscribe.</p>
<p>Our producer is Sean Birch. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Elizabeth Pampalone, and this is Deemable Tech. Thanks for listening. Have a great week.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#54 Teenage Mutant Ninja Deemable" data-link="/2013/11/54-teenage-mutant-ninja-deemable/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#54 Teenage Mutant Ninja Deemable" data-link="/2013/11/54-teenage-mutant-ninja-deemable/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/11/54-teenage-mutant-ninja-deemable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-11-03.mp3" length="31698039" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#41 &#8211; The Legend of GAAM Is EXTREME, But It&#8217;s Not Free-99</title>
		<link>/2013/06/41-the-legend-of-gaam-is-extreme-but-its-not-free-99/</link>
		<comments>/2013/06/41-the-legend-of-gaam-is-extreme-but-its-not-free-99/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 03:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GAAM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Reader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MacBook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Macbook Pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RSS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RSS readers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7399</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/06/GAAMShow-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="The Legend of GAAM" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />If you missed it live, Ryan Thompson from GAAM, Games Art and Music, stopped by the studio tonight to talk to us about the upcoming The Legend of GAAM Show July 13 at 6:00 PM at the Museum and Gardens <a href="/2013/06/41-the-legend-of-gaam-is-extreme-but-its-not-free-99/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/06/41-the-legend-of-gaam-is-extreme-but-its-not-free-99/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/06/GAAMShow-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="The Legend of GAAM" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/06/GAAMShow.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright wp-image-7406" alt="The Legend of GAAM" src="//media/2013/06/GAAMShow.jpg"  width="200" height="200"></a>If you missed it live, Ryan Thompson from <a href="http://gaamshow.com/">GAAM, Games Art and Music</a>, stopped by the studio tonight to talk to us about the upcoming <a href="http://gaam.eventbrite.com/">The Legend of GAAM Show</a> July 13 at 6:00 PM at the Museum and Gardens at 4160 Boulevard Center Drive, Jacksonville, Florida. Before we talked to him about that, we answered Joel&rsquo;s question about which Macbook Pro and which Airport to pick. Then, we helped Katy pick a newsreader for her Android phone.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/ILoveGAAM">GAAM on Facebook</a></p>
<span class="embed-youtube" style="text-align:center; display: block;"><iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="752" height="453" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BqSJroMH6O4?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-7399-2" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-06-23.mp3?_=2"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-06-23.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-06-23.mp3</a></audio><p><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-06-23.mp3">#41 &ndash; The Legend of GAAM Is EXTREME, But It&rsquo;s Not Free-99</a><br>
DRAFT SCRIPT</p>
<p>RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>TOM: I&rsquo;m Tom Braun,</p>
<p>RAY: and this is Deemable Tech, tech help worth listening to.</p>
<p>RAY: This week&rsquo;s episode of the Deemable Tech podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p>TOM: And, by <a href="http://audibletrial.com/Deemable">audible.com</a> &ndash; Deemable Tech listeners can get a FREE audiobook download at <a href="http://audibletrial.com/Deemable">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a> Over 100,000 titles to choose from for your iPhone, Android, Kindle or mp3 player.</p>
<p>RAY: And, from All Florida Insurance Options, an authorized Progressive agency, helping people shop for insurance at 904-757-3288 or at their office in Highland Square on Dunn Avenue in North Jacksonville.</p>
<p>TOM: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? Give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at questions@deemable.com.</p>
<p>RAY: So, if you haven&rsquo;t noticed, the podcast has been a little sporadic lately. We&rsquo;ve been only doing the show every other week.</p>
<p>Summer vacation!</p>
<p>We have good reasons, I have a pile of products to review like the Therapik and the Jabra Halo 2.<br>
We&rsquo;re also working on getting the app developed. Starting in September we&rsquo;ll come back with weekly podcasts.</p>
<p>Today on the show we have a special guest, Ryan Thompson, creator and President of GAAM, which stands for Games, Art and Music.</p>
<p>But first we have a couple questions from listeners.</p>
<p>Joel writes: Hey Ray and Tom,<br>
You may remember me from such questions as, &ldquo;should I sick my finger in there?&rdquo; and &ldquo;is this burning sensation normal?&rdquo;<br>
Today I&rsquo;d like to know about the differences between some Apple products.<br>
I&rsquo;m slowing being turned to the Gala side (that&rsquo;s an apple joke) and switching to more and more Apple products.<br>
I would specifically like to know about the differences between two products:<br>
MacBook Pro vs. MacBook Pro w/Retina Display<br>
and<br>
AirPort vs. AirPort EXTREME!<br>
For the MacBook Pro, it&rsquo;s important to note that I am not a graphic designer/artists. The extent of my photo editing skills will just be basic touch-up of photos. I&rsquo;m not looking for a gaming rig, just something that&rsquo;s reliable, fast, and that has a decent battery life.<br>
For the AirPort vs. Extreme, other than awesome flashbacks to the &rsquo;90s,<br>
what makes the EXTREME so EXTREME?<br>
RAY: OK, let me answer your first question. Here&rsquo;s the differences between the Macbook Pro and the Macbook Pro with Retina Display.<br>
Obviously the Retina Display model has a retina display. 2880 x 1800 pixels vs 1440 x 900 pixels<br>
-More pixels, brighter screen, incredibly high detail. More room for photo and video editing<br>
&ndash; Also the Retina display model is thinner and about a pound lighter.<br>
The retina model comes with more standard RAM, 8 GB vs 4 GB, but you can get 8 GB in the standard Macbook Pro model.<br>
The retina model comes with 768 GB flash storage, but the standard model comes with 512 Solid State drive or 1 TB hard drive.<br>
Also, the retina model does not have an optical drive so no DVDs or CDs.<br>
If you are graphic designer, or video editor, I&rsquo;d say go with the retina model if you can afford it. Otherwise, I&rsquo;d stick with the standard model, unless you just really want the retina display.<br>
&mdash;&ndash;<br>
Now, for Airport vs Airport Extreme<br>
There&rsquo;s actually three options, Airport Express, Airport Extreme and Airport Time Capsule.<br>
The difference is in the price, size, speed and capability of the routers.<br>
The Airport Express is the cheapest at $99, smallest at about the same size as an Apple TV (about a 4 inch square, 1 inch tall.). It&rsquo;s also the slowest. It only runs up to 802.11n. It also only has one Ethernet ports and one USB port. You can plug a printer into it and share it on your network. You can also use the Airport Express for audio AirPlay. So, you can play music or podcasts wireless from your iOS devices or Mac computers to speakers plugged into your Airport Express.<br>
The Airport Extreme costs $199, and it is about the same size, but about 4 times taller. It looks like four Airport Expresses stacked on top of each other. It runs 802.11ac which is the fastest existing WiFi standard. It can run up to 3 times faster than 802.11n, if you have a computer with a 802.11ac wifi adapter. With the Airport Extreme you can also share a hard drive on your network in addition to a printer.<br>
The Airport Time Capsule is basically an Airport Extreme with a hard drive built in. The 2 TB model costs $299, and the 3 TB model costs $399.<br>
Strangely the Time Capsule and the Extreme both dropped the AirPlay feature.<br>
Also, if you were wondering, because I was, neither the Macbook Pro, nor the Macbook Pro with Retina Display come with 802.11ac wifi. They only have 802.11n.<br>
The only Mac that is currently for sale with 802.11ac is the new Macbook Air. The new Mac Pro (the well designed trash can) will have 802.11ac.</p>
<p>Katy writes: Hello Tom and Ray!<br>
I like to follow a few blogs and would love to get updates when new posts are added. Can you recommend a blog reader app for my Droid?<br>
Thanks guys!<br>
PS, we love your show! My twin babies Christopher &amp; Clara like to listen to it with us every Thursday morning. They&rsquo;re going to be so smart!<br>
TOM: Wow, those poor kids. Thanks for listening, Katy! Anyway, what you need in as RSS reader app. We&rsquo;ve talked about RSS before. It&rsquo;s basically the way that blogs can publish their content to third party apps. Almost every blog out there supports this.<br>
RAY: Lots of news sites do also.<br>
TOM: Yeah. So with a good RSS reader app you can get all your news and favorite blogs in one place. If you go to the Google Play Market and search for ?RSS reader&rsquo; you&rsquo;ll see dozens of apps, most of them free.<br>
A word of caution, though: do not download the Google Reader app. Google Reader is being shut down July 1st, 2013. So if you download it now you&rsquo;ll only have a matter days of before it stops working.<br>
RAY: It&rsquo;s too bad, since Google Reader was kind of the 900 lbs gorilla of the RSS reader world.<br>
TOM: That&rsquo;s true. In fact Google Reader was more than just an app, it was also an entire back-end database that synched what you had and hadn&rsquo;t read across multiple devices. A lot of other apps actually depended on it. And that&rsquo;s why you also need to avoid apps that are dependent on Google Reader, because those will also stop working on July 1st. A few examples include the NewsRob and GoodNews apps. Those tell you that they run off Google Reader and that they will be shutting down. Be sure to check for that on any app you download.<br>
RAY: Okay, so those are apps not to use. What are some suggestions for apps that Katy should use?<br>
TOM: Feedly.<br>
RAY: Feedly?<br>
TOM: Feedly.<br>
Feedly is the heir apparent to Google Reader. If you were previously using Google Reader, Feedly is making it very easy to migrate to Feedly. Like Google Reader, it allows you to synchronize what you&rsquo;ve read across multiple devices, like your desktop and your phone. It looks and feels similar to Google Reader, except it is more customizable. Feedly would be my #1 and probably my #2 suggestion for an RSS Reader app for Android right now.<br>
RAY: Yeah, Feedly is great. And it&rsquo;s also available for the iPhone in the App Store.<br>
TOM: gReader is another app that is getting strong reviews. It used to connect Google Reader, but now you can connect it to Feedly.<br>
RAY: Why wouldn&rsquo;t people just use the Feedly app?<br>
TOM: Well, it&rsquo;s possible people might like the feel of gReader more. But yeah, if you&rsquo;re just starting out like Katy is, I would recommend Feedly. And the best part of all, it doesn&rsquo;t cost a thing!<br>
TOM: It&rsquo;s Free-99!<br>
RAY: It&rsquo;s Free-99?<br>
TOM: It&rsquo;s Free-99!<br>
RAY: Personally, after I heard the news about Google Reader, I spent the requisite amount of time mourning my favorite news reader, but after that I decided not to move on and find another reader. I&rsquo;ve gone back to just reading Google News for the big headlines, and checking the individual websites. I do use Flipboard a bit to follow some sites, but otherwise, I have reduced the amount of news reading I have done by about 90%. I&rsquo;m not sure if I&rsquo;ll go back or not, but for now, I&rsquo;m satisfied with Flipboard.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#41 - The Legend of GAAM Is EXTREME, But It's Not Free-99" data-link="/2013/06/41-the-legend-of-gaam-is-extreme-but-its-not-free-99/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#41 - The Legend of GAAM Is EXTREME, But It's Not Free-99" data-link="/2013/06/41-the-legend-of-gaam-is-extreme-but-its-not-free-99/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/06/41-the-legend-of-gaam-is-extreme-but-its-not-free-99/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-06-23.mp3" length="60022700" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
