<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Windows 10</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/windows-10/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Ask Deemable Tech: Do I Need To Wait To Upgrade To Windows 10?</title>
		<link>/2016/02/10527/</link>
		<comments>/2016/02/10527/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 23:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10527</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/02/windows_10_logo-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="windows_10_logo" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Joan writes, &#8220;I&#8217;m running Windows 7 on my laptop, and for the past five months I&#8217;ve had a request pending to get the upgrade to Windows 10. Am I supposed to just keep waiting patiently, or is there something else <a href="/2016/02/10527/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2016/02/10527/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/02/windows_10_logo-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="windows_10_logo" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2016/02/windows_10_logo.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10528 alignleft" src="/media/2016/02/windows_10_logo-300x247.jpg"  alt="windows_10_logo" width="300" height="247"></a>Joan writes, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m running Windows 7 on my laptop, and for the past five months I&rsquo;ve had a request pending to get the upgrade to Windows 10. Am I supposed to just keep waiting patiently, or is there something else I&rsquo;m supposed to do?&rdquo;</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10527-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/02/adt20160225.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/02/adt20160225.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/02/adt20160225.mp3</a></audio><p>Congratulations, Joan, on being way more patient than we are! We&rsquo;re about to lose our minds just waiting for the next season of &ldquo;Sherlock&rdquo; to air.</p>
<p>You should be able to download and upgrade to Windows 10 right now for free, if you&rsquo;re currently using Windows 7, 8 or 8.1 Most Windows users have been receiving little notifications about the update since July 2015. If you clicked on that notification and followed the directions, it should have upgraded your system as soon as Windows 10 became available.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re not getting those notifications, or that option just didn&rsquo;t work for some reason, you can go to <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/windows-10-upgrade" target="_blank">Microsoft&rsquo;s website</a> and click the Windows 10 link to manually start the download and installation.</p>
<p>But why would you want to upgrade to Windows 10? Well, it depends on which operating system you&rsquo;re currently using.</p>
<p>Windows 10 is a much smaller installation than Windows 7. It runs a lot faster, and you&rsquo;ll see a big performance boost by upgrading, even without changing any of the hardware in your computer.</p>
<p>For those readers currently running Windows 8, you absolutely have to upgrade to Windows 10 as soon as possible. Microsoft dropped support for Windows 8 in early 2016, which means there won&rsquo;t be any more security updates, software patches or bug fixes.</p>
<p>There aren&rsquo;t as many differences between Windows 8.1 and Windows 10, but we still suggest upgrading anyway. You&rsquo;ll get the latest version that should be supported for longer, and you?ll get some cool new features like Cortana, Microsoft&rsquo;s virtual assistant that is sort of like Siri for your home PC.</p>
<p>Another new feature we really like are virtual desktops, which let you set up multiple virtual workspaces on one computer and switch back and forth between them. It&rsquo;s like having multiple screens without having extra monitors.</p>
<p>So, Joan, go ahead and upgrade, and see if you like it!</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Ask Deemable Tech: Do I Need To Wait To Upgrade To Windows 10?" data-link="/2016/02/10527/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Ask Deemable Tech: Do I Need To Wait To Upgrade To Windows 10?" data-link="/2016/02/10527/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/02/10527/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/02/adt20160225.mp3" length="3353129" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#95 Murder, She Robot</title>
		<link>/2015/08/95-murder-she-robot/</link>
		<comments>/2015/08/95-murder-she-robot/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 20:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Dott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firmware worm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fujifilm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Glass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HitchBot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kentucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MacBook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philadelphia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thunderstrike 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VLC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows Media Player]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wired]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10195</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/08/MurderSheRobot-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Murder She Robot" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Murdered robots, silent video chat, drones being shot out of the sky, X-ray vision cameras and more Windows 10 news. All the tech news worth talking about this week on Deemable Tech. If you&#8217;re listening to Deemable Tech on the&#160;website, <a href="/2015/08/95-murder-she-robot/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/08/95-murder-she-robot/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/08/MurderSheRobot-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Murder She Robot" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2015/08/MurderSheRobot.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright wp-image-10206 size-medium" src="/media/2015/08/MurderSheRobot-300x225.jpg"  alt="Murder She Robot" width="300" height="225"></a>Murdered robots, silent video chat, drones being shot out of the sky, X-ray vision cameras and more Windows 10 news. All the tech news worth talking about this week on Deemable Tech.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on the&nbsp;website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you&rsquo;re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10195-2" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-07.mp3?_=2"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-07.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-07.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S RUNDOWN</h1>
<h3>Yahoo released Yahoo LiveText. No one is sure why.</h3>
<p>Yahoo announced a new app this week called Yahoo Livetext on <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/yahoo-livetext-video-messenger/id995121875?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yahoo.arrow&amp;hl=en" target="_blank">Android</a>. With the new app you can chat with people you know, while you look at them on a live video. What makes Livetext different than any other video chat app out there like Skype, Facetime or Google Hangouts is that you cannot hear the person on the other end. Don&rsquo;t worry, it&rsquo;s not your phone. Yahoo designed it like that? for some reason. We tried it out.</p>
<h3>Windows 10 Updates</h3>
<p>Windows 10 has been out for a week now and we&rsquo;ve learned a few more things about it.</p>
<p>Among other things, it turns out that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Finformation-technology%2F2015%2F08%2Fwindows-10-doesnt-offer-much-privacy-by-default-heres-how-to-fix-it%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFNt9WQE9YVYd_TzjZRUFFsmnVLWw">Windows 10 collects a </a><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Finformation-technology%2F2015%2F08%2Fwindows-10-doesnt-offer-much-privacy-by-default-heres-how-to-fix-it%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFNt9WQE9YVYd_TzjZRUFFsmnVLWw">lot</a><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Finformation-technology%2F2015%2F08%2Fwindows-10-doesnt-offer-much-privacy-by-default-heres-how-to-fix-it%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFNt9WQE9YVYd_TzjZRUFFsmnVLWw">&nbsp;more data on its users than previous version of the operating system did</a>. The main reason for this appears to be Cortana: the nifty digital personal assistant needs a lot more personal data to power her search results and voice recognition. Of course, that isn&rsquo;t to say that Microsoft isn&rsquo;t just taking a page from Google and Facebook here.</p>
<p>If you want to stop Windows 10 from&nbsp;gathering up your contacts, calendar details, text and touch input, location data, and a whole lot more and sending it off into the cloud, you will need to let Windows know. This can be done at installation: you&rsquo;ll need to select &lsquo;custom settings&rsquo; instead of &lsquo;express&rsquo; and then you will see the personalized settings for what data Windows will collect on you. If you&rsquo;ve already installed Windows 10, you can also limit the data it is phoning home by signing in with a strictly local account rather than a Microsoft one.</p>
<p>Cortana herself also has settings that you will need to adjust.</p>
<p>Needless to say, you may find Cortana to be less functional if you disable all of these options.</p>
<p>Another surprise in store for those upgrading to Windows 10: Windows Media Center, Microsoft&rsquo;s free media player which has for years allowed DVD playback in Windows, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.co.uk%2Fgadgets%2F2015%2F08%2Fmicrosoft-wants-you-to-pay-12-for-dvd-playback-in-windows-10%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGC5ZriS3JrOPrORaN7R8k4VcH_DA">will disappear</a>. Its replacement is an app in the Windows Store called Windows DVD Player, but this new app isn&rsquo;t free &ndash; it will cost you $14.99. Which is too bad, considering that it doesn&rsquo;t do any of the cool stuff Media Center used to do, like DVR, image slideshows, and media organization.</p>
<p>DVD playback isn&rsquo;t the only formerly free feature is holding its hand out for your credit card in Windows 10. Minesweeper and Solitaire, those old Windows standbys, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsweek.com%2Fsolitaire-microsoft-windows-10-pay-freemium-358366&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNG7YuZ0qsu9H-shQrfSe2N6LRCHUQ">are now full of intrusive ads unless you pay a $9.99 annual fee</a>. That&rsquo;s not so great.</p>
<p>You know what IS great? VLC media player! It&rsquo;s still free, it still plays DVDs, and it still works with Windows 10. We&rsquo;re just saying.</p>
<h3>More fun drone news</h3>
<p>The Daily Dot is reporting that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.dailydot.com%2Ftechnology%2Fkentucky-drone-shooting%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGjOlEq-0UIwu5nIrHki0Rnw55hBA">a Kentucky man blew a drone out of the sky with a shotgun</a>. He claims that his kids told him the drone had passed over the house multiple times before, and he claims that the drone dropped down to close to the ground and was hovering over his back deck where his 16-year-old daughter was sun bathing. He had enough at that point and fired duck shot knocking it out of the sky. When the drone pilot and three of his buddies showed up to collect the drone, the father told them,&nbsp;&ldquo;If you cross that sidewalk onto my property, there&rsquo;s going to be another shooting.&rdquo; Instead of doing that, they waited for the police to arrive and the father was arrested and charged with wanton endangerment and criminal mischief related to his firing the gun.</p>
<p>The drone owner has since released video to WDRB in Louisville showing <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wdrb.com%2Fstory%2F29670583%2Fupdate-drone-owner-disputes-shooters-story-produces-video-he-claims-shows-flight-path&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNH6Be_M9SpDhcvdKCB_mNz-QiUxdA">the drone was almost 200 feet above the ground</a>&nbsp;and it moving when it was shot. The drone operator says he was heading to his friends house to shoot pictures for him at his request and was only passing by.</p>
<h3>When you shut down the newsstand, you don&rsquo;t sell newspapers</h3>
<p>Back in October 2014, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Ftech-policy%2F2014%2F10%2Fcountry-by-country-europe-falls-in-and-out-of-love-with-a-google-tax%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNE20zuj9MGEQ-Bm-lZSguRO7nfIDA">Spain decided to impose a levy on Google for using snippets of Spanish news articles</a>&nbsp;and linking to news articles in Google News. Google responded by almost immediately <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Ftech-policy%2F2014%2F12%2Fthe-predictable-result-of-spains-google-tax-no-more-google-news%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHyZZXOUa9yAL7EvaqU_zGriVZQ6w">removing all Spanish news outlets from Google News</a>.</p>
<p>A report commissioned by the Asociacio?n Espan?ola de Editoriales de Publicaciones Perio?dicas (Spanish Association of Publishers of Periodicals) came out last week showing that Spains little experiment is working? for no one.</p>
<p>The study showed that in the short term, the law will cost publishers about ?10 million or about $10.9 million. The cost will fall especially on smaller news outlets who disproportionately are getting less traffic since Google News went dark in Spain.</p>
<h2>Fujifilm camera sees through clothes</h2>
<p>Fujifilm has announced a new camera called the X-T1 IR which boasts a 16 megapixel sensor, high speed autofocus, and wifi connectivity. Oh yeah, and <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wired.com%2F2015%2F08%2Ffujifilm-x-t1-infrared%2F%3Fmbid%3Dsocial_twitter&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGytZDHQFzB7hfzooshAYk37R-lcw">according to a new Wired report, it may be able to see through some clothes</a>. That&rsquo;s right, the &ldquo;IR&rdquo; in X-T1 IR stands for &lsquo;infrared&rsquo;. Infrared photography allows would-be shutterbugs to capture some trippy and dreamlike images and helps specialists like crime-scene techs locate blood spatter. But it can also allow pervs with cameras to get an eyeful, given the right conditions. Specifically, the clothing in question would have to be pretty thin in the first place for these cameras to see through it.</p>
<p>Hopefully dweebs hanging around the girls&rsquo; locker room will be priced out of the market: the cameras will start at $1700 when they go on sale in October.</p>
<p><span style="overflow: hidden; display: inline-block; margin: 0.00px 0.00px; border: 0.00px solid #000000; transform: rotate(0.00rad) translateZ(0px); -webkit-transform: rotate(0.00rad) translateZ(0px);"><img style="margin-left: 0.00px; margin-top: 0.00px; transform: rotate(0.00rad) translateZ(0px); -webkit-transform: rotate(0.00rad) translateZ(0px);" title="" src="/media/2015/08/Script-08-07-2015-95-.jpg" alt=""></span></p>
<h3>Macs get malware too</h3>
<p>Wired is reporting that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wired.com%2F2015%2F08%2Fresearchers-create-first-firmware-worm-attacks-macs%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFrxxSQq7hhSMoXNqtt_Sc0GmlTQw">the first firmware worm for Mac</a>&nbsp;has been developed. The worm dubbed &ldquo;Thunderstrike 2&rdquo; is a proof-of-concept. (The original Thunderstrike did the same thing, but required physical access to the computer) The worm can spread from Mac to Mac without it needing to be networked. Even air-gapped Apple computers would be vulnerable to the attack. Since it is a firmware worm, the processor chip would have to be reflashed to eliminate the worm, and since these are Macs we are talking about, this basically means they would have to be thrown away, because who can work on Macs, amirite?</p>
<p>Fortunately, the worm was created by hackers who are discussing their findings at the Black Hat Conference this week in Las Vegas, so manufacturers like Apple will be able to use their research to improve the security of firmware.</p>
<h3>The mysterious murder of HitchBot in the city of brotherly love</h3>
<p>Our next story is something of an unfolding saga.</p>
<p>A year ago, a team of Canadian researchers created a small robot which they dubbed HitchBot. HitchBot was completely immobile, but it could interact with people. It&rsquo;s mission was to hitchhike from place to place. In 2014 it successfully hitched all the way across Canada. Later it made a similar journey through Germany and the Netherlands. On July 17th of this year, HitchBot set out for its biggest road trip yet: crossing the US, starting in Massachusetts and hopefully winding up in San Francisco&rsquo;s Exploratorium. Sadly, the little bot that could had only made it to the city of Philadelphia <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Fthe-multiverse%2F2015%2F08%2Frobot-depending-on-kindness-of-strangers-meets-its-demise-in-philadelphia%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEa1ajU5izrdTqNMgedD4S1ALBs9w">when tragedy struck</a>.</p>
<p>The precise details aren&rsquo;t known, but HitchBot was found dismembered, its limbs strewn across the street and its internal wiring damaged or scooped out. Although HitchBot reportedly takes a picture every ten minutes or so of its currently location, no picture was taken of its assailant.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.crossingbroad.com%2F2015%2F08%2Fhitchbot-was-actually-destroyed-but-surveillance-video-was-dumb-youtube-prank.html&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFzmmF_VQeqoCONKkbdvA-Zwpw7vw">This is where things get a little weird</a>: two Philly-based YouTubers were reportedly the last people who the bot &lsquo;hitched&rsquo; a ride with before it was destroyed. They then came forward claiming to have obtained surveillance footage from a nearby camera showing the attacker. The footage they delivered appeared to show one of the YouTubers kicking and stomping on an obscured object and waving what looked like HitchBot&rsquo;s limbs around. After some initial confusion, the YouTubers said this was a prank and that they in fact had nothing to do with HitchBot&rsquo;s demise.</p>
<p>There are still some good Samaritans in the City of Brotherly Love. Hackers from a local makerspace <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Fthe-multiverse%2F2015%2F08%2Fwe-can-rebuild-him-philadelphia-hackers-offer-brotherly-love-to-fallen-robot%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFq41VBrFc4VLE5sHarrsmnXrWiDg">offered to rebuild HitchBot</a>. However, the bot&rsquo;s original creators intend to rebuild it themselves better than before, so that it will be ready for its next big trip. The predicted starting point? Philadelphia.</p>
<hr><p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#95 Murder, She Robot" data-link="/2015/08/95-murder-she-robot/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#95 Murder, She Robot" data-link="/2015/08/95-murder-she-robot/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/08/95-murder-she-robot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-07.mp3" length="30825089" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#94 Windows 10 Is Out But We’re Still Sticking With Windows 9</title>
		<link>/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/</link>
		<comments>/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 22:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiat Chrysler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Firefox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet.org]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smart Guns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stephen Hawking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Wozniak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10183</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/Windows10cropped-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="So much for Windows 10 fun. Now Ray has to reinstall Windows 8.1 just so he can upgrade it to 10, so he can reinstall Windows 10!" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Killer robots, self-aware robots, cars, guns and Android phones getting hacked into and the death of another Google product? Yeah, that sounds like a typical Deemable Tech episode. If you?re listening to Deemable Tech on the&#160;website, make sure to&#160;subscribe to <a href="/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/Windows10cropped-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="So much for Windows 10 fun. Now Ray has to reinstall Windows 8.1 just so he can upgrade it to 10, so he can reinstall Windows 10!" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_10185" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10185" src="/media/2015/07/Windows10cropped-300x212.jpg" alt="So much for Windows 10 fun. Now Ray has to reinstall Windows 8.1 just so he can upgrade it to 10, so he can reinstall Windows 10!" width="300" height="212"><p class="wp-caption-text">So much for Windows 10 fun. Now Ray has to reinstall Windows 8.1 just so he can upgrade it to 10, so he can reinstall Windows 10!</p></div>
<p>Killer robots, self-aware robots, cars, guns and Android phones getting hacked into and the death of another Google product? Yeah, that sounds like a typical Deemable Tech episode.</p>
<p>If you?re listening to Deemable Tech on the&nbsp;website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you?re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there. We?re also looking for a new admin to help manage and moderate our subreddit page. Submit a text post to our subreddit explaining why you would make a great admin.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10183-3" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-31.mp3?_=3"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-31.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-31.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK?S RUNDOWN</h1>
<h3><strong>Windows 10 is released.</strong></h3>
<p>Our top story this week is the long-awaited release of Microsoft?s Windows 10. In an unprecedented move, Microsoft has made the new Windows available as a free upgrade to anyone who had Windows 7, 8 or 8.1. The upgrade became available to download for most of those folks starting on Wednesday.</p>
<p>With Windows 10, Microsoft hopes to reunite its fractured userbase, many of whom are still stuck way back on Windows XP. Windows 10 will feature continuous upgrades and may be the last major windows version for the foreseeable future. To lure back customers scared off by the controversial Windows 8, Windows 10 brings back the Start Button and does away with the charms menu.</p>
<p>Other new features include the integration of Microsoft?s Siri-like virtual assistant Cortana, the brand new Edge web browser, virtual desktops, and Mission Control, which gives you an overview of all the apps you have running.</p>
<p>Ray Hollister has bravely volunteered to install Windows the 10th on the dual boot partition of his MacBook, so let?s dive right in.</p>
<p>The beauty of Windows 10 is that you can&rsquo;t install Windows 10 as a fresh, clean install. Except you can. But you can&rsquo;t.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/antonyleather/2015/07/30/windows-10-updating-reinstalling-and-activation-guide-essential-advice-to-avoid-problems/">Forbes &ndash; Windows 10 Updating, Reinstalling And Activation Guide: Essential Advice To Avoid Problems</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/29/9058825/windows-10-macbook-how-to-install-osx">The Verge &ndash; How to get Windows 10 on your Mac</a></p>
<h3><strong>CEO of Mozilla Firefox complains in an open letter that Windows 10 upgrade resets default web browser</strong></h3>
<p>Mozilla CEO Chris Beard is one person who is less than pleased with Windows 10. It appears that when you do an upgrade with ?Express Settings? that <a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2015/07/windows-10-upgrade-resets-your-default-browser-to-edge-mozilla-is-very-unhappy/">it will default your browser to Microsoft?s Edge browser</a>, even if you had Firefox selected by default before. Even worse, in Windows 10 the default browser is now buried down in the settings control panel, meaning that it is difficult to find for non-technical users. Microsoft defends the changes as making the upgrade ?simple and cohesive? for users and says that they may make ?improvements? in the future.</p>
<h3><strong>Facebook builds an Internet drone</strong></h3>
<p>The BBC is reporting that <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-33728704">Facebook has built a drone</a>, with the wingspan of a Boeing 737 that will fly as high as 90,000 feet and for up to 90 days at a time to provide wireless Internet access at up to 10 Gigabits per second.</p>
<p>The drone will communicate via a laser beam that can hit a target the size of a dime more than 10 miles away. The lasers will connect the drones together and to the ground.</p>
<p>This is part of Facebook&rsquo;s Internet.org project to bring Internet access to the developing world. No word on whether this will be like Internet.org&rsquo;s last launch which only included access to a few sites, which caused a bit of a backlash since the access gave an unfair advantage to those sites.</p>
<p>Facebook will be testing the drones later this year in the United States.</p>
<h3><strong>Google+ dies a slow and painful death</strong></h3>
<p>Google?s ill-fated Facebook competitor, Google+, courted a lot of controversy in 2013 when Google started requiring users to create a Google+ profile to comment on YouTube. This week on the official Google blog, <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2015/07/everything-in-its-right-place.html">the search giant announced that they would be hitting the ?undo? button on that policy</a>. They said that a Google account would be all you need to share content, create contacts, comment on YouTube, and more, across all of Google. This change will reportedly be rolled out ?in the coming months.? This announcement comes on the heels of Google splitting Google+ in two, with Google Photos becoming its own stand-alone service and app.</p>
<h3><strong>Killer Robots</strong></h3>
<p>I posted this on our Facebook page, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Deemable">facebook.com/Deemable</a>, but it bears repeating. As a general rule, everyone here at Deemable Tech is anti-killer robots.</p>
<p>Unless, as I said, the uprising has already happened, in which case, let me rephrase that: How may we serve you, robot masters?</p>
<p>I bring this all up because Elon Musk (you know, Iron Man, the guy who brought you PayPal, Tesla, SpaceX, the Hyperloop, and who plans to die on Mars) and Steve Wozniak, (the reason why you have a computer at your desk, smartphone in your pocket and ultimately why you&rsquo;re listening to this podcast) and Stephen Hawking (who you&rsquo;ll know as the guy who played poker with Data, Albert Einstein and Isaac Newton.) and have joined a letter calling for the banning of autonomous weapons.</p>
<p>We talked about a weaponized drone last week that had a gun attached to it, well imagine an autonomous drone with a gun. The icons aren&rsquo;t as concerned about them throwing a revolution and killing humanity as they are concerned about another cold war arms race where every country tries to build bigger, better faster killing machines. But considering a <a href="http://www.slashgear.com/nao-robot-becomes-self-aware-very-briefly-20393569/">robot recently demonstrated self awareness</a>, perhaps they should be concerned about a robot uprising too.</p>
<h3><strong>Hacking Smart Rifles</strong></h3>
<p>Speaking of things that shouldn&rsquo;t be connected to the Internet, like killer robots. As much as I love my connected light bulbs, switches and thermostat, The Internet of things is not necessarily a good thing. Not everything should be connected to the Internet. Case in point, smart guns. In case you didn&rsquo;t know, <a href="http://tracking-point.com/">TrackingPoint makes an smart rifle</a> that almost anyone can use to hit a bullseye up to a mile away. The gun, which sells for $13,000, has a computer screen for a scope where you can enter wind speed, ammunition weight and distance. The computer calculates the correct aim and after you pull the trigger, it waits until you have the shot lined up perfectly before firing the gun.</p>
<p>The Mirror is reporting that a couple of <a href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/technology-science/technology/hackers-force-gun-blast-wrong-6171684">married hackers have hacked the gun wirelessly to shoot 2.5 feet away from the intended target</a>. They also managed to get it to disable the firing pin, making the gun unable to fire.</p>
<h3><strong>Android hack</strong></h3>
<p>Speaking of hacks, <a href="http://news.wjct.org/post/major-flaw-android-phones-would-let-hackers-just-text">NPR is reporting that the security firm Zimperium says there&rsquo;s a &ldquo;gaping hole&rdquo; in Android</a> that would allow hackers to take over your phone, and all they need is your phone number.</p>
<p>The app Hangouts automatically processes videos when they are received by text message. So, all a hacker has to do is send a video with malware inside it and send it to your phone. Since Hangouts instantly processes the videos, there&rsquo;s nothing you can do to stop it.</p>
<p>Google has released a patch and manufacturers have been notified, but we&rsquo;ll see how long it takes for them to get the update sent out to users.</p>
<h3><strong>Fiat Chrysler follow-up</strong></h3>
<p>Last week we reported that if you had a Jeep Cherokee with Fiat Chrysler?s ?uConnect? system, hackers could remotely take control of your vehicle and destroy everyone that you hold dear. It turns out that this was a source of some concern to Chrysler Fiat, as they have issued an official recall for 1.4 million vehicles to patch the issue. Affected models include certain Dodge Rams, Dodge Vipers, Dodge Chargers, Dodge Challengers, Chrysler 200s and 300s, and of course Jeep Grand Cherokees, all model year 2013 or later. If you are driving one of those vehicles you should check to see if your specific model is affected. The recall does not actually require the vehicles to be taken to the dealer: affected owners will receive a USB device which can be used to load the patch into their uConnect systems.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/07/gadget-hacks-gm-cars-locate-unlock-start/"><strong>Wired &ndash; This Gadget Hacks GM Cars to Locate, Unlock, and Start Them</strong></a></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#94 Windows 10 Is Out But We?re Still Sticking With Windows 9" data-link="/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#94 Windows 10 Is Out But We?re Still Sticking With Windows 9" data-link="/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-31.mp3" length="38005829" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#89 Tom Loves T. Swift</title>
		<link>/2015/06/89-tom-loves-t-swift/</link>
		<comments>/2015/06/89-tom-loves-t-swift/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 19:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facial Recognition Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gmail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taylor Swift]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows XP]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10112</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/06/taylor_swift-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Jana Beamer / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week Tom shares news about Taylor Swift tackling problems with Apple Music, Sean hits the &#8220;undo send&#8221; button on that embarrassing email he just sent, and Ray looks at why a branch of the U.S. military is still running <a href="/2015/06/89-tom-loves-t-swift/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/06/89-tom-loves-t-swift/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/06/taylor_swift-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Jana Beamer / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week Tom shares news about Taylor Swift tackling problems with Apple Music, Sean hits the &ldquo;undo send&rdquo; button on that embarrassing email he just sent, and Ray looks at why a branch of the U.S. military is still running Windows XP. That and more on this week&rsquo;s Deemable Tech!<span id="more-10112"></span></p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on our website, would you subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>? And, while you&rsquo;re there, would you leave a review and say a few nice things about us? The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there. We&rsquo;re also looking for a new admin to help manage and moderate our subreddit page. Submit a text post to our subreddit explaining why you would make a great admin.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10112-4" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-26.mp3?_=4"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-26.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-26.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S RUNDOWN</h1>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><b>Taylor Swift makes Apple change its mind about paying artists during free trial period of Apple Music</b></h3>
<p><b> </b>In an abrupt about-face, Apple has changed course and decided to <a href="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/apple-music-backs-down-will-804050?utm" target="_blank">pay artists during the free trial period of Apple Music streaming</a>.</p>
<p>Apple executive Eddie Cue specifically attributed this change of heart to an open letter penned to the company by Taylor Swift, in which she said that she would not be making her album &ldquo;1989&rdquo; available on the streaming service because she felt they were not compensating artists fairly. Since Apple&rsquo;s announcement, several indie labels have announced that they were signing up with Apple Music.</p>
<div id="attachment_10116" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2015/06/taylor_swift.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-10116" src="/media/2015/06/taylor_swift-300x294.jpg"  alt="Image credit: Jana Beamer / Flickr" width="400" height="392"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: Jana Beamer / Flickr</p></div>
<h3></h3>
<h3><b>Gmail officially adds &ldquo;Undo Send&rdquo; feature</b></h3>
<p>If you&rsquo;ve ever sent an email and realized that you didn&rsquo;t attach an attachment &mdash; or worse, wrote something you never meant to say to the other person &mdash; Gmail added a feature this week that you will love: <a href="http://gizmodo.com/gmail-officially-adds-undo-send-turn-it-on-right-now-1713353235">Undo Send!</a></p>
<p>Well, maybe &ldquo;Undo Send&rdquo; is a bit of a misnomer. What the feature really does is delay sending your message for 5, 10, 20 or 30 seconds to give you the chance to change your mind.&nbsp;Just turn on &ldquo;Undo Send&rdquo; in your Gmail settings, and the next time you send something you didn&rsquo;t mean to you can just hit the &ldquo;undo&rdquo; button at the top of the page.</p>
<p>The team at Gmail has actually been experimenting with this feature for the past six years (and you could use it before now, if you knew that it existed and knew how their Google Labs section works), but they officially made it part of their mail service this week.</p>
<p>We should note that this appears to only work for personal Gmail accounts at the moment. So if your employer uses Gmail for your work email, you still need to be cautious about what you send for the time being.</p>
<h3><b>Disney and ABC TV cancel plans to offshore IT jobs</b></h3>
<p>Back in October, Disney gave notice to around 250 IT employees that work for Walt Disney Parks and Resorts. To make it worse, they thought they were being called in to find out they were getting bonuses.</p>
<p>Actually, no, it gets worse than that, they then found out that they were being &ldquo;given the opportunity&rdquo; to work longer if they stuck around and trained their replacements. The controversial part was their replacements were foreigners in the country on H-1B Visas. The purpose of the H-1B visas was to attract IT workers to the US to fill the gaps in tech labor shortages, not to replace American workers with lower wage earning employees.</p>
<p>Some <a href="http://www.computerworld.com/article/2915904/it-outsourcing/fury-rises-at-disney-over-use-of-foreign-workers.html">media outlets mentioned it</a>, but it really picked up steam when a few weeks ago, Disney&rsquo;s ABC Television Group called in about 35 application developers for a meeting, and told them they were being laid off, and they were going to be training their replacements, more foreign employees on H-1B visas.</p>
<p>However, just last week, Disney did a complete about-face, and canceled the layoffs. Of course, no one would speak to the media on the record, but <a href="http://www.computerworld.com/article/2934978/it-outsourcing/in-a-turnabout-disney-abc-tv-cancels-plans-to-outsource-it-jobs.html">an anonymous source told Computerworld</a> that Disney just &ldquo;want[s] this to go away &mdash; right now.&rdquo;</p>
<p>A source at Disney also told Computerworld that this change had absolutely nothing to do with the dozens of negative news stories that popped up after the news got out.</p>
<h3><b>You can get Windows 10 for free, but there&rsquo;s a catch</b></h3>
<p>Since Windows 10 was first announced, Microsoft has released a lot of conflicting statements about who exactly would be able to get it free. From the beginning they&rsquo;ve been consistent in saying Windows 10 will be a free upgrade to users who have Windows 7 and Windows 8 and 8.1. But for other users, things have been less clear.</p>
<p>First they said that even users without legitimate copies of Windows would be able to upgrade, then they said they wouldn&rsquo;t. Then this week there was more confusion. It appeared that Microsoft would be giving away a free copy of Windows 10 to any user who agreed to test it. However it now appears that <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2015/06/22/windows-10-licensing-explained-beta/" target="_blank">the situation is more complicated than that.</a></p>
<p>Installing the Windows 10 preview <i>will </i>grant users free access to Windows 10, but only as long as they stay in the preview program. If they leave at any point, their preview copy will eventually expire. In other words, you can get Windows free as long as you agree to beta test new releases of the operating system&hellip; forever.</p>
<h3><b>Facebook working on facial recognition software that doesn&rsquo;t need to see your face</b></h3>
<p>Facebook researchers say they are working on experimental systems that will allow Facebook to recognize users in photos <a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2015/06/facebooks-facial-recognition-will-one-day-find-you-even-while-facing-away/" target="_blank">based off their hairstyle and clothing</a>. In other words, it is facial recognition that doesn&rsquo;t actually need to see your face.</p>
<p>According to the researchers, the new system is accurate 83 percent of the time, far better than current facial recognition systems which need clear, full frontal shots of people&rsquo;s faces to recognize them. The researchers described the project as &ldquo;experimental&rdquo; and &ldquo;long term&rdquo; and said that we shouldn&rsquo;t expect it to be rolled out on the site any time soon.</p>
<p>Good thing, considering the controversies that Facebook&rsquo;s facial recognition algorithms have caused in the past.</p>
<h3><b>The Navy says Windows XP is worth $9 million</b></h3>
<p>According to Computerworld, <a href="http://www.computerworld.com/article/2939435/government-it/us-navy-paid-millions-to-stay-on-windows-xp.html">the U.S. Navy has about 100,000 computers</a> running Windows XP, Windows Server 2003, Office 2003 and Exchange 2003. Server 2003 expires in July, and all of the others have been expired. To keep their computers running in tip-top shape with security updates, the Navy is paying Microsoft $9.1 million.</p>
<p>If there was ever a computer you wanted to be secure, it would be a computer in the Navy.</p>
<p>And, to be fair to the Navy, Windows XP still has approximately 10-14 percent market share, depending on who&rsquo;s counting, which, either way, still puts it over Apple&rsquo;s OS X.</p>
<h3><b>Ebay and Amazon banning confederate flag merchandise</b></h3>
<p>Major online retailers, including Amazon, eBay, and Alibaba are <a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2015/06/ebay-bans-confederate-battle-flag-other-items-bearing-racist-icon/" target="_blank">banning and removing Confederate flag merchandise from their inventories</a> in the wake of the tragic shooting at Emmanuel AME Church in Charleston, South Carolina. The man the police have identified as the shooter, Dylann Roof, had posed in several photographs with a Confederate flag. As calls have spread for the flag to be removed from state flags and capitals, retailers have been quick to distance themselves from it publicly.</p>
<p>Actually getting flag merchandise off the shelf may take time, however. As of the time when we recorded this episode, however, some confederate flag merchandise was still available.</p>
<h3><b>Microsoft Office coming to Android</b></h3>
<p>Microsoft released <a href="http://time.com/3934630/microsoft-office-android-apps/" target="_blank">full versions of its Office productivity apps (Word, Excel and PowerPoint) for the Android operation system</a> this week.</p>
<p>This comes after about month of beta versions of these apps being available for Android users. Microsoft said in a statement that the incorporated a lot of feedback from users of these early versions into the final ones.</p>
<p>These apps won&rsquo;t work on all Android devices, especially older ones, but they will work on a majority of smartphones and tablets. The Microsoft Office mobile apps are currently free in the Google Play store.</p>
<h3><b>Amazon now paying Kindle Unlimited authors by the page</b></h3>
<p>Amazon has announced that starting on July 1, they will begin paying authors in the Kindle Unlimited and Kindle Lending Library programs <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2015/06/amazon-publishing-authors-payment-writing/396269/" target="_blank">by the number of pages read, rather than simply when their book is downloaded</a>. To keep the system from being gamed by large fonts, Amazon has introduced the Kindle Edition Normalized Page Count, or KENPC, which is a formula that will attempt to standardize page counts for all books.<br>
&mdash;</p>
<p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable&nbsp;dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there.</p>
<p><em>Photo Credit: &ldquo;<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/94347223@N07/8588000453/" target="_blank">Taylor Swift RED tour 2013</a>&rdquo;&nbsp;by <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/jazills/" target="_blank">Jana Beamer</a>&nbsp;is used under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/" target="_blank">CC BY 2.0.</a></em></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#89 Tom Loves T. Swift" data-link="/2015/06/89-tom-loves-t-swift/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#89 Tom Loves T. Swift" data-link="/2015/06/89-tom-loves-t-swift/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/06/89-tom-loves-t-swift/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-26.mp3" length="31797950" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#83 It&#8217;s Time to Play the Feud!</title>
		<link>/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/</link>
		<comments>/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 17:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSDs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verizon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10014</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/google_feud2-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="google_feud2" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week Ray warns us about storing our SSDs in hot places, unless you want to wipe your drives clean. Tom explores the dangers of asking questions on Quora.&#160;And Sean finds out why one company is trying to make the <a href="/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/google_feud2-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="google_feud2" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week Ray warns us about storing our SSDs in hot places, unless you want to wipe your drives clean. Tom explores the dangers of asking questions on Quora.&nbsp;And Sean finds out why one company is trying to make the food replicators from Star Trek a reality. Plus the guys look at Facebook&rsquo;s new &ldquo;instant articles,&rdquo; learn why Microsoft is saying Windows 10 will be the last version of Windows they&rsquo;ll release, and delve into Verizon&rsquo;s purchase of AOL. Then later, Sean acts like Steve Harvey as Tom and Ray play a few rounds of the online game Google Feud.</p>
<p>But first, could we&nbsp;ask a favor of you? If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on our website, would you subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>? And, while you&rsquo;re there, would you leave a review and say a few nice things about us? The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10014-5" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-15.mp3?_=5"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-15.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-15.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3><b>SSDs can lose data really fast</b></h3>
<p>You know those amazingly fast SSDs that are replacing hard drives in high end laptops like practically every Mac on the market? Well, there is a trade off. You definitely don&rsquo;t want to store your wedding pictures on them. Or your tax records. Or your receipts from Best Buy. Because, some SSDs can lose their data in <b>only a few days</b>.</p>
<p>According to Gizmodo, heat is the enemy. <a href="http://gizmodo.com/some-ssds-can-lose-data-after-just-a-few-days-in-storag-1703490139">The length of data retention is cut in half for every nine degrees of temperature increase</a>. So, if you do like a lot of people Ray has talked to have done, and stick your old computer in a hot storage unit, expect to reinstall Windows on it when you get it out, because the SSD might be blank.</p>
<p>Just another reminder to back up your data!</p>
<h3><b>Man weighing two job offers finds one of them retracted after asking Quora which of them he should take</b></h3>
<p>In the news this week, yet another cautionary tale about being very careful with what you post online.</p>
<p>Last week a San Francisco engineer who was weighing competing job offers from Uber and Zenefits posted on Quora, asking the advice of its users on which to take. The engineer said that he liked what Zenefits was offering but that it didn&rsquo;t seem as compelling a ?buzzword? to have on his resume as Uber.</p>
<p>The dilemma was presumably cleared up for the engineer <a href="http://qz.com/400027/engineer-asks-quora-which-job-offer-to-take-ceo-replies-not-ours/" target="_blank">when Zenefits&rsquo; CEO responded, saying &ldquo;Definitely not Zenefits,&rdquo; and retracting the job offer</a>.</p>
<p>While the post was later changed to remove the public job retraction, presumably the damage was done. It was not clear if the candidate, who remains anonymous, had accepted Uber&rsquo;s offer.</p>
<h3><b>Microsoft representative claims that Windows 10 is the &ldquo;last&rdquo; version of Windows</b></h3>
<p>This week at Microsoft&rsquo;s Ignite conference, tech evangelist Jerry Nixon was quoted as saying, &ldquo;Right now we&rsquo;re releasing Windows 10, and because Windows 10 is the last version of Windows, we&rsquo;re all still working on Windows 10.&rdquo; <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/5/7/8568473/windows-10-last-version-of-windows" target="_blank">Microsoft confirmed this statement to The Verge</a>, saying that it would be focusing on &ldquo;Windows as a service,&rdquo; delivering continuous updates to the system rather than rolling out new versions of Windows.</p>
<p>That is of course until the next time Marketing gets a bright idea in its head and they announce Windows 20.</p>
<h3><b>Facebook rolls out &ldquo;instant articles&rdquo; from major news publishers</b></h3>
<p>Starting this week on the iOS Facebook app, some news articles will load much, much faster when you click on them. <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/5/13/8595263/facebooks-instant-articles-arrive-to-speed-up-the-news-feed" target="_blank">Facebook is calling these ?instant articles?</a>, and they will be available from a handful of publishers that have partnered with Facebook, including the New York Times, BuzzFeed, The Atlantic, BBC News and National Geographic, among others. Instant articles won?t look much different to users, at least at first &ndash; they will just load instantly when clicked. In the future, however, Facebook may add auto-playing &ldquo;video covers&rdquo; as well.</p>
<p>Facebook will allow new, special interactions with Instant Articles, including audio captions, geotagged photos, and interactive maps. And of course, there will be no ads.</p>
<p>No word yet on when Android users will see this feature.</p>
<h3><b>Israeli company creates Genie, a futuristic appliance that can create instant meals on demand</b></h3>
<p>A new Israeli device called the Genie, which claims its inspiration from Star Trek&rsquo;s fictional replicators, <a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/closest-thing-to-star-trek-replicator-makes-meals-in-30-seconds/" target="_blank">can turn pods of dehydrated powders into meals on demand</a>. While details are light, supposedly the meals can be customized to personal preference, including specifying whether they should be gluten-, dairy-, or egg-free. The Genie will also work with smartphones and mobile devices.</p>
<p>No word if it responds to voice commands like, &ldquo;Tea, earl gray, hot.&rdquo;</p>
<h3><b>Verizon announces plan to buy AOL for 4.4 billion dollars</b></h3>
<p>In a surprise announcement this week, <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/13/business/dealbook/verizon-to-buy-aol-for-4-4-billion.html?hp&amp;action=click&amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;module=first-column-region&amp;region=top-news&amp;WT.nav=top-news" target="_blank">Verizon and AOL announced that Verizon will buy AOL for $4.4 billion dollars</a>. People with knowledge of the matter say that Verizon is looking to acquire AOL&rsquo;s mobile, video and advertising technology. Verizon may be looking to offer its own streaming video platform which it can sell ads against. It will also acquire popular news site The Huffington Post, not to mention the legacy dial-up service which once made AOL a powerhouse.</p>
<p>Verizon is currently valued at $200 billion dollars, making the four and a half billion in cash they plan to spend on AOL little more than a rounding error.</p>
<h1>It&rsquo;s time to play the feud!</h1>
<div id="attachment_10015" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2015/05/google_feud.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-10015 size-full" src="/media/2015/05/google_feud.jpg"  alt="Credit: Google Feud" width="500" height="104"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Credit: Google Feud</p></div>
<p>You may have seen the site <a href="http://www.googlefeud.com/" target="_blank">Google Feud</a> making the rounds on social media recently. This online game combines weird Google autocomplete search suggestions with Family Feud style game play, in which you have to guess the top 10 ways Google autocompletes a specific sentence or question (for example, &ldquo;Is it weird to _____&rdquo;). Sean plays the role of Steve Harvey &ndash; or John O&rsquo;Hurley, Louie Anderson, Richard Dawson, or whoever you favorite Family Feud host was &ndash; while Ray and Tom guess their way through a few rounds.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#83 It's Time to Play the Feud!" data-link="/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#83 It's Time to Play the Feud!" data-link="/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-15.mp3" length="42870134" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#76 Oh, Sweet Internet Explorer, Go Gently Into That Good Night &#8211; OR &#8211; Parting With Bing Is Such Sweet Sorrow</title>
		<link>/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/</link>
		<comments>/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 00:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 8.1]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9817</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/03/InternetExplorerVoodooDoll-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Photo Credit: Internet Explorer, a web developers menace by Jorgen Kesseler is used under CC BY-SA 2.0." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week the guys are elated about the death of Internet Explorer, the low, low price of free to upgrade to&#160;Windows 10, (even if you never paid for Windows 7 or 8) and&#160;Mario, Zelda and the gang are finally coming <a href="/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/03/InternetExplorerVoodooDoll-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Photo Credit: Internet Explorer, a web developers menace by Jorgen Kesseler is used under CC BY-SA 2.0." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-9819 size-large" src="/media/2015/03/InternetExplorerVoodooDoll-1024x768.jpg" alt="Photo Credit: Internet Explorer, a web developers menace by Jorgen Kesseler is used under CC BY-SA 2.0." width="659" height="494"></p>
<p>This week the guys are elated about the death of Internet Explorer, the low, low price of free to upgrade to&nbsp;Windows 10, (even if you never paid for Windows 7 or 8) and&nbsp;Mario, Zelda and the gang are finally coming to mobile phones, but not the way you want them to.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>If you haven&rsquo;t <a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/ca/podcast/deemable-tech-wjct/id540595466?mt=2" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">subscribed to Deemable Tech</a> yet, get on it! Subscribe to <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">Deemable Tech&nbsp;in iTunes</a>,&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a> or&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech Podcast!" href="http://dmbl.co/pod">subscribe to the show in another podcast reader</a>. Make sure to leave us a review in iTunes and Stitcher. The more reviews we have the higher we&rsquo;ll be listed, and the more listeners will see our show.</p>
<p>And make sure to&nbsp;share us on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-9817-6" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/DeemableTech_2015-03-20.mp3?_=6"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/DeemableTech_2015-03-20.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/DeemableTech_2015-03-20.mp3</a></audio><h2>This Week&rsquo;s Run Down</h2>
<h3>Windows 10 is free for everybody!</h3>
<p>So, you may have heard of the latest version of Windows that Microsoft is working on releasing later this summer. If you haven&rsquo;t, it&rsquo;s called Windows 10. If you&rsquo;re wondering why it&rsquo;s called Windows 10 instead of&hellip; you know&hellip; Windows 9, it&rsquo;s because of a little coding shortcut where programmers referred to Windows 95 and Windows 98 as &ndash; you guessed it&nbsp;&ndash;&nbsp;&ldquo;Windows 9.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Well, it turns out that <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/3/18/8241023/windows-10-free-for-software-pirates">Windows 10 is going to be FREE for everyone</a>, well almost everyone.</p>
<p>Terry Myerson, Microsoft&rsquo;s Windows chief to Reuters &ldquo;We are upgrading all qualified PCs, genuine and non-genuine, to Windows 10&rdquo;</p>
<p>So that means, as long as you have a computer running Windows 7 or Window 8 or 8.1 you can install 10 on your computer, at no charge, even if you stole the version that&rsquo;s on your computer right now.</p>
<h3>The Death of Internet Explorer</h3>
<p>Microsoft confirmed this week that Internet Explorer will not be the primary web browser in Windows 10. Yes, the venerable <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/3/17/8230631/microsoft-is-killing-off-the-internet-explorer-brand">Internet Explorer, which has been a part of Windows since Windows 95, is being put out to pasture</a>. It will still ship with the next version of Microsoft&rsquo;s operating system for backwards compatibility reasons, but a new browser with the codename Project Spartan will be Microsoft&rsquo;s flagship browser. Project Spartan&rsquo;s real name has not been released yet but Microsoft says that it will not use the Internet Explorer branding.</p>
<h3>Nintendo to develop mobile games</h3>
<p>After years of speculation, <a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/03/nintendo-dena-mobile/">Nintendo is moving into the mobile game market</a>. They announced this week that they have partnered with Japanese mobile game giant DeNA to &ldquo;develop and operate new game apps based on Nintendo&rsquo;s intellectual property, including its iconic game characters, for smart devices.&rdquo;</p>
<p>They were quick to point out that their primary focus will still be their game consoles like the Wii U and 3DS, and that these new mobile apps are intended to complement, not replace, those systems. In the same announcement, Nintendo president Satoru Iwata said that a new console codenamed NX is development.</p>
<p>Unfortunately for those of us hoping this means we&rsquo;ll be able to play classic Mario or Zelda games on our devices, Iwata also said that Nintendo&rsquo;s plans do not include direct ports of console games. He cited differences between dedicated controllers and touchscreens as the reason.</p>
<p>&mdash;-</p>
<p>If you have a comment, contact us at feedback at deemable.com or leave us a voicemail at 1-888-972-9868.</p>
<p>Help us decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story. Or vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Tech on Reddit" href="http://reddit.com/r/Deemable" target="_blank">reddit.com/r/Deemable</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Photo Credit: <a href="https://flic.kr/p/9dAWZW">Internet Explorer, a web developers menace</a> by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/verpletterend/">Jorgen Kesseler</a> is used under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/">CC BY-SA 2.0</a>.</em></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#76 Oh, Sweet Internet Explorer, Go Gently Into That Good Night - OR - Parting With Bing Is Such Sweet Sorrow" data-link="/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#76 Oh, Sweet Internet Explorer, Go Gently Into That Good Night - OR - Parting With Bing Is Such Sweet Sorrow" data-link="/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/DeemableTech_2015-03-20.mp3" length="20553128" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
