<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Palm</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/palm/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Episode 11 &#8211; Call Me (Internationally), Maybe?</title>
		<link>/2012/08/deemable-tech-episode-11-call-me-internationally-maybe/</link>
		<comments>/2012/08/deemable-tech-episode-11-call-me-internationally-maybe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 19:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DRM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eBooks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OnLive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Square]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=5361</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/06/DeemableTechLogoSquare-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Deemable Tech Logo" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Deemable Tech &#8211; Episode 11 &#8211; Call Me (Internationally), Maybe The Deemable Dozen: Apple&#8217;s attorney&#8217;s are on crack?&#160; As the legal smack-down in California heads into its final stretch, District Court Judge Lucy Koh&#8217;s patience appears to be wearing thin. <a href="/2012/08/deemable-tech-episode-11-call-me-internationally-maybe/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2012/08/deemable-tech-episode-11-call-me-internationally-maybe/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/06/DeemableTechLogoSquare-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Deemable Tech Logo" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="alignright  wp-image-5185" title="Deemable Tech Logo" src="//media/2012/06/DeemableTechLogoSquare-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="200"></p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-5361-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-08-20.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-08-20.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-08-20.mp3</a></audio><p><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-08-20.mp3">Deemable Tech &ndash; Episode 11 &ndash; Call Me (Internationally), Maybe</a></p>
<h3>The Deemable Dozen:</h3>
<ol><li><strong>Apple&rsquo;s attorney&rsquo;s are on crack?&nbsp;</strong><br>
As the legal smack-down in California heads into its final stretch, District Court Judge Lucy Koh&rsquo;s patience appears to be wearing thin. With Samsung having rested their case and Apple left with only a few hours to wind up theirs, they submitted a massive 75-page document detailing 22 separate witnesses that they supposedly intended to call. Judge Koh reportedly told Apple&rsquo;s attorney, ?Unless you&rsquo;re smoking crack, you know these witnesses aren&rsquo;t going to be called when you have less than four hours.? Apple&rsquo;s lawyer protested that he was not smoking crack, but agreed to pare down the list. The trial is expected to wind up this week, which will give everyone a brief reprieve before the inevitable appeal process begins.</li>
<li><strong>Motorola-Google fires first shot at Apple, seeks ban of all major devices in US.</strong><br>
In other tech lawsuit news, Google&rsquo;s Motorola Mobility division, which Google purchased for its extensive patent portfolio, is seeking an injunction from the US International Trade Commission against just about everything Apple makes. Motorola claims that Apple has violated patents it owns regarding email notifications, location reminders, and phones that can also play video. Siri, Apple&rsquo;s popular voice-recognition software, is also implicated in the lawsuit.</li>
<li><strong>Apple&nbsp;rumored&nbsp;to be in talks with cable companies.<br></strong>The Wall Street Journal reports that Apple is apparently in talks with cable companies to add cable service to their set-top box. Although AppleTV has been something of a hobbiest&rsquo;s toy up until now, being able to get cable through it would definitely be a game-changer. On the other hand, after seeing what Apple did to the music and publishing industries, the cable companies probably&nbsp;aren&rsquo;t&nbsp;going to roll over easily on this one.</li>
<li><strong>HP turns Palm into Gram.</strong><br>
Fans of the old Palm WebOS rejoiced last week with word that HP was forming a subsidiary called Gram to manage the now fully open-source mobile platform, which they own. But don&rsquo;t get too excited guys, because HP has also created another mobility unit which will apparently work on Windows tablets. At this point HP&rsquo;s strategy appears to be: ?Yes, let&rsquo;s do something with mobile&hellip; stuff.? They are also&nbsp;rumored&nbsp;to have ?the cloud&hellip;&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Square&rsquo;s flat rate.</strong><br>
In a bid to court small businesses, mobile payment provider Square has announced that it will begin offering flat rates for companies that are processing less than $250k in transactions through the service. Square normally takes a 2.75% cut of each transaction, but are now offering smaller users the option to pay $275 a month. That sounds like a lot to me, but people don&rsquo;t offer me their credit card numbers a lot, so what do I know?</li>
<li><strong>Facebook&rsquo;s stock fall.</strong><br>
Facebook&rsquo;s stock took a huge hit Friday, tumbling to $19/share, half of what it was at the company&rsquo;s Initial Public Offering in May. The plunge comes a day after the expiration of a lock-down period where early investors and insiders were required to hold onto their shares. Apparently once they were free to dump them, they did. Since Facebook went public it has taken a real beating in the stock market. I wonder if Mark Zuckerberg has updated his Linked In profile recently?</li>
<li><strong>Washington state to enable Facebook voter registration.</strong><br>
Washington state is poised to allow citizens to register to vote through Facebook. Washington was the second state in the US to allow online voter registration. I suppose this is the next logical step. At least half my Facebook friends already seem to think that ?Liking? Obama or Romney is equivalent to voting for them.</li>
<li><strong>iPhone SMS spoofing.</strong><br>
?White hat hackers? (those are the good kind) have discovered an iPhone bug that allows someone to send text messages masquerading as any phone number. ?Black hat hackers? (those are the bad kind) might be able to use this technique to impersonate friends and extract personal information from iPhone users. So play it safe: when your friend starts texting you and asking for your credit card number and SSN, don&rsquo;t give it to him.</li>
<li><strong>Adobe announces Flash for Android is dead!<br></strong>Flash is dead. Long live Flash. Adobe pulled the Flash Player from the Google Play store this week, meaning it is no longer available for download for Android devices. For nearly a decade Flash was the technology of choice for doing things like animation or streaming video on the web. Things took a turn for the worse for Adobe&rsquo;s platform after Apple spurned it by refusing to allow it on iOS. Last Christmas Adobe apparently saw the writing on the wall and announced that it would begin focusing on other technologies. If you already have Flash on your Android phone or tablet, it&rsquo;s not going away, but many websites and apps are already steering away from using Flash towards sleeker, more reliable mobile-friendly technologies such as HTML5.</li>
<li><strong>eBay to officially ban ?intangible? items, such as including ?spells, curses, hexes, conjuring, magic, prayers, blessing services, magic potions, healing sessions?.</strong><br>
Bad news for enterprising Hogwarts students: Ebay has updated its selling policies to ban sales of &ldquo;advice, spells, curses, hexing, conjuring, magic, prayers, blessing services, magic potions, [and] healing sessions,&rdquo; beginning in September. In related news, Magical Ebay has reportedly banned sales of ?useless muggle items such as cars, power-tools and digital wristwatches.? This just in: this may be the nerdiest news item we have ever reported.</li>
<li><strong>Publishers fight over whether or not to sell DRM-free (Digital Rights Management) eBooks.<br></strong>E-books outsold traditional&nbsp;hard-cover&nbsp;books for the first time in the first quarter of this year. They are now officially Big Business. Tor, the world&rsquo;s largest science fiction publishing imprint announced in April that it would release all of it&rsquo;s books without any Digital Rights Management. That announcement didn&rsquo;t sit well with British publisher Hatchette UK, who this week sent out a letter to its authors gently suggesting that they are not okay with having books they sell with DRM sold DRM-free in another territory. Science fiction author, Boing-Boing editor and opponent of all things DRM Cory Doctorow lashed out at Hatchette, saying ?Hachette has balls the size of Mars if it thinks it can dictate what other publishers do with titles in territories where it has no rights.?</li>
<li><strong>Cloud gaming service ?OnLive? has been sold.</strong><br>
Cloud-based gaming service ?OnLive? announced Friday morning that it had laid off all 200 or so of its employees and sold all of its assets to a new owner. OnLive later issued a press release claiming that it would continue to offer all its services, that nearly half of its employees would be hired back, and that everything was ?business as usual&rsquo;. Dissolving your entire company only to re-form it hours later&nbsp;doesn&rsquo;t&nbsp;sound like ?business as usual&rsquo; to us.</li>
</ol><div><strong>Today&rsquo;s Questions:</strong></div>
<div>
<ol><li>Are there any alternatives to Vonage?</li>
<li>Why won&rsquo;t my Apple TV do Airplay with my 2010 iMac?</li>
<li>How do I change the font size in the Inbox Column?</li>
<li>What software should I use to convert my videos?</li>
</ol></div>
<h3>Links we mentioned on today&rsquo;s show:</h3>
<ul><li><a href="http://speedtest.net/">http://speedtest.net/</a></li>
</ul><h3>Bumper Music</h3>
<ul><li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VSBefGi7F-Y">Violin Super Mario!!!!!</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gg290v572Zw">Skrillex &ndash; Scary Monsters And Nice Sprites &ndash; Ferro Version (piano tutorial with sheet music)</a></li>
</ul><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Episode 11 - Call Me (Internationally), Maybe?" data-link="/2012/08/deemable-tech-episode-11-call-me-internationally-maybe/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Episode 11 - Call Me (Internationally), Maybe?" data-link="/2012/08/deemable-tech-episode-11-call-me-internationally-maybe/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2012/08/deemable-tech-episode-11-call-me-internationally-maybe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-08-20.mp3" length="51407991" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>HP webOS, I’m Sorry. I Can’t. Don’t Hate Me.</title>
		<link>/2011/06/im-sorry-hp-webos-but-im-leaving-you/</link>
		<comments>/2011/06/im-sorry-hp-webos-but-im-leaving-you/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 15:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Break Up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goodbye webOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP WebOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm Pixi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm Pre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PreCentral]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TouchPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=3485</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/06/webos-break-up-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="webos-break-up.jpg" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Dear HP webOS, When I first met you, you took my breath away. I fell in love with you at first sight. The way you multitasked was so elegant and simple, and back then, no other mobile OS could even <a href="/2011/06/im-sorry-hp-webos-but-im-leaving-you/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/06/im-sorry-hp-webos-but-im-leaving-you/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/06/webos-break-up-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="webos-break-up.jpg" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/webos-break-up.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright" title='The "webOS" Break Up' src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/webos-break-up-300x300.jpg"  alt='The "webOS" Break Up' width="300" height="300"></a>Dear HP webOS,</p>
<p>When I <a title="Palm announces webOS platform -- Engadget" href="http://www.engadget.com/2009/01/08/palm-announces-web-os-platform/" target="_blank">first met you</a>, you took my breath away. I fell in love with you at first sight. The way you <a title="Palm Pre Review | Multitasking | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/palm-pre-review#Card-View-Multitasking" target="_blank">multitasked was so elegant and simple</a>, and back then, no other mobile OS could even multitask at all. Your <a title="Palm Pre Review | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/palm-pre-review#Notifications" target="_blank">notifications were so polite and beautiful</a>; you never interrupted me or nagged me. Your <a title="Palm USA | HP Touchstone Technology" href="http://www.hpwebos.com/us/products/accessories/touchstone-technology.html" target="_blank">Touchstone wireless charger</a> was so much fun, and the fact that you had a hardware keyboard and a touch screen was just so sexy. Our relationship was so easy. I never had to share you with a computer; you just downloaded all of your updates over the air. You kept track of everything on Google and Facebook and pulled it all together with <a title="Palm Pre Review | Synergy | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/palm-pre-review#Synergy" target="_blank">Synergy</a>, and you never made me synchronize you. You took care of everything in the background, and I could just enjoy quality spending time with you.</p>
<p>When we got together, I was just getting out of the relationship with your older sister, Palm OS, and you were there to help me through the pain of the break up. I had flirted with iOS (she just called herself iPhone OS back then) before you and I got together, but I missed being around your folks so much that being with you just felt natural. Even though a lot of my friends gave me a hard time because you didn&rsquo;t do as much as iOS and Android did, you were learning so much, so fast.&nbsp; It seemed like we were only together a few months, and you already had <a title="The Official HP Palm Blog: What's new in Palm webOS 1.4?" href="http://blog.palm.com/palm/2010/02/whats-new-in-palm-webos-14.html" target="_blank">video recording </a>and you had&nbsp;<a title="Palm Introduces 3D Games for webOS." href="http://investor.palm.com/releasedetail.cfm?releaseid=436243" target="_blank">3D games</a>.</p>
<p>However, I think I may have rushed into this relationship too fast, and forgot to get to know you first. We should have taken our time. For example, I thought that you would <a title="WebOS to Support Palm OS Emulation | PreCentral.net |  The #1 Palm Pre and Pixi Community" href="http://www.precentral.net/webos-support-palm-os-emulation" target="_blank">support Palm OS and me still being friends</a>, but it wasn&rsquo;t too long before you <a title="With webOS 2.0, MotionApps drops Classic PalmOS Emulator in Palm's lap | PreCentral.net |  The #1 Palm Pre and Pixi Community" href="http://www.precentral.net/webos-2-0-motionapps-drops-classic-palmos-emulator-palm-s-lap" target="_blank">insisted that we never speak again</a>. I thought that you told me that you would <a title="Native Office Document Editing on the Pre | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/native-office-document-editing-pre" target="_blank">support full document editing at launch</a>, but here we are over two years later, and you still can&rsquo;t even edit a spreadsheet.</p>
<p>For several months now, I&rsquo;ve felt us growing farther and farther apart. I don&rsquo;t blame you for what happened. I think it was one of those things where we drifted apart for all sorts of reasons, including <a title="Palm Cuts Its Forecast, and Its Shares Fall - NYTimes.com" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/02/26/technology/26palm.html" target="_blank">your near bankruptcy</a>, the <a title="HP to Acquire Palm for $1.2 Billion" href="http://www.hp.com/hpinfo/newsroom/press/2010/100428xa.html" target="_blank">merger with HP</a>, and the pressure of supporting you through your <a title="Palm's Major Credibility Problem - CNBC" href="http://www.cnbc.com/id/35607982/site/14081545" target="_blank">various crises</a>.</p>
<p>Maybe I&rsquo;m a fool for leaving you, especially now, but I just need some time to find myself. I know that you are on the <a title="HP webOS 3.0: what we know, what we don't" href="http://www.precentral.net/hp-webos-3-0-what-we-know-what-we-don-t" target="_blank">verge of some major breakthroughs</a>. You keep telling me that you are going to change &ldquo;<a title="Round Table: In the coming months | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/round-table-coming-months" target="_blank">in the coming months</a>&rdquo; and now &ldquo;<a title="HP Responds: Veer's &quot;Big Push&quot; is coming &quot;In the Weeks Ahead&quot;  | webOSroundup" href="http://www.webosroundup.com/2011/05/hp-responds-veers-big-push-is-coming-in-the-weeks-ahead/" target="_blank">in the coming weeks</a>.&rdquo;&nbsp;Honestly though, I am afraid&nbsp;that you aren&rsquo;t&nbsp;really going to change, because the way you have talked about <a title='Big Talk from HP Europe: TouchPad will be "Better than #1" with thousands of big name apps | PreCentral.net | The #1 Palm Pre and Pixi Community' href="http://www.precentral.net/hp-europe-talks-big-touchpad-will-be-better-1-thousands-big-name-apps" target="_blank">how you are going to</a> change <a title="HP thinks the TouchPad will be 'better than number one,' if that's even possible -- Engadget" href="http://www.engadget.com/2011/05/23/hp-thinks-the-touchpad-will-be-better-than-number-one-if-that/" target="_blank">doesn&rsquo;t instill confidence</a>. It just sounds like <a title="Apotheker: HP to ship products within weeks of announcement, wants to sit at the cool kids table | PreCentral.net | The #1 Palm Pre and Pixi Community" href="http://www.precentral.net/apotheker-hp-ship-products-within-weeks-announcement-wants-sit-cool-kids-table" target="_blank">the puffed up bravado you&rsquo;ve given me in the past</a>. Ultimately, you <a title='webOS 2.0 will be released to "all devices" in coming months (Update: Video online) | PreCentral.net | The #1 Palm Pre and Pixi Community' href="http://www.precentral.net/webos-2-0-will-be-released-all-devices-coming-months-update-video-online" target="_blank">made me promises</a> that <a title="No major webOS OTA Updates to Pre, Pre Plus, Pixi, Pixi Plus - Updated: none at all | PreCentral.net | The #1 Palm Pre and Pixi Community" href="http://www.precentral.net/no-major-webos-ota-updates-pre-pre-plus-pixi-pixi-plus" target="_blank">you didn&rsquo;t keep</a>, and I think that&rsquo;s what hurt me the most. Some people have acted like that it <a title='TOO SOON? YouTube Video Pokes Fun at webOS "Whiners" (UPDATE! We Find TWO Opposing Videos) | webOSroundup' href="http://www.webosroundup.com/2011/02/too-soon-youtube-video-pokes-fun-at-webos-whiners/" target="_blank">shouldn&rsquo;t bother me</a>, and told me that, ultimately, it was <a title="Making the Case: Why HP isn't allowing OTA updates (and why we think it's a good thing) | webOSroundup" href="http://www.webosroundup.com/2011/02/making-the-case-why-hp-isnt-allowing-ota-updates-and-why-we-think-it-is-a-good-thing/" target="_blank">the right decision for you to make</a>, but it still makes it hard to trust you.</p>
<p>I think we both know this hasn&rsquo;t been working out. It&rsquo;s been over a while now, and last weekend I &lsquo;moved-on&rsquo;. I need to tell you that someone from my past, iOS,&nbsp;has come back into my life. I knew her years ago but there were so many things that <a title="The iPhone is the worst... BGR" href="http://www.bgr.com/2010/10/22/the-iphone-is-the-worst/" target="_blank">interfered with her and I having a relationship</a> that could not be overcome, but <a title="Apple announces iOS 5: 1500 new APT for developers, 200 new features for users | TiPb" href="http://www.tipb.com/2011/06/06/apple-announces-ios-5-1500-api-developers-200-features-users/" target="_blank">that has passed</a> and although <a title="iOS 5: What we didn't get | TiPb" href="http://www.tipb.com/2011/06/07/ios-5/" target="_blank">she is still not perfect</a>, she and I are making another attempt. We were at the Apple store, and well, one thing lead to another and she ended up coming home with me.</p>
<p>I think that we&rsquo;ll be better off apart than we were together. You don&rsquo;t need me.&nbsp;I know you have a lot of <a title="HP webOS Marketing Blitz to feature Lady Gaga, Russel Brand, Jay-Z, Kanye West? | PreCentral.net | The #1 Palm Pre and Pixi Community" href="http://www.precentral.net/hp-webos-marketing-blitz-feature-lady-gaga-russel-brand-jay-z-kanye-west" target="_blank">friend who are supporting you now</a>, and I know <a title="Editorial: The un-penetrated market of non-smartphone users | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/editorial-un-penetrated-market-non-smartphone-users" target="_blank">you&rsquo;ll find someone else</a>. I loved you more than I probably will ever <a title="webOS Users: The most passionately in love with their platform | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/webos-users-most-passionately-love-their-platform" target="_blank">love another mobile OS</a>. If things don&rsquo;t work out with iOS, maybe we&rsquo;ll be together again someday, if it&rsquo;s our fate. Either way, I hope we can still be friends. My contract doesn&rsquo;t run out for another few months, so I&rsquo;d still like to hang out with you from time to time. Also, I still have a lot of stuff I need to get from your place, and move over to iOS&rsquo;s.</p>
<p>Again, I really am sorry. I wish we could have made this work.</p>
<p>Goodbye webOS.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&ndash; Ray</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">P.S. I&rsquo;m sorry I had to do this in writing instead of in person, but at least I didn&rsquo;t just leave you a Post-it note, right?</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://deemable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/bergerspostitnote.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-3525" title="Berger's Post-it Note for Carrie. &quot;I'm Sorry. I Can't. Don't Hate Me.&quot;" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/bergerspostitnote.jpg"  alt="Berger's Post-it Note for Carrie. &quot;I'm Sorry. I Can't. Don't Hate Me.&quot;" width="256" height="227"></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="http://deemable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/webos-break-up.jpg" href="http://deemable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/webos-break-up.jpg"></a></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="HP webOS, I?m Sorry. I Can?t. Don?t Hate Me." data-link="/2011/06/im-sorry-hp-webos-but-im-leaving-you/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="HP webOS, I?m Sorry. I Can?t. Don?t Hate Me." data-link="/2011/06/im-sorry-hp-webos-but-im-leaving-you/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/06/im-sorry-hp-webos-but-im-leaving-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>HP&#8217;s cards are finally on the table, but not all of them are good.</title>
		<link>/2011/02/hps-cards-are-finally-on-the-table-but-not-all-of-them-are-good/</link>
		<comments>/2011/02/hps-cards-are-finally-on-the-table-but-not-all-of-them-are-good/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 13:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP Pre3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP Slate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP TouchPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP Veer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP WebOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm Pre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm Pre 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pre3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Think Beyond]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TouchPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WebOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WebOS 2.0]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=215</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/02/HPsCardsAreOnTheTable-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="HPsCardsAreOnTheTable" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Yesterday HP had its big announcement that had the tech world waiting on pins and needles. A lot of famous people were in the audience, including the requisite journalists and even a few minor celebrities (MC Hammer and&#160;Serena Williams). The <a href="/2011/02/hps-cards-are-finally-on-the-table-but-not-all-of-them-are-good/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/02/hps-cards-are-finally-on-the-table-but-not-all-of-them-are-good/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/02/HPsCardsAreOnTheTable-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="HPsCardsAreOnTheTable" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-240" title="HPs Cards Are On The Table" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/HPsCardsAreOnTheTable.jpg" alt="HPs Cards Are On The Table" width="480" height="200"></p>
<p>Yesterday HP had its big announcement that had the tech world waiting on pins and needles. A lot of famous people were in the audience, including the requisite journalists and even a few minor celebrities (MC Hammer and&nbsp;Serena Williams<em>).</em> The one thing that <a title="RIP, Palm: 1992 - 2011 -- Engadget" href="http://www.engadget.com/2011/02/09/rip-palm-1992-2011/" target="_blank">everyone</a> seemed to&nbsp;<a title="Fare thee well, Palm -- we'll miss you | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/fare-thee-well-palm-we-ll-miss-you" target="_blank">noticed</a> was suspiciously missing was the Palm logo, which is <a title="Palm's site updated with newly announced devices (but lacking Palm logo) | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/palm-s-site-updated-newly-announced-devices-but-lacking-palm-logo" target="_blank">now missing</a> from <a title="Palm USA | Mobile Products for Consumers, Professionals, and Businesses" href="http://www.palm.com/us/" target="_blank">Palm&rsquo;s website</a>. [<strong>UPDATE</strong>:&nbsp;OK, now it&rsquo;s back? Make up your mind people!]&nbsp;This was just a foreshadow of the real stab to the hearts of Palm fans that would come later in the day.<span id="more-215"></span></p>
<p>The&nbsp;announcement&nbsp;yesterday wasn&rsquo;t quite a royal flush; it was more like 3 of a kind and a couple of jokers. I know that would normally be an incredible hand, but suffice it to say that these jokers were not good ones. Let me start with the three of a kind: HP announced three new devices yesterday.</p>
<p><a href="http://deemable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/veer-open-left.png"></a><a href="http://deemable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/veer-open-left.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-237" title="HP Veer" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/veer-open-left.jpg"  alt="HP Veer" width="75" height="150"></a>The first device announced, the <a title="HP Veer Phone | Features, Details" href="http://www.palm.com/us/products/phones/veer/index.html" target="_blank">HP Veer</a>, is an incredibly small, and pretty much adorable, device that is apparently replacing the Palm Pixi line. The Veer has a 2.6 inches&nbsp;screen, which is almost exactly the same size as the Pixi. However, the Veer is a portrait slider instead of a candybar. Another differentiating factor is that in addition to being&nbsp;compatible&nbsp;with the iconic Touchstone charger it has a magnetic USB connector that it charges through and transmits data through. The Veer camera is significantly upgraded over the Pixi with a 5-megapixel camera with extended depth of field. Most of the reviewers that got their hands on it were surprised at how&nbsp;comfortable&nbsp;it was to use, despite its diminutive size. The question remains though, &ldquo;<a title="The HP Veer Gamble | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/hp-veer-gamble" target="_blank">Is there a market for a small smartphone like the Veer?</a>&rdquo; Other companies have tried and failed. Does the Veer have something that will set it apart, or will it crash and burn like the others?</p>
<p><a href="http://deemable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/pre3-front-left-opened.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-full wp-image-232 alignleft" title="HP Pre3" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/pre3-front-left-opened.jpg"  alt="HP Pre3" width="75" height="150"></a>Their second device they announced yesterday is the one that most Palm fanboys and girls were waiting on: the next iteration of what was Palm&rsquo;s flagship phone, the&nbsp;<a title="HP Pre 3 Phone | Features, Details" href="http://www.palm.com/us/products/phones/pre3/index.html" target="_blank">HP Pre<sup>3</sup></a>. In addition to having an annoying superscripted number three at the end of its name, the Pre<sup>3</sup> also comes with a larger, 3.58 inch, 800 x 480 pixel screen and a 1.4 GHz Qualcomm Snapdragon processor. It also has a front-facing VGA camera and a rear-facing 5-megapixel auto-focus camera with LED flash, and HD 720p video recording. Some other minor upgrades include a digital compass, dual-mic noise cancellation, and a slightly larger battery. Many fans were hoping for something larger, but one of the presenters said that HP wanted to differentiate themselves from the &ldquo;bigger is better&rdquo; crowd.</p>
<p><a href="http://deemable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/tp-left-front.jpg"></a><a href="http://deemable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/tp-left-front.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-235" title="HP TouchPad" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/tp-left-front.jpg"  alt="HP TouchPad" width="100" height="160"></a>The&nbsp;pi&egrave;ce de r&eacute;sistance of the event was the <a title="Palm USA | HP TouchPad" href="http://www.palm.com/us/products/pads/touchpad/index.html" target="_blank">HP TouchPad</a>. This was the device that kept <a title="HP can't help but tease after slate leak: &quot;Think again.&quot; | PreCentral.net | The #1 Palm Pre and Pixi Community" href="http://www.precentral.net/hp-can-t-help-tease-after-slate-leak-think-again" target="_blank">sneaking out and starting rumors</a>. The TouchPad has&nbsp;a 9.7-inch XGA capacitive, multitouch, 1024&times;768 resolution display and a front-facing 1.3-megapixel webcam. One of the features of the TouchPad that HP seemed to be the proudest of was the integration of&nbsp;<a href="http://www.beatsbydre.com/">Beats Audio<sup>?</sup> by Dr. Dre</a>. Although there aren&rsquo;t any technical specifics about what makes this brand of sound equipment better, HP says that it &ldquo;reproduces the original sonic integrity of digital tracks?letting you hear the music the way recording artists intended.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Although the hardware was certainly impressive, a large portion of the event was spent talking about new apps for the devices. HP especially focused on the applications that are designed specifically for the TouchPad, such as the new Time Inc, magazines, the Kindle app, and Quickoffice. However, the highlight of the event was seeing how the new version of WebOS, verions 2.2 on the Pre<sup>3</sup> and Veer, and 3.0 on the TouchPad, work and how they work together. For example, you can &ldquo;move&rdquo; web content that you are viewing on one device to another just by taping the two devices together. Also, you can answer a phone call or receive text messages that came in on your WebOS Phone on your TouchPad instead.&nbsp;HP also gave us a sneak peak into the future. HP intends to bring WebOS to desktops and laptops, thus bridging the gap from mobile devices to our more stationary devices and extending the experience.</p>
<p>The two daggers to the hearts of Palm fans that I mentioned earlier were discovered after the bright lights had come down and had everyone started to trickle out of the Herbst Pavilion. First, even though HP CEO <a title='HP CEO Apotheker: "the [new webOS] hardware is ready" | PreCentral.net' href="http://www.precentral.net/hp-ceo-apotheker-the-hardware-ready" target="_blank">Leo Apotheker promised that the new HP WebOS hardware was ready</a> and that it&nbsp;<a title="BBC News - Can Leo Apotheker make Hewlett Packard a cool company?" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-12291529" target="_blank">would be ready to ship within weeks of the announcement</a>, the Veer is the only device shipping within the next few <em>months</em>. HP officially says on its website that the TouchPad and the Pre<sup>3</sup> are planned to be available this summer, and the Veer is planned to be available this spring. These statements have the sad, familiar ring of the line that became infamous within the WebOS community: &ldquo;in the coming months.&rdquo;&nbsp;&nbsp;This was the answer every time there was a <a title="YouTube - I said release the pre" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8Kgex9Q69lY" target="_blank">delay in releasing the Palm Pre</a>, &nbsp;<a title='Verizon and Canada to get Pre 2 in "coming months" | PreCentral.net' href="http://www.precentral.net/verizon-and-canada-get-pre-2-coming-months" target="_blank">the Pre 2,</a> <a title='webOS 2.0 will be released to "all devices" in coming months (Update: Video online) | PreCentral.net' href="http://www.precentral.net/webos-2-0-will-be-released-all-devices-coming-months-update-video-online" target="_blank">WebOS 2.0</a> and <a title="Flash Player 10.1 coming to Palm Pre (Adobe Flash Platform Blog) " href="http://blogs.adobe.com/flashplatform/2010/01/flash_player_101_coming_to_pal.html" target="_blank">Adobe Flash support</a>.&nbsp;It was also noted that neither the price of these new devices or the carriers that they would be on was disclosed.</p>
<p>The second and most painful wound for WebOS fans came when both&nbsp;<a title="Original Pre, Pre Plus, Pixi and Pixi Plus won't get updated to webOS 2.0" href="http://www.engadget.com/2011/02/09/original-pre-pre-plus-pixi-and-pixi-plus-wont-get-updated-to/" target="_blank">Engadget</a> and <a title="No major webOS OTA Updates to Pre, Pre Plus, Pixi, Pixi Plus" href="http://www.precentral.net/no-major-webos-ota-updates-pre-pre-plus-pixi-pixi-plus" target="_blank">PreCentral</a> spoke to the folks at HP behind WebOS and they confirmed to both sites that the Palm Pre, Pixi, Pre Plus, and Pixi Plus will not receive any more major over-the-air updates of WebOS. Jon Rubinstein told Engadget that the older devices simply did not have the necessary specs to support WebOS 2.0 properly. Apparently HP has &ldquo;something special&rdquo; planned for owners of the older devices when the new devices go on sale; what that means at this point is anyone&rsquo;s guess. In the midst of the resulting torch and pitchfork waving from the incited masses, HP showed its humanity and compassion towards its loyal users when <a title="Twitter / @Lisa Brewster" href="http://twitter.com/#!/Adora/status/35517969089953792" target="_blank">Lisa Brewster of Palm Developer Relations tweeted</a>: &ldquo;We&rsquo;ve broken a promise to our most faithful users, and that has my heart heavy tonight. Ppl keep asking if I&rsquo;m ok.&rdquo; <a title="Twitter / @palm" href="http://twitter.com/#!/palm/status/35490855481507840" target="_blank">Palm later tweeted</a> from their official Twitter account: &ldquo;All the feedback and questions are appreciated &mdash; will be sharing as much info as possible as soon as possible&rdquo;</p>
<p>In the end, HP may have scored a win with the general public, but they also scored an epic fail with their fiercely loyal fans that stuck with them through <a title="Crossing the webOS Desert | WebOS Roundup" href="http://www.webosroundup.com/2010/06/crossing-the-webos-desert/" target="_blank">the WebOS Desert</a>. HP needs to respond quickly to this <a title="Twitter / @Ray Hollister" href="http://twitter.com/#!/RayHollister/status/35468167048466432" target="_blank">PR nightmare</a> with something that will salve the wounds that they inflicted. Then, HP needs to get these devices out quickly before new iOS and Android hardware comes out that make the new HP devices look beige and boring again.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="HP's cards are finally on the table, but not all of them are good." data-link="/2011/02/hps-cards-are-finally-on-the-table-but-not-all-of-them-are-good/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="HP's cards are finally on the table, but not all of them are good." data-link="/2011/02/hps-cards-are-finally-on-the-table-but-not-all-of-them-are-good/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/02/hps-cards-are-finally-on-the-table-but-not-all-of-them-are-good/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What kind of cards are HP holding in its Palm?</title>
		<link>/2011/02/what-kind-of-cards-are-hp-holding-in-its-palm/</link>
		<comments>/2011/02/what-kind-of-cards-are-hp-holding-in-its-palm/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 04:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[February 9th]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP Slate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP WebOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm Pre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm Pre 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Think Beyond]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WebOS]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=172</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/02/handofcards-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="A picture of a royal flush, but the cards are branded with the HP Palm logo." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />HP and Palm have both been historically known for showing off fantastic technology that they are still developing or even just considering developing. Unfortunately, they are also known for never bringing those items, like the Palm Foleo, to market, and for bringing them to market so late, like the HP Slate, that they are already irrelevant. However, ever since the formerly struggling and weak Palm was bought by the benevolent, behemoth that is HP and became HP's Palm Global Business Unit, both have been playing their hands a little closer to the vest. <p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/02/what-kind-of-cards-are-hp-holding-in-its-palm/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/02/handofcards-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="A picture of a royal flush, but the cards are branded with the HP Palm logo." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p style="text-align: center;"><img class="size-full wp-image-197 aligncenter" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" title="Does HP Palm have a royal flush, or are they just bluffing?" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/handofcards.jpg" alt="A picture of a royal flush, but the cards are branded with the HP Palm logo." width="400" height="400"><a title="HP to hold webOS event on February 9: ?Think big. Think small. Think beyond.?  | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/hp-hold-webos-event-february-9-?think-big-think-small-think-beyond-?" target="_blank"></a></p>
<p>HP and Palm are holding a big event&nbsp;this Wednesday, February 9th. Both been historically known for showing off <a title="Flexible displays in webOS's (distant) future? | PreCentral.net" href="http://www.precentral.net/flexible-displays-webos-s-distant-future" target="_blank">fantastic technology</a> that they are still developing or even just considering developing. Unfortunately, they are also known for never bringing those items, like the <a title="The Official Palm Blog | A Message to Palm Customers, Partners and Developers" href="http://blog.palm.com/palm/2007/09/a-message-to-pa.html" target="_blank">Palm Foleo</a>, to market, and for bringing them to market so late, like the <a title="HP's Slate gets delayed | The Inquirer" href="http://www.theinquirer.net/inquirer/news/1603807/hp-slate-delayed" target="_blank">HP Slate</a>,&nbsp;that they are already irrelevant.&nbsp;However, ever since the formerly struggling and weak <a title="The Official HP Palm Blog: Palm and HP" href="http://blog.palm.com/palm/2010/04/palm-and-hp.html" target="_blank">Palm was bought</a> by the benevolent,&nbsp;behemoth that is HP and became HP&rsquo;s Palm Global Business Unit, both have been playing their hands a little closer to the vest.&nbsp;Recently hired HP CEO, Leo Apotheker, has made it clear that <a title="Apotheker: HP to ship products within weeks of announcement, wants to sit at the cool kids table | PreCentral.net | The #1 Palm Pre and Pixi Community" href="http://www.precentral.net/apotheker-hp-ship-products-within-weeks-announcement-wants-sit-cool-kids-table" target="_blank">HP is gonna play it cool</a> from now on. The days of announcing a product many months&nbsp;before the product is ready to roll off the production lines are over. HP plans on having their products ready to ship within weeks of the upcoming announcement on February 9th.</p>
<p>HP and Palm have been doing their best to keep&nbsp;a weary fan base&nbsp;excited while keeping their employees&rsquo; lip&rsquo;s locked. When a little bit of information did manage to squeeze its way out of their vice grip,&nbsp;<a title="HP can't help but tease after slate leak: &quot;Think again.&quot; | PreCentral.net | The #1 Palm Pre and Pixi Community" href="http://www.precentral.net/hp-can-t-help-tease-after-slate-leak-think-again" target="_blank">Palm was quick to brush it off with a laugh</a>. Palm has also been teasing us with &nbsp;<a title="The Official HP Palm Blog: 'Twas the week after Christmas" href="http://blog.palm.com/palm/2011/01/twas-the-week-after-christmas.html" target="_blank">poetic humor</a> and more recently with what could only be called a <a title="The Official HP Palm Blog: Ready to peek into the beyond?" href="http://blog.palm.com/palm/2011/02/ready-to-peek-into-the-beyond.html" target="_blank">peep show</a>. See the video below. Don&rsquo;t worry, it&rsquo;s rated G.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><object classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" width="480" height="385" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"><param name="src" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/uhzS_5jUHBc?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US"><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="480" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/uhzS_5jUHBc?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></div>
<p>So, the question on the minds of those following the news out of Sunnyvale, CA is &ldquo;What is HP going to announce on the 9th?&rdquo; HP has said that they will definitely launch a WebOS tablet in 2011, so we&rsquo;ll likely see some sort of tablet device. Other than that, it&rsquo;s anyone&rsquo;s guess. Their tagline for the event, &ldquo;Think big. Think small. Think beyond? leaves a lot to the imagination; it doesn&rsquo;t promise anything, and yet it promises everything. Will Palm fanboys and girls finally get new phones to run their beloved WebOS on? Will WebOS finally catch up with every other major smartphone OS and get a Kindle, Netflix, Nook, and/or Hulu app? Will HP announce something that will change the mobile market in such a major way that it will make the iPhone announcement in 2007 pale in comparison, or will we find out what I believe many WebOS fans are secretly dreading: HP was really bluffing the whole time. We won&rsquo;t know until February 9th at 10:00 AM PST. Until then, we&rsquo;ll have to wait. For what? We don&rsquo;t know, but <a title="Something Amazing | YouTube" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vNX3rRH5ZPM" target="_blank">we hope it&rsquo;s something amazing</a>.</p>
<p>For those of you that belong to the uninitiated masses, the card analogy that was beaten to death in this article is, of course, &nbsp;in reference to the gorgeous, intuitive user interface that is the keystone of HP WebOS (formerly Palm WebOS). HP WebOS is the operating system that runs the Palm Pre and Pixi and all of their later iterations and will be in whatever new device(s) that HP announces Wednesday. HP WebOS is arguably the only mobile operating system that is currently on the market that allows you to really multitask, i.e. run two or more programs at the same time. While iOS&nbsp;finally&nbsp;has the ability in versions 4 and above to allow some things to run in the background, WebOS has always allowed multitasking. (iOS is the operating system in all of the i- prefixed devices made by a certain&nbsp;<a title="Fruit Company Quote from Forrest Gump" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SNa4EMUWnAc" target="_blank">fruit company</a>)&nbsp;Also, the way that cards work on WebOS is what is truly amazing. Instead of having to use some awkward combination of button presses and waiting for the app to &ldquo;wiggle,&rdquo; to open a new app in WebOS, you simply tap the center of the gesture bar at the bottom of the screen. The app then shrinks to 3/4 of the screen and looks like a little card. Then, you can search for the app you want to open. After you have two or more apps open, you can slide back and forth between them easily. Watch this video and see how easy it is:</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><object classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" width="480" height="385" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"><param name="src" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/pcow6eydZFw?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US"><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="480" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/pcow6eydZFw?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></div>
<p><em>Royal Flush image by <a title="Royal Flush | Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mawel/2115190646/" target="_blank">Marc Wellek&ouml;tter</a> via Flickr. Image mashup by Ray Hollister.</em></p>
<p>UPDATE: <a title="Your HP Think Beyond webOS Event Liveblog is right here, Bookmark it | PreCentral.net | The #1 Palm Pre and Pixi Community" href="http://www.precentral.net/hp-palm-thinkbeyond-liveblog">PreCentral.net is going to be live blogging the HP Palm event</a>, and webOSroundup is having a <a href="http://www.webosroundup.com/2011/02/no-press-pass-for-hps-press-event-no-problem-head-to-the-webosgatherup/">webOSGatherup in San Francisco</a>.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="What kind of cards are HP holding in its Palm?" data-link="/2011/02/what-kind-of-cards-are-hp-holding-in-its-palm/" data-summary="HP and Palm have both been historically known for showing off fantastic technology that they are still developing or even just considering developing. Unfortunately, they are also known for never bringing those items, like the Palm Foleo, to market, and for bringing them to market so late, like the HP Slate, that they are already irrelevant. However, ever since the formerly struggling and weak Palm was bought by the benevolent, behemoth that is HP and became HP's Palm Global Business Unit,"></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="What kind of cards are HP holding in its Palm?" data-link="/2011/02/what-kind-of-cards-are-hp-holding-in-its-palm/" data-summary="HP and Palm have both been historically known for showing off fantastic technology that they are still developing or even just considering developing. Unfortunately, they are also known for never bringing those items, like the Palm Foleo, to market, and for bringing them to market so late, like the HP Slate, that they are already irrelevant. However, ever since the formerly struggling and weak Palm was bought by the benevolent, behemoth that is HP and became HP's Palm Global Business Unit,"></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/02/what-kind-of-cards-are-hp-holding-in-its-palm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
