<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; SSDs</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/ssds/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#83 It&#8217;s Time to Play the Feud!</title>
		<link>/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/</link>
		<comments>/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 17:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSDs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verizon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10014</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/google_feud2-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="google_feud2" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week Ray warns us about storing our SSDs in hot places, unless you want to wipe your drives clean. Tom explores the dangers of asking questions on Quora.&#160;And Sean finds out why one company is trying to make the <a href="/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/google_feud2-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="google_feud2" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week Ray warns us about storing our SSDs in hot places, unless you want to wipe your drives clean. Tom explores the dangers of asking questions on Quora.&nbsp;And Sean finds out why one company is trying to make the food replicators from Star Trek a reality. Plus the guys look at Facebook&rsquo;s new &ldquo;instant articles,&rdquo; learn why Microsoft is saying Windows 10 will be the last version of Windows they&rsquo;ll release, and delve into Verizon&rsquo;s purchase of AOL. Then later, Sean acts like Steve Harvey as Tom and Ray play a few rounds of the online game Google Feud.</p>
<p>But first, could we&nbsp;ask a favor of you? If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on our website, would you subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>? And, while you&rsquo;re there, would you leave a review and say a few nice things about us? The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10014-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-15.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-15.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-15.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3><b>SSDs can lose data really fast</b></h3>
<p>You know those amazingly fast SSDs that are replacing hard drives in high end laptops like practically every Mac on the market? Well, there is a trade off. You definitely don&rsquo;t want to store your wedding pictures on them. Or your tax records. Or your receipts from Best Buy. Because, some SSDs can lose their data in <b>only a few days</b>.</p>
<p>According to Gizmodo, heat is the enemy. <a href="http://gizmodo.com/some-ssds-can-lose-data-after-just-a-few-days-in-storag-1703490139">The length of data retention is cut in half for every nine degrees of temperature increase</a>. So, if you do like a lot of people Ray has talked to have done, and stick your old computer in a hot storage unit, expect to reinstall Windows on it when you get it out, because the SSD might be blank.</p>
<p>Just another reminder to back up your data!</p>
<h3><b>Man weighing two job offers finds one of them retracted after asking Quora which of them he should take</b></h3>
<p>In the news this week, yet another cautionary tale about being very careful with what you post online.</p>
<p>Last week a San Francisco engineer who was weighing competing job offers from Uber and Zenefits posted on Quora, asking the advice of its users on which to take. The engineer said that he liked what Zenefits was offering but that it didn&rsquo;t seem as compelling a ?buzzword? to have on his resume as Uber.</p>
<p>The dilemma was presumably cleared up for the engineer <a href="http://qz.com/400027/engineer-asks-quora-which-job-offer-to-take-ceo-replies-not-ours/" target="_blank">when Zenefits&rsquo; CEO responded, saying &ldquo;Definitely not Zenefits,&rdquo; and retracting the job offer</a>.</p>
<p>While the post was later changed to remove the public job retraction, presumably the damage was done. It was not clear if the candidate, who remains anonymous, had accepted Uber&rsquo;s offer.</p>
<h3><b>Microsoft representative claims that Windows 10 is the &ldquo;last&rdquo; version of Windows</b></h3>
<p>This week at Microsoft&rsquo;s Ignite conference, tech evangelist Jerry Nixon was quoted as saying, &ldquo;Right now we&rsquo;re releasing Windows 10, and because Windows 10 is the last version of Windows, we&rsquo;re all still working on Windows 10.&rdquo; <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/5/7/8568473/windows-10-last-version-of-windows" target="_blank">Microsoft confirmed this statement to The Verge</a>, saying that it would be focusing on &ldquo;Windows as a service,&rdquo; delivering continuous updates to the system rather than rolling out new versions of Windows.</p>
<p>That is of course until the next time Marketing gets a bright idea in its head and they announce Windows 20.</p>
<h3><b>Facebook rolls out &ldquo;instant articles&rdquo; from major news publishers</b></h3>
<p>Starting this week on the iOS Facebook app, some news articles will load much, much faster when you click on them. <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/5/13/8595263/facebooks-instant-articles-arrive-to-speed-up-the-news-feed" target="_blank">Facebook is calling these ?instant articles?</a>, and they will be available from a handful of publishers that have partnered with Facebook, including the New York Times, BuzzFeed, The Atlantic, BBC News and National Geographic, among others. Instant articles won?t look much different to users, at least at first &ndash; they will just load instantly when clicked. In the future, however, Facebook may add auto-playing &ldquo;video covers&rdquo; as well.</p>
<p>Facebook will allow new, special interactions with Instant Articles, including audio captions, geotagged photos, and interactive maps. And of course, there will be no ads.</p>
<p>No word yet on when Android users will see this feature.</p>
<h3><b>Israeli company creates Genie, a futuristic appliance that can create instant meals on demand</b></h3>
<p>A new Israeli device called the Genie, which claims its inspiration from Star Trek&rsquo;s fictional replicators, <a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/closest-thing-to-star-trek-replicator-makes-meals-in-30-seconds/" target="_blank">can turn pods of dehydrated powders into meals on demand</a>. While details are light, supposedly the meals can be customized to personal preference, including specifying whether they should be gluten-, dairy-, or egg-free. The Genie will also work with smartphones and mobile devices.</p>
<p>No word if it responds to voice commands like, &ldquo;Tea, earl gray, hot.&rdquo;</p>
<h3><b>Verizon announces plan to buy AOL for 4.4 billion dollars</b></h3>
<p>In a surprise announcement this week, <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/13/business/dealbook/verizon-to-buy-aol-for-4-4-billion.html?hp&amp;action=click&amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;module=first-column-region&amp;region=top-news&amp;WT.nav=top-news" target="_blank">Verizon and AOL announced that Verizon will buy AOL for $4.4 billion dollars</a>. People with knowledge of the matter say that Verizon is looking to acquire AOL&rsquo;s mobile, video and advertising technology. Verizon may be looking to offer its own streaming video platform which it can sell ads against. It will also acquire popular news site The Huffington Post, not to mention the legacy dial-up service which once made AOL a powerhouse.</p>
<p>Verizon is currently valued at $200 billion dollars, making the four and a half billion in cash they plan to spend on AOL little more than a rounding error.</p>
<h1>It&rsquo;s time to play the feud!</h1>
<div id="attachment_10015" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/media/2015/05/google_feud.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-10015 size-full" src="/media/2015/05/google_feud.jpg"  alt="Credit: Google Feud" width="500" height="104"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Credit: Google Feud</p></div>
<p>You may have seen the site <a href="http://www.googlefeud.com/" target="_blank">Google Feud</a> making the rounds on social media recently. This online game combines weird Google autocomplete search suggestions with Family Feud style game play, in which you have to guess the top 10 ways Google autocompletes a specific sentence or question (for example, &ldquo;Is it weird to _____&rdquo;). Sean plays the role of Steve Harvey &ndash; or John O&rsquo;Hurley, Louie Anderson, Richard Dawson, or whoever you favorite Family Feud host was &ndash; while Ray and Tom guess their way through a few rounds.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#83 It's Time to Play the Feud!" data-link="/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#83 It's Time to Play the Feud!" data-link="/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/05/83-its-time-to-play-the-feud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-15.mp3" length="42870134" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
