<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; MS-DOS</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/ms-dos/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#90 Cutting Cords and Fiber Optic Cables</title>
		<link>/2015/07/90-cutting-cords-and-fiber-optic-cables/</link>
		<comments>/2015/07/90-cutting-cords-and-fiber-optic-cables/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2015 00:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MS-DOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NetFlix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Siri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10124</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/divide_zero_by_zero_square-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="divide_zero_by_zero_square" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week Ray, Tom and Sean discuss news about Netflix&#8217;s growth, videos on Facebook, SpaceX and more. Plus, Siri hits a little too close to home when we ask her to divide zero by zero. That and more on this <a href="/2015/07/90-cutting-cords-and-fiber-optic-cables/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/07/90-cutting-cords-and-fiber-optic-cables/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/divide_zero_by_zero_square-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="divide_zero_by_zero_square" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week Ray, Tom and Sean discuss news about Netflix&rsquo;s growth, videos on Facebook, SpaceX and more. Plus, Siri hits a little too close to home when we ask her to divide zero by zero. That and more on this week&rsquo;s Deemable Tech!</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on our website, would you subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>? And, while you&rsquo;re there, would you leave a review and say a few nice things about us? The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="//media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="//media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there. We&rsquo;re also looking for a new admin to help manage and moderate our subreddit page. Submit a text post to our subreddit explaining why you would make a great admin.</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10124-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-03.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-03.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-03.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S RUNDOWN</h1>
<h3>Netflix expected to be bigger than major TV networks</h3>
<p><a href="http://gizmodo.com/netflix-s-about-to-be-bigger-than-abc-cbs-nbc-and-fo-1713886024">A Wall Street research firm estimates that Netflix will have more viewers than ABC, CBS, NBC and FOX </a>within a year. Or at least it would, if Netflix were a 24-hour broadcast television network and not a streaming video service. The way the networks and Netflix measure viewership are different, and they also serve up different kinds of programming. For instance, the networks carry live sports events and Netflix does not. Even so, a rough crunch of the numbers shows that Netflix is expanding rapidly even as the TV networks&rsquo; audiences are shrinking, which means that by next year Netflix will probably have more eyeballs than any of the big four.</p>
<h3>Google Photos tags African-American developer as &ldquo;gorilla&rdquo;</h3>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/167FIBRcN9IPRtSpwP3uUHtc_don83UaXNDbIwjs9Zxk/edit?pli=1">Google Photos found itself scrambling to do damage control</a> when a black developer found that the service had tagged pictures of him with his black female friend with the tag &ldquo;gorillas.&rdquo; After the dev posted a screenshot of the issue on Twitter, Google?s Chief Social Architect reached out to him within an hour-and-a-half saying, &ldquo;This is 100% not OK.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Google says that the &ldquo;gorilla&rdquo; tag has since been removed from the tag database and that Google is tweaking its algorithms, specifically in regards to dark-skinned faces. Google says that this is not the first time the automatic image tagging has had issues, and that an early bug labeled humans of all races as &ldquo;dogs.&rdquo;</p>
<h3><b>Facebook considers paying video content creators</b></h3>
<p>Facebook has built a video empire off of letting people rip videos off of YouTube and post them on its site. We can&rsquo;t tell you how many times we&rsquo;ve seen a video on Facebook that I know the person who posted it did not own.</p>
<p>To make things worse, Facebook reduced the size of YouTube video previews, so the creators had to choose between posting the video on Facebook natively where lots of people would see it, but not receiving any revenue, or posting the video on YouTube and sharing it on Facebook and few people seeing it.</p>
<p>Facebook is finally letting creators earn a bit of money. Now when you are watching a &ldquo;suggested video&rdquo; ? perhaps after you watched a funny cat video that your friend posted ? you&rsquo;ll see a short ad before Facebook automatically goes to the next video. Facebook will keep 45% of the revenue and give the rest to the partner who posted the video which is right on par with YouTube&rsquo;s rev-share terms.</p>
<p>Dan Rose, Facebook?s VP of partnerships <a href="http://variety.com/2015/digital/news/facebook-video-ad-revenue-partners-1201532366/">told Variety</a>, &ldquo;We&rsquo;ve heard consistently from media companies and other video creators that if they were able to make money from their videos, they would publish more.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The question is going to be how will Facebook get rid of all of the pirated content on its website?</p>
<h3>&ldquo;Rampage&rdquo; game developer releasing MS-DOS version</h3>
<p>Game developer Vblank has announced that it will <a href="http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2015/06/ms-dos-is-getting-a-new-game-in-the-form-of-retro-city-rampage-486/">release a new version of its 8-bit-style game Retro City Rampage for MS-DOS</a>. The game will be called Retro City Rampage 486, and the system requirements include 3.7 MB of hard drive space, 4 MB of RAM and, yes, an Intel 486 CPU. Oh, and a copy of MS-DOS, obviously. That&rsquo;s the one with the blinking text prompt that you had to use before Windows 95, in case you&rsquo;ve forgotten. You mean you don?t have a copy sitting around on six floppies somewhere?</p>
<p>This is not Vblank&rsquo;s first port of Rampage to a decidedly &ldquo;retro&rdquo; system. They also recently finished a port designed to run on an original Nintendo. In case you?re keeping track, a classic Nintendo console squeezes out barely 300K of memory all told. Wow.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re eager to run the game but don&rsquo;t have a working computer from 1992 sitting around the house, we recommend the emulator DOSBox.</p>
<h3>Leap second causes &ldquo;sporadic outages&rdquo; across the Internet</h3>
<p>You may have heard that the world&rsquo;s official time keepers added a leap second to the world&rsquo;s official clocks this week. They do this every so often to keep the clocks in sync with the spinning of the earth &ndash; apparently the atomic clocks we use don&rsquo;t account for small changes in the earth&rsquo;s behavior. Time keepers have had to add 25 of these leap seconds since 1973.</p>
<p>You might think that one second wouldn&rsquo;t make much of a difference to anything, but it totally does when computers are involved. Most machines rely on software code that isn&rsquo;t prepared to deal with this extra second. In fact, the last time a leap second was added in 2012 sites like Reddit went down, and flights in Australia were grounded because machines at Qanta Airways went dark.</p>
<p>Companies were a little more prepared this time around, but according to analysis from a firm called <a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/07/leap-second-causes-sporadic-outages-across-internet/">Dyn Research, the leap second still caused sporadic Internet outages including a hiccup that lasted about five minutes</a>. And apparently it was caused by a particular router.</p>
<p>There was a lag as internet service providers and other companies worked to reroute data through other paths.</p>
<h3>SpaceX rocket explodes shortly after launch</h3>
<p>Over the weekend NASA&rsquo;s partnership with privately owned company SpaceX suffered a setback when an unmanned rocket on a mission to resupply the International Space Station <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/6/28/8858801/spacex-falcon-9-rocket-explosion-nasa">exploded approximately two and a half minutes after launch</a>. In a Tweet, SpaceX founder Elon Musk said that there had been an &ldquo;overpressure event in the upper stage liquid oxygen tank.&rdquo; Up until Saturday&rsquo;s explosion, the Falcon 9 rockets used by SpaceX have always been perfectly reliable. This is, however, the third ISS resupply mission in a row to fail. The ISS crew is currently reported to have enough supplies to last through September.</p>
<h3>Someone is cutting internet cables in California</h3>
<p>The Wall Street Journal <a href="http://news.wjct.org/post/somebody-cutting-internet-cables-california">reported that early Tuesday morning unknown persons severed fiber-optic cables carrying internet traffic across Northern California, apparently intentionally</a>. This was the most recent of several such attacks on internet infrastructure in California in the last year. Internet disruptions and slowdowns were reported between Sacramento and Seattle. The FBI says that someone broke into an underground vault to attack the cables. They are asking for the public&rsquo;s assistance in finding the culprits.</p>
<h3>Fiber goes faster</h3>
<p>Speaking of fiber optic cables, reddit user FrakinBeast posted a story from Gizmodo that <a href="http://gizmodo.com/engineers-just-broke-the-capacity-limit-for-fiber-optic-1714070706">engineers were able to make fiber optic cables carry more data</a> even further than ever before. The electrical engineers at UC San Diego got a transmission to travel 7,400 miles. Unfortunately, that&rsquo;s all that we could understand in this story.</p>
<h3>Ask Siri to divide zero by zero</h3>
<p>An Easter egg found in Apple&rsquo;s Siri virtual assistant has social media abuzz this week. When asked the question &ldquo;What is zero divided by zero?&rdquo; Siri responds with a philosophical &ndash; and at times personal &ndash; answer.</p>
<p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2015/07/divide_zero_by_zero.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-10127" src="//media/2015/07/divide_zero_by_zero-300x99.jpg"  alt="divide_zero_by_zero" width="500" height="165"></a></p>
<p>&mdash;</p>
<p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable&nbsp;dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#90 Cutting Cords and Fiber Optic Cables" data-link="/2015/07/90-cutting-cords-and-fiber-optic-cables/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#90 Cutting Cords and Fiber Optic Cables" data-link="/2015/07/90-cutting-cords-and-fiber-optic-cables/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/07/90-cutting-cords-and-fiber-optic-cables/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-03.mp3" length="24205214" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#82 Demand for Deemable Tech is Crazy Off The Hook!</title>
		<link>/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/</link>
		<comments>/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 21:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boeing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boeing 787]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Surface]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MS-DOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Powerwall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Surface]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The IT Crowd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9987</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/MarioKart-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Mario Kart" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week Tom&#160;brings the joyous news that Nintendoland is coming! Ray wants fast passes to the Mario Kart ride. But none of the guys want to ride on a Boeing 787 after Ray tells the guys that some of the <a href="/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/MarioKart-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Mario Kart" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week Tom&nbsp;brings the joyous news that Nintendoland is coming! Ray wants fast passes to the Mario Kart ride. But none of the guys want to ride on a Boeing 787 after Ray tells the guys that some of the planes are turning off&hellip; in mid air. Not good. Oculus finally announces a consumer model of the Oculus Rift. People are breaking/not breaking their Microsoft Surface 3 tablets. Twitter broke MS-DOS games, and&nbsp;Tesla just brought the future one step closer to today. All that on this week&rsquo;s episode.</p>
<p>But first, could we&nbsp;ask a favor of you? If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on our website, would you subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>? And, while you&rsquo;re there, would you leave a review and say a few nice things about us? The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="//media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="//media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-9987-2" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-08.mp3?_=2"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-08.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-08.mp3</a></audio><h1><a name="h.xvjwtmnq4snt"></a>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S&nbsp;RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3><a name="h.52mal8gpu9c8"></a>Nintendo Theme Park</h3>
<p>Who is up for Mario Kart in real life? <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.businessinsider.com%2Fnintendo-partnered-with-universal-studios-2015-5&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHBXxqKCVD6dQJ6jJMbbnq4IUyX-A">Nintendo announced during an earnings call this week</a>&nbsp;that it is partnering with Universal Parks and Resorts which runs the Universal Studios theme parks to create Nintendo-themed rides and attractions. Nintendo has not announced specific details on which of its properties it would adapt, but it seems like a safe bet that it will leverage long lasting and popular characters and games like Mario, Zelda and Donkey Kong. In fact, Universal executive Tom Schroder said pretty much exactly that in a press release: &ldquo;The immersive experiences will include major attractions at Universal?s theme parks and will feature Nintendo?s most famous characters and games.&rdquo;</p>
<h3><a name="h.chtqttd17zg"></a>Have you tried turning your plane off and on again?</h3>
<p>The FAA sent out a warning on May 1st that Boeing 787s may have some computer problems that could cause your terrible, terrible death. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fmashable.com%2F2015%2F05%2F01%2Ffaa-warns-of-bug-on-boeing-787%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHpr42SZ-Q17g9cTWkuLitARPC79w">Mashable reports</a>&nbsp;that the administration discovered the computers in 787s have a &ldquo;software counter&rdquo; that periodically shuts down all electrical systems, which results in &ldquo;loss of control of the airplane.&rdquo; Now, I&rsquo;m not an aviation expert, but I think that is a bad thing. Am I right in assuming that guys?</p>
<p>Boeing is working out a software update that will eliminate the problem, but until then, they have issued a work around. If you work in the IT industry or have ever worked technical support you are probably familiar with it:</p>
<p>&ldquo;Have you tried turning it off and on again?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Yes folks, it&rsquo;s the I.T. Crowd fix.</p>
<p>Call Roy and Moss or your plane will crash to the ground.</p>
<h3><a name="h.dxy8cs4kfy0p"></a>Oculus announces &ldquo;Q1 2016&rdquo; release for Rift</h3>
<p>In other news that is sure to have gamers everywhere jumping for joy, Oculus announced this week that the <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Fgaming%2F2015%2F05%2Foculus-announces-q1-2016-release-for-first-consumer-oculus-rift%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFqIkbhnovA8nKPyPA46K6bc4aeUg">first commercial release of their hotly anticipated virtual reality headset the Oculus Rift</a>&nbsp;will be in early 2016.</p>
<p>The company also released promotional images of the sleek final consumer product after several years of prototypes.</p>
<p>Oculus first made a splash at the E3 gaming expo in 2012, followed by a very successful Kickstarter campaign. They also kicked off a virtual reality race, with other big companies like Sony and Valve and HTC working on releasing their own VR products.</p>
<h3><a name="h.z3sx0snlkkb2"></a>How low can you go?</h3>
<p>One of the most interesting tablets to come out, other than the iPad, has definitely been the Microsoft Surface. Sure, it&rsquo;s had its share of troubles. It came out with Windows RT, which was this weird, stripped down version of Windows. It had two interfaces, the desktop and the &ldquo;tablet&rdquo; UI which really confused people. But, it was an incredible design that really changed the market, making it a serious contender for a laptop replacement. One of its signature features was the coveted kickstand that can hold the tablet in one of three positions. Well, now the Verge is reporting that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2015%2F5%2F5%2F8552361%2Fmicrosoft-surface-3-kickstand-secret-position&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEbF6-vUmOr1nwmHZTHk2rehCYQ6g">Redditors have discovered a secret fourth position for the Surface 3 kickstand</a>. Apparently, if you keep pressing the kickstand back after the third position it will break away and fold all the way back.</p>
<p>Microsoft said in a statement that the kickstand &ldquo;contains a safety mechanism unique to Surface 3 to help protect the device, but the mechanism is not designed for use as a fourth kickstand position.&rdquo;</p>
<p>So it might work once, twice or maybe even a few times, but it&rsquo;s probably going to ruin your Surface 3.</p>
<p>The lesson here is, don&rsquo;t play too rough with your toys. Just like a Slinky, once you bend it out of shape, you can&rsquo;t bend it back, no matter what happened in Toy Story.</p>
<h3>MS-DOS games on Twitter update</h3>
<p>Last week we told you how you can embed and play classic MS-DOS games in tweets. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theguardian.com%2Ftechnology%2F2015%2Fmay%2F04%2Ftwitter-kills-ms-dos-games-embedded-in-tweets&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNE6Ik7_hQBAUxmlYM6C49m8hpVt_A">Sadly, it looks like Twitter has put a stop to that. </a></p>
<p>It was discovered last week that Twitter users could embed these games from the Internet Archive?s site into tweets using Twitter?s Cards widget (that?s the system that allows videos, images and other media to be displayed in-line in the Twitter stream). But it turns out that embedding interactive media, specifically games, is against the terms of service for Twitter Cards.</p>
<p>You can, however, still play the MS-DOS games at the Internet Archive?s site, <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Farchive.org%2Fdetails%2Fsoftwarelibrary_msdos_games&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGqHjyZZyBFozCkw1Xnf43Qi2ZmxQ">archive.org.</a></p>
<h3><a name="h.lejhs5fy0tk3"></a>Powerwall</h3>
<p>Elon Musk, CEO of Tesla, the maker of powerful electric sports cars recently announced that his company will begin manufacturing batteries for homes. This week Elon Musk announced that demand for their ?Powerwall? batteries was ?<a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.engadget.com%2F2015%2F05%2F06%2Ftesla-powerwall-earnings%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGSKjl4SPWNblaSQLI8gnOkuKE24g">crazy off the hook</a>?. He said they have received over 38,000 reservations, a level of demand which could take them up to a year to fulfill. Orders included over 2,500 from companies for their commercial-ready Powerpack.</p>
<p>The Powerwall batteries are designed for a 24-hour charge-and-discharge cycle, which would be ideal in combination with a solar power system that could charge them during the day letting them run the house at night. The batteries are designed to be mounted on the wall and a 7kWh unit starts at $3,000.</p>
<p>Note from Ray: The Powerwall is apparently <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AacoxHFYvZw">not nearly as bad as the Power Glove</a>.</p>
<p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable&nbsp;dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#82 Demand for Deemable Tech is Crazy Off The Hook!" data-link="/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#82 Demand for Deemable Tech is Crazy Off The Hook!" data-link="/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-08.mp3" length="24373189" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#81 Don&#8217;t Call It A Gate!</title>
		<link>/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/</link>
		<comments>/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple watch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chromebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MS-DOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 8]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9969</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/ScratchediPod-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="ScratchediPod" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week, Google launched&#160;a Mobile Virtual Network Operator (MVNO). The new phone service uses Sprint, T0Mobile and Wi-Fi,&#160;but it only has one phone, the Nexus 6. There&#8217;s a few Apple Watch &#8216;scandals&#8217; ramping up: tattoo-gate, scratch-gate and tap-gate. Microsoft has <a href="/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/ScratchediPod-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="ScratchediPod" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_9972" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2015/05/ScratchediPod.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-9972" src="//media/2015/05/ScratchediPod.jpg"  alt="ScratchediPod" width="400" height="300"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Anyone who&rsquo;s ever owned an iPod knows that stainless steel scratches.</p></div>
<p>This week, Google launched&nbsp;a Mobile Virtual Network Operator (MVNO). The new phone service uses Sprint, T0Mobile and Wi-Fi,&nbsp;but it only has one phone, the Nexus 6. There&rsquo;s a few Apple Watch &lsquo;scandals&rsquo; ramping up: tattoo-gate, scratch-gate and tap-gate. Microsoft has a new &ldquo;edge&rdquo;ier web browser, a man shoots up his Dell and the robots are coming to steal your car.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="//media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="//media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>If you haven?t <a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/ca/podcast/deemable-tech-wjct/id540595466?mt=2" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">subscribed to Deemable Tech</a> yet, get on it! Subscribe to <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">Deemable Tech&nbsp;in iTunes</a>,&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>or&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech Podcast!" href="http://dmbl.co/pod">subscribe to the show in another podcast reader</a>. Make sure to leave a review on iTunes and Stitcher. The more reviews posted,&nbsp;the higher Deemable Tech will&nbsp;be listed, and the more listeners will see the&nbsp;show.</p>
<p>And make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-9969-3" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-01.mp3?_=3"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-01.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-01.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S&nbsp;RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>You can now embed playable MS-DOS games inside tweets</h3>
<p>Earlier this year, the Internet Archive added roughly <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Farchive.org%2Fdetails%2Fsoftwarelibrary_msdos_games%26tab%3Dcollection&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNF_I9w3Ka6yoFsvfYIUcO27Ep4P8w">2,400 MS-DOS games to their digital archive that are playable through your web browser</a>&nbsp;on their site, Archive.org. But if you?re too scared to leave Twitter to check this out, never fear. The folks at Wired discovered this week that you can <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wired.com%2F2015%2F04%2Fembed-games-into-tweets%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFDEVcY7zZYUSwZ25qRCYuZhKsR8w">embed the games inside of tweets</a>&nbsp;and play them right from those tweets.</p>
<p>So, you can now get your Oregon Trail, Sim City or Wolfenstein 3D fix from Twitter. Or, you can try out other classic games like the adaptation of the 1991 Hulk Hogan cinematic masterpiece <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Farchive.org%2Fdetails%2Fmsdos_Suburban_Commando_1993&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFmxb8aGo-5rR7cKBu4ZqyEQHYjFg">Suburban Commando</a>&nbsp;(just kidding, you should never do that).</p>
<h3>Google announces cellular data network, which is actually two networks.</h3>
<p>Google has <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Fgadgets%2F2015%2F04%2F22%2Fhow-googles-project-fi-pricing-stacks-up-to-the-competition%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEIfE5LtjuX1Y_5Bd4Nvlx3TETCsQ">officially announced</a>&nbsp;its long-rumored cellular data network: its name is ProjectFi. As anticipated it is an MVNO network, which means that Google is ?renting? time on someone else?s network like many other small cellular companies. The differences is that Google is renting not from one other network, but two: Sprint &amp; T-mobile, as well as WiFi. When you are on a ProjectFi connection your phone will seamlessly switch to whichever one of those networks is strongest. ProjectFi?s offers a very straightforward billing structure which will be appealing to some. It also will let you ?bank? unused minutes each month. And it offers promises of more innovations to come. The catch? Right now it is only offered for a single phone: the Nexus 6, and there is no LTE high speed service.</p>
<h3>Robot car movers</h3>
<p>The <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fgizmodo.com%2Fthis-gang-of-flat-robots-can-autonomously-steal-or-par-1700680911&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNG_oJhAxLaHutxwvtz7d5M95pfVzQ">robots are coming to steal your car</a>, or just move it out of the way. Gizmodo shared a story that researchers in Europe have created AVERT, the Autonomous Vehicle Emergency Recovery Tool. It is a system of robots that look like something out of Battle Bots. They are flat pieces of steel with rotors on the ends of them. Eight of them work together to pick up your cars tires and wheel it away. They only lift the car about an inch off the ground, but that&rsquo;s all they need to move it out of the way. The idea is that the robots can easily move a car parked in a tight spot if there is a bomb in a nearby car. They could also be used to move an illegally parked car or a car that is blocking emergency services. Or, when the robots become sentient, they will likely start a car robbing career.</p>
<h3>Man puts 8 bullets in his Dell desktop, tells police it was worth the ticket.</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Ftech-policy%2F2015%2F04%2F22%2Fman-puts-8-bullets-in-his-dell-tells-police-its-worth-the-ticket%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHxdiaHiFSLGSpGwTy-gaDAVGHevw">Police say that at 7 PM on a Monday, Lucas Hinch, the owner of a homeopathic herb store in Colorado Springs, Colorado, took his Dell XPS 410 out into an alley behind the store and unloaded eight bullets into it with a 9mm pistol</a>. Hinch was ticketed for discharging a gun within city limits.</p>
<p>Lynch told the Los Angeles Times, which interviewed him, that the machine kept giving him the blue screen of death and that he had ?had enough.? He said that the shooting was ?definitely premeditated? and that he had no regrets. He reportedly told officers he did not know he was breaking the law in discharging his weapon.</p>
<h3>Microsoft unveils Edge browser</h3>
<p>During the opening keynote of their Microsoft Build developers conference this week, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.pcmag.com%2Farticle2%2F0%2C2817%2C2483459%2C00.asp&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGk4Rk3f2KJLqhuVRuTqKtqFY2aGw">Microsoft unveiled the successor to their Internet Explorer browser (which they recently announced was ending).</a></p>
<p>The new browser, now called Edge (formerly Project Spartan), is said to be faster and more modern and will be a universal app across all Windows devices. Features will include, among others, extensions like you find for Chrome and Firefox, integration of Microsoft?s Cortana virtual assistant to help you search for things, reading mode (which removes everything from a page except for the text), and an annotation tool (which lets you draw on a webpage, take a picture of it and share that picture).</p>
<p>The new browser will not be in the initial release of Windows 10 this year, but will be included in a later update. Windows 10 will be shipped with Internet Explorer 11 for legacy compatibility, so you will have one last chance to use everyone?s favorite browser before it goes softly into that good night.</p>
<h3>Tired of remember your passwords? Try swallowing them instead?</h3>
<p>In a recent interview with The Wall Street Journal, Paypal?s global head of developer advocacy, Jonathan Leblanc, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.motherjones.com%2Fkevin-drum%2F2015%2F04%2Fswallowing-passwords-biometric-paypal-leblanc&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEVa64GMFTci-ARVRnBbhwV4EHOrQ">said that passwords might soon be available as ?embeddable, injectable and ingestible devices.?</a>&nbsp;Mr. Leblanc said that in the near future thin silicon chips might be embedded under our skin or capsules might detect glucose levels to verify that someone is who they say they are.</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal notes, &ldquo;Mr. Leblanc admits that there&rsquo;s still a ways to go before cultural norms catch up with ingestible and injectable ID devices.&rdquo;</p>
<h3>Google files patent for laptop with no spacebar.</h3>
<p>Google already kicked the CAPS-LOCK key to the curb with its Chromebooks and <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fqz.com%2F393209%2Fgoogle-wants-to-do-away-with-space-bars%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEFH21pgG7RnHwMAN_uw08JgYP6QQ">now it appears it may be preparing to do the same thing to the spacebar</a>. In a patent filed this week the company outlines a design where the spacebar is replaced by an extended trackpad. Sensors would determine whether the user wants the top of the trackpad to be treated as a spacebar or a mouse. Google told Quartz, who broke the story, that some patents get turned into products and some don?t, so only time will tell whether we will see a spacebar-free Chromebook.</p>
<h3>Apple Watch &ndash; Tattoo-gate</h3>
<p>Reports are coming in on Twitter and Reddit that people with tattoos on their wrists may have difficulty using their new Apple watches. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.imore.com%2Fheres-why-apple-watch-does-not-play-nice-with-some-tattoos&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHxa84tcqtJg-bjrlAehBVvopWbQQ">iMore.com looked into it and confirmed the reports</a>. The heart sensor detects pulse by flashing an LED light on your skin and senses the reflection. The problem is when you have a tattoo the reflection is distorted by the ink. Your mileage may vary, but for some folks it is really annoying. The Apple Watch uses the heart sensor to detect if you are wearing the watch, so when it doesn&rsquo;t sense your heart rate, it forces you to re-enter your pin number.</p>
<h3>Apple Watch &ndash; Scratch-gate</h3>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t like scratches, you probably shouldn&rsquo;t get the stainless steel Apple watch. A lot of folks are reporting on social media that their steel <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fmashable.com%2F2015%2F04%2F27%2Fapple-watch-stainless-steel-scratches%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNH6Stlu5qbDBdG14wctYlZbAEg-WQ">Apple watches are already scratched up</a>. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2F9to5mac.com%2F2015%2F04%2F26%2Fapple-watch-fix-scratches%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGyOd9RtCgjPs8gKhLvKrKICr5diQ">9to5Mac.com has an easy fix. Just buff it, like every other stainless steel watch in </a><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2F9to5mac.com%2F2015%2F04%2F26%2Fapple-watch-fix-scratches%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGyOd9RtCgjPs8gKhLvKrKICr5diQ">existence</a><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2F9to5mac.com%2F2015%2F04%2F26%2Fapple-watch-fix-scratches%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGyOd9RtCgjPs8gKhLvKrKICr5diQ">.</a>&nbsp;Or, get the aluminum model, which is actually harder than the steel version.</p>
<h3>Apple Watch &ndash; Tap-gate</h3>
<p>Now for the first, actual, real problem with the Apple watch. According to the Wall Street Journal, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wsj.com%2Farticles%2Fapple-watch-faulty-taptic-engine-slows-roll-out-1430339460&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNG_NZhwUZRibof94tZ5XtkKmUiqhA">Apple has found a major defect in the taptic engine</a>&nbsp;in the watches. The taptic engine is the feature that causes the watch to vibrate or tap the wearer. It was a pretty groundbreaking feature because it models sounds so a tweet &ldquo;feels&rdquo; like a tweet, and a tap feels like a tap. Two companies built the taptic engines, but one of the suppliers has produced faulty engines. The Verge says that Daring Fireball&rsquo;s John Gruber received an Apple Watch that had a taptic engine that didn&rsquo;t work.</p>
<h1>OUTRO</h1>
<p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback@deemable.com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. deemable.com/reddit will take you there</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, I&rsquo;m Sean Birch and this is Deemable Tech. Thanks for listening.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#81 Don't Call It A Gate!" data-link="/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#81 Don't Call It A Gate!" data-link="/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-01.mp3" length="32491838" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
