<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Joe asks, &#8220;Is there a cheaper alternative to inkjet printers?&#8221;</title>
	<atom:link href="/2013/05/joe-asks-is-there-a-cheaper-alternative-to-inkjet-printers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2013/05/joe-asks-is-there-a-cheaper-alternative-to-inkjet-printers/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 19:14:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: Nilus Dionis</title>
		<link>/2013/05/joe-asks-is-there-a-cheaper-alternative-to-inkjet-printers/#comment-7124</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nilus Dionis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 21:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7358#comment-7124</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Wow ignorance is bliss...that&#039;s your advice for a cheaper printer...ouch. For one a tablet does not replace a printer - there are many reasons one may need to print something like having to sign important documents downloaded online or emailed to you and email them back or even fax them. But I could go on and on about that...the point is - a tablet is not a printer. But what&#039;s more important do not just get a printer - get a multi-function device: printer, scanner, copier, fax and even with duplex to save paper. Those can be very handy in situations you lease expect.

Next, while black and white laser printers have a reasonably low cost per page - and I&#039;ve considered them, there are some health concerns associated with laser toner. You can Google it and read - plenty research has been done on the matter. While the amount of harm it can do is inconclusive and depends on the printer and frequency of use, I would think twice before having one next to you - call me paranoid. At work they are far and away in a large space so I don&#039;t care.

Finally and here comes the main point - do your research on the printers. Inkjet printers and their toners are not all created equal. Some will have a significantly lower cost per page than other and much longer lasting cartridges. Not only that but for many cartridges can be purchased online from 3rd party manufacturer which can also be very high quality at a fraction of the cost of the original. In additional places like Costco and I think Walgreen have ink refilling services for some types of toner. Again that would be a fraction of a cost of the original but not all printer and toner types are compatible - do you research.

Before I say the following please be aware I am not affiliated in ANY way with the companies and products I am about to mention - they are a result of me doing sufficient research online. I own a hp officejet pro 8620 and prior purchased 8600 for another family member. If you research even the original toner for those printers (same type) will beat most lasers for cost per page and rated for many pages especially the XL toner (don&#039;t want to be wrong on numbers so look it up). Not only that but I have purchased 3rd party ink before from ldproducts.com for the 8600 and it was good quality at a fraction of a cost and the ink really does last a significant time and both of those mutifunctions are very good machines - they will not wow you in photo printing quality but they are great for everything else.

Again your mileage may wary so do your own research but this is some real advice for you on saving money with an inkjet printer.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wow ignorance is bliss&#8230;that&#8217;s your advice for a cheaper printer&#8230;ouch. For one a tablet does not replace a printer &#8211; there are many reasons one may need to print something like having to sign important documents downloaded online or emailed to you and email them back or even fax them. But I could go on and on about that&#8230;the point is &#8211; a tablet is not a printer. But what&#8217;s more important do not just get a printer &#8211; get a multi-function device: printer, scanner, copier, fax and even with duplex to save paper. Those can be very handy in situations you lease expect.</p>
<p>Next, while black and white laser printers have a reasonably low cost per page &#8211; and I&#8217;ve considered them, there are some health concerns associated with laser toner. You can Google it and read &#8211; plenty research has been done on the matter. While the amount of harm it can do is inconclusive and depends on the printer and frequency of use, I would think twice before having one next to you &#8211; call me paranoid. At work they are far and away in a large space so I don&#8217;t care.</p>
<p>Finally and here comes the main point &#8211; do your research on the printers. Inkjet printers and their toners are not all created equal. Some will have a significantly lower cost per page than other and much longer lasting cartridges. Not only that but for many cartridges can be purchased online from 3rd party manufacturer which can also be very high quality at a fraction of the cost of the original. In additional places like Costco and I think Walgreen have ink refilling services for some types of toner. Again that would be a fraction of a cost of the original but not all printer and toner types are compatible &#8211; do you research.</p>
<p>Before I say the following please be aware I am not affiliated in ANY way with the companies and products I am about to mention &#8211; they are a result of me doing sufficient research online. I own a hp officejet pro 8620 and prior purchased 8600 for another family member. If you research even the original toner for those printers (same type) will beat most lasers for cost per page and rated for many pages especially the XL toner (don&#8217;t want to be wrong on numbers so look it up). Not only that but I have purchased 3rd party ink before from ldproducts.com for the 8600 and it was good quality at a fraction of a cost and the ink really does last a significant time and both of those mutifunctions are very good machines &#8211; they will not wow you in photo printing quality but they are great for everything else.</p>
<p>Again your mileage may wary so do your own research but this is some real advice for you on saving money with an inkjet printer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Mike</title>
		<link>/2013/05/joe-asks-is-there-a-cheaper-alternative-to-inkjet-printers/#comment-998</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 23:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7358#comment-998</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So I guess the answer to the question “Is there a cheaper alternative to inkjet printers?” is &quot;No&quot;, unless you only need black and white. But it sounds like, if you want to print color from home... &quot;NO&quot;.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So I guess the answer to the question “Is there a cheaper alternative to inkjet printers?” is &#8220;No&#8221;, unless you only need black and white. But it sounds like, if you want to print color from home&#8230; &#8220;NO&#8221;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Jazz Gill</title>
		<link>/2013/05/joe-asks-is-there-a-cheaper-alternative-to-inkjet-printers/#comment-936</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jazz Gill]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 18:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7358#comment-936</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[hi...the information you provide is really good. Most of people feel really confused when they have to buy the printer. Laser printers are really better than inkjet printers. I want to share your this article link on my Facebook. Please reply author can I share this to help the people ?]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>hi&#8230;the information you provide is really good. Most of people feel really confused when they have to buy the printer. Laser printers are really better than inkjet printers. I want to share your this article link on my Facebook. Please reply author can I share this to help the people ?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Jaye &#124; InkjetUniverse</title>
		<link>/2013/05/joe-asks-is-there-a-cheaper-alternative-to-inkjet-printers/#comment-874</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaye &#124; InkjetUniverse]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 06:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7358#comment-874</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Everything that they have mentioned were absolutely right, it all make sense. In fact, with this, anyone who&#039;s planning to buy a new printer must know those things. I&#039;m quite surprise how they deliver every point in a nice way. Way to go, Deemable tech]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Everything that they have mentioned were absolutely right, it all make sense. In fact, with this, anyone who&#8217;s planning to buy a new printer must know those things. I&#8217;m quite surprise how they deliver every point in a nice way. Way to go, Deemable tech</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
