<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Apple iPhone</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/apple-iphone/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#81 Don&#8217;t Call It A Gate!</title>
		<link>/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/</link>
		<comments>/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple watch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chromebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MS-DOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 8]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9969</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/ScratchediPod-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="ScratchediPod" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week, Google launched&#160;a Mobile Virtual Network Operator (MVNO). The new phone service uses Sprint, T0Mobile and Wi-Fi,&#160;but it only has one phone, the Nexus 6. There&#8217;s a few Apple Watch &#8216;scandals&#8217; ramping up: tattoo-gate, scratch-gate and tap-gate. Microsoft has <a href="/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/ScratchediPod-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="ScratchediPod" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_9972" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2015/05/ScratchediPod.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-9972" src="//media/2015/05/ScratchediPod.jpg"  alt="ScratchediPod" width="400" height="300"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Anyone who&rsquo;s ever owned an iPod knows that stainless steel scratches.</p></div>
<p>This week, Google launched&nbsp;a Mobile Virtual Network Operator (MVNO). The new phone service uses Sprint, T0Mobile and Wi-Fi,&nbsp;but it only has one phone, the Nexus 6. There&rsquo;s a few Apple Watch &lsquo;scandals&rsquo; ramping up: tattoo-gate, scratch-gate and tap-gate. Microsoft has a new &ldquo;edge&rdquo;ier web browser, a man shoots up his Dell and the robots are coming to steal your car.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="//media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="//media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>If you haven?t <a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/ca/podcast/deemable-tech-wjct/id540595466?mt=2" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">subscribed to Deemable Tech</a> yet, get on it! Subscribe to <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">Deemable Tech&nbsp;in iTunes</a>,&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>or&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech Podcast!" href="http://dmbl.co/pod">subscribe to the show in another podcast reader</a>. Make sure to leave a review on iTunes and Stitcher. The more reviews posted,&nbsp;the higher Deemable Tech will&nbsp;be listed, and the more listeners will see the&nbsp;show.</p>
<p>And make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-9969-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-01.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-01.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-01.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S&nbsp;RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>You can now embed playable MS-DOS games inside tweets</h3>
<p>Earlier this year, the Internet Archive added roughly <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Farchive.org%2Fdetails%2Fsoftwarelibrary_msdos_games%26tab%3Dcollection&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNF_I9w3Ka6yoFsvfYIUcO27Ep4P8w">2,400 MS-DOS games to their digital archive that are playable through your web browser</a>&nbsp;on their site, Archive.org. But if you?re too scared to leave Twitter to check this out, never fear. The folks at Wired discovered this week that you can <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wired.com%2F2015%2F04%2Fembed-games-into-tweets%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFDEVcY7zZYUSwZ25qRCYuZhKsR8w">embed the games inside of tweets</a>&nbsp;and play them right from those tweets.</p>
<p>So, you can now get your Oregon Trail, Sim City or Wolfenstein 3D fix from Twitter. Or, you can try out other classic games like the adaptation of the 1991 Hulk Hogan cinematic masterpiece <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Farchive.org%2Fdetails%2Fmsdos_Suburban_Commando_1993&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFmxb8aGo-5rR7cKBu4ZqyEQHYjFg">Suburban Commando</a>&nbsp;(just kidding, you should never do that).</p>
<h3>Google announces cellular data network, which is actually two networks.</h3>
<p>Google has <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Fgadgets%2F2015%2F04%2F22%2Fhow-googles-project-fi-pricing-stacks-up-to-the-competition%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEIfE5LtjuX1Y_5Bd4Nvlx3TETCsQ">officially announced</a>&nbsp;its long-rumored cellular data network: its name is ProjectFi. As anticipated it is an MVNO network, which means that Google is ?renting? time on someone else?s network like many other small cellular companies. The differences is that Google is renting not from one other network, but two: Sprint &amp; T-mobile, as well as WiFi. When you are on a ProjectFi connection your phone will seamlessly switch to whichever one of those networks is strongest. ProjectFi?s offers a very straightforward billing structure which will be appealing to some. It also will let you ?bank? unused minutes each month. And it offers promises of more innovations to come. The catch? Right now it is only offered for a single phone: the Nexus 6, and there is no LTE high speed service.</p>
<h3>Robot car movers</h3>
<p>The <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fgizmodo.com%2Fthis-gang-of-flat-robots-can-autonomously-steal-or-par-1700680911&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNG_oJhAxLaHutxwvtz7d5M95pfVzQ">robots are coming to steal your car</a>, or just move it out of the way. Gizmodo shared a story that researchers in Europe have created AVERT, the Autonomous Vehicle Emergency Recovery Tool. It is a system of robots that look like something out of Battle Bots. They are flat pieces of steel with rotors on the ends of them. Eight of them work together to pick up your cars tires and wheel it away. They only lift the car about an inch off the ground, but that&rsquo;s all they need to move it out of the way. The idea is that the robots can easily move a car parked in a tight spot if there is a bomb in a nearby car. They could also be used to move an illegally parked car or a car that is blocking emergency services. Or, when the robots become sentient, they will likely start a car robbing career.</p>
<h3>Man puts 8 bullets in his Dell desktop, tells police it was worth the ticket.</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Ftech-policy%2F2015%2F04%2F22%2Fman-puts-8-bullets-in-his-dell-tells-police-its-worth-the-ticket%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHxdiaHiFSLGSpGwTy-gaDAVGHevw">Police say that at 7 PM on a Monday, Lucas Hinch, the owner of a homeopathic herb store in Colorado Springs, Colorado, took his Dell XPS 410 out into an alley behind the store and unloaded eight bullets into it with a 9mm pistol</a>. Hinch was ticketed for discharging a gun within city limits.</p>
<p>Lynch told the Los Angeles Times, which interviewed him, that the machine kept giving him the blue screen of death and that he had ?had enough.? He said that the shooting was ?definitely premeditated? and that he had no regrets. He reportedly told officers he did not know he was breaking the law in discharging his weapon.</p>
<h3>Microsoft unveils Edge browser</h3>
<p>During the opening keynote of their Microsoft Build developers conference this week, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.pcmag.com%2Farticle2%2F0%2C2817%2C2483459%2C00.asp&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGk4Rk3f2KJLqhuVRuTqKtqFY2aGw">Microsoft unveiled the successor to their Internet Explorer browser (which they recently announced was ending).</a></p>
<p>The new browser, now called Edge (formerly Project Spartan), is said to be faster and more modern and will be a universal app across all Windows devices. Features will include, among others, extensions like you find for Chrome and Firefox, integration of Microsoft?s Cortana virtual assistant to help you search for things, reading mode (which removes everything from a page except for the text), and an annotation tool (which lets you draw on a webpage, take a picture of it and share that picture).</p>
<p>The new browser will not be in the initial release of Windows 10 this year, but will be included in a later update. Windows 10 will be shipped with Internet Explorer 11 for legacy compatibility, so you will have one last chance to use everyone?s favorite browser before it goes softly into that good night.</p>
<h3>Tired of remember your passwords? Try swallowing them instead?</h3>
<p>In a recent interview with The Wall Street Journal, Paypal?s global head of developer advocacy, Jonathan Leblanc, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.motherjones.com%2Fkevin-drum%2F2015%2F04%2Fswallowing-passwords-biometric-paypal-leblanc&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEVa64GMFTci-ARVRnBbhwV4EHOrQ">said that passwords might soon be available as ?embeddable, injectable and ingestible devices.?</a>&nbsp;Mr. Leblanc said that in the near future thin silicon chips might be embedded under our skin or capsules might detect glucose levels to verify that someone is who they say they are.</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal notes, &ldquo;Mr. Leblanc admits that there&rsquo;s still a ways to go before cultural norms catch up with ingestible and injectable ID devices.&rdquo;</p>
<h3>Google files patent for laptop with no spacebar.</h3>
<p>Google already kicked the CAPS-LOCK key to the curb with its Chromebooks and <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fqz.com%2F393209%2Fgoogle-wants-to-do-away-with-space-bars%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEFH21pgG7RnHwMAN_uw08JgYP6QQ">now it appears it may be preparing to do the same thing to the spacebar</a>. In a patent filed this week the company outlines a design where the spacebar is replaced by an extended trackpad. Sensors would determine whether the user wants the top of the trackpad to be treated as a spacebar or a mouse. Google told Quartz, who broke the story, that some patents get turned into products and some don?t, so only time will tell whether we will see a spacebar-free Chromebook.</p>
<h3>Apple Watch &ndash; Tattoo-gate</h3>
<p>Reports are coming in on Twitter and Reddit that people with tattoos on their wrists may have difficulty using their new Apple watches. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.imore.com%2Fheres-why-apple-watch-does-not-play-nice-with-some-tattoos&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHxa84tcqtJg-bjrlAehBVvopWbQQ">iMore.com looked into it and confirmed the reports</a>. The heart sensor detects pulse by flashing an LED light on your skin and senses the reflection. The problem is when you have a tattoo the reflection is distorted by the ink. Your mileage may vary, but for some folks it is really annoying. The Apple Watch uses the heart sensor to detect if you are wearing the watch, so when it doesn&rsquo;t sense your heart rate, it forces you to re-enter your pin number.</p>
<h3>Apple Watch &ndash; Scratch-gate</h3>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t like scratches, you probably shouldn&rsquo;t get the stainless steel Apple watch. A lot of folks are reporting on social media that their steel <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fmashable.com%2F2015%2F04%2F27%2Fapple-watch-stainless-steel-scratches%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNH6Stlu5qbDBdG14wctYlZbAEg-WQ">Apple watches are already scratched up</a>. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2F9to5mac.com%2F2015%2F04%2F26%2Fapple-watch-fix-scratches%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGyOd9RtCgjPs8gKhLvKrKICr5diQ">9to5Mac.com has an easy fix. Just buff it, like every other stainless steel watch in </a><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2F9to5mac.com%2F2015%2F04%2F26%2Fapple-watch-fix-scratches%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGyOd9RtCgjPs8gKhLvKrKICr5diQ">existence</a><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2F9to5mac.com%2F2015%2F04%2F26%2Fapple-watch-fix-scratches%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGyOd9RtCgjPs8gKhLvKrKICr5diQ">.</a>&nbsp;Or, get the aluminum model, which is actually harder than the steel version.</p>
<h3>Apple Watch &ndash; Tap-gate</h3>
<p>Now for the first, actual, real problem with the Apple watch. According to the Wall Street Journal, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wsj.com%2Farticles%2Fapple-watch-faulty-taptic-engine-slows-roll-out-1430339460&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNG_NZhwUZRibof94tZ5XtkKmUiqhA">Apple has found a major defect in the taptic engine</a>&nbsp;in the watches. The taptic engine is the feature that causes the watch to vibrate or tap the wearer. It was a pretty groundbreaking feature because it models sounds so a tweet &ldquo;feels&rdquo; like a tweet, and a tap feels like a tap. Two companies built the taptic engines, but one of the suppliers has produced faulty engines. The Verge says that Daring Fireball&rsquo;s John Gruber received an Apple Watch that had a taptic engine that didn&rsquo;t work.</p>
<h1>OUTRO</h1>
<p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback@deemable.com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. deemable.com/reddit will take you there</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, I&rsquo;m Sean Birch and this is Deemable Tech. Thanks for listening.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#81 Don't Call It A Gate!" data-link="/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#81 Don't Call It A Gate!" data-link="/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/05/81-dont-call-it-a-gate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-01.mp3" length="32491838" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#80 The Smartphone Wars Turn Deadly</title>
		<link>/2015/04/80-the-smartphone-wars-turn-deadly/</link>
		<comments>/2015/04/80-the-smartphone-wars-turn-deadly/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 16:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gigabit Pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York City]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One World Trade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time Warner Cable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9952</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/04/3905907831_cff11a8808_b-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="iPhone vs Android" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week, Comcast can&#8217;t keep itself out of the news. First, Comcast&#160;announces that it is&#160;bringing the fastest Interwebs in the country to Jacksonville (WOOT!) and other cities in Florida. Then, the FCC and the Justice Department rain on Comcast&#8217;s&#160;parade and <a href="/2015/04/80-the-smartphone-wars-turn-deadly/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/04/80-the-smartphone-wars-turn-deadly/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/04/3905907831_cff11a8808_b-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="iPhone vs Android" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2015/04/3905907831_cff11a8808_b.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright wp-image-9959 size-medium" src="//media/2015/04/3905907831_cff11a8808_b-300x200.jpg"  alt="iPhone vs Android" width="300" height="200"></a>This week, Comcast can&rsquo;t keep itself out of the news. First, Comcast&nbsp;announces that it is&nbsp;bringing the fastest Interwebs in the country to Jacksonville (WOOT!) and other cities in Florida. Then, the FCC and the Justice Department rain on Comcast&rsquo;s&nbsp;parade and lets&nbsp;it know they are not going to let it merge with Time Warner Cable. In other news, a paranoid dad flew a drone to school with his daughter, and two guys took the iPhone/Android fight way too far.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="//media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="//media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>If you haven?t <a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/ca/podcast/deemable-tech-wjct/id540595466?mt=2" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">subscribed to Deemable Tech</a> yet, get on it! Subscribe to <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">Deemable Tech&nbsp;in iTunes</a>,&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>or&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech Podcast!" href="http://dmbl.co/pod">subscribe to the show in another podcast reader</a>. Make sure to leave a review on iTunes and Stitcher. The more reviews posted,&nbsp;the higher Deemable Tech will&nbsp;be listed, and the more listeners will see the&nbsp;show.</p>
<p>And make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-9952-2" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/04/DeemableTech_2015-04-24.mp3?_=2"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/04/DeemableTech_2015-04-24.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/04/DeemableTech_2015-04-24.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S&nbsp;RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>Comcast Gigabit Pro</h3>
<p>People in Jacksonville and some other towns in Florida are going to be pretty excited next month. In a story Jessica Palombo contributed to Deemable.com, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2F2015%2F04%2Fcomcast-to-begin-offering-floridians-fastest-internet-in-the-country%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGVubtVCY6Eqqpd5B_PrGjLtXzZfA">Comcast is bringing the fastest fiber optic Internet service in the country</a>&nbsp;to a few cities in Florida, including our own fair town. The service, which is called Gigabit Pro, will actually have 2 Gbps download and upload speeds ? more than twice the speed of Google Fiber.</p>
<p>However, Comcast would not give a price for the new service. The next fastest service from Comcast is Extreme 505, which runs up to 505 Mbps up and down, and costs over $400 a month with taxes and fees.</p>
<h3>Comcast Drops Its Bid to Merge With Time Warner Cable</h3>
<p>Speaking of Comcast, earlier this week it was looking pretty &nbsp;looked bad for its merger with Time Warner Cable. According to Bloomberg, the <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.bloomberg.com%2Fnews%2Farticles%2F2015-04-17%2Fu-s-antitrust-lawyers-said-to-be-leaning-against-comcast-merger&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFxhG6OrQAnZUGZxB2U32vhPKpqPw">Justice Department&rsquo;s antitrust department was going to recommend blocking the merger</a>. And, the FCC was not negotiating the terms of the deal with Comcast, which made it look even less likely that it was going to go through.</p>
<p>But now, ?people with knowledge of the matter? have told Bloomberg that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.bloomberg.com%2Fnews%2Farticles%2F2015-04-23%2Fcomcast-said-planning-to-withdraw-offer-for-time-warner-cable&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGpwgeroBsNi-Il6dH68GJLDEdxDA">Comcast is backing out of the merger</a>. There was supposed to be a board meeting Thursday. And an official &nbsp;announcement will probably come Friday.</p>
<p>As the Verge pointed out in an editorial, throughout this whole process, Comcast has never answered this simple question: <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2015%2F4%2F22%2F8470873%2Fcomcast-twc-defense&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGjzkjudzu8zRpTX8T7KqYI5Ege2w">Why not compete?</a></p>
<h3>Verizon to offer custom pay TV packages, let customers choose monthly programming bundles</h3>
<p>And while we?re on the subject of Internet and TV providers, in move that is one small step closer to a la carte cable TV, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.reuters.com%2Farticle%2F2015%2F04%2F17%2Fverizon-fios-idUSL2N0XD36J20150417&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNE6PXxsPut3_sN_10ePy8zCVmVEfg">Verizon recently announced that they are rolling out a new pay TV service</a>&nbsp;that will let customers choose from channel bundles that they change monthly.</p>
<p>These Verizon FiOS ?Custom TV? packages will start at 65 dollars a month for broadband service, 36 fixed basic cable channels, and two genre-based channel packs that customers can swap or unsubscribe from after a month. You can also add packs for an extra 10 dollars. Verizon has seven of these packs to choose from, including sports and children?s programming.</p>
<p>Verizon says they are going after customers who want something in between giant, fully loaded cable packages and cheaper basic packages offered by their competitors.</p>
<h3>After &ldquo;Drone Dad&rdquo; follows his daughter to school, DJI Phantom 2 grounded</h3>
<p>Tennessee father Chris Early?s daughter decided she wanted to walk to the school bus by herself so he did what any tech-inclined father would do: <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Fgadgets%2F2015%2F04%2Fafter-drone-dad-follows-his-daughter-to-school-dji-phantom-2-grounded%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGXD6Y8ND_hBoQlLnXVuJ7a67pTjQ">he followed her with a drone</a>.</p>
<p>The drone was a model known as a DJI Phantom 2 which has a high def video camera mounted on it. Early followed his daughter with the drone. A local news station caught wind of this and the story went nationwide. Chris Early has been called ?overprotective?, ?the world?s most embarrassing father? and &lsquo;drone dad&rsquo;. As a result of all the attention he says he has grounded the drone for now.</p>
<h3>One World Trade Center Elevator Shows 515 Years Of New York City</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2F2015%2F04%2Fbreathtaking-one-world-trade-center-elevator-shows-515-years-of-new-york-city%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEk8BcDdWQz0n620aPnWXkM9Ovu0g">One World Trade Center has added an elevator that displays 515 years of New York City history in 50 seconds</a>.</p>
<p>The New York Times covered this story, but I wrote an article about it for Deemable.com.</p>
<p>While they haven?t developed time travel, the engineers and designers behind the elevators that takes guests to the observatory at the very top of One World Trade Center in New York City have come pretty close. When you board the elevators, you will see a panoramic view of New York City rising out of the underground in the 1500s all the way up through time to the 102nd floor today.</p>
<p>The elevator uses nine 75-inch screens to create the illusion that it is a glass-walled elevator traveling through time.</p>
<p>Along the way, you&rsquo;ll see the arrival of the Europeans, the Revolution and the rise of the skyscrapers. Inevitably, as time travels through the late-1900s, one of the Twin Towers enters your sight and just as quickly fades away as the 2000s begin. It is a touching, beautiful memorial to the history of the site. You can see The New York Times video of the elevator on our website at Deemable.com</p>
<h3>YouTube celebrates 10 year anniversary</h3>
<p>This week marks the <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.yahoo.com%2Ftech%2Fs%2Fyoutube-celebrates-10-anniversary-105136844.html&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHE6bPIHeiXJiT-PjpfPJtZbhFuzw">10 year anniversary of the first video being uploaded to YouTube</a>.</p>
<p>On April 23 2005, YouTube co-founder Jawed Karim posted a 19 second clip of elephants at the zoo titled &ldquo;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jNQXAC9IVRw">Me at the zoo</a>.&rdquo; &nbsp;In it, Karim discusses the elephants&rsquo; &ldquo;really, really, really long trunks&rdquo; and, well, that&rsquo;s all. Pretty tame compared to what you can find on YouTube today.</p>
<p>About a year after this video was posted, Google acquired YouTube for $1.6 billion.</p>
<p>According to reports, YouTube will mark the anniversary with a month-long celebration starting next week.</p>
<h3>Skycure Hack Can Use Wifi To Disable iOS Devices</h3>
<p>A research firm called Skycure reported that it has developed a hack based around a bug in iOS that could allow it to <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fmashable.com%2F2015%2F04%2F23%2Fhack-nearby-ios-devices%2F%3Futm_cid%3Dmash-com-fb-main-link&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEBwoGMoQQX1B7xKeTEhVRKLoCCdw">disable all nearby iOS devices using a wifi router</a>. The wifi router has to be configured in a specific way. It will then cause any device connected to it to keep crashing and rebooting in an endless loop. It can be combined with another hack that forces iOS devices to connect to that network. Essentially the only way to escape the endless cycle of rebooting would be to get out of range of the router.</p>
<p>Skycure has not publicly released technical specifications for the bug it used to create the hack to give Apple time to patch it.</p>
<h3>Argument Over Which Smartphone Is Better Turns Deadly</h3>
<p>Police in Tulsa, OK apprehended a man staggering around a parking lot late at night cut up and covered in blood. The man reported to them that he had been in a fight with his roommate over <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2015/04/android-versus-iphone-debate-escalates-into-stabbing-and-car-theft/" target="_blank">which smartphone was better &ndash; the iPhone or the new Samsung Galaxy</a>. iPhone versus Android fights can get heated, but most stop short of physical conflict. The man reported that he and his roommate had been drinking and wound up stabbing each other with broken beer bottles. Both were admitted to the hospital and are expected to make a full recovery. No word on whether either man was arrested or whether either had his mind changed about his preferred choice of phone.</p>
<h3>How many tabs does it take to get to the center of a Tootsie Pop?</h3>
<p>Redditor Peanut Butter Shudder suggested an answer to Ray&rsquo;s question. Last week during Shower Thoughts, Ray said he didn&rsquo;t know how many tabs he had ever opened in his life. Peanut Butter Shudder mentioned <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.tabforacause.org%2F%3Fr%3D11049744&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFxt1WhtHrRjahBv7lwele8dNCDOA">Tab for a Cause</a>&nbsp;on our reddit page (reddit.com/r/deemable) Tab for a Cause apparently tracks how many tabs you open and it has a bit of slacktivism built into it. If you install the browser extension, you&rsquo;ll raise money for charities simply by browsing the internet. Heck, why not?</p>
<h3>Who had the best segue?</h3>
<p>Vote! Send us an&nbsp;email to feedback at deemable dot com or leave us a voicemail at&nbsp;1-888-972-9868.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Photo credit: <a href="https://flic.kr/p/6X9Njt" target="_blank">iPhone vs Android</a>&nbsp;by <a href="http://nrkbeta.no/" rel="nofollow" data-rapid_p="27">nrkbeta.no</a> is licensed under&nbsp;<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/no/" rel="nofollow" data-rapid_p="28">Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0</a>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#80 The Smartphone Wars Turn Deadly" data-link="/2015/04/80-the-smartphone-wars-turn-deadly/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#80 The Smartphone Wars Turn Deadly" data-link="/2015/04/80-the-smartphone-wars-turn-deadly/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/04/80-the-smartphone-wars-turn-deadly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/04/DeemableTech_2015-04-24.mp3" length="31206644" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#76 Oh, Sweet Internet Explorer, Go Gently Into That Good Night &#8211; OR &#8211; Parting With Bing Is Such Sweet Sorrow</title>
		<link>/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/</link>
		<comments>/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 00:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 8.1]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9817</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/03/InternetExplorerVoodooDoll-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Photo Credit: Internet Explorer, a web developers menace by Jorgen Kesseler is used under CC BY-SA 2.0." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week the guys are elated about the death of Internet Explorer, the low, low price of free to upgrade to&#160;Windows 10, (even if you never paid for Windows 7 or 8) and&#160;Mario, Zelda and the gang are finally coming <a href="/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/03/InternetExplorerVoodooDoll-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Photo Credit: Internet Explorer, a web developers menace by Jorgen Kesseler is used under CC BY-SA 2.0." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-9819 size-large" src="//media/2015/03/InternetExplorerVoodooDoll-1024x768.jpg" alt="Photo Credit: Internet Explorer, a web developers menace by Jorgen Kesseler is used under CC BY-SA 2.0." width="659" height="494"></p>
<p>This week the guys are elated about the death of Internet Explorer, the low, low price of free to upgrade to&nbsp;Windows 10, (even if you never paid for Windows 7 or 8) and&nbsp;Mario, Zelda and the gang are finally coming to mobile phones, but not the way you want them to.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="//media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="//media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>If you haven&rsquo;t <a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/ca/podcast/deemable-tech-wjct/id540595466?mt=2" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">subscribed to Deemable Tech</a> yet, get on it! Subscribe to <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">Deemable Tech&nbsp;in iTunes</a>,&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a> or&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech Podcast!" href="http://dmbl.co/pod">subscribe to the show in another podcast reader</a>. Make sure to leave us a review in iTunes and Stitcher. The more reviews we have the higher we&rsquo;ll be listed, and the more listeners will see our show.</p>
<p>And make sure to&nbsp;share us on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-9817-3" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/DeemableTech_2015-03-20.mp3?_=3"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/DeemableTech_2015-03-20.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/DeemableTech_2015-03-20.mp3</a></audio><h2>This Week&rsquo;s Run Down</h2>
<h3>Windows 10 is free for everybody!</h3>
<p>So, you may have heard of the latest version of Windows that Microsoft is working on releasing later this summer. If you haven&rsquo;t, it&rsquo;s called Windows 10. If you&rsquo;re wondering why it&rsquo;s called Windows 10 instead of&hellip; you know&hellip; Windows 9, it&rsquo;s because of a little coding shortcut where programmers referred to Windows 95 and Windows 98 as &ndash; you guessed it&nbsp;&ndash;&nbsp;&ldquo;Windows 9.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Well, it turns out that <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/3/18/8241023/windows-10-free-for-software-pirates">Windows 10 is going to be FREE for everyone</a>, well almost everyone.</p>
<p>Terry Myerson, Microsoft&rsquo;s Windows chief to Reuters &ldquo;We are upgrading all qualified PCs, genuine and non-genuine, to Windows 10&rdquo;</p>
<p>So that means, as long as you have a computer running Windows 7 or Window 8 or 8.1 you can install 10 on your computer, at no charge, even if you stole the version that&rsquo;s on your computer right now.</p>
<h3>The Death of Internet Explorer</h3>
<p>Microsoft confirmed this week that Internet Explorer will not be the primary web browser in Windows 10. Yes, the venerable <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/3/17/8230631/microsoft-is-killing-off-the-internet-explorer-brand">Internet Explorer, which has been a part of Windows since Windows 95, is being put out to pasture</a>. It will still ship with the next version of Microsoft&rsquo;s operating system for backwards compatibility reasons, but a new browser with the codename Project Spartan will be Microsoft&rsquo;s flagship browser. Project Spartan&rsquo;s real name has not been released yet but Microsoft says that it will not use the Internet Explorer branding.</p>
<h3>Nintendo to develop mobile games</h3>
<p>After years of speculation, <a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/03/nintendo-dena-mobile/">Nintendo is moving into the mobile game market</a>. They announced this week that they have partnered with Japanese mobile game giant DeNA to &ldquo;develop and operate new game apps based on Nintendo&rsquo;s intellectual property, including its iconic game characters, for smart devices.&rdquo;</p>
<p>They were quick to point out that their primary focus will still be their game consoles like the Wii U and 3DS, and that these new mobile apps are intended to complement, not replace, those systems. In the same announcement, Nintendo president Satoru Iwata said that a new console codenamed NX is development.</p>
<p>Unfortunately for those of us hoping this means we&rsquo;ll be able to play classic Mario or Zelda games on our devices, Iwata also said that Nintendo&rsquo;s plans do not include direct ports of console games. He cited differences between dedicated controllers and touchscreens as the reason.</p>
<p>&mdash;-</p>
<p>If you have a comment, contact us at feedback at deemable.com or leave us a voicemail at 1-888-972-9868.</p>
<p>Help us decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story. Or vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Tech on Reddit" href="http://reddit.com/r/Deemable" target="_blank">reddit.com/r/Deemable</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Photo Credit: <a href="https://flic.kr/p/9dAWZW">Internet Explorer, a web developers menace</a> by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/verpletterend/">Jorgen Kesseler</a> is used under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/">CC BY-SA 2.0</a>.</em></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#76 Oh, Sweet Internet Explorer, Go Gently Into That Good Night - OR - Parting With Bing Is Such Sweet Sorrow" data-link="/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#76 Oh, Sweet Internet Explorer, Go Gently Into That Good Night - OR - Parting With Bing Is Such Sweet Sorrow" data-link="/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/03/76-oh-sweet-internet-explorer-go-gently-into-that-good-night-or-parting-with-bing-is-such-sweet-sorrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/DeemableTech_2015-03-20.mp3" length="20553128" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Miraya asks, &#8220;How do I use different keyboards on my iPhone?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2014/10/miraya-asks-use-different-keyboards-iphone/</link>
		<comments>/2014/10/miraya-asks-use-different-keyboards-iphone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 21:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 6]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Third-Party Keyboards]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9314</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/10/swype_keyboard_ipad-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="The Swype keyboard running on an iPad with iOS 8. Image credit: Swype" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Q: I just got an iPhone 6. I heard about the new keyboards in i0S 8, but I can&#8217;t figure out how to use them. How do I get them installed and what do they do? A: iOS 8, the <a href="/2014/10/miraya-asks-use-different-keyboards-iphone/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2014/10/miraya-asks-use-different-keyboards-iphone/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/10/swype_keyboard_ipad-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="The Swype keyboard running on an iPad with iOS 8. Image credit: Swype" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><script id="prx-p132283-embed" src="http://www.prx.org/p/132283/embed.js?size=small"></script></p>
<p><strong>Q: </strong>I just got an iPhone 6. I heard about the new keyboards in i0S 8, but I can&rsquo;t figure out how to use them. How do I get them installed and what do they do?<span id="more-9314"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_9316" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2014/10/swype_keyboard_ipad.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-9316" src="//media/2014/10/swype_keyboard_ipad-225x300.jpg"  alt="The Swype keyboard running on an iPad with iOS 8. Image credit: Swype" width="300" height="400"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Swype keyboard running on an iPad with iOS 8. Image credit: Swype</p></div>
<p><strong>A: </strong>iOS 8, the operating system that comes standard with the iPhone 6 and 6 Plus, added the ability to install third-party keyboards. These let you type on your phone or tablet in a way that the company that made it didn&rsquo;t originally design. For instance, instead of tapping individual keys, some of them let you type by drawing continuous lines from one letter to another. This style of typing was originally popularized by the Swype keyboard.</p>
<p>Third-party keyboards have been available on Android phones for several years, but iOS 8 is the first operating system to support them on iPhones.</p>
<p>To install third-party keyboards on the iPhone, you&rsquo;ll first need to find the one you want in the Apple App Store and download it. Then, you&rsquo;ll open the Settings app, look for &ldquo;Keyboards&rdquo; under the &ldquo;General&rdquo; menu, and tap &ldquo;Add New Keyboard&rdquo; and select the one you just downloaded. Then, tap the name of the keyboard again, and hit the &ldquo;Allow Full Access&rdquo; switch. Almost every iOS keyboard app will also explain these steps when you open the app.</p>
<p>Once you have the keyboards installed, you can switch between them while typing by tapping the globe icon in the bottom left corner of the keyboard.</p>
<p>Third-party keyboards are basically like any apps on Android &ndash; you download them and they automatically install. You can switch keyboards under the main settings on the device, under the &ldquo;Language and Input&rdquo; menu. There will be a list of all your installed keyboards and you can swap between them there.</p>
<p>We have been testing out a few third-party keyboards on iOS 8 since it was released. Swipe-to-type keyboards like Swype and Swiftkey definitely make typing a lot faster, but one of our favorites is called Fleksy. This keyboard basically lets you type as sloppy as you want, and as long as you tap somewhere near where the key is the keyboard will figure out what you&rsquo;re trying to type.</p>
<p>Try some of them out, Miraya, and remember: the best third-part keyboard is the one you feel most comfortable typing on.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title='Miraya asks, "How do I use different keyboards on my iPhone?"' data-link="/2014/10/miraya-asks-use-different-keyboards-iphone/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title='Miraya asks, "How do I use different keyboards on my iPhone?"' data-link="/2014/10/miraya-asks-use-different-keyboards-iphone/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/10/miraya-asks-use-different-keyboards-iphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trent asks, &#8220;How do I wipe my smartphone?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2014/07/trent-asks-wipe-smartphone/</link>
		<comments>/2014/07/trent-asks-wipe-smartphone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 10:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9022</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/07/samsung-galaxy-s5-7193-041-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Josh Miller / CNET" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Q: I am giving my old phone to a friend. How do I make sure I&#8217;ve gotten all my private data off it first? A: That&#8217;s a great question, Trent, and one that everyone who owns a smartphone probably needs <a href="/2014/07/trent-asks-wipe-smartphone/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2014/07/trent-asks-wipe-smartphone/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/07/samsung-galaxy-s5-7193-041-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Josh Miller / CNET" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><script id="prx-p123927-embed" src="http://www.prx.org/p/123927/embed.js?size=small"></script></p>
<p><strong>Q: </strong>I am giving my old phone to a friend. How do I make sure I&rsquo;ve gotten all my private data off it first?<span id="more-9022"></span></p>
<p><strong>A: </strong>That&rsquo;s a great question, Trent, and one that everyone who owns a smartphone probably needs to know the answer to. Our smartphones hold all kinds of personal data, like our contact list, browser history and even our credit card information. Before you give your phone to someone, exchange it for a different model or even throw it away, you need to make sure you wipe all of this information off of it first.</p>
<div id="attachment_9023" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2014/07/samsung-galaxy-s5-7193-041.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-9023" src="//media/2014/07/samsung-galaxy-s5-7193-041-300x168.jpg"  alt="Image credit: Josh Miller / CNET" width="300" height="168"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: Josh Miller / CNET</p></div>
<p>Fortunately, every smartphone comes with the ability to reset it to what the manufacturers refer to as &ldquo;factory settings&rdquo;. This wipes the device completely, and turns it into a blank slate just like the day you bought it. Of course, you need to make sure you perform a full backup of your phone before you even think about wiping it.</p>
<p>To do a factory reset on an iPhone, you&rsquo;ll need to open the &ldquo;Settings&rdquo; app, tap &ldquo;General&rdquo; and find the &ldquo;Reset&rdquo; button at the bottom of that screen. Tap this and you&rsquo;ll see a few options including &ldquo;Erase All Content and Settings,&rdquo; which is the one you want. If you tap this, a message will pop up asking you to confirm that you really want to do this because it will erase everything. Hit yes and the reset begins.</p>
<p>The process for resetting Android phones can differ from model to model, but most of them are pretty similar. For example, to wipe a Samsung Galaxy smartphone, you would just go to the &ldquo;Settings&rdquo; menu, tap &ldquo;Backup and Reset&rdquo; and hit the &ldquo;Factory Data Reset&rdquo; option. Be sure to read through the manual of your specific smartphone to find the directions.</p>
<p>Your phone will take a minute or two to reset to factory settings. Once it&rsquo;s done, it should be just like you&rsquo;re turning it on for the first time. Now you can give away your phone without worrying about your private information falling into the wrong hands.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s one more thing we should mention if your smartphone has a removable SD card. Resetting the phone to factory settings will not erase the data on that card, so you&rsquo;ll need to erase the files off of it separately. If your phone comes with a file manager app, you can do it through that. You can also connect your phone to your computer, open the SD card and drag the files to the trash. Or you can keep it simple and just remove the SD card from the phone.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title='Trent asks, "How do I wipe my smartphone?"' data-link="/2014/07/trent-asks-wipe-smartphone/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title='Trent asks, "How do I wipe my smartphone?"' data-link="/2014/07/trent-asks-wipe-smartphone/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/07/trent-asks-wipe-smartphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amanda asks, &#8220;How can I restrict in-app purchases on my iPad?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2014/06/amanda-asks-can-restrict-app-purchases-ipad/</link>
		<comments>/2014/06/amanda-asks-can-restrict-app-purchases-ipad/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 19:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[in-app purchases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parental controls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restrictions]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8862</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/06/child_ipad-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Brad Flickinger / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Q: Our family recently got our first iPad. We want the kids to be allowed to use it, but I am worried that they will get into trouble with it. Many of the games on the iPad ask you to <a href="/2014/06/amanda-asks-can-restrict-app-purchases-ipad/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2014/06/amanda-asks-can-restrict-app-purchases-ipad/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/06/child_ipad-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Brad Flickinger / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><script id="prx-p121195-embed" src="http://www.prx.org/p/121195/embed.js?size=small"></script></p>
<p><strong>Q: </strong>Our family recently got our first iPad. We want the kids to be allowed to use it, but I am worried that they will get into trouble with it. Many of the games on the iPad ask you to buy things. I don&rsquo;t want my kids running up a big credit card bill! Is there a way to stop this from happening?<span id="more-8862"></span></p>
<p><strong>A:</strong> Great question, Amanda. In-app purchases are an issue with smartphones and tablets that not nearly enough parents are aware of. In fact, we&rsquo;ve heard news stories about kids accidentally running up thousands of dollars in charges in their favorite mobile game. Fortunately, iPhones and iPads both come with built-in tools that allow parents to control what their kids are getting into.</p>
<div id="attachment_8863" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2014/06/child_ipad.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-8863 size-medium" src="//media/2014/06/child_ipad-300x220.jpg"  alt="Image credit: Brad Flickinger / Flickr" width="300" height="220"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: Brad Flickinger / Flickr</p></div>
<p>Open the Settings icon on your iPad, and look for &ldquo;Restrictions&rdquo; under &ldquo;General&rdquo;. Tap &ldquo;enable restrictions&rdquo; and you&rsquo;ll be asked to create a passcode. Be sure to use a different passcode than the one you use to lock your device, since your kids probably already know that code.</p>
<p>After you&rsquo;ve created the passcode, you&rsquo;ll see a list of features you can restrict access to, including in-app purchases, Safari and even the camera. Tap the button next to &ldquo;in-app purchases&rdquo; and any other feature you want to be restricted (that button will be green when the feature isn&rsquo;t restricted, and white when the restriction is on). This will turn off these features.</p>
<p>Now keep in mind, Amanda, that when <em>you</em> enter that passcode to make an in-app purchase, the restriction will be turned off for 15 minutes by default. If you&rsquo;re worried that you might put down your iPad and one of your kids might rush over and start buying things within that window, you can set it to ask for the passcode every single time. Go back to the &ldquo;Restrictions&rdquo; screen, re-enter your code and scroll down to the option that says &ldquo;Require password&rdquo;. Tap that and select &ldquo;Immediately&rdquo;. Now the iPad will require the passcode every time anyone tries to make an in-app purchase.</p>
<p>Android devices also have the power to restrict in-app purchases. On your Android tablet or smartphone, open the Play Store (the app you use to download other apps) and go to the settings menu. There you will see an option that says &ldquo;Use password to restrict purchases&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Android doesn&rsquo;t have as many built-in parental control features as iOS does, but there are a ton of great parental control apps out there. You can find them by searching &ldquo;parental controls&rdquo; in the Play Store.</p>
<p>Whether you&rsquo;ve got a table or a smartphone, iOS or Android, there are a many easy-to-use options to allow your family to safely enjoy their new toy.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title='Amanda asks, "How can I restrict in-app purchases on my iPad?"' data-link="/2014/06/amanda-asks-can-restrict-app-purchases-ipad/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title='Amanda asks, "How can I restrict in-app purchases on my iPad?"' data-link="/2014/06/amanda-asks-can-restrict-app-purchases-ipad/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/06/amanda-asks-can-restrict-app-purchases-ipad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opinion: Seeing Through Apple&#8217;s &#8220;New&#8221; iPhone 5c Illusion</title>
		<link>/2013/09/opinion-seeing-apples-new-iphone-5c-illusion/</link>
		<comments>/2013/09/opinion-seeing-apples-new-iphone-5c-illusion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 19:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Syndicated]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 5C]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8279</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/repost-us-7376473-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="repost-us-image-7376473" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />The iPhone 5 Clad In Plastic, Same Price I trust that most of you have already caught a ton of the news, previews, early reviews, and analysis concerning the new iPhones. So I’ll spare you the ad nauseam re-hash of the facts, and cut straight to the&#8230;<p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/09/opinion-seeing-apples-new-iphone-5c-illusion/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/repost-us-7376473-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="repost-us-image-7376473" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div class="rpuEmbedCode">
<div class="rpuArticle rpuRepost-5AA7D95681DEC8CFA5BBB2F7E7541672-top rpuNoTitle" style="margin:0;padding:0;">
<script src="https://1.rp-api.com/rjs/repost-article.js?3" type="text/javascript" data-cfasync="false"></script><a href="http://s.tt/1LWNf" class="rpuThumb" rel="norewrite"><img src="//img.1.rp-api.com/thumb/7376473" style="float:left;margin-right:10px;"></a><a href="http://s.tt/1LWNf" class="rpuTitle" rel="norewrite"><strong>Opinion: Seeing Through Apple&rsquo;s &ldquo;New&rdquo; iPhone 5c Illusion</strong></a> (via <a href="http://s.tt/1LWNf" class="rpuHost" rel="norewrite">Tom&rsquo;s Hardware</a>)
<p class="rpuSnip">
The iPhone 5 Clad In Plastic, Same Price I trust that most of you have already caught a ton of the news, previews, early reviews, and analysis concerning the new iPhones. So I?ll spare you the ad nauseam re-hash of the facts, and cut straight to the&hellip;
</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><!-- put the "tease", "jump" or "more" break here --><br></p><hr id="system-readmore" style="display: none;"><span id="more-8279"></span><!--break--><br><hr class="at-page-break" style="display: none;"><div class="rpuEmbedCode">
<div class="rpuArticle rpuRepostMain rpuRepost-5AA7D95681DEC8CFA5BBB2F7E7541672-bottom" style="display:none;">&nbsp;</div>
<div style="display: none;"><!-- How to customize this embed: http://www.repost.us/article-preview/hash/5aa7d95681dec8cfa5bbb2f7e7541672 --></div>
</div>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Opinion: Seeing Through Apple's &quot;New&quot; iPhone 5c Illusion" data-link="/2013/09/opinion-seeing-apples-new-iphone-5c-illusion/" data-summary="The iPhone 5 Clad In Plastic, Same Price I trust that most of you have already caught a ton of the news, previews, early reviews, and analysis concerning the new iPhones. So I?ll spare you the ad nauseam re-hash of the facts, and cut straight to the&amp;hellip;"></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Opinion: Seeing Through Apple's &quot;New&quot; iPhone 5c Illusion" data-link="/2013/09/opinion-seeing-apples-new-iphone-5c-illusion/" data-summary="The iPhone 5 Clad In Plastic, Same Price I trust that most of you have already caught a ton of the news, previews, early reviews, and analysis concerning the new iPhones. So I?ll spare you the ad nauseam re-hash of the facts, and cut straight to the&amp;hellip;"></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/09/opinion-seeing-apples-new-iphone-5c-illusion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apps Crashing? You May Want to Wait on iOS 7 Upgrade</title>
		<link>/2013/09/apps-crashing-may-want-wait-ios-7-upgrade/</link>
		<comments>/2013/09/apps-crashing-may-want-wait-ios-7-upgrade/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 14:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian P. Rubin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upgrade iOS]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8254</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/repost-us-7260131-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="You Might Want to Wait Before Upgrading to iOS 7" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Anytime an operating system gets an update—be it for a mobile phone or a full-on computer—some things are bound do get a little wonky. Sure, the new version of the OS may promise all kinds of improvements, but between unexpected issues and older applications not working with the newest update&#8230;<p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/09/apps-crashing-may-want-wait-ios-7-upgrade/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/repost-us-7260131-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="You Might Want to Wait Before Upgrading to iOS 7" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div class="rpuEmbedCode">
<div class="rpuArticle rpuRepost-968BB7D47C38F35211501AC4B0586E80-top rpuNoTitle" style="margin:0;padding:0;">
<script src="https://1.rp-api.com/rjs/repost-article.js?3" type="text/javascript" data-cfasync="false"></script><a href="http://s.tt/1LsEK" class="rpuThumb" rel="norewrite"><br><img src="//media/2013/09/repost-us-7260131.jpg" alt="You Might Want to Wait Before Upgrading to iOS 7 " width="650" height="322" class="alignright size-full wp-image-8255"><br></a><a href="http://s.tt/1LsEK" class="rpuTitle" rel="norewrite"><strong>Apps Crashing? You May Want to Wait on iOS 7 Upgrade</strong></a> (via <a href="http://s.tt/1LsEK" class="rpuHost" rel="norewrite">http://www.besttechie.com/</a>)
<p class="rpuSnip">
Anytime an operating system gets an update&ndash;be it for a mobile phone or a full-on computer&ndash;some things are bound do get a little wonky. Sure, the new version of the OS may promise all kinds of improvements, but between unexpected issues and older applications not working with the newest update&hellip;
</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><!-- put the "tease", "jump" or "more" break here --><br></p><hr id="system-readmore" style="display: none;"><span id="more-8254"></span><!--break--><br><hr class="at-page-break" style="display: none;"><div class="rpuEmbedCode">
<div class="rpuArticle rpuRepostMain rpuRepost-968BB7D47C38F35211501AC4B0586E80-bottom" style="display:none;">&nbsp;</div>
<div style="display: none;"><!-- How to customize this embed: http://www.repost.us/article-preview/hash/968bb7d47c38f35211501ac4b0586e80 --></div>
</div>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Apps Crashing? You May Want to Wait on iOS 7 Upgrade" data-link="/2013/09/apps-crashing-may-want-wait-ios-7-upgrade/" data-summary="Anytime an operating system gets an update?be it for a mobile phone or a full-on computer?some things are bound do get a little wonky. Sure, the new version of the OS may promise all kinds of improvements, but between unexpected issues and older applications not working with the newest update&amp;hellip;"></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Apps Crashing? You May Want to Wait on iOS 7 Upgrade" data-link="/2013/09/apps-crashing-may-want-wait-ios-7-upgrade/" data-summary="Anytime an operating system gets an update?be it for a mobile phone or a full-on computer?some things are bound do get a little wonky. Sure, the new version of the OS may promise all kinds of improvements, but between unexpected issues and older applications not working with the newest update&amp;hellip;"></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/09/apps-crashing-may-want-wait-ios-7-upgrade/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple Unveils the iPhone 5C and iPhone 5S</title>
		<link>/2013/09/apple-unveils-iphone-5c-iphone-5s/</link>
		<comments>/2013/09/apple-unveils-iphone-5c-iphone-5s/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 19:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nick Kolakowski]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone 5S Announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone Event]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 5C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 5S]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8231</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/repost-us-7108077-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="repost-us-image-7108077" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Apple has unveiled a pair of new iPhones. Apple CEO Tim Cook took to a California stage Sept. 10 and, after a couple of brief updates on the iTunes Festival (now in its seventh year, this edition featuring musicians such as Justin Timberlake and Katy Perry) and the company’s retail operations, moved onto the meat of the unveiling event. The first big announcement&#8230;<p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/09/apple-unveils-iphone-5c-iphone-5s/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/repost-us-7108077-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="repost-us-image-7108077" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div class="rpuEmbedCode">
<div class="rpuArticle rpuRepost-B59E5BC06C803AD3DC87B3D5A7497EF9-top rpuNoTitle" style="margin:0;padding:0;">
<script src="https://1.rp-api.com/rjs/repost-article.js?3" type="text/javascript" data-cfasync="false"></script><a href="http://s.tt/1KPjh" class="rpuThumb" rel="norewrite"><img src="//img.1.rp-api.com/thumb/7108077" style="float:left;margin-right:10px;"></a><a href="http://s.tt/1KPjh" class="rpuTitle" rel="norewrite"><strong>Apple Unveils iPhone 5C, iPhone 5S</strong></a> (via <a href="http://s.tt/1KPjh" class="rpuHost" rel="norewrite">slashdot</a>)
<p class="rpuSnip">
Apple has unveiled a pair of new iPhones. Apple CEO Tim Cook took to a California stage Sept. 10 and, after a couple of brief updates on the iTunes Festival (now in its seventh year, this edition featuring musicians such as Justin Timberlake and Katy Perry) and the company&rsquo;s retail operations, moved onto the meat of the unveiling event. The first big announcement&hellip;</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><!-- put the "tease", "jump" or "more" break here --><br></p><hr id="system-readmore" style="display: none;"><span id="more-8231"></span><!--break--><br><hr class="at-page-break" style="display: none;"><div class="rpuEmbedCode">
<div class="rpuArticle rpuRepostMain rpuRepost-B59E5BC06C803AD3DC87B3D5A7497EF9-bottom" style="display:none;">&nbsp;</div>
<div style="display: none;"><!-- How to customize this embed: http://www.repost.us/article-preview/hash/b59e5bc06c803ad3dc87b3d5a7497ef9 --></div>
</div>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Apple Unveils the iPhone 5C and iPhone 5S" data-link="/2013/09/apple-unveils-iphone-5c-iphone-5s/" data-summary="Apple has unveiled a pair of new iPhones. Apple CEO Tim Cook took to a California stage Sept. 10 and, after a couple of brief updates on the iTunes Festival (now in its seventh year, this edition featuring musicians such as Justin Timberlake and Katy Perry) and the company?s retail operations, moved onto the meat of the unveiling event. The first big announcement&amp;hellip;"></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Apple Unveils the iPhone 5C and iPhone 5S" data-link="/2013/09/apple-unveils-iphone-5c-iphone-5s/" data-summary="Apple has unveiled a pair of new iPhones. Apple CEO Tim Cook took to a California stage Sept. 10 and, after a couple of brief updates on the iTunes Festival (now in its seventh year, this edition featuring musicians such as Justin Timberlake and Katy Perry) and the company?s retail operations, moved onto the meat of the unveiling event. The first big announcement&amp;hellip;"></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/09/apple-unveils-iphone-5c-iphone-5s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Early Leak of the the iPhone 5S Announcement?</title>
		<link>/2013/09/early-leak-iphone-5s-announcement/</link>
		<comments>/2013/09/early-leak-iphone-5s-announcement/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 14:42:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Event]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone 5S Announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 5C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 5S]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8204</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/AppleiPhone5SAnnouncement-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Leaked Apple iPhone5S Announcement?" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Is this a early leak of the iPhone 5S product video? No, it's just some good-hearted ribbing of the way that Apple presents something as remarkable and magical that otherwise would seem pretty mediocre. Here's to hoping <p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/09/early-leak-iphone-5s-announcement/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/AppleiPhone5SAnnouncement-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Leaked Apple iPhone5S Announcement?" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>Is this a early leak of the iPhone 5S product video? No, it&rsquo;s just some good-hearted ribbing of the way that Apple presents something as remarkable and magical that otherwise would seem pretty mediocre. Here&rsquo;s to hoping the event is a little more spectacular than this video. It would be pretty hilarious if they showed this video during the <a href="http://deemable.com/2013/09/can-watch-2013-apple-iphone-event-live/" title="Where Can I Watch the 2013 Apple iPhone Event Live?">Apple Live event</a> though! The S stands for Same.</p>
<p><iframe width="480" height="360" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/1sIWez9HAbA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><img src="//media/2013/09/AppleiPhone5SAnnouncement-300x177.png" alt="Leaked Apple iPhone5S Announcement?" width="300" height="177" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-8207"></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Early Leak of the the iPhone 5S Announcement?" data-link="/2013/09/early-leak-iphone-5s-announcement/" data-summary="Is this a early leak of the iPhone 5S product video? No, it's just some good-hearted ribbing of the way that Apple presents something as remarkable and magical that otherwise would seem pretty mediocre. Here's to hoping"></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Early Leak of the the iPhone 5S Announcement?" data-link="/2013/09/early-leak-iphone-5s-announcement/" data-summary="Is this a early leak of the iPhone 5S product video? No, it's just some good-hearted ribbing of the way that Apple presents something as remarkable and magical that otherwise would seem pretty mediocre. Here's to hoping"></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/09/early-leak-iphone-5s-announcement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Redesigned PayPal Mobile App May Become Your Digital Wallet</title>
		<link>/2013/09/redesigned-paypal-mobile-app-may-become-digital-wallet/</link>
		<comments>/2013/09/redesigned-paypal-mobile-app-may-become-digital-wallet/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 14:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8199</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/repost-us-6937724-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="PayPal, with its newly redesigned mobile app for iPhone and Android, hopes to start changing people’s minds on mobile payments once again." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />In recent years, financial management companies like PayPal, Square and even Google's Wallet have been pushing for the world to embrace digital, on-the-go payments in place of (or in addition to) traditional methods like cash and credit cards. Though a small few have found success, like Square planting its feet in retail outlets big and small (from Starbucks stores to hot dog stands), many mobile payment methods are laborious and simply less convenient…<p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/09/redesigned-paypal-mobile-app-may-become-digital-wallet/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/repost-us-6937724-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="PayPal, with its newly redesigned mobile app for iPhone and Android, hopes to start changing people’s minds on mobile payments once again." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>Back in the 90&rsquo;s Bill Gates predicted that we would all be carrying &ldquo;wallet PCs,&rdquo; small computers with screens the size of a wallet that we would hold our money, ID, credit cards and tickets, and would have basic computing functions like calculator, calendar and note applications. Unfortunately, he did not predict that we would also use them to watch endless cat videos and fling birds at green pigs. The modern smart phone has practically fulfilled his prediction, except for replacing the fundamental functions of the old leather wallet. All but very few of us still carry a piece of leather that holds our IDs and credit and debit cards. The problem with most digital wallet apps has been that none of them have yet to become more convenient than simply pulling out a debit card and swiping it. Even Apple&rsquo;s Passbook, which was supposed&nbsp;to be&nbsp;the pinacle of simplicity, is much more complicated than most people are willing to put up with. Until an app makes paying for something with your smartphone as simple and easy as paying for something with a credit card, digital wallets will never replace credit cards. But, PayPal is still willing to try with its latest app update. For more on that story, here is&nbsp;<a title="View more posts by this author" href="http://www.besttechie.com/author/landon/">Landon Robinson</a>&lsquo;s article from BestTechie.</p>
<div class="rpuEmbedCode">
<div class="rpuArticle rpuRepost-583146FFFE6F2AD7F4F4240B412112AA-top rpuNoTitle" style="margin: 0; padding: 0;">
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-8201" alt="PayPal, with its newly redesigned mobile app for iPhone and Android, hopes to start changing people's minds on mobile payments once again." src="//media/2013/09/repost-us-6937724.jpg" width="580" height="387"></p>
<p><a class="rpuTitle" href="http://s.tt/1Kc3U" rel="norewrite"><strong>Redesigned PayPal Mobile App May Become Your Digital Wallet</strong></a> (via <a class="rpuHost" href="http://s.tt/1Kc3U" rel="norewrite">http://www.besttechie.com/</a>)</p>
<p class="rpuSnip">In recent years, financial management companies like PayPal, Square and even Google&rsquo;s Wallet have been pushing for the world to embrace digital, on-the-go payments in place of (or in addition to) traditional methods like cash and credit cards. Though a small few have found success, like Square planting its feet in retail outlets big and small (from Starbucks stores to hot dog stands), many mobile payment methods are laborious and simply less convenient?</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><!-- put the "tease", "jump" or "more" break here --></p>
<hr id="system-readmore" style="display: none;"><p><span id="more-8199"></span><!--break--></p>
<hr class="at-page-break" style="display: none;"><div class="rpuEmbedCode">
<div class="rpuArticle rpuRepostMain rpuRepost-583146FFFE6F2AD7F4F4240B412112AA-bottom" style="display: none;">&nbsp;</div>
<div style="display: none;"><!-- How to customize this embed: http://www.repost.us/article-preview/hash/583146fffe6f2ad7f4f4240b412112aa --></div>
</div>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Redesigned PayPal Mobile App May Become Your Digital Wallet" data-link="/2013/09/redesigned-paypal-mobile-app-may-become-digital-wallet/" data-summary="In recent years, financial management companies like PayPal, Square and even Google's Wallet have been pushing for the world to embrace digital, on-the-go payments in place of (or in addition to) traditional methods like cash and credit cards. Though a small few have found success, like Square planting its feet in retail outlets big and small (from Starbucks stores to hot dog stands), many mobile payment methods are laborious and simply less convenient?"></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Redesigned PayPal Mobile App May Become Your Digital Wallet" data-link="/2013/09/redesigned-paypal-mobile-app-may-become-digital-wallet/" data-summary="In recent years, financial management companies like PayPal, Square and even Google's Wallet have been pushing for the world to embrace digital, on-the-go payments in place of (or in addition to) traditional methods like cash and credit cards. Though a small few have found success, like Square planting its feet in retail outlets big and small (from Starbucks stores to hot dog stands), many mobile payment methods are laborious and simply less convenient?"></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/09/redesigned-paypal-mobile-app-may-become-digital-wallet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Episode 14 &#8211; Cats on a Laptop</title>
		<link>/2012/09/deemable-tech-episode-14-cats-on-a-laptop/</link>
		<comments>/2012/09/deemable-tech-episode-14-cats-on-a-laptop/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 17:42:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple EarPods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[case]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earbuds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EarPods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[headphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[headsets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[in-ear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wii U]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=5529</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/09/kitten-on-laptop-if-not-for-sits-why-is-it-made-of-warm-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="IF NOT FOR SITS, WHY IS IT MADE OF WARM?" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Today, Ray and Tom finally took down the &#8220;NO GIRLS ALLOWED&#8221; sign as they were joined in the studio by&#160;Kristen Spencer, video game journalist and editor of&#160;CountGameula.com to talk to us about the Nintendo Wii U announcement. Deemable Tech &#8211; <a href="/2012/09/deemable-tech-episode-14-cats-on-a-laptop/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2012/09/deemable-tech-episode-14-cats-on-a-laptop/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/09/kitten-on-laptop-if-not-for-sits-why-is-it-made-of-warm-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="IF NOT FOR SITS, WHY IS IT MADE OF WARM?" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>Today, Ray and Tom finally took down the &ldquo;NO GIRLS ALLOWED&rdquo; sign as they were joined in the studio by&nbsp;Kristen Spencer, video game journalist and editor of&nbsp;<a title="Count Gameula | Gaming news you can really sink your teeth into." href="http://countgameula.com/">CountGameula.com</a> to talk to us about the Nintendo Wii U announcement.</p>
<p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2012/09/kitten-on-laptop-if-not-for-sits-why-is-it-made-of-warm.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-5535" title="IF NOT FOR SITS, WHY IS IT MADE OF WARM? " src="//media/2012/09/kitten-on-laptop-if-not-for-sits-why-is-it-made-of-warm-300x251.jpg"  alt="" width="300" height="251"></a></p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-5529-4" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-09-17.mp3?_=4"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-09-17.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-09-17.mp3</a></audio><p><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-09-17.mp3">Deemable Tech &ndash; Episode 14 &ndash; Cats on a Laptop</a></p>
<div><strong>Today&rsquo;s Questions:</strong></div>
<div>
<ul><li>Lauren:<br>
Every time I&rsquo;m watching Netflix on my Wii, it gets hung up. I have to sit and wait for it to finish buffering all the time, and it will get hung up in the middle of watching a show. Is there anyway for me to make my Wi-Fi run faster or is this a problem with Netflix?</li>
<li>Jessica:<br>
My cat is a spoiled brat who only likes sitting on things, because I guess the floor or the couch are too plain for her. Her favorite thing to sit on (other than me) is my laptop. She just really likes to sit on the closed lid. Is this bad, or is the outside of the lid going to protect the laptop sufficiently? If it makes any difference, it&rsquo;s a Dell, and Tesla is not a big cat, weighing only about 10 pounds.</li>
<li>The above-mentioned laptop did a weird thing at startup recently. I logged in to Windows and tried to start up Firefox, but it didn&rsquo;t do anything, and started trying to lock up. I noticed that down in the system tray, there was an icon for Intel Rapid Storage Technology, with a blue circle on it. When I hovered my mouse over it, it said that Intel Rapid Storage Technology was not running. I rebooted, and when it came back up the same icon was there, but it went from a blue circle to a green checkmark, and everything was fine. Firefox came up, and all was happy. Was that the problem, or just a coincidence? I&rsquo;ve never paid attention to that icon before, but now every time I look for it, it has a green check except *right* at startup.</li>
<li>Why are graphics specifications so dumb? I bought a game that, turns out, only supports something like 12 very specific graphics card models. Mine wasn&rsquo;t on that list, so I can&rsquo;t play it. Since then, I&rsquo;ve tried to look at requirements for games before buying them, and most of it&rsquo;s pretty straight forward, like X amount of RAM or a Y Ghz processor or whatever. But the graphics requirements are all different. They always seem to list certain brands and models, then say &ldquo;or better,&rdquo; which is basically useless to me or anyone else using a brand other than the two or three listed. I don&rsquo;t know how my card compares to those specific cards! Why can&rsquo;t they just be numbers, like the other specifications? Do they do this on purpose to make me sad?</li>
<li>Hi, I have a question for ya.<br>
I sometimes listen to Deemable Tech on my iPhone. The problem is, the phone automatically goes to sleep about every 3 minutes and interrupts the show. Is there any way to deactivate this while listening to your show, without having to change it in my settings every time and then change it back once I&rsquo;m finished?<br>
-a Canadian listener</li>
<li>Hunter writes, ?Is there a way to share a website from my computer to my phone besides just emailing myself? It would be nice if there were a quick, easy way to do this. I have a Moto Razr Maxx running Android.?</li>
</ul></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div>Need tech help? &nbsp;Got a problem with your computer, phone or tablet? Give us a call and leave us a voice mail at 904-372-DEEM (3336), or send us an email and questions@deemable.com. We&rsquo;ll take the best questions and answer them on the show.</div>
</div>
<div>
<h3>The News Feed:</h3>
<ul><li>Apple announces the iPhone 5, new iPod touches, and ruins the iPod Nano</li>
<li>Nintendo announces the Wii U</li>
</ul></div>
<h3>Links we mentioned on today&rsquo;s show:</h3>
<ul><li><a title="Support for Intel&reg; Rapid Storage Technology (Intel&reg; RST)" href="http://www.intel.com/p/en_US/support/highlights/chpsts/imsm">Intel&reg; Rapid Storage Technology (Intel&reg; RST)</a></li>
<li><a title="Chrome Web Store - Google Chrome to Phone Extension" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/oadboiipflhobonjjffjbfekfjcgkhco">Chrome Web Store &ndash; Google Chrome to Phone Extension</a></li>
<li><a title="Google Chrome to Phone - Android Apps on Google Play" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.chrometophone">Google Chrome to Phone &ndash; Android Apps on Google Play</a></li>
<li><a title="Downcast" href="http://www.downcastapp.com/">Downcast</a></li>
<li><a title="Podcasts for iPhone 3GS, iPhone 4, iPhone 4S, iPod touch (3rd generation), iPod touch (4th generation) and iPad on the iTunes App Store" href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/podcasts/id525463029" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Podcasts by Apple</a></li>
<li><a title="Talk radio, podcasts and live radio on demand in 1 mobile app | Stitcher Smart Radio" href="http://www.stitcher.com/">Stitcher</a></li>
<li>Our podcast RSS feed: <a title="Deemable Tech Podcast | Put this in your Podcatcher if you can't find Deemable Tech in the directory." href="http://dmbl.co/pod">http://dmbl.co/pod</a></li>
<li><a title="Why Mobile E-mail Signatures Can Hurt Your Business Relationships" href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-505143_162-28648083/why-mobile-e-mail-signatures-can-hurt-your-business-relationships/">Why Mobile E-mail Signatures Can Hurt Your Business Relationships &ndash; CBSNews.com</a></li>
</ul><h3>Bumper Music</h3>
<ul><li><a title="Paul McCartney - Band On The Run (8-Bit Remix) - YouTube" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gJqHKV5jVvs">Paul McCartney &ndash; Band On The Run (8-Bit Remix)</a></li>
<li><a title="The Beatles- Here Comes The Sun 8-bit - YouTube" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PTbpBi5oEvQ">The Beatles- Here Comes The Sun 8-bit</a></li>
</ul><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Episode 14 - Cats on a Laptop" data-link="/2012/09/deemable-tech-episode-14-cats-on-a-laptop/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Episode 14 - Cats on a Laptop" data-link="/2012/09/deemable-tech-episode-14-cats-on-a-laptop/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2012/09/deemable-tech-episode-14-cats-on-a-laptop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2012-09-17.mp3" length="51360914" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
