<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; PrepChefs</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/prepchefs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#48 PrepChefs.com, New iPhones and In-security Questions</title>
		<link>/2013/09/48-prepchefs-com-new-iphones-security-questions/</link>
		<comments>/2013/09/48-prepchefs-com-new-iphones-security-questions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food Delivery Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 5C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 5S]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PrepChefs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PrepChefs.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security questions]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8241</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/Episode48-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="#48 PrepChefs.com, the New iPhones and In-security Questions." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week, we&#8217;re finally half-back in studio. &#8220;Half-back&#8221; because Tom was out sick, but Amber Hollister, Ray&#8217;s wife, came in to fill Tom&#8217;s shoes. Ray and Amber were joined&#160;in the studio by Brian DeAlexandris, the owner of PrepChefs.com, to talk <a href="/2013/09/48-prepchefs-com-new-iphones-security-questions/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/09/48-prepchefs-com-new-iphones-security-questions/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/Episode48-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="#48 PrepChefs.com, the New iPhones and In-security Questions." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/09/Episode48.png" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class=" wp-image-8245 alignright" alt="#48 PrepChefs.com, the New iPhones and In-security Questions." src="/media/2013/09/Episode48.png"  width="320" height="180"></a>This week, we&rsquo;re finally half-back in studio. &ldquo;Half-back&rdquo; because Tom was out sick, but Amber Hollister, Ray&rsquo;s wife, came in to fill Tom&rsquo;s shoes. Ray and Amber were joined&nbsp;in the studio by Brian DeAlexandris, the owner of <a href="http://PrepChefs.com/">PrepChefs.com</a>, to talk about his incredible company that delivers&nbsp;delicious, ready-to-cook,&nbsp;homemade style meals. If you&rsquo;ve ever wished that you could pick up your iPhone and make dinner for the entire week appear at your doorstep, you need to listen to this episode!</p>
<p>After the interview, Ray and Amber recapped the Apple iPhone 5C&nbsp;and 5S announcement and answered a listener&rsquo;s question about security questions.</p>
<span class="embed-youtube" style="text-align:center; display: block;"><iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="752" height="453" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xUdl0nQx304?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
<p><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-8241-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-09-14.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-09-14.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-09-14.mp3</a></audio><br><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-09-14.mp3">#48 PrepChefs.com, New iPhones and In-security Questions</a></p>
<h4>DRAFT TRANSCRIPT</h4>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p dir="ltr">AMBER: I&rsquo;m Amber Hollister,</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: and this is Deemable Tech, tech help worth listening to.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: This week&rsquo;s episode of the Deemable Tech podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: So, as you can tell Tom is out of the studio today, so we&rsquo;re joined today by wife Amber Hollister.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Does it feel weird being in here instead of at home watching the show on the website?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? Give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at <a href="mailto:questions@deemable.com">questions@deemable.com</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Well, as you might remember, we were doing a contest to win a $50 Amazon Gift Card, and the time is now to announce the winner.</p>
<p dir="ltr">[Drumroll]</p>
<p dir="ltr">&hellip; No one!</p>
<p dir="ltr">That&rsquo;s right. A lot of people liked us on Facebook and Twitter and subscribed to the show on iTunes and YouTube, but not a single person emailed us at <a href="mailto:giftcard@deemable.com">giftcard@deemable.com</a> to enter the contest, except for one guy that sent us some spam. So, that contest was an epic fail.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But we&rsquo;ve learned from the experience, and we are starting a new Amazon Gift Card contest that is much easier to enter. All you have to do is answer a few questions about the Deemable Tech podcast.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Don&rsquo;t worry, it&rsquo;s not a trivia contest. We just need your opinion on a few questions. If you could take a few minutes and answer our survey it will really help us out a lot. And, just for doing so, you&rsquo;ll be entered to win a $20 Amazon Gift Card.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Just go to Deemable.com and click the link to take the survey. &nbsp;You can&rsquo;t miss it, it will be the first or second article at the top until the contest is over. Speaking of which, it ends September 30th, so don&rsquo;t wait, go submit&nbsp;your survey answers right now,&hellip; unless you&rsquo;re listening live, then just load the page in the background and answer the questions after the show is over.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Now, on to the show. So, Amber you remember the 90s, right?</p>
<p dir="ltr">AMBER: Sure,</p>
<ul><li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">it started with the end of the Cold War and the collapse of the Soviet Union,</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">They were playing alternative, grunge and ska on the radio,</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Dolly the sheep was the first cloned animal,</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">There was the Iraq war, the Lewinski scandal, the ramp up to the fear of Y2K bug,</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">and of course, that was the decade when Al Gore invented the Internet.</p>
</li>
</ul><p dir="ltr">RAY: Wow, that was a really in depth description.</p>
<p dir="ltr">AMBER: [pause] I just looked on Wikipedia.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Ah. Well, I ask because remember how back in the old days of the Information Superhighway, the Internet was going to change how we did everything? Back then, they predicted that by now, we would be doing all of our shopping on the Internet. Brick and mortar stores would be relics of the past. We would buy everything online, all of our electronics, all of our clothes, all of our groceries would be bought online.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I have never bought a single piece of clothing online, have you?</p>
<p dir="ltr">AMBER: *answer, and vamp*</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Well, obviously the Internet has turned out a bit differently than they predicted. But, there&rsquo;s one thing that you can do online that they did predict right. That is buying your food online. Now, I&rsquo;m not talking about going to the grocery store and buying your groceries online, although there are services that will do that for you, and you can even buy groceries on Amazon. What I&rsquo;m talking about is delicious, ready to cook meals delivered to your door.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So, a little over a month ago I found out about this website that is here in Jacksonville called PrepChefs.com. The website looked fantastic, so we decided to check it out. My wife Amber and I have been using&nbsp;the service for about a month now, and we have loved it, so I invited the owner Brian DeAlexandris to join us here in the studio to tell us more about it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Thanks for joining us Brian.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Also, because, I&rsquo;ll be honest, she knows more about cooking these days than I do, I also invited my wife Amber to join us in the studio to tell us about her experience using the service.</p>
<p><strong>OUTRO</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Thanks for all your questions, and keep them coming. Call us at our toll-free number, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com. Also, subscribe to the show! Search for Deemable Tech on iTunes or point your favorite podcast app to dmbl.co/pod.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Our producer is Sean Birch. Thanks to Robert Snyder for Video Production Assistance. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, and this is Deemable Tech. Thanks for listening. Have a great week.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#48 PrepChefs.com, New iPhones and In-security Questions" data-link="/2013/09/48-prepchefs-com-new-iphones-security-questions/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#48 PrepChefs.com, New iPhones and In-security Questions" data-link="/2013/09/48-prepchefs-com-new-iphones-security-questions/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/09/48-prepchefs-com-new-iphones-security-questions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-09-14.mp3" length="64738116" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
