<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Aurora App</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/aurora-app/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#44 Angel Torres, Aurora App 2.0, and Deemable Tech App 1.0</title>
		<link>/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/</link>
		<comments>/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 15:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angel Torres]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aurora App]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Logica]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7757</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/07/DeemableTechEpisode44AngelTorres-e1375109234120-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Deemable Tech Episode 44 Angel Torres and Aurora App 2.0" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />On this episode of Deemable Tech, Angel Torres from The Logica visits us in the studio again to tell us what he&#8217;s been up to since One Spark, and to tell us about some big news from the Aurora App. <a href="/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/07/DeemableTechEpisode44AngelTorres-e1375109234120-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Deemable Tech Episode 44 Angel Torres and Aurora App 2.0" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/07/DeemableTechEpisode44AngelTorres.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-7761" alt="Deemable Tech Episode 44 Angel Torres and Aurora App 2.0" src="/media/2013/07/DeemableTechEpisode44AngelTorres-300x164.jpg"  width="300" height="164"></a>On this episode of Deemable Tech, Angel Torres from <a href="http://www.thelogica.com/">The Logica</a> visits us in the studio again to tell us what he&rsquo;s been up to since One Spark, and to tell us about some big news from the Aurora App. Also, we help Amber remove a forgotten PIN restriction on her iPhone, and we helped Lynda figure out why apps keep redone loading on her iPod touch after she deleted them.</p>
<p>We also announced an Amazon Gift Card give away! We really need your help growing our show, and what better way to do that than through bribery! That&rsquo;s right, if Deemable Tech gets at least 500 subscribers on iTunes and at least 200 subscribers on YouTube by the end of August, we are going to give away an Amazon Gift Card worth $50!</p>
<p>To be eligible to win the $50 Amazon Gift Card, you have to Subscribe to us on <a href="http://youtube.com/DeemableTech">YouTube</a> and <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/deemable-tech/id540595466" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iTunes</a>, Like us on <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable">Facebook</a> and follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable">Twitter</a>. Then, send us an email at giftcard@deemable.com. In that email, tell us your Facebook name, Twitter and YouTube username. We&rsquo;ll pick one eligible email at random and we&rsquo;ll announce it on the show. You got to do all of it and include all of it in the email. If you don&rsquo;t, you&rsquo;re disqualified! We&rsquo;re gonna check!</p>
<p>Now, remember, we can&rsquo;t give away the $50 Amazon Gift Card unless we hit 500 subscribers on iTunes and 200 subscribers on YouTube by the end of August. So, you&rsquo;ve got to tell your friends about Deemable Tech, and tell them to subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes and YouTube! Not only does this put you in the running for a $50 Amazon Gift Card, but it will really help us to grow Deemable Tech. So, whether you do it out of altruistic motives, or out of pure selfishness, make sure to tell everyone you know about Deemable Tech, and make sure to like us on <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable">Facebook</a>, Subscribe to us on <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/deemable-tech/id540595466" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iTunes</a> and <a href="http://youtube.com/DeemableTech">YouTube</a> and Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable">Twitter</a>! The links to all of our profiles are in the top right corner of the website under the heading, Follow Deemable Tech.</p>
<p>Also, we almost forgot to mention that we launched the Deemable Tech app! The Deemable Tech app is now available for <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/deemable-tech/id671758316" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iPhone, iPod touch and iPad in the App Store</a> and for <a>Android phones and tablets in the Google Play store</a>. You can find a link to the app simply by visiting <a href="Deemable.com">Deemable.com</a> on your mobile device. On the Deemable Tech app you can listen or watch the latest episodes of Deemable Tech, read the latest articles, and submit questions right on your smart phone or tablet. You can receive notifications on your phone when new articles and episodes are posted too! Thanks to all of our Kickstarter supporters. We couldn&rsquo;t have done it without you.</p>
<p>All that, plus our app recommendations of the week on this episode of Deemable Tech!</p>
<span class="embed-youtube" style="text-align:center; display: block;"><iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="752" height="453" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1ElfXftGY40?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
<p><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-7757-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-28.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-28.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-28.mp3</a></audio><br><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-28.mp3">#44 Angel Torres and the Aurora App 2.0</a></p>
<p>DRAFT TRANSCRIPT</p>
<h4>SEGMENT A INTRO</h4>
<p>RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>TOM: I&rsquo;m Tom Braun,</p>
<p>RAY: and this is Deemable Tech, tech help worth listening to.</p>
<p>RAY: This week&rsquo;s episode of the Deemable Tech podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p>And, by audible.com &ndash; Deemable Tech listeners can get a FREE audiobook download at <a href="http://audibletrial.com/Deemable">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a> Over 100,000 titles to choose from for your iPhone, Android, Kindle or mp3 player.</p>
<p>TOM: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? Give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at questions@deemable.com.</p>
<h4>Amazon Gift Card Contest Announcement</h4>
<p>RAY: Tonight, on Deemable Tech, folks, we need you to do us a favor. If you like the show, if you want to hear more episodes of Deemable Tech, we need you to do something for us. We need you to tell your friends about us. We need you to share us on Facebook, tweet about us on Twitter, just send an email to your friends and tell them to check us out. Or if you talk to people in real life, you can tell them there. Give them a call on the phone.</p>
<p>You know how Tinkerbell would die if people don&rsquo;t believe in her? Well, we&rsquo;re kinda like that. Except the energy that we depend on is Subscriptions, Likes, and Follows.</p>
<p>If you haven&rsquo;t done it already,<br>
Subscribe to us on <a href="http://youtube.com/DeemableTech">YouTube</a> and <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/deemable-tech/id540595466" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iTunes</a>.<br>
Like us on <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable">Facebook</a> and follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable">Twitter</a>.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ll be honest, right now, the Deemable Tech community is pretty small. We only have about 150 subscribers on our podcast, we have about 25 subscribers on YouTube. We do have about 1,000 likes on Facebook and followers on Twitter, but the subscribers is what really counts, because those are people who are actually watching or listening to the show.</p>
<p>Tell you what, I have a deal for you. If we hit 500 subscribers on iTunes and 200 subscribers on YouTube, I&rsquo;ll give away an Amazon gift card. Sound good?</p>
<p>TOM: How much?</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what you have to do to be eligible to receive a $50 Amazon Gift Card. You have to Subscribe to us on <a href="http://youtube.com/DeemableTech">YouTube</a> and <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/deemable-tech/id540595466" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iTunes</a>, Like us on <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable">Facebook</a> and follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable">Twitter</a>, and send us an email at giftcard@deemable.com. In that email, tell us your Facebook name, Twitter and YouTube username. We&rsquo;ll pick one eligible email at random and we&rsquo;ll announce it on the show. You got to include all of it. If you don&rsquo;t you&rsquo;re disqualified. We need that information because we&rsquo;re gonna check! If you didn&rsquo;t like us, you&rsquo;re disqualified. etc.</p>
<p>You can like us on <a href="http://dmbl.co/gp">Google Plus</a> too, but nobody really cares.</p>
<p>On this week&rsquo;s episode we have a special guest, back with us in the studio again, Angel Torres, the CEO and founder of The Logica, a web and app development company. You might know him from when he was on the show back in February, or you might know him if you came to One Spark. Thanks for coming on the show, Angel.</p>
<p>So, I want to ask you about what&rsquo;s been going on with the Aurora App, and any other projects that The Logica is up to that you can talk about, but I&rsquo;m sure you&rsquo;ve heard about the changes at One Spark that are coming for One Spark 2014. I want to see what you think about that too. Sound fun?</p>
<p>All right, but first, let&rsquo;s talk about apps.</p>
<h4>That App Segment</h4>
<p><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ifttt/id660944635" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">IFTTT &ndash; If This Then That</a></p>
<p><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/limbo-game/id656951157?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">LIMBO Game</a></p>
<p><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/aurora-app/id632041573" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">Aurora App</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>All right, well let&rsquo;s answer a couple of listener&rsquo;s questions.</p>
<p>Amber wrote in and asked, at some point I created a PIN number for my iPhone&rsquo;s &ldquo;Restrictions&rdquo; setting. I can&rsquo;t remember it now, and I have 9 failed passcode attempts. Will I ever be able to get in and change my restrictions&hellip; or will I be stuck with in-app purchases turned off forever? Help! How can I fix this?<br>
Well, hopefully you have synced your iPhone with iTunes on your computer at least once before. If you have this going to be a lot easier. All you&rsquo;ll have to do is open iTunes, and plug your iPhone in, and that will reset the count of how many times you can enter the passcode. So, theoretically you could enter pin numbers until the end of time. Hopefully at some point you&rsquo;ll be able to figure out what your pin number was.<br>
If you can&rsquo;t figure out what your pin number was, then that&rsquo;s a slightly bigger problem. You&rsquo;re going to have to backup your iPhone, and then restore it from that backup. That will clear the PIN number. But, that will only work, if you have synced your iPhone with iTunes on your computer in the past. If you haven&rsquo;t, you&rsquo;re going to have to reset your iPhone to factory settings. That is why I said I hope that you have synced it before, because if you haven&rsquo;t, you&rsquo;re going to lose all your settings and all your stuff on your iPhone.<br>
So, what I would do is start by plugging in your iPhone and trying those passcodes again, and keep track of which ones you&rsquo;ve tried, especially if you&rsquo;re only doing a four digit pin code. I mean there&rsquo;s only 9,999 options. You&rsquo;ve got to hit it eventually, right?<br>
We will include a link to instructions how to reset your iPhone to factory settings, and how to restore your iPhone from a previous back up in the show notes for the episode.</p>
<p><a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1212">iOS: Forgotten passcode or device disabled after entering wrong passcode</a></p>
<p>Lynda asked I keep deleting apps off of my iPod touch, but they keep reinstalling whenever the app gets updated. Why? It&rsquo;s driving me crazy. I want to be able to delete apps and for them to stay deleted. What&rsquo;s going on? I am running iOS 6.1.3 on a 4th generation iPod. I am running iTunes on my Windows 7 laptop. iTunes syncs over the WiFi.</p>
<p>I am going to guess that you probably don&rsquo;t keep your laptop running all the time. Here&rsquo;s what I think is happening: You are connecting to iTunes, and syncing. Then, later you install an app, and delete it before you sync with your computer again. Now what happens, is the next time you sync your computer with your iPod, iTunes downloads the app, and then it sees that you don&rsquo;t have the new app on your iPod. So, in trying to be helpful, it reinstalls it on your iPod for you. Now, you&rsquo;re probably only just noticing it when the App Store has an update for the app.</p>
<p><a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/ht4539">How to enable Automatic Downloads on your computer and on your iPhone, iPad and iPod touch</a></p>
<p>QUESTIONS FOR ANGEL</p>
<p>How did things turn out for you guys at One Spark?<br>
What would you do different?<br>
Are you planning on entering One Spark 2014?<br>
What happening with the Aurora app?<br>
What projects are working on now?</p>
<p>Changes for One Spark 2014 http://beonespark.tumblr.com/post/55001047087/one-spark-2014-press-release</p>
<p>More money up for grabs: $300,000<br>
Distributed differently:<br>
$200,000 guaranteed crowdfund distributed solely on public vote,<br>
five $10,000 bonuses awarded to the top-voted creator in each category,<br>
five $10,000 juried prizes and immediate individual contributions from attendees.<br>
Other changes<br>
Five creator categories, art, innovation, music, science and technology<br>
More walkable, concentrated event footprint that will include 20 square blocks and additional programming throughout.<br>
Significant number of additional voting and information kiosk locations.</p>
<h4>SPONSOR</h4>
<p>For the listeners of the Deemable Tech podcast, Audible is offering a free audiobook download with a free 30-day trial to give you the opportunity to check out their service.</p>
<p>To download your free audiobook today go to <a href="http://audibletrial.com/Deemable">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a>. Again, that&rsquo;s audibletrial.com/Deemable for your free audiobook!</p>
<h4>OUTRO</h4>
<p>Thanks for all your questions, and keep them coming. Call us at our toll-free number, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com. Also, subscribe to the show! Search for Deemable Tech on iTunes or point your favorite podcast app to dmbl.co/pod.</p>
<p>Our producer is Sean Birch. Thanks to Robert Snyder for Video Production Assistance. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, and this is Deemable Tech. Thanks for listening. Have a great week.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#44 Angel Torres, Aurora App 2.0, and Deemable Tech App 1.0" data-link="/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#44 Angel Torres, Aurora App 2.0, and Deemable Tech App 1.0" data-link="/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-07-28.mp3" length="65736620" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Episode 30 &#8211; Angel Ayala Torres and the Awesome Aurora App</title>
		<link>/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/</link>
		<comments>/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 03:35:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aurora App]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=6826</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/02/AuroraApp-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Aurora App" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week on Deemable Tech Ray and Tom were joined in the studio by Angel Ayala Torres, the&#160;CEO and founder of The Logica, a web and app development company that has a very interesting app that they are going to <a href="/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/02/AuroraApp-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Aurora App" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/02/AuroraApp.png" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright wp-image-6828" alt="Aurora App" src="/media/2013/02/AuroraApp.png"  width="280" height="160"></a></p>
<p>This week on Deemable Tech Ray and Tom were joined in the studio by Angel Ayala Torres, the&nbsp;CEO and founder of <a title="The Logica Creative Studio" href="http://www.thelogica.com/" target="_blank">The Logica</a>, a web and app development company that has a very interesting app that they are going to be releasing very soon called <a title="AuroraApp" href="http://auroraapp.com/" target="_blank">Aurora</a>. Both Deemable Tech and Aurora will be at <a title="One Spark: The World's Crowdfunding Festival " href="http://beonespark.com/" target="_blank">One Spark</a>, a crowd funding festival happening in Jacksonville, Florida April 17-21, 2013. Be sure to come and visit Aurora&rsquo;s booth at <a title="CoWork Jax | CoWorking Space in Downtown Jacksonville" href="http://www.coworkjax.com/" target="_blank">CoWork&nbsp;Jax</a> at <a title="5 W. Forsyth Street" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=5+W.+Forsyth+St.&amp;hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;hnear=5+W+Forsyth+St,+Jacksonville,+Duval,+Florida+32202&amp;t=h&amp;z=16" target="_blank">Forsyth and Main Street</a>&nbsp;and Deemable Tech&rsquo;s booth at a yet to be&nbsp;disclosed location, and make sure to vote for Aurora and Deemable Tech at One Spark!</p>
<p>All that and more, on this episode of Deemable Tech!</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img title="Subscribe on iTunes" alt="" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" width="160" height="59"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">subscribe to the show in iTunes by clicking here</a>, or&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech Podcast!" href="http://dmbl.co/pod">subscribe to the show in another podcast reader by clicking here</a>. Also,&nbsp;make sure to leave us a review in iTunes. The more reviews we have the higher we&rsquo;ll be listed in iTunes and the more listeners will see our show!</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-6826-2" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-11.mp3?_=2"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-11.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-11.mp3</a></audio><p><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-11.mp3" target="_blank">Download Episode 30 &ndash; Angel Ayala Torres and the Awesome Aurora App</a></p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget, next week is our Live Event at Bold Bean Coffee Roasters! &nbsp;Monday, February 18th, 7 PM Bold Bean Coffee Roasters on Stockton Street. If you&rsquo;re in Jacksonville, come visit us and listen to the show live.&nbsp;<a title="Deemable Tech Live at Bold Bean Coffee Roasters!" href="http://dmbl.co/dtatbb" target="_blank">RSVP on Facebook</a>.</p>
<p>Send in your questions for our live event.</p>
<p>Need tech help? Got a problem or tech question about your computer, phone or tablet? Give us a call and leave us a voice mail at 1-888-972-9868, or send us an email to questions at deemable dot com. We&rsquo;ll take the best questions and answer them on the show.</p>
<h4>Links mentioned on this week&rsquo;s show:</h4>
<ul><li><a title="AuroraApp - Coming Soon 2013" href="http://AuroraApp.com/" target="_blank">AuroraApp.com</a></li>
<li><a title="Aurora App on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/auroraapp" target="_blank">Aurora on Facebook</a></li>
<li><a title="Aurora (meetaurora) on Twitter" href="https://twitter.com/meetaurora" target="_blank">Aurora on Twitter</a></li>
</ul><ul><li><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/the-dark-knight-rises-z+/id542656871?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">The Dark Knight Rises Z+</a></li>
<li><a href="http://invaders.soulbit7.com/">AR Invaders</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.dishpointer.com/">DishPointer</a></li>
<li><a href="http://golfscapeapp.com/">Golfscape GPS Rangefinder</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vitotechnology.com/star-walk.html">Star Walk</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.gosoftworks.com/GoSkyWatch/GoSkyWatch.html">GoSkyWatch Planetarium</a></li>
</ul><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Episode 30 - Angel Ayala Torres and the Awesome Aurora App" data-link="/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Episode 30 - Angel Ayala Torres and the Awesome Aurora App" data-link="/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/02/angel-ayala-torres-and-the-awesome-aurora-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-02-11.mp3" length="39000607" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
