<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; data plan</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/data-plan/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Ask Deemable Tech: Why Am I Using So Much Data?</title>
		<link>/2015/05/ask-deemable-tech-why-am-i-using-so-much-data/</link>
		<comments>/2015/05/ask-deemable-tech-why-am-i-using-so-much-data/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 19:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data usage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10028</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/iphone6_pixabay-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: JESHOOTS / Pixabay" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Donna writes, &#8220;I share a data plan with my family. I&#8217;m the biggest user of data, but I&#8217;m also the least tech savvy. I do very little downloading! I mostly just check emails. If someone sends me a link and <a href="/2015/05/ask-deemable-tech-why-am-i-using-so-much-data/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/05/ask-deemable-tech-why-am-i-using-so-much-data/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/iphone6_pixabay-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: JESHOOTS / Pixabay" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]--><html><body><audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10028-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/adt_20150521_using_so_much_data.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/adt_20150521_using_so_much_data.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/adt_20150521_using_so_much_data.mp3</a></audio><div id="attachment_10029" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2015/05/iphone6_pixabay.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-10029 size-medium" src="/media/2015/05/iphone6_pixabay-300x200.jpg"  alt="Image credit: JESHOOTS / Pixabay" width="300" height="200"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: JESHOOTS / Pixabay</p></div>
<p><strong>Donna writes, &ldquo;I share a data plan with my family. I&rsquo;m the biggest user of data, but I&rsquo;m also the least tech savvy. I do very little downloading! I mostly just check emails. If someone sends me a link and I open it, am I downloading? Sometimes I use my iPhone as a hotspot for my laptop. Is that downloading? Why am I using so much data?&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Any time your phone gets information over the Internet, Donna, that counts against your data plan. This includes reading an email, opening a link from that email, and using your phone as a hotspot so your laptop can connect to the Internet.</p>
<p>In fact, that last one is one of the most data-intensive activities you can do with your phone. Your laptop is a powerful machine that can request a lot of data in a hurry, especially if you have more than one website open at a time. All of the images, ads and videos on those sites are being downloaded through your phone?s connection, which can eat up a lot of data really fast. This is why most websites offer lightweight versions that are optimized for browsing on phones and mobile devices.</p>
<p>Other activities that can use a lot of data include streaming music through apps like Spotify and Pandora, downloading podcasts, and even sharing those vacation pictures you snapped with your friends on Facebook or Instagram. If you do a lot of driving, navigation apps like Google Maps and Apple Maps can also use a lot of data downloading directions and maps.</p>
<p>The sneakiest drainers of data plans we&rsquo;ve found are free games. While you downloaded basically all of the data for those games when you first got them from the app store, that didn&rsquo;t include those annoying little ads you see while you&rsquo;re playing them. Those ads are downloaded while you&rsquo;re running the app, chewing up your data plan in the process.</p>
<p>It may seem like everyone is after your data plan, but luckily there is a way to stop them: Wi-Fi. When your phone is connected to a wireless network, it uses Wi-Fi to download things instead of your cell data. We recommend turning off your cell data and using Wi-Fi any time you&rsquo;re at home or work. If you don&rsquo;t have a home wireless network, you may want to consider <a href="/2014/05/glen-asks-set-home-wi-fi-network/" target="_blank">setting one up</a>. This will cost some money, but it will almost definitely be cheaper than paying overage charges to your carrier.</p>
<p>Also, all wireless providers offer <a href="/2014/09/angela-asks-can-monthly-usage-smartphone/" target="_blank">a special phone number you can call or text to see what your current monthly usage is</a>. Find out what yours is and take advantage of it before you get slapped with fees!</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="Ask Deemable Tech: Why Am I Using So Much Data?" data-link="/2015/05/ask-deemable-tech-why-am-i-using-so-much-data/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="Ask Deemable Tech: Why Am I Using So Much Data?" data-link="/2015/05/ask-deemable-tech-why-am-i-using-so-much-data/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/05/ask-deemable-tech-why-am-i-using-so-much-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/adt_20150521_using_so_much_data.mp3" length="3421934" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Michelle asks, How can I lower my data usage on my iPhone?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2013/04/michelle-asks-how-can-i-lower-my-data-usage-on-my-iphone/</link>
		<comments>/2013/04/michelle-asks-how-can-i-lower-my-data-usage-on-my-iphone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3G]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4G]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cellular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data caps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data monitoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data usage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7300</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Smart phones put the Internet at your fingertips, allowing you to check your email and surf the web from anywhere with the power of 3G and 4G. However, if you don&#8217;t have an unlimited data plan, you can be charged <a href="/2013/04/michelle-asks-how-can-i-lower-my-data-usage-on-my-iphone/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/04/michelle-asks-how-can-i-lower-my-data-usage-on-my-iphone/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>Smart phones put the Internet at your fingertips, allowing you to check your email and surf the web from anywhere with the power of 3G and 4G. However, if you don&rsquo;t have an unlimited data plan, you can be charged more if you use it too much. Ray and Tom have some tips to make sure you&rsquo;re not going over your data limit on this week&rsquo;s Ask Deemable Tech.</p>
<p>And if you like our radio segments, make sure to check out <a href="/category/podcast/">Deemable Tech&rsquo;s weekly hour-long podcast.</a> You can subscribe to the show by clicking the following links or by searching for <a href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">Deemable Tech in iTunes</a> or <a href="http://youtube.com/deemabletech">YouTube</a>.</p>
<p><script id="prx-p96321-embed" src="http://www.prx.org/p/96321/embed.js?size=full"></script></p>
<p>RAY: Hi, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>TOM: I&rsquo;m Tom Braun,</p>
<p>RAY: and we&rsquo;re the hosts of Deemable Tech. On the show, we answer your questions about computers, tablets, mobile phones and the Internet, like this question:</p>
<p>TOM: Michelle asks, I was wondering about ways to lower my data usage on my iPhone. I always seem to go over my limit, and then I am slapped with another monthly charge. What things can I turn &ldquo;off&rdquo; or put away unless I need them, and how do I do it?</p>
<p>RAY: Thanks for your question, Michelle. iPhones and Android phones can eat up a data plan like a 5 year old with an unattended candy bowl. Unless you&rsquo;re on an unlimited data plan, you have to keep an eye on what your phone is downloading and sending, or it&rsquo;ll end up taking a bite out of your wallet.<br>
Periodically check your cellular data usage on your iPhone by opening your Settings app, and tapping General, Usage and then Cellular Usage at the bottom. On that screen you can see how much data your phone has sent and received. Each month, at the end of your billing cycle, tap the Reset Statistics button to clear out the counters and start over.</p>
<p>TOM: Well, Ray, that&rsquo;s good information about how to keep track of how much data you&rsquo;re using on an iPhone, but Michelle wanted to know how to reduce the amount of data she&rsquo;s using on an iPhone. Come on man, stay focused!</p>
<p>RAY: Well, you&rsquo;re right, but the first step to any diet is keeping track of how much you&rsquo;re consuming, or so I&rsquo;ve heard. Knowing how much data you&rsquo;re using in the first place will help to stay you on track. Now, here&rsquo;s a few tips to keep your cellular data usage low. First of all, don&rsquo;t download or stream any video or audio unless you are connected to a Wi-Fi network. Those NPR, Netflix, Hulu and PBS Kids apps will devour your cellular data. I&rsquo;m not saying don&rsquo;t use them! They&rsquo;re great apps. Just make sure to use them when you are connected to a Wi-Fi network if you&rsquo;re trying to save your cellular data.</p>
<p>TOM: And, if you have streaming video or music that you just have to watch or listen to over 3G or 4G, go for the Non-HD version or the lower quality version. That will save you a bunch of data, too. If you use Spotify, make your playlists Available Offline so that the next time you&rsquo;re away from home they&rsquo;ll play from your phone instead of over the Internet.</p>
<p>RAY: The same thing is true for Amazon Cloud Player and the Podcast app; make sure to download your songs and new podcast episodes to your device before you leave the house. Also, and it&rsquo;s probably obvious, but make sure to only download new apps and updates when you are on a Wi-Fi network too.</p>
<p>TOM: Also, try reducing the number of times that your phone downloads new email. On the iPhone, open your Settings app and tap &ldquo;Mail, Contacts, Calendars&rdquo; and then, Fetch New Data. Turn off Push, and change Fetch to Manually or, at most, Hourly.</p>
<p>RAY: Finally, If you see that you&rsquo;re getting close to your limit, or you just want to save your data plan for later in the month, turn your cellular data off. On the iPhone go to the General menu under Settings, tap Cellular and then tap the Cellular Data on/off switch. You&rsquo;ll still get phone calls and text messages, but you won&rsquo;t be able to browse the web and none of your apps will access the Internet either unless you are connected to a Wi-Fi network. You can also turn off Cellular data for specific built-in functions like iTunes, FaceTime, and Personal Hotspot in that same menu.</p>
<p>TOM: Follow all of these tips, and you should have a thinner waistline &ndash; oops, cellular bill &ndash; within a month or two!</p>
<p>RAY: To hear more answers to questions like this one, listen to our show at Deemable dot com, that&rsquo;s D-E E-M A-B-L-E dot com. There you can listen to all of our previous episodes and subscribe to our podcast.</p>
<p>TOM: If you have a question for Deemable Tech give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or you can send us an email at questions at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>RAY: For Deemable Tech, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p>TOM: And I&rsquo;m Tom Braun.</p>
<p><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/production.mediajoint.prx.org/public/piece_images/226950/hand_holding_iphone_medium.jpg" title="iPhone"></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title='Michelle asks, How can I lower my data usage on my iPhone?"' data-link="/2013/04/michelle-asks-how-can-i-lower-my-data-usage-on-my-iphone/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title='Michelle asks, How can I lower my data usage on my iPhone?"' data-link="/2013/04/michelle-asks-how-can-i-lower-my-data-usage-on-my-iphone/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/04/michelle-asks-how-can-i-lower-my-data-usage-on-my-iphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
