<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; iPhone electrocution</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/iphone-electrocution/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>iPhone 5 User Alegedly Electrocuted By Phone Charger</title>
		<link>/2013/07/iphone-5-user-alegedly-electrocuted-by-phone-charger/</link>
		<comments>/2013/07/iphone-5-user-alegedly-electrocuted-by-phone-charger/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 14:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lynn S]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone charger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone electrocution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ma Ailun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xinjiang]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7528</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/07/MaAilun-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Ma Ailun" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Recent reports involving the death of a 23-year old Chinese while using her iPhone got mixed reactions on the Internet. This news created speculations and doubts on the true cause following her death in July 11. Despite the press release <a href="/2013/07/iphone-5-user-alegedly-electrocuted-by-phone-charger/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/07/iphone-5-user-alegedly-electrocuted-by-phone-charger/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/07/MaAilun-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Ma Ailun" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/07/MaAilun.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright wp-image-7530" title="Ma Ailun, young bride-to-be tragically killed by electricution according to the victims family" alt="Ma Ailun" src="/media/2013/07/MaAilun.jpg"  width="384" height="215"></a>Recent reports involving the death of a 23-year old Chinese while using her iPhone got mixed reactions on the Internet. This news created speculations and doubts on the true cause following her death in July 11. Despite the press release by Apple Incorporated to &ldquo;fully investigate&rdquo; the matter, people from all over the world are shaken by the news and the Chinese community is jittery with this tragic incident.</p>
<p>According to the family of the victim, Ma Ailun was bathing when her phone rang. The former flight attendant from China&rsquo;s Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region quickly stepped into to her room and picked up the phone to answer the call while it was charging. The family also claimed that the victim was using the original accessories after purchasing the device from an authorized distributor in China way back December.</p>
<p>The Public Safety Bureau in Xinjiang conducted a detailed investigation proving that Ms. Ma&rsquo;s death was due to obvious electronic injury on her neck. However, the claim that her iPhone had something to do with it is yet to be determined.</p>
<p>Apple Inc. extended its utmost and deepest condolences to the bereaved family. &ldquo;We are saddened to learn about this tragic incident and offer our condolences to the Ma family. We will fully investigate and cooperate with authorities in this matter,&rdquo; says Apple.</p>
<p>However, Ms. Ma&rsquo;s sister vented out her grief and frustration in the most popular social media in China, Seina Weibo, which is a social network similar to Twitter. &ldquo;I hope that Apple Inc. can give us an explanation and I also hope that all you will refrain from using your mobile devices while charging,&rdquo; she wrote.</p>
<p>While it is true that using unauthorized charges and accessories to mobile devices can cause harm to the user, Prof. Will Stewart from the Institute of Engineering and Technology proved that using a mobile device while its charging is completely safe and acceptable. &ldquo;The charger&rsquo;s output is low voltage?about five volts?a weak capability to be considered dangerous,&rdquo; according to the doctor.</p>
<p>In addition, he reiterated that something in the actual charger could be at fault for the electrocution. It could also be the main plug. He said that &ldquo;owners of mobile devices should try to avoid using mains-connected equipment while in the bath. If they are extremely wet, the water could run down the wire and into the plug.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Whether these allegations are true or not but it is very essential to stay safe while using your mobile devices. It is imperative to buy gadgets through authorized distributors and use only authentic accessories to keep you out from harm&rsquo;s way.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="iPhone 5 User Alegedly Electrocuted By Phone Charger" data-link="/2013/07/iphone-5-user-alegedly-electrocuted-by-phone-charger/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="iPhone 5 User Alegedly Electrocuted By Phone Charger" data-link="/2013/07/iphone-5-user-alegedly-electrocuted-by-phone-charger/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/07/iphone-5-user-alegedly-electrocuted-by-phone-charger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
