<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Hilary Clinton</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/hilary-clinton/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#74 Ray Likes His Crow Breaded With A Light, Crispy Panko Crust</title>
		<link>/2015/03/74-ray-likes-his-crow-breaded-with-a-light-crispy-panko-crust/</link>
		<comments>/2015/03/74-ray-likes-his-crow-breaded-with-a-light-crispy-panko-crust/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 22:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BACTrack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hilary Clinton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LoopPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S6]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S6 Edge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SamsungPay]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9777</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week Ray, Tom and Sean talk about how Hilary Clinton used her personal email address the entire time she worked at the State Department. They discussed the announcement&#160;of the Samsung Galaxy S6 and S6 Edge, (which included the announcement <a href="/2015/03/74-ray-likes-his-crow-breaded-with-a-light-crispy-panko-crust/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/03/74-ray-likes-his-crow-breaded-with-a-light-crispy-panko-crust/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_9779" style="width: 669px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pIvLTUUm1I0"><img class="wp-image-9779 size-large" src="/media/2015/03/Ray-Hollister-reviews-the-BACTrack-Mobile-Breathalizer-on-Deemable-Tech-1024x570.png" alt="Ray Hollister reviews the BACTrack Mobile Breathalizer on Deemable Tech" width="659" height="367"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ray Hollister reviews the BACtrack Mobile Breathalyzer on Deemable Tech</p></div>
<p>This week Ray, Tom and Sean talk about how Hilary Clinton used her personal email address the entire time she worked at the State Department. They discussed the announcement&nbsp;of the Samsung Galaxy S6 and S6 Edge, (which included the announcement of SamsungPay which is the implementation of LoopPay into the Samsung phones which Ray insisted two weeks ago would not happen!) They also talked about the death of Google+ and Google starting its own wireless carrier. Then, Ray shared his review of the BACtrack Mobile Breathalyzer. If you&rsquo;re just here for the video, make sure to scroll all the way to the bottom.</p>
<p><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-9777-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/DeemableTech_2015-03-06.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/DeemableTech_2015-03-06.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/DeemableTech_2015-03-06.mp3</a></audio><br><a title="#74 Ray Likes His Crow Breaded With A Light, Crispy Panko Crust" href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/DeemableTech_2015-03-06.mp3">#74 Ray Likes His Crow Breaded With A Light, Crispy Panko Crust</a></p>
<h1><strong>RUN DOWN</strong></h1>
<h3>Samsung Galaxy S6 &amp; S6 Edge</h3>
<p>This week was the Mobile World Congress in Barcelona Spain and Samsung used the opportunity to take the wraps off the next iteration of its flagship phone, the <a href="http://gizmodo.com/galaxy-s6-hands-on-samsungs-got-a-whole-new-look-1688066043" target="_blank">Samsung Galaxy S6</a>? <em>and</em> the <a href="http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2015/03/samsungs-new-flagship-smartphones-the-galaxy-s6-and-galaxy-s6-edge/" target="_blank">Samsung Galaxy S6 Edge</a>. That?s right, the S6 will come in two formats &ndash; a standard rectangular shape and a more curvy version with a display that wraps around the edge and which can display alerts by lighting up.</p>
<p>Regardless of what you think about Samsung?s latest gimmick, both phones are aimed squarely at the premium smartphone market. Samsung has ditched the removable plastic cases of previous Galaxy S?s for a phone that is completely encased in aluminum and Gorilla Glass, similar to the iPhone. The phone boasts an almost ridiculous Quad HD (2560 x 1440) Super AMOLED. Why would anyone need that kind of resolution on a 5.1 inch screen? Virtual Reality! You can strap your S6 into the latest version of Samsung?s Gear VR for a super-high-res virtual reality experience. Since the screen will be literally centimeters from your face, it has to look good.</p>
<p>Not all of Samsung?s longtime users are excited about the S6. The premium case materials means that the newest Galaxy phones no longer allow for a removable battery or an expandable SD memory card, two longstanding features of the Galaxy line.</p>
<p>Samsung Pay, formerly known as Loop Pay, with its magnetic card swiping technology, is built right into the phone.</p>
<p>Google announced that Google+, its one-time ambitious attempt to take on Facebook and Twitter, is going under the knife.</p>
<h3>Google+&nbsp;Divests</h3>
<p>The Verge is reporting that the <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/3/2/8131639/google-officially-splits-into-photos-and-streams" target="_blank">Google+ social network is getting split up into Streams, Photos and Hangouts</a>. It is also getting a new lead: Bradley Horowitz, a long time VP, is taking over from David Besbris. Besbris had held his position less than a year after Vic Gundotra was let go with little fanfare.</p>
<p>Google+ was originally pitched to be Google?s answer to rivals like Facebook and Twitter. In 2012 it took the controversial step of forcibly assigning every Google user across all of its services a Google+ account. Despite this, Google+ never reached the critical mass of user activity needed to take on the big guys. Google has since backed away from their one-size-fits-all approach.</p>
<p>Google execs are now calling the social network side of the product ?Streams? and considering them to be separate from Photos, home of the ridiculous Auto-Awesome feature, and Hangouts, Google?s free and easy-to-use chat and videoconferencing system.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.androidcentral.com/how-manually-make-auto-awesome-google" target="_blank">How to Auto-Awesome your photos manually &ndash; AndroidCentral</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>While Google has not officially announced the death of ?Streams? as a product, some experts are predicting it could be on the chopping block soon.</p>
<h3>Google Wireless</h3>
<p>According to Mashable, <a href="http://mashable.com/2015/03/02/google-confirms-wireless-carrier-service/" target="_blank">Google?s latest crazy plan is to become a wireless carrier</a>.</p>
<p>Google revealed this week at Mobile World Congress that it plans to get into the wireless carrier business, offering mobile voice and data service to customers. Google says that it will do this on a small scale, buying wholesale access from Sprint and T-Mobile?s networks and selling them to customers. Google says it wants to ?push the needle? when it comes to features offered to mobile customers, for instance allowing users to seamlessly transition between wifi and cellular connections.</p>
<p>Google was careful to emphasize that it does not intend to compete with AT&amp;T and Verizon and that they have been informed of its plans.</p>
<h2><strong>BIG STORY</strong><strong><strong><br></strong></strong></h2>
<p>Hillary Clinton used a personal email account the entire time she was US Secretary of State</p>
<p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/03/03/us/politics/hillary-clintons-use-of-private-email-at-state-department-raises-flags.html">http://www.nytimes.com/2015/03/03/us/politics/hillary-clintons-use-of-private-email-at-state-department-raises-flags.html</a></p>
<p>Clinton apparently set up an email account one week prior to President Obama&rsquo;s inauguration, and she did not use an official @state.gov email address.</p>
<p>For comparison, according to NBC News,&nbsp;Former secretary of State Condelezza Rice did not use personal email while she was in office, but she rarely used email at all.&nbsp;Clinton aides have also said that, Colin Powell did regularly use a personal e-mail account while Secretary of State.</p>
<p>A Powell aide confirmed that information, saying, &ldquo;General Powell used a personal email account during his tenure as Secretary of State. He was not aware of any restrictions nor does he recall being made aware of any over the four years he served at State.&rdquo;</p>
<p>According to the <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/clintons-use-of-personal-e-mail-at-state-dept-violated-obama-directive/2015/03/03/454d7938-c1b9-11e4-9271-610273846239_story.html" target="_blank">Washington Post</a>, &ldquo;Former secretary of state Hillary Rodham Clinton appears to have operated in violation of what the White House said Tuesday was ?very specific guidance? that members of the Obama administration use government e-mail accounts to carry out official business.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Hillary Clinton said on Twitter :</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en-gb"><p>I want the public to see my email. I asked State to release them. They said they will review them for release as soon as possible.</p>
<p>? Hillary Clinton (@HillaryClinton) <a href="https://twitter.com/HillaryClinton/status/573340998287413248">March 5, 2015</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async="" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<h2><strong>REVIEWS</strong></h2>
<h3><strong><strong>BACtrack MobileBreathalyzer Review</strong></strong></h3>
<p>Last year Ray&nbsp;received the BACtrack Mobile&nbsp;Breathalyzer, which, unsurprisingly, tracks your BAC or your blood alcohol content. In other words, it&rsquo;s a mobile Breathalyzer.</p>
<p>It&nbsp;is a really great product. (Disclaimer, BACtrack did provide a sample unit for review.) The BACtrack Mobile Breathalyzer connects with your Smartphone via Bluetooth.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s pretty comfortable to hold in your hand, and it is very easy to use. You just turn it on, open the BACtrack app and pair it with your phone via bluetooth and follow the on screen instructions.</p>
<p>It keeps track of your blood alcohol level over time while you are drinking, and it calculates how long it will take for you to be sober. In addition to a number calculation of your BAC, it give you an idea of where you should be feeling. It will say things like &ldquo;You are experiencing slight alcohol intoxication.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The strangest feature of the device is that it let&rsquo;s you post your blood alcohol level on social media. I personally never use that feature, but I can definitely see it going horribly, horribly wrong. I can only imagine the legal implications but it could possibly have too. But, it would help to explain all of those wacky drunk pictures.</p>
<p>If you are a frequent drinker, this breathalyzer has a great feature that will let you track when and where you drank. You can choose what you share otherwise it always stays private.</p>
<p>The BACtrack Mobile Breathalyzer cost $99 now. It was $149 when I reviewed it. I feel like it was worth $149, but I think that $99 is the perfect price point for the features it has.</p>
<p>Now, there are other breathalyzers that BACtrack makes that are cheaper. They have a model that uses a different sensor that only costs $49, and they have keychain models that do not connect to your smartphone that are $29.</p>
<p>Personally, I like the model that uses the same technology that the police use to check blood alcohol level, because if I am trusting something to check if I am below the legal limit or not, I want to be absolutely certain it is right!</p>
<p>That being said, this is in no way an endorsement to drive while intoxicated. It&rsquo;s never safe to drink under the influence of alcohol, and you can be arrested for DUI even if you&rsquo;re under the legal limit.</p>
<p>The thing that surprised me most about using the backtrack mobile breathalyzer was that I am apparently a cheap date. I was drunk long before the device said I was a legally drunk. Or, at least I felt like I was drunk.</p>
<p>It was crazy to me that at .02, I felt that I could not drive a car, but I was still legal to drive.</p>
<p>Check out the video of the review below:</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pIvLTUUm1I0" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>UNCUT!</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JqWQ195c7Kc" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#74 Ray Likes His Crow Breaded With A Light, Crispy Panko Crust" data-link="/2015/03/74-ray-likes-his-crow-breaded-with-a-light-crispy-panko-crust/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#74 Ray Likes His Crow Breaded With A Light, Crispy Panko Crust" data-link="/2015/03/74-ray-likes-his-crow-breaded-with-a-light-crispy-panko-crust/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/03/74-ray-likes-his-crow-breaded-with-a-light-crispy-panko-crust/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/03/DeemableTech_2015-03-06.mp3" length="36045929" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
