<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; The IT Crowd</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/the-it-crowd/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#82 Demand for Deemable Tech is Crazy Off The Hook!</title>
		<link>/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/</link>
		<comments>/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 21:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boeing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boeing 787]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Surface]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MS-DOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Powerwall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Surface]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The IT Crowd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9987</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/MarioKart-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Mario Kart" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week Tom&#160;brings the joyous news that Nintendoland is coming! Ray wants fast passes to the Mario Kart ride. But none of the guys want to ride on a Boeing 787 after Ray tells the guys that some of the <a href="/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/MarioKart-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Mario Kart" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week Tom&nbsp;brings the joyous news that Nintendoland is coming! Ray wants fast passes to the Mario Kart ride. But none of the guys want to ride on a Boeing 787 after Ray tells the guys that some of the planes are turning off&hellip; in mid air. Not good. Oculus finally announces a consumer model of the Oculus Rift. People are breaking/not breaking their Microsoft Surface 3 tablets. Twitter broke MS-DOS games, and&nbsp;Tesla just brought the future one step closer to today. All that on this week&rsquo;s episode.</p>
<p>But first, could we&nbsp;ask a favor of you? If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on our website, would you subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>? And, while you&rsquo;re there, would you leave a review and say a few nice things about us? The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="//media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="//media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-9987-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-08.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-08.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-08.mp3</a></audio><h1><a name="h.xvjwtmnq4snt"></a>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S&nbsp;RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3><a name="h.52mal8gpu9c8"></a>Nintendo Theme Park</h3>
<p>Who is up for Mario Kart in real life? <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.businessinsider.com%2Fnintendo-partnered-with-universal-studios-2015-5&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHBXxqKCVD6dQJ6jJMbbnq4IUyX-A">Nintendo announced during an earnings call this week</a>&nbsp;that it is partnering with Universal Parks and Resorts which runs the Universal Studios theme parks to create Nintendo-themed rides and attractions. Nintendo has not announced specific details on which of its properties it would adapt, but it seems like a safe bet that it will leverage long lasting and popular characters and games like Mario, Zelda and Donkey Kong. In fact, Universal executive Tom Schroder said pretty much exactly that in a press release: &ldquo;The immersive experiences will include major attractions at Universal?s theme parks and will feature Nintendo?s most famous characters and games.&rdquo;</p>
<h3><a name="h.chtqttd17zg"></a>Have you tried turning your plane off and on again?</h3>
<p>The FAA sent out a warning on May 1st that Boeing 787s may have some computer problems that could cause your terrible, terrible death. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fmashable.com%2F2015%2F05%2F01%2Ffaa-warns-of-bug-on-boeing-787%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHpr42SZ-Q17g9cTWkuLitARPC79w">Mashable reports</a>&nbsp;that the administration discovered the computers in 787s have a &ldquo;software counter&rdquo; that periodically shuts down all electrical systems, which results in &ldquo;loss of control of the airplane.&rdquo; Now, I&rsquo;m not an aviation expert, but I think that is a bad thing. Am I right in assuming that guys?</p>
<p>Boeing is working out a software update that will eliminate the problem, but until then, they have issued a work around. If you work in the IT industry or have ever worked technical support you are probably familiar with it:</p>
<p>&ldquo;Have you tried turning it off and on again?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Yes folks, it&rsquo;s the I.T. Crowd fix.</p>
<p>Call Roy and Moss or your plane will crash to the ground.</p>
<h3><a name="h.dxy8cs4kfy0p"></a>Oculus announces &ldquo;Q1 2016&rdquo; release for Rift</h3>
<p>In other news that is sure to have gamers everywhere jumping for joy, Oculus announced this week that the <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Fgaming%2F2015%2F05%2Foculus-announces-q1-2016-release-for-first-consumer-oculus-rift%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFqIkbhnovA8nKPyPA46K6bc4aeUg">first commercial release of their hotly anticipated virtual reality headset the Oculus Rift</a>&nbsp;will be in early 2016.</p>
<p>The company also released promotional images of the sleek final consumer product after several years of prototypes.</p>
<p>Oculus first made a splash at the E3 gaming expo in 2012, followed by a very successful Kickstarter campaign. They also kicked off a virtual reality race, with other big companies like Sony and Valve and HTC working on releasing their own VR products.</p>
<h3><a name="h.z3sx0snlkkb2"></a>How low can you go?</h3>
<p>One of the most interesting tablets to come out, other than the iPad, has definitely been the Microsoft Surface. Sure, it&rsquo;s had its share of troubles. It came out with Windows RT, which was this weird, stripped down version of Windows. It had two interfaces, the desktop and the &ldquo;tablet&rdquo; UI which really confused people. But, it was an incredible design that really changed the market, making it a serious contender for a laptop replacement. One of its signature features was the coveted kickstand that can hold the tablet in one of three positions. Well, now the Verge is reporting that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2015%2F5%2F5%2F8552361%2Fmicrosoft-surface-3-kickstand-secret-position&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEbF6-vUmOr1nwmHZTHk2rehCYQ6g">Redditors have discovered a secret fourth position for the Surface 3 kickstand</a>. Apparently, if you keep pressing the kickstand back after the third position it will break away and fold all the way back.</p>
<p>Microsoft said in a statement that the kickstand &ldquo;contains a safety mechanism unique to Surface 3 to help protect the device, but the mechanism is not designed for use as a fourth kickstand position.&rdquo;</p>
<p>So it might work once, twice or maybe even a few times, but it&rsquo;s probably going to ruin your Surface 3.</p>
<p>The lesson here is, don&rsquo;t play too rough with your toys. Just like a Slinky, once you bend it out of shape, you can&rsquo;t bend it back, no matter what happened in Toy Story.</p>
<h3>MS-DOS games on Twitter update</h3>
<p>Last week we told you how you can embed and play classic MS-DOS games in tweets. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theguardian.com%2Ftechnology%2F2015%2Fmay%2F04%2Ftwitter-kills-ms-dos-games-embedded-in-tweets&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNE6Ik7_hQBAUxmlYM6C49m8hpVt_A">Sadly, it looks like Twitter has put a stop to that. </a></p>
<p>It was discovered last week that Twitter users could embed these games from the Internet Archive?s site into tweets using Twitter?s Cards widget (that?s the system that allows videos, images and other media to be displayed in-line in the Twitter stream). But it turns out that embedding interactive media, specifically games, is against the terms of service for Twitter Cards.</p>
<p>You can, however, still play the MS-DOS games at the Internet Archive?s site, <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Farchive.org%2Fdetails%2Fsoftwarelibrary_msdos_games&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGqHjyZZyBFozCkw1Xnf43Qi2ZmxQ">archive.org.</a></p>
<h3><a name="h.lejhs5fy0tk3"></a>Powerwall</h3>
<p>Elon Musk, CEO of Tesla, the maker of powerful electric sports cars recently announced that his company will begin manufacturing batteries for homes. This week Elon Musk announced that demand for their ?Powerwall? batteries was ?<a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.engadget.com%2F2015%2F05%2F06%2Ftesla-powerwall-earnings%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGSKjl4SPWNblaSQLI8gnOkuKE24g">crazy off the hook</a>?. He said they have received over 38,000 reservations, a level of demand which could take them up to a year to fulfill. Orders included over 2,500 from companies for their commercial-ready Powerpack.</p>
<p>The Powerwall batteries are designed for a 24-hour charge-and-discharge cycle, which would be ideal in combination with a solar power system that could charge them during the day letting them run the house at night. The batteries are designed to be mounted on the wall and a 7kWh unit starts at $3,000.</p>
<p>Note from Ray: The Powerwall is apparently <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AacoxHFYvZw">not nearly as bad as the Power Glove</a>.</p>
<p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable&nbsp;dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#82 Demand for Deemable Tech is Crazy Off The Hook!" data-link="/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#82 Demand for Deemable Tech is Crazy Off The Hook!" data-link="/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-08.mp3" length="24373189" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
