<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Oculus</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/oculus/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#105 The Rumor Mill</title>
		<link>/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/</link>
		<comments>/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 20:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NetFlix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10391</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/01/Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="That rumor mill&#039;s a-churning. Image credit: Wikimedia Commons" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week, Ray, Tom and Sean delve into rumors about the next iPhone as well as Twitter&#8217;s famous 140-character limit. Plus, the latest about the Oculus Rift, and the story of a man who found more than he bargained for <a href="/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2016/01/Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="That rumor mill&#039;s a-churning. Image credit: Wikimedia Commons" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_10394" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2016/01/Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10394" src="//media/2016/01/Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square-300x300.jpg"  alt="That rumor mill's a-churning. Image credit: Wikimedia Commons" width="300" height="300"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">That rumor mill&rsquo;s a-churning. Image credit: Wikimedia Commons</p></div>
<p>This week, Ray, Tom and Sean delve into rumors about the next iPhone as well as Twitter&rsquo;s famous 140-character limit. Plus, the latest about the Oculus Rift, and the story of a man who found more than he bargained for in his Amazon cart.</p>
<p><span id="more-10391"></span></p>
<p>By the way, we don&rsquo;t just have a subreddit page for the fame and the glory. We have it because we want to know what you want us to talk about! We know you&rsquo;re purusing the tech news all week.&nbsp;Go to our subreddit page, <a href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">reddit.com/r/deemable</a>, and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down.</p>
<p>And make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show and leave a review&nbsp;<a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at&nbsp;<a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10391-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/01/DeemableTech_2016-01-14.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/01/DeemableTech_2016-01-14.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/01/DeemableTech_2016-01-14.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>Apple planning to remove headphone jack on the iPhone 7</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The rumor mill about the next iPhone is churning and this time it has come up with a doozy. In order to get the next version of the iPhone even slimmer, Apple is supposedly going to ditch the headphone jack. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These rumors actually started swirling about a month ago, but now </span><a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3055208/its-true-apple-will-drop-the-headphone-jack-to-make-the-iphone-7-slimmer-and-simpler" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fast Company has a new source which has confirmed them</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, along with adding new details: that the replacement will be a lightning jack with a headphone adaptor, or completely wireless EarPods.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fast Company also says that the next iPhone will employ a new noise-cancelling technology to improve sound quality. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Oculus Rift announces release date, final price</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The product that arguably has launched the current wave of excitement about virtual-reality-tech has finally gotten a price, and a date on which you will be able to buy it. That product, of course, is the Oculus Rift. The date? Sometime in March, assuming you pre-ordered, oh, last week. The price? $599.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/01/virtually-a-reality-oculus-rift-goes-on-sale/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Ars Technica</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, that scores you a cutting-edge VR headset, a head-tracking camera, an Xbox One controller, an Oculus remote, cables, a carrying case, and two games. That sounds pretty good, but note that it doesn&rsquo;t include the beefy high-end PC you&rsquo;ll need to plug your headset into.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If all you&rsquo;ve got at home right now is Sean Birch&rsquo;s Chromebook, expect to drop $1,500 to gain access to a high resolution universe of virtual wonder.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After two dev kits, which were priced at $300 and $350 respectively, and Oculus founder Palmer Lucky stating in an interview in October that the Rift would cost &ldquo;more than $350,&rdquo; many eager fans are experiencing sticker shock. They have taken to the internets to express their anger. </span><a href="http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/01/oculus-founder-apologizes-for-messaging-poorly-on-599-rift-price/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Outrage was so great that Palmer Lucky popped up on reddit to apologize for misleading people</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. That said, if you pre-order the Rift right now, you&rsquo;ll be lucky to get it by April, so clearly the high price has not been enough to discourage everyone.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Netflix gives customers socks for the holidays</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You probably remember the Netflix-and-chill button that Netflix recently released design specs for so DIY enthusiasts could build their own. Well the company has topped themselves with their latest DIY brainstorm &ndash; Netflix socks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you regularly binge watch so much that you fall asleep, Netflix socks are for you. These socks detect when you&rsquo;ve fallen asleep and send a pause signal to Netflix, so you won&rsquo;t miss a moment of Jessica Jones! You can check them out at </span><a href="https://makeit.netflix.com/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">makeit.netflix.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. There are even multiple snazzy templates for great Netflix-themed patterns! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just to be clear, you can&rsquo;t buy these &ndash; you have to make them! So get out your darning needles and soldering iron and get to work! If any Deemable Tech listeners are planning on building this or the Netflix button, we&rsquo;d love to see your work!</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Lenovo ditching the Motorola brand name, but keeping &ldquo;Moto&rdquo;</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Motorola was once a powerhouse in mobile phones, but it has been through a lot of changes lately. First it was purchased by Google, which launched the Moto X line of phones, and then it was sold to Lenovo. </span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/goodbye-moto-rola-iconic-brand-name-to-be-phased-out/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In an interview with Cnet this month</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> while at CES, Lenovo announced that it would begin phasing out the &ldquo;Motorola&rdquo; branding on its phones and replacing it with Lenovo branding. Lenovo will, however, be keeping the &ldquo;Moto&rdquo; name and the iconic &ldquo;batwing&rdquo; logo. So you can still say, &ldquo;Hello, Moto.&rdquo; But really, it is goodbye to Motorola as we know it.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Twitter to break the 140 character limit, probably for real this time</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are always endless rumors swirling that Twitter is about to increase its famous 140 character limit. And actually right now it looks like those rumors have some substance. </span></p>
<p><a href="http://recode.net/2016/01/05/twitter-considering-10000-character-limit-for-tweets/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to re/code</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, sources within the company say that tweets will still initially appear in your Twitter feed as 140 characters, but will then feature some kind of call to action which allows them to be expanded, showing up to 10,000 characters of text. This would be a pretty significant change for a company that has built its reputation on very brief messages. The same rumors also say that Twitter is experimenting with changing its reverse chronological timeline, another core feature from early days.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since Twitter went public in 2013 it has struggled to impress investors with steady growth. CEO Jack Dorsey and other company heads are definitely looking at radical changes to keep the social media giant relevant. </span></p>
<h3>IE is Dead, Long Live Edge&hellip; and IE</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Microsoft finally </span><a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/3021789/windows/microsoft-patch-tuesday-kills-off-windows-8-and-internet-explorer-8-9-and-10.html" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">buried Internet Explorers</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 8, 9 and 10. If you have one of them installed on your computer it will still work, but just like when Microsoft pulled the plug on Windows XP back in 2013, you won&rsquo;t receive any security updates anymore. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Speaking of operating systems, Windows killed another operating system this week. No, it wasn&rsquo;t Vista, it was Windows 8! If you&rsquo;re running Windows 8, you need to upgrade to 8.1 or 10, because you will no longer get bug fixes or security updates. Why did Microsoft skip Vista? Who knows, but our guess is that there is a very small user base running 8 compared to Vista. But the reaper is coming for Vista too. Vista will swim with the fishes in April 2017.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Customer finds unexpected dildo in his shopping cart after poor customer service experience at Amazon.de</h3>
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/01/amazon-customer-complains-finds-spiteful-10-inch-dildo-in-his-shopping-basket/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ars Technica reported on an unusual customer service snafu last week</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Not that customer service screw ups are unusual, but this one came from Amazon, typically known for their top notch customer service. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An IT contractor living in Ireland had ordered a textbook from Amazon.de, the Germany-based version of the site. Unfortunately he was shipped the wrong edition. After spending a great deal of time on the phone with a customer service rep, he was informed that the company did not have the right edition and they would only be able to credit him his money back.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Upset, the contractor left a negative review on a customer satisfaction survey.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A few days later he was browsing the site at work and noticed that there was something in his shopping basket. Not having added anything to the cart, he clicked to see what it was. At this point he discovered that a dildo known as &ldquo;The Hulk&rdquo; had been added to his basket. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since the contractor was at his job and was being observed by coworkers, including a woman, he was not pleased by this. He reports that he was able to get in touch with an executive at Amazon.de and had been credited with 100 euros for the incident. The company hinted that the dildo had been added to the contractor&rsquo;s basket by the customer service rep, but would not say if any steps had been taken to discipline the rep.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Image credit: Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill.jpg: Gabor Eszes (UED77)derivative work: WVhybrid at en.wikipedia (Glade_Creek_Grist_Mill.jpg) [<a href="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/fdl.html">GFDL</a> or <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC-BY-SA-3.0</a>], <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File%3AGlade_Creek_Grist_Mill-square.jpg">via Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#105 The Rumor Mill" data-link="/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#105 The Rumor Mill" data-link="/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2016/01/105-the-rumor-mill/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2016/01/DeemableTech_2016-01-14.mp3" length="36476269" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#87 The Episode Where We Don&#8217;t Talk About Soylent Because There&#8217;s Too Much News</title>
		<link>/2015/06/87-the-episode-where-we-dont-talk-about-soylent-because-theres-too-much-news/</link>
		<comments>/2015/06/87-the-episode-where-we-dont-talk-about-soylent-because-theres-too-much-news/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 18:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10090</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week, Ray, Tom and Sean look at some of the news coming out of&#160;Apple&#8217;s annual&#160;Wordwide Developers Conference (WWDC), including the unveiling of the latest version of the iOS mobile operating system and the new music streaming app Apple Music. <a href="/2015/06/87-the-episode-where-we-dont-talk-about-soylent-because-theres-too-much-news/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/06/87-the-episode-where-we-dont-talk-about-soylent-because-theres-too-much-news/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week, Ray, Tom and Sean look at some of the news coming out of&nbsp;Apple&rsquo;s annual&nbsp;Wordwide Developers Conference (WWDC), including the unveiling of the latest version of the iOS mobile operating system and the new music streaming app Apple Music. That and much more on this week&rsquo;s Deemable Tech!</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on our website, would you subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>? And, while you&rsquo;re there, would you leave a review and say a few nice things about us? The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="//media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="//media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there. We&rsquo;re also looking for a new admin to help manage and moderate our subreddit page. Submit a text post to our subreddit explaining why you would make a great admin.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10090-2" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-12_3.mp3?_=2"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-12_3.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-12_3.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>Apple WWDC&nbsp;2015</h3>
<p>This week Apple&nbsp;held their annual conference to showcase its new software to developers.&nbsp;Since there was so much to talk about, we are just going to focus on the stuff we found really interesting.&nbsp;For full coverage of the announcements made at WWDC 2015, check out <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.imore.com%2Feverything-you-need-know-about-wwdc-2015-keynote&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGbADMk3MLOvEUxDrItCFevv1crbQ" target="_blank">iMore&rsquo;s article about everything you need to know about they keynote</a>.</p>
<h4>iOS 9 to offer ad blocking</h4>
<p>Apple unveiled the latest version of its mobile operating system this week, and with it comes a host of new features.&nbsp;iOS 9 is going to have ad blocking for the first time ever. Specifically, Safari is going to allow extensions that include the ability to block ads. Publishers that depend on ad revenue to stay in business are super excited about this announcement.</p>
<h4>Six-digit passcodes</h4>
<p>In an effort to make their devices harder to break into, Apple revealed that newer iPhones and iPads that have TouchID and are running iOS 9 will be <a href="http://arstechnica.com/apple/2015/06/apple-to-require-6-digit-passcodes-on-newer-iphones-ipads-under-ios-9/" target="_blank">required to upgrade from a four-digit passcode to a six-digit one</a>. Passcodes will remain optional, but if you choose to use one you will have to change it to at least six alphanumeric digits.</p>
<p>Another safeguard they introduced: after 10 failed attempts to enter your passcode, your device will erase itself.</p>
<h4>iOS 9 brings multitasking to iPads</h4>
<p>iOS 9 will also introduce a <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2015%2F6%2F8%2F8737639%2Fapple-ipad-split-screen-multitasking-wwdc-2015&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGzgPEvtseUymuKYbkwyKGbw5huFg" target="_blank">long-expected feature for iPads: multitasking</a>. This comes in the form of three features, actually, called SlideOver, Splitview and picture-in-picture.</p>
<p>SlideOver will let you quickly slide in another app from a menu on the right side of the screen. For example, you could be using Safari to read restaurant reviews and then slide in Messages to message your friend. Other apps they showed taking advantage of this feature were the Calendar app and Notes.</p>
<p>There will also be a more traditional Split View mode where you can have your screen equally divided up between two apps running simultaneously and independent of each other.</p>
<p>There will also be a picture-in-picture mode that will let you have a small video player on top of other apps. Yes, Apple has finally added a feature all of our TVs had in 1993.</p>
<p>Not all of these features will be available on all devices. The Split View mode will only work on the iPad Air 2. SlideOver and picture-in-picture will be available on late 2013 or newer iPad Airs as well as all iPad Minis.</p>
<h4>iOS 9 brings battery life, performance boost</h4>
<p>Apple says that<a href="http://www.imore.com/ios-9s-performance-boosts-focus-efficiency-and-battery-life" target="_blank"> iOS 9 is all about making the existing hardware run better</a>. They said that they have seen an extra hour of battery life on the iPhone 6, and iOS 9 has a new lower power mode that can save iPhones an additional 3 hours of battery life.</p>
<h4>Apple News</h4>
<p>Apple News is Apple&rsquo;s latest attempt to disrupt a dying industry. This new app will be built into iOS 9, but fortunately it will replace the utterly useless hunk of trash app that was Newsstand. Instead of being what was essentially a folder for news and magazine apps, Apple News is going to be a a news curator app. You&rsquo;ll be able to read Sport Illustrated, the New York Times, Wired and tons of other top tier media and some not so top tier media like local newspapers, TV and radio stations.</p>
<p>According to Apple, the new app learns what you like and suggests similar content. We&rsquo;ll believe that when I see it. The promise of learning content has always been higher than the actual end product.</p>
<p>Apple News can include a lot of interactive features like charts, graphs, videos, and photos. So, it&rsquo;s basically just like Flipboard, except it&rsquo;s built into your iPhone. So, it&rsquo;s going to destroy Flipboard.</p>
<h4>Apple Swift programming language will be open-sourced</h4>
<p><a href="http://www.imore.com/swift-2-programming-language-will-become-open-source-project-apple">Apple Swift programming language is going to be open-sourced</a>. For the first time ever, developers will be able to create apps for iOS and OS X on a computer that isn&rsquo;t a Mac OS X. Don&rsquo;t get too excited Windows Developers, it only runs on Linux.</p>
<h4>Apple Music</h4>
<p>Apple&rsquo;s &ldquo;one more thing&rdquo; this year was Apple Music. Apple basically took Beats Music, Ping (you guys remember Ping, right?) and the new MySpace (you guys remember MySpace, right?) and stuck them in a Blendtec blender and poured out what was left and called it Apple Music. With Apple Music, you can listen for free to a 24 hour online radio stream called Beats 1, or you can listen to streaming music on-demand for $9.99 for a single membership or $14.99 for a family of up to six. They&rsquo;ll give you a free, three?month trial membership to get you hooked too.</p>
<p>So, yeah, Apple created a Spotify killer. Built into the iPhone and you&rsquo;ll be able to get it on Android too. That&rsquo;s fine, but apparently Apple thinks that you don&rsquo;t have enough social media accounts in your life, and you need one dedicated to communicating with your favorite artists with. You know, just like they thought when they came out with Ping. And it flopped. And, just like Justin Timberlake and the gang thought when they bought MySpace from News Corp and relaunched it as a social media site for musicians, and it? well we don&rsquo;t know what happened to it because we&rsquo;ve never been back for more than enough time to download our pictures and videos. But we&rsquo;ve heard it&rsquo;s a barren wasteland.</p>
<p>On Apple Music, you&rsquo;ll be able to get exclusive content like behind-the-scenes videos, intimate conversations with the artists and musicians can post blogs and updates on Apple Music. You know, just like they can do on Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Pinterest, Tumblr, and their own website.</p>
<h3>Oculus Rift reveals&nbsp;consumer version of virtual reality headset</h3>
<p>Oculus Rift held a major live event this week, <a href="http://www.anandtech.com/show/9374/oculus-rift-controllers-vr-games-and-software-features-announced">officially unveiling the consumer version of their long-awaited, greatly hyped VR headset</a>. Purportedly light and comfortable, the headset slips on like a baseball cap, is easily adjustable, and allows users to substitute their own headphones for the pair that comes with it. The screen is actually a pair of small, high-res LED screens set right in front of the user?s eyes.</p>
<p>Two controllers were announced. The one that it will ship with? The Xbox One wireless controller. Yep. A slightly more revolutionary controller called the Oculus Touch was also announced: this is a pair of thumbsticks with motion tracking and haptic feedback which the user holds in each hand. The Touch will release in 2016 but is not expected to be available when the Oculus Rift first launches.</p>
<p>Speaking of launching, you are probably wondering when exactly the Rift will launch and how much it will cost. That was one thing the press conference did not shed any light on. The company still says that it is targeting 2016 and there are rumors of a price point around $400.</p>
<h3>Comcast takes away woman&rsquo;s email address, gives it to new customer with the same name</h3>
<p>Cable internet provider Comcast is infamous for their poor customer service, and this next story is not going to help their reputation any. <a href="http://www.firstcoastnews.com/story/news/local/consumer/on-your-side/2015/06/10/put-it-back-the-way-it-was-thats-what-i-want/71031836/">Ken Amaro of First Coast News reports</a> that Comcast took thirteen year veteran customer Kathleen Cox?s email address away and gave it to another customer with the same name who had just signed up in Michigan. Kathleen had used her Comcast email address as her primary email account and when it was taken away lost access to all her emails. She said that it wasn?t until local news took up the story that Comcast finally returned the address to her. No word on whether she got her old emails back as well.</p>
<h3>Google Chrome will start pausing auto-playing Flash videos</h3>
<p>Google says that their next version of Chrome will roll out a feature <a href="http://gizmodo.com/future-versions-of-chrome-will-kill-flash-in-the-name-1709212263">that &ldquo;intelligently pauses&rdquo; Flash content that isn?t central to the web page</a>. This is in the interest of memory and battery life for laptops. By some estimates, disabling Flash while using Chrome on your laptop could give you 10-20% more battery life.</p>
<h3>PornHub crowdfunding sex tape shot in space</h3>
<p>Major porn site PornHub has launched <a href="http://gizmodo.com/pornhub-wants-your-money-to-make-a-porno-in-space-1710530225?utm_campaign=socialflow_gizmodo_facebook&amp;utm_source=gizmodo_facebook&amp;utm_medium=socialflow" target="_blank">a crowdfunding campaign on IndieGogo to raise money to shoot a sex tape in space</a>. The campaign is looking for $3.4 million in funding which takes into account chartering the flight, insurance, crew, equipment, as well as backer perks. PornHub has not specified who exactly they plan to fly with or the exact date they plan to film on. They do, however, have the actors picked out.</p>
<h3>Facebook payments</h3>
<p>And here&rsquo;s a story we apparently overlooked back in March that recently came to our attention. You can send your friends on Facebook money through Facebook messenger. If you have a debit card on file with Facebook (perhaps you have bought an ad or a dumb game), when you message someone on the Facebook messenger either the app or on the desktop website, you&rsquo;ll see a dollar sign with a circle around it. Click that button and you can send your friends money. Right now it doesn&rsquo;t cost anything to send or receive money via Facebook Messenger. Fortunately, you can set a PIN code for payments so that when you accidently leave your Facebook profile logged in and your friend or girlfriend &ldquo;hacks&rdquo; you, he or she won&rsquo;t be able to transfer all of your money to a new account.</p>
<h3>Reddit bans FatPeople Hate subreddit, throws angry redditors into an uproar</h3>
<p>Reddit, which bills itself as ?the front page of the internet?, and is of course where post the news stories we are working on for this podcast, <a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/6/11/8767035/fatpeoplehate-reddit-ban">saw some major drama this week</a>. Reddit has long had a policy of allowing people to create subreddits around virtually any topic they want, even when those topics are awful. There are subreddits devoted to racism, bigotry, and all kinds of vile stuff. Reddit generally leaves them alone, unless they start crossing certain lines.</p>
<p>This week, apparently, lines were crossed. Reddit banned five subreddits, the largest of which was one called FatPeopleHate, which boasted over 150,000 subscribers. At the risk of editorializing, FatPeopleHate was actually even worse than it sounded, as redditors there had linked to the Twitter feeds, YouTube channels and personal information of real people, allowing other redditors to pour abuse, bile and mockery on them. FatPeopleHate had also become very popular and was regularly voting threads to the top of reddit?s /r/all, the ?front page? of the internet?s front page.</p>
<p>Reddit said that FatPeopleHate and the other four subreddits had crossed the line by getting involved in harassment instead of just being about ideas. This did not go down well with a very vocal part of reddit?s userbase, who begin creating a flood of alternate subreddits like FatPeopleHate2 and FatterPeopleHate and filling up unrelated subreddits with angry posts about reddit CEO Ellen Pao.</p>
<p>This is not the first time reddit has had problems moderating its own users. There was similar outrage when it tried to crackdown on users posting images from the nude celebrity leaks last year and before that when it attempted to purge subreddits dedicated to ?creepshots?, where men shared sexualized pictures taken of women without their consent.</p>
<p>The problem for reddit is that it doesn?t even require an email address to sign up for the service, and creating a new subreddit is the work of a moment, thus creating a situation that is very difficult to moderate.</p>
<p>&mdash;</p>
<p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable&nbsp;dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#87 The Episode Where We Don't Talk About Soylent Because There's Too Much News" data-link="/2015/06/87-the-episode-where-we-dont-talk-about-soylent-because-theres-too-much-news/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#87 The Episode Where We Don't Talk About Soylent Because There's Too Much News" data-link="/2015/06/87-the-episode-where-we-dont-talk-about-soylent-because-theres-too-much-news/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/06/87-the-episode-where-we-dont-talk-about-soylent-because-theres-too-much-news/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-12_3.mp3" length="45129023" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#82 Demand for Deemable Tech is Crazy Off The Hook!</title>
		<link>/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/</link>
		<comments>/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 21:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boeing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boeing 787]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Surface]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MS-DOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Powerwall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Surface]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The IT Crowd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=9987</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/MarioKart-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Mario Kart" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week Tom&#160;brings the joyous news that Nintendoland is coming! Ray wants fast passes to the Mario Kart ride. But none of the guys want to ride on a Boeing 787 after Ray tells the guys that some of the <a href="/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/05/MarioKart-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Mario Kart" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week Tom&nbsp;brings the joyous news that Nintendoland is coming! Ray wants fast passes to the Mario Kart ride. But none of the guys want to ride on a Boeing 787 after Ray tells the guys that some of the planes are turning off&hellip; in mid air. Not good. Oculus finally announces a consumer model of the Oculus Rift. People are breaking/not breaking their Microsoft Surface 3 tablets. Twitter broke MS-DOS games, and&nbsp;Tesla just brought the future one step closer to today. All that on this week&rsquo;s episode.</p>
<p>But first, could we&nbsp;ask a favor of you? If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on our website, would you subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>? And, while you&rsquo;re there, would you leave a review and say a few nice things about us? The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="//media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="//media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-9987-3" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-08.mp3?_=3"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-08.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-08.mp3</a></audio><h1><a name="h.xvjwtmnq4snt"></a>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S&nbsp;RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3><a name="h.52mal8gpu9c8"></a>Nintendo Theme Park</h3>
<p>Who is up for Mario Kart in real life? <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.businessinsider.com%2Fnintendo-partnered-with-universal-studios-2015-5&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHBXxqKCVD6dQJ6jJMbbnq4IUyX-A">Nintendo announced during an earnings call this week</a>&nbsp;that it is partnering with Universal Parks and Resorts which runs the Universal Studios theme parks to create Nintendo-themed rides and attractions. Nintendo has not announced specific details on which of its properties it would adapt, but it seems like a safe bet that it will leverage long lasting and popular characters and games like Mario, Zelda and Donkey Kong. In fact, Universal executive Tom Schroder said pretty much exactly that in a press release: &ldquo;The immersive experiences will include major attractions at Universal?s theme parks and will feature Nintendo?s most famous characters and games.&rdquo;</p>
<h3><a name="h.chtqttd17zg"></a>Have you tried turning your plane off and on again?</h3>
<p>The FAA sent out a warning on May 1st that Boeing 787s may have some computer problems that could cause your terrible, terrible death. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fmashable.com%2F2015%2F05%2F01%2Ffaa-warns-of-bug-on-boeing-787%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHpr42SZ-Q17g9cTWkuLitARPC79w">Mashable reports</a>&nbsp;that the administration discovered the computers in 787s have a &ldquo;software counter&rdquo; that periodically shuts down all electrical systems, which results in &ldquo;loss of control of the airplane.&rdquo; Now, I&rsquo;m not an aviation expert, but I think that is a bad thing. Am I right in assuming that guys?</p>
<p>Boeing is working out a software update that will eliminate the problem, but until then, they have issued a work around. If you work in the IT industry or have ever worked technical support you are probably familiar with it:</p>
<p>&ldquo;Have you tried turning it off and on again?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Yes folks, it&rsquo;s the I.T. Crowd fix.</p>
<p>Call Roy and Moss or your plane will crash to the ground.</p>
<h3><a name="h.dxy8cs4kfy0p"></a>Oculus announces &ldquo;Q1 2016&rdquo; release for Rift</h3>
<p>In other news that is sure to have gamers everywhere jumping for joy, Oculus announced this week that the <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Farstechnica.com%2Fgaming%2F2015%2F05%2Foculus-announces-q1-2016-release-for-first-consumer-oculus-rift%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFqIkbhnovA8nKPyPA46K6bc4aeUg">first commercial release of their hotly anticipated virtual reality headset the Oculus Rift</a>&nbsp;will be in early 2016.</p>
<p>The company also released promotional images of the sleek final consumer product after several years of prototypes.</p>
<p>Oculus first made a splash at the E3 gaming expo in 2012, followed by a very successful Kickstarter campaign. They also kicked off a virtual reality race, with other big companies like Sony and Valve and HTC working on releasing their own VR products.</p>
<h3><a name="h.z3sx0snlkkb2"></a>How low can you go?</h3>
<p>One of the most interesting tablets to come out, other than the iPad, has definitely been the Microsoft Surface. Sure, it&rsquo;s had its share of troubles. It came out with Windows RT, which was this weird, stripped down version of Windows. It had two interfaces, the desktop and the &ldquo;tablet&rdquo; UI which really confused people. But, it was an incredible design that really changed the market, making it a serious contender for a laptop replacement. One of its signature features was the coveted kickstand that can hold the tablet in one of three positions. Well, now the Verge is reporting that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2015%2F5%2F5%2F8552361%2Fmicrosoft-surface-3-kickstand-secret-position&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEbF6-vUmOr1nwmHZTHk2rehCYQ6g">Redditors have discovered a secret fourth position for the Surface 3 kickstand</a>. Apparently, if you keep pressing the kickstand back after the third position it will break away and fold all the way back.</p>
<p>Microsoft said in a statement that the kickstand &ldquo;contains a safety mechanism unique to Surface 3 to help protect the device, but the mechanism is not designed for use as a fourth kickstand position.&rdquo;</p>
<p>So it might work once, twice or maybe even a few times, but it&rsquo;s probably going to ruin your Surface 3.</p>
<p>The lesson here is, don&rsquo;t play too rough with your toys. Just like a Slinky, once you bend it out of shape, you can&rsquo;t bend it back, no matter what happened in Toy Story.</p>
<h3>MS-DOS games on Twitter update</h3>
<p>Last week we told you how you can embed and play classic MS-DOS games in tweets. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theguardian.com%2Ftechnology%2F2015%2Fmay%2F04%2Ftwitter-kills-ms-dos-games-embedded-in-tweets&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNE6Ik7_hQBAUxmlYM6C49m8hpVt_A">Sadly, it looks like Twitter has put a stop to that. </a></p>
<p>It was discovered last week that Twitter users could embed these games from the Internet Archive?s site into tweets using Twitter?s Cards widget (that?s the system that allows videos, images and other media to be displayed in-line in the Twitter stream). But it turns out that embedding interactive media, specifically games, is against the terms of service for Twitter Cards.</p>
<p>You can, however, still play the MS-DOS games at the Internet Archive?s site, <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Farchive.org%2Fdetails%2Fsoftwarelibrary_msdos_games&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGqHjyZZyBFozCkw1Xnf43Qi2ZmxQ">archive.org.</a></p>
<h3><a name="h.lejhs5fy0tk3"></a>Powerwall</h3>
<p>Elon Musk, CEO of Tesla, the maker of powerful electric sports cars recently announced that his company will begin manufacturing batteries for homes. This week Elon Musk announced that demand for their ?Powerwall? batteries was ?<a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.engadget.com%2F2015%2F05%2F06%2Ftesla-powerwall-earnings%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGSKjl4SPWNblaSQLI8gnOkuKE24g">crazy off the hook</a>?. He said they have received over 38,000 reservations, a level of demand which could take them up to a year to fulfill. Orders included over 2,500 from companies for their commercial-ready Powerpack.</p>
<p>The Powerwall batteries are designed for a 24-hour charge-and-discharge cycle, which would be ideal in combination with a solar power system that could charge them during the day letting them run the house at night. The batteries are designed to be mounted on the wall and a 7kWh unit starts at $3,000.</p>
<p>Note from Ray: The Powerwall is apparently <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AacoxHFYvZw">not nearly as bad as the Power Glove</a>.</p>
<p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable&nbsp;dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#82 Demand for Deemable Tech is Crazy Off The Hook!" data-link="/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#82 Demand for Deemable Tech is Crazy Off The Hook!" data-link="/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/05/82-demand-for-deemable-tech-is-crazy-off-the-hook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/05/DeemableTech_2015-05-08.mp3" length="24373189" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
