<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Elon Musk</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/elon-musk/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#94 Windows 10 Is Out But We’re Still Sticking With Windows 9</title>
		<link>/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/</link>
		<comments>/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 22:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiat Chrysler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Firefox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet.org]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smart Guns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stephen Hawking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Wozniak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10183</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/Windows10cropped-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="So much for Windows 10 fun. Now Ray has to reinstall Windows 8.1 just so he can upgrade it to 10, so he can reinstall Windows 10!" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Killer robots, self-aware robots, cars, guns and Android phones getting hacked into and the death of another Google product? Yeah, that sounds like a typical Deemable Tech episode. If you?re listening to Deemable Tech on the&#160;website, make sure to&#160;subscribe to <a href="/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/07/Windows10cropped-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="So much for Windows 10 fun. Now Ray has to reinstall Windows 8.1 just so he can upgrade it to 10, so he can reinstall Windows 10!" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_10185" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img class="size-medium wp-image-10185" src="/media/2015/07/Windows10cropped-300x212.jpg" alt="So much for Windows 10 fun. Now Ray has to reinstall Windows 8.1 just so he can upgrade it to 10, so he can reinstall Windows 10!" width="300" height="212"><p class="wp-caption-text">So much for Windows 10 fun. Now Ray has to reinstall Windows 8.1 just so he can upgrade it to 10, so he can reinstall Windows 10!</p></div>
<p>Killer robots, self-aware robots, cars, guns and Android phones getting hacked into and the death of another Google product? Yeah, that sounds like a typical Deemable Tech episode.</p>
<p>If you?re listening to Deemable Tech on the&nbsp;website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you?re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="//reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there. We?re also looking for a new admin to help manage and moderate our subreddit page. Submit a text post to our subreddit explaining why you would make a great admin.</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10183-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-31.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-31.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-31.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK?S RUNDOWN</h1>
<h3><strong>Windows 10 is released.</strong></h3>
<p>Our top story this week is the long-awaited release of Microsoft?s Windows 10. In an unprecedented move, Microsoft has made the new Windows available as a free upgrade to anyone who had Windows 7, 8 or 8.1. The upgrade became available to download for most of those folks starting on Wednesday.</p>
<p>With Windows 10, Microsoft hopes to reunite its fractured userbase, many of whom are still stuck way back on Windows XP. Windows 10 will feature continuous upgrades and may be the last major windows version for the foreseeable future. To lure back customers scared off by the controversial Windows 8, Windows 10 brings back the Start Button and does away with the charms menu.</p>
<p>Other new features include the integration of Microsoft?s Siri-like virtual assistant Cortana, the brand new Edge web browser, virtual desktops, and Mission Control, which gives you an overview of all the apps you have running.</p>
<p>Ray Hollister has bravely volunteered to install Windows the 10th on the dual boot partition of his MacBook, so let?s dive right in.</p>
<p>The beauty of Windows 10 is that you can&rsquo;t install Windows 10 as a fresh, clean install. Except you can. But you can&rsquo;t.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/antonyleather/2015/07/30/windows-10-updating-reinstalling-and-activation-guide-essential-advice-to-avoid-problems/">Forbes &ndash; Windows 10 Updating, Reinstalling And Activation Guide: Essential Advice To Avoid Problems</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/29/9058825/windows-10-macbook-how-to-install-osx">The Verge &ndash; How to get Windows 10 on your Mac</a></p>
<h3><strong>CEO of Mozilla Firefox complains in an open letter that Windows 10 upgrade resets default web browser</strong></h3>
<p>Mozilla CEO Chris Beard is one person who is less than pleased with Windows 10. It appears that when you do an upgrade with ?Express Settings? that <a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2015/07/windows-10-upgrade-resets-your-default-browser-to-edge-mozilla-is-very-unhappy/">it will default your browser to Microsoft?s Edge browser</a>, even if you had Firefox selected by default before. Even worse, in Windows 10 the default browser is now buried down in the settings control panel, meaning that it is difficult to find for non-technical users. Microsoft defends the changes as making the upgrade ?simple and cohesive? for users and says that they may make ?improvements? in the future.</p>
<h3><strong>Facebook builds an Internet drone</strong></h3>
<p>The BBC is reporting that <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-33728704">Facebook has built a drone</a>, with the wingspan of a Boeing 737 that will fly as high as 90,000 feet and for up to 90 days at a time to provide wireless Internet access at up to 10 Gigabits per second.</p>
<p>The drone will communicate via a laser beam that can hit a target the size of a dime more than 10 miles away. The lasers will connect the drones together and to the ground.</p>
<p>This is part of Facebook&rsquo;s Internet.org project to bring Internet access to the developing world. No word on whether this will be like Internet.org&rsquo;s last launch which only included access to a few sites, which caused a bit of a backlash since the access gave an unfair advantage to those sites.</p>
<p>Facebook will be testing the drones later this year in the United States.</p>
<h3><strong>Google+ dies a slow and painful death</strong></h3>
<p>Google?s ill-fated Facebook competitor, Google+, courted a lot of controversy in 2013 when Google started requiring users to create a Google+ profile to comment on YouTube. This week on the official Google blog, <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2015/07/everything-in-its-right-place.html">the search giant announced that they would be hitting the ?undo? button on that policy</a>. They said that a Google account would be all you need to share content, create contacts, comment on YouTube, and more, across all of Google. This change will reportedly be rolled out ?in the coming months.? This announcement comes on the heels of Google splitting Google+ in two, with Google Photos becoming its own stand-alone service and app.</p>
<h3><strong>Killer Robots</strong></h3>
<p>I posted this on our Facebook page, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Deemable">facebook.com/Deemable</a>, but it bears repeating. As a general rule, everyone here at Deemable Tech is anti-killer robots.</p>
<p>Unless, as I said, the uprising has already happened, in which case, let me rephrase that: How may we serve you, robot masters?</p>
<p>I bring this all up because Elon Musk (you know, Iron Man, the guy who brought you PayPal, Tesla, SpaceX, the Hyperloop, and who plans to die on Mars) and Steve Wozniak, (the reason why you have a computer at your desk, smartphone in your pocket and ultimately why you&rsquo;re listening to this podcast) and Stephen Hawking (who you&rsquo;ll know as the guy who played poker with Data, Albert Einstein and Isaac Newton.) and have joined a letter calling for the banning of autonomous weapons.</p>
<p>We talked about a weaponized drone last week that had a gun attached to it, well imagine an autonomous drone with a gun. The icons aren&rsquo;t as concerned about them throwing a revolution and killing humanity as they are concerned about another cold war arms race where every country tries to build bigger, better faster killing machines. But considering a <a href="http://www.slashgear.com/nao-robot-becomes-self-aware-very-briefly-20393569/">robot recently demonstrated self awareness</a>, perhaps they should be concerned about a robot uprising too.</p>
<h3><strong>Hacking Smart Rifles</strong></h3>
<p>Speaking of things that shouldn&rsquo;t be connected to the Internet, like killer robots. As much as I love my connected light bulbs, switches and thermostat, The Internet of things is not necessarily a good thing. Not everything should be connected to the Internet. Case in point, smart guns. In case you didn&rsquo;t know, <a href="http://tracking-point.com/">TrackingPoint makes an smart rifle</a> that almost anyone can use to hit a bullseye up to a mile away. The gun, which sells for $13,000, has a computer screen for a scope where you can enter wind speed, ammunition weight and distance. The computer calculates the correct aim and after you pull the trigger, it waits until you have the shot lined up perfectly before firing the gun.</p>
<p>The Mirror is reporting that a couple of <a href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/technology-science/technology/hackers-force-gun-blast-wrong-6171684">married hackers have hacked the gun wirelessly to shoot 2.5 feet away from the intended target</a>. They also managed to get it to disable the firing pin, making the gun unable to fire.</p>
<h3><strong>Android hack</strong></h3>
<p>Speaking of hacks, <a href="http://news.wjct.org/post/major-flaw-android-phones-would-let-hackers-just-text">NPR is reporting that the security firm Zimperium says there&rsquo;s a &ldquo;gaping hole&rdquo; in Android</a> that would allow hackers to take over your phone, and all they need is your phone number.</p>
<p>The app Hangouts automatically processes videos when they are received by text message. So, all a hacker has to do is send a video with malware inside it and send it to your phone. Since Hangouts instantly processes the videos, there&rsquo;s nothing you can do to stop it.</p>
<p>Google has released a patch and manufacturers have been notified, but we&rsquo;ll see how long it takes for them to get the update sent out to users.</p>
<h3><strong>Fiat Chrysler follow-up</strong></h3>
<p>Last week we reported that if you had a Jeep Cherokee with Fiat Chrysler?s ?uConnect? system, hackers could remotely take control of your vehicle and destroy everyone that you hold dear. It turns out that this was a source of some concern to Chrysler Fiat, as they have issued an official recall for 1.4 million vehicles to patch the issue. Affected models include certain Dodge Rams, Dodge Vipers, Dodge Chargers, Dodge Challengers, Chrysler 200s and 300s, and of course Jeep Grand Cherokees, all model year 2013 or later. If you are driving one of those vehicles you should check to see if your specific model is affected. The recall does not actually require the vehicles to be taken to the dealer: affected owners will receive a USB device which can be used to load the patch into their uConnect systems.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/07/gadget-hacks-gm-cars-locate-unlock-start/"><strong>Wired &ndash; This Gadget Hacks GM Cars to Locate, Unlock, and Start Them</strong></a></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/07/94-windows-10-is-out-but-were-still-sticking-with-windows-9/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/07/DeemableTech_2015-07-31.mp3" length="38005829" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
