<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Apple iPad</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/apple-ipad/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Amanda asks, &#8220;How can I restrict in-app purchases on my iPad?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2014/06/amanda-asks-can-restrict-app-purchases-ipad/</link>
		<comments>/2014/06/amanda-asks-can-restrict-app-purchases-ipad/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 19:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[in-app purchases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parental controls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restrictions]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8862</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/06/child_ipad-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Brad Flickinger / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Q: Our family recently got our first iPad. We want the kids to be allowed to use it, but I am worried that they will get into trouble with it. Many of the games on the iPad ask you to <a href="/2014/06/amanda-asks-can-restrict-app-purchases-ipad/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2014/06/amanda-asks-can-restrict-app-purchases-ipad/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/06/child_ipad-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: Brad Flickinger / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><script id="prx-p121195-embed" src="http://www.prx.org/p/121195/embed.js?size=small"></script></p>
<p><strong>Q: </strong>Our family recently got our first iPad. We want the kids to be allowed to use it, but I am worried that they will get into trouble with it. Many of the games on the iPad ask you to buy things. I don&rsquo;t want my kids running up a big credit card bill! Is there a way to stop this from happening?<span id="more-8862"></span></p>
<p><strong>A:</strong> Great question, Amanda. In-app purchases are an issue with smartphones and tablets that not nearly enough parents are aware of. In fact, we&rsquo;ve heard news stories about kids accidentally running up thousands of dollars in charges in their favorite mobile game. Fortunately, iPhones and iPads both come with built-in tools that allow parents to control what their kids are getting into.</p>
<div id="attachment_8863" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2014/06/child_ipad.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-8863 size-medium" src="/media/2014/06/child_ipad-300x220.jpg"  alt="Image credit: Brad Flickinger / Flickr" width="300" height="220"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: Brad Flickinger / Flickr</p></div>
<p>Open the Settings icon on your iPad, and look for &ldquo;Restrictions&rdquo; under &ldquo;General&rdquo;. Tap &ldquo;enable restrictions&rdquo; and you&rsquo;ll be asked to create a passcode. Be sure to use a different passcode than the one you use to lock your device, since your kids probably already know that code.</p>
<p>After you&rsquo;ve created the passcode, you&rsquo;ll see a list of features you can restrict access to, including in-app purchases, Safari and even the camera. Tap the button next to &ldquo;in-app purchases&rdquo; and any other feature you want to be restricted (that button will be green when the feature isn&rsquo;t restricted, and white when the restriction is on). This will turn off these features.</p>
<p>Now keep in mind, Amanda, that when <em>you</em> enter that passcode to make an in-app purchase, the restriction will be turned off for 15 minutes by default. If you&rsquo;re worried that you might put down your iPad and one of your kids might rush over and start buying things within that window, you can set it to ask for the passcode every single time. Go back to the &ldquo;Restrictions&rdquo; screen, re-enter your code and scroll down to the option that says &ldquo;Require password&rdquo;. Tap that and select &ldquo;Immediately&rdquo;. Now the iPad will require the passcode every time anyone tries to make an in-app purchase.</p>
<p>Android devices also have the power to restrict in-app purchases. On your Android tablet or smartphone, open the Play Store (the app you use to download other apps) and go to the settings menu. There you will see an option that says &ldquo;Use password to restrict purchases&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Android doesn&rsquo;t have as many built-in parental control features as iOS does, but there are a ton of great parental control apps out there. You can find them by searching &ldquo;parental controls&rdquo; in the Play Store.</p>
<p>Whether you&rsquo;ve got a table or a smartphone, iOS or Android, there are a many easy-to-use options to allow your family to safely enjoy their new toy.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/06/amanda-asks-can-restrict-app-purchases-ipad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Glen asks, &#8220;How do I set up a home Wi-Fi network?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2014/05/glen-asks-set-home-wi-fi-network/</link>
		<comments>/2014/05/glen-asks-set-home-wi-fi-network/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 10:38:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wi-Fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wireless router]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8813</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/05/wireless_router-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="The wireless router: your pathway to the land of Wi-Fi.

Credit: Wikimedia Commons" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2014/05/glen-asks-set-home-wi-fi-network/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/05/wireless_router-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="The wireless router: your pathway to the land of Wi-Fi.

Credit: Wikimedia Commons" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><script id="prx-p119220-embed" src="http://www.prx.org/p/119220/embed.js?size=small">// <![CDATA[


<strong>Q: I just got an iPad Mini. I already have a computer connected to the internet at home, and I'm wondering what equipment I need to set up Wi-Fi to use with the iPad. I have never had wireless in my house.<span id="more-8813">

<strong>A: Setting up a wireless network for your home is a fairly easy process, Glen. To get started, you'll need to purchase a device called a wireless router from your local electronics store or online. Before you do, though, there are a few things you need to know.


[caption id="attachment_8814" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="/media/2014/05/wireless_router.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-8814" src="/media/2014/05/wireless_router-300x201.jpg" alt="The wireless router: your pathway to the land of Wi-Fi. Credit: Wikimedia Commons" width="300" height="201" /> The wireless router: your pathway to the land of Wi-Fi.
Credit: Wikimedia Commons[/caption]



First of all, you'll want to make sure that the router you buy will support the right Wi-Fi standards for your needs. The most common ones you'll see these days are G, N and AC, with the speed of the connection increasing in that order. A lot of wireless devices (including your new iPad) will work with G, but we recommend going with an N router (this will be listed on the package). All routers support older standards, so don't worry that getting a new one will stop your older devices from connecting with it.

At your house, you're most likely connected to the internet through a cable or phone line coming out of the wall (depending on whether you have cable internet or DSL). That line plugs into a device commonly known as a modem, which decodes the signal into something computers can understand. Another line coming from your modem is currently plugged into your computer's network card (this will be an Ethernet cable, which sort of looks like a phone cord only bigger).

When you get your router, you'll need to unplug that Ethernet cable from your computer, and plug it into the router instead. Then you'll connect your computer to the router with another Ethernet cable. Now all of the internet traffic going to your computer and iPad will be routed through the router (which is why they call it... well, you get the idea).

Most router manufacturers include an easy-to-follow "quick setup" manual that will guide you through setting it up. These steps will be different from router to router, but here are a few general things to keep in mind:


<ul>

	
<li>Place your router somewhere relatively high up and free from obstruction. This will help to ensure that your Wi-Fi signal reaches as far as possible without interference. You should especially avoid placing it near large metal objects.









<ul>

	
<li>Make sure you turn on wireless security on the router (you should be given the option during installation). This will require anyone wanting to use your wireless network to enter a password. You'll see a few different security protocols to choose from in the setup, including WPA, WPA2 and WEP. We recommend using WPA or WPA2, because WEP is the weakest of the three. Make sure you come up with a strong password that can't be easily guessed by your neighbors. An unsecured network will allow them to use up your bandwidth, or worse, hack into your computers.









<ul>

	
<li>Your router will also have a host of other settings that you can change through its control panel, which you can access by entering a special address into your web browser. This is often something like "routerlogin.com" or a string of numbers like "192.168.0.1" - the specific address for your router, as well as the login information for that control panel, will be listed in the user manual.









<ul>

	
<li>You'll have the option to give your new wireless network a name while you're setting up. Some people go with the default one that comes with the router, but feel free to name it whatever you want. We suggest "Deemable Tech Is Da Bomb," but that's just us.








Once you've got everything ready, Glen, get out your new iPad. Open Settings, tap "Wi-Fi", and you should see your new Wi-Fi network in the list of available ones. Select it, enter your password and connect. If you can reach the internet from your iPad, congratulations! You just set up a home Wi-Fi network!
// ]]&gt;
// ]]&gt;</script></p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/05/glen-asks-set-home-wi-fi-network/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Casey asks, &#8220;Should I buy a tablet or an eReader?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2014/01/casey-asks-buy-tablet-ereader/</link>
		<comments>/2014/01/casey-asks-buy-tablet-ereader/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 11:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eBooks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eReaders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Nexus 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablets]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8526</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/01/kindle_ipad-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: kodomut / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Q: I enjoy reading and want to start reading more eBooks, but I don&#8217;t know if I should get a tablet or an eReader. Do you have any suggestions? A: That&#8217;s a tough one, Casey! Tablets like the iPad, the <a href="/2014/01/casey-asks-buy-tablet-ereader/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2014/01/casey-asks-buy-tablet-ereader/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2014/01/kindle_ipad-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image credit: kodomut / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><script id="prx-p108970-embed" src="http://www.prx.org/p/108970/embed.js?size=small"></script></p>
<p><strong>Q: </strong>I enjoy reading and want to start reading more eBooks, but I don&rsquo;t know if I should get a tablet or an eReader. Do you have any suggestions?<span id="more-8526"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_8527" style="width: 373px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2014/01/kindle_ipad.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class=" wp-image-8527    " src="/media/2014/01/kindle_ipad.jpg"  alt="Image credit: kodomut / Flickr" width="363" height="203"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: kodomut / Flickr</p></div>
<p><strong>A: </strong>That&rsquo;s a tough one, Casey! Tablets like the iPad, the Nexus and the Kindle Fire can make great eReaders in addition to everything else they do. But dedicated eReaders like the regular Kindle or the Nook are tailored to the reading experience. There are definitely major differences between the two.</p>
<p>The most obvious difference is the screen. Tablets have backlit screens, while Kindles and Nooks have e-ink screens which are lit from the front or not at all. Some people find a backlit screen to be hard on their eyes over long periods of time, but a backlit screen is a plus if you&rsquo;re reading in the dark. Some eReaders like the Kindle Paperwhite and the Nook GlowLight also have built-in lighting, but they are front lit so the light doesn&rsquo;t shine in your eyes.</p>
<p>If you enjoy reading at the beach, an eReader is your best bet. Direct sunlight will wash out a backlit screen, making it hard to read (even in the shade you may have glare issues). If you&rsquo;re reading mostly indoors or on an airplane this won&rsquo;t be a problem for you.</p>
<p>A great thing about the e-ink screens on dedicated eReaders is that it doesn&rsquo;t even feel like you&rsquo;re looking at a screen. A good eReader very closely mirrors the experience of reading a good old fashioned paperback.</p>
<p>On the flip side, if you want to read magazines, comic books, graphic novels, or just non-fiction books with photos or charts, you&rsquo;ll really want to get a tablet. eReaders only have black-and-white screens. And while e-ink screens are great for reading, they don&rsquo;t come anywhere near the picture quality you&rsquo;ll find on tablets. Reading full color comic books on your retina display tablet is really a treat.</p>
<p>Another thing you need to consider is battery life. Most tablets will last you eight hours or so. eReaders, on the other hand, can last for <i>weeks</i> between charges. On a long plane ride, a dedicated eReader will last you way longer than a tablet.</p>
<p>A bigger consideration for many people is price. The cheapest Nexus 7 tablet is $229, while the cheapest iPad, the iPad Mini, starts at $399. The Kindle starts as low as $69, as long as you don&rsquo;t mind seeing ads on your screensaver. What will make the higher price worth it for some people is that you can do a lot more than just read books on your iPad. Tablets can run apps, play games, check email and surf the web.</p>
<p>So, getting back to your question, which one should you choose? Well, if you&rsquo;re a casual reader who wants to read some books and run apps then look into getting a tablet. They make good eReaders and they do a lot of other fun stuff too.</p>
<p>Zealous readers or people who like taking books to the beach should consider a dedicated reading device like the Kindle. Not only will it be easier to read outdoors, but it will only cost $69 to replace when you accidentally drop it in a tide pool.</p>
<p>Speaking of which, whatever device you decide to buy, do yourself a favor and get a case!</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2014/01/casey-asks-buy-tablet-ereader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Michael asks, &#8220;How do you move to a new iPad?&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2013/09/michael-asks-move-new-ipad/</link>
		<comments>/2013/09/michael-asks-move-new-ipad/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 10:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Segments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad mini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[question]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio segments]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=8311</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/ipads-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image Credit: Ben Miller / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Q: My son recently gave his mother an iPad as a birthday gift. He bought it earlier this year, but he decided he wanted an iPad mini instead. What&#8217;s the best way to delete all of his data and accounts <a href="/2013/09/michael-asks-move-new-ipad/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/09/michael-asks-move-new-ipad/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/09/ipads-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Image Credit: Ben Miller / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><script id="prx-p103616-embed" src="http://www.prx.org/p/103616/embed.js?size=small"></script></p>
<p><strong>Q:</strong> My son recently gave his mother an iPad as a birthday gift. He bought it earlier this year, but he decided he wanted an iPad mini instead. What&rsquo;s the best way to delete all of his data and accounts on the iPad, and get him moved over to the&nbsp;iPad Mini without losing all of his emails, contacts, music and apps?</p>
<div id="attachment_8312" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/media/2013/09/ipads.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-8312" alt="Image Credit: Ben Miller / Flickr" src="/media/2013/09/ipads-300x200.jpg"  width="300" height="200"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image Credit: Ben Miller / Flickr</p></div>
<p><strong>A:</strong> It is really important to clear your iPad out before you give it to someone else. You don&rsquo;t want to hand out your personal information when you sell or give someone your iPad or iPhone. But, it&rsquo;s also good to do, even if the only reason is so that the other person has more room for their own stuff. So, here&rsquo;s what you do on your iPad to clear it out.</p>
<p>First, you want to back it up and sync it with his computer before you do anything to it. Backing it up saves his settings, Messages, photos in his Camera Roll, documents, saved games, and other data. Syncing his iPad saves all of his downloadable purchased content such as movies, music, podcasts, and apps.</p>
<p>In general, you should sync and back up any iOS device, like an iPad, iPhone or iPod touch once a day, but if you only back it up once every couple of weeks, or even once a month, it&rsquo;s OK. I won&rsquo;t tell on you. Just keep in mind, you could lose anything that&rsquo;s on your iPad at any time since the last time you backed up and synced your iPad. So, the more often you back it up and sync it, the better.</p>
<p>Just plug his iPad into his computer, and you&rsquo;ll be able to back it up and sync it in iTunes. Once you&rsquo;re done with that you can take his iPad Mini and plug it into his computer, and restore it using the backup you just made of his old iPad. Just plug it in, and tap Restore iPad. If it asks you which backup to use, make sure to choose the most recent backup. Once iTunes is done restoring and syncing his content, he should have everything back and it should look just like his old iPad. Of course, it will look a little smaller since it is an iPad mini.</p>
<p>Now, the next step is to wipe the old iPad. Now, don&rsquo;t take this step lightly. Once you&rsquo;ve done it it cannot be undone. His iPad will be completely wiped clean, and it will look brand new like the day he bought it. Well, except for those scratches and the ding on the corner.</p>
<p>To wipe his iPad, open the Settings app and tap General, then tap Reset, then tap Erase All Content and Settings. The iPad will give you one warning to try to pull you to your senses. If you&rsquo;re sure you want to do it, pull the trigger and tap Erase iPad. It will take a few minutes to do it&rsquo;s magic, but once it&rsquo;s done, it will reboot, and you&rsquo;ll be greeted with the setup greeting screen, just like he was when he first got the iPad.</p>
<p>Sounds easy, right?</p>
<p>Well, it is easy, if it works. I&rsquo;ll be honest, this is the one area where Apple to this day has still dropped the ball when it comes to the iPhone and iPad. If it works, it&rsquo;s seamless and polished. But, a lot of times, it just doesn&rsquo;t work, and it is very complicated to make sure you have all of your files from your old iOS device on your new iOS device. So, if you try it and it doesn&rsquo;t work, you may want to contact a professional before you wipe the old iPad.</p>
<p>If you were wondering, yes, this is exactly how it works to move from an old iPhone to a new iPhone as well.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/09/michael-asks-move-new-ipad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Want to watch the Apple iPad 3 event live? Good luck!</title>
		<link>/2012/03/want-to-watch-the-apple-ipad-3-event-live-good-luck/</link>
		<comments>/2012/03/want-to-watch-the-apple-ipad-3-event-live-good-luck/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Keynote]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[live blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[March 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yerba Buena Center for the Arts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=5053</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/03/AppleInvitation-e1330996843406-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="We have something you really have to see. And touch." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Starting at 10 AM PST, Wednesday March 7, 2012, Apple fanboys and tech news fanatics will be scouring the Internet for every scrap and morsel falling from the keyboards of the journalists attending the event that Apple is holding at the Yerba Buena Center for the Arts in San Francisco. Unfortunately, just like the last Apple press event, the one thing that they will most likely not find is a live video stream of the Apple iPad event.<p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2012/03/want-to-watch-the-apple-ipad-3-event-live-good-luck/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2012/03/AppleInvitation-e1330996843406-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="We have something you really have to see. And touch." style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><strong>Updated: 3/6/2012&nbsp;2:47:08 PM&nbsp;PMEST</strong></p>
<p><a href="//wp-content/uploads/2012/03/AppleInvitation.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class=" wp-image-5074 alignright" title="Apple's Invitation | &quot;We have something you really have to see. And touch.&quot;" src="//wp-content/uploads/2012/03/AppleInvitation.jpg"  alt="We have something you really have to see. And touch." width="341" height="286"></a>Starting at 10 AM PST, Wednesday March 7, 2012, Apple fanboys and tech news fanatics will be scouring the Internet for every scrap and morsel falling from the keyboards of the journalists attending the iPad 3 (or the <a title="Next iPad rumored to be called iPad HD | iMore" href="http://www.imore.com/2012/03/05/ipad-rumored-called-ipad-hd/">iPad HD</a> if you believe the rumors) event that Apple is holding at the Yerba Buena Center for the Arts in San Francisco. Unfortunately, just like <a title="Where Can I Watch the Apple iPhone Event Live? | Deemable" href="//2011/10/where-can-i-watch-the-apple-iphone-event-live/">the last Apple press event</a>, the one thing that they will most likely not find is a live video stream of the Apple iPad event.</p>
<p><span id="more-5053"></span></p>
<p>Although <a title="Apple Events" href="http://www.apple.com/apple-events/" target="_blank">Apple always posts high-definition video from the keynote events</a> on its website afterwards, the last time that <a title="Apple - Press Info - Apple to Provide Live Video Streaming" href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2010/08/31Apple-to-Provide-Live-Video-Streaming-of-September-1-Event.html" target="_blank">Apple live streamed an event</a> was in 2010. A few reporters have tried to stream audio or video from the event, however they have allegedly been blacklisted by Apple&rsquo;s PR folks from then on.</p>
<p>These sites have confirmed that they will be live blogging the Apple iPad 3 event:</p>
<ul><li><a title="Apple iPad live blog (Wednesday, March 7) | CNET" href="http://live.cnet.com/Event/Apples_March_7_special_event_live_from_SF" target="_blank">CNET</a></li>
<li><a title="Engadget" href="http://www.engadget.com/" target="_blank">Engadget</a></li>
<li><a title="Gizmodo, the Gadget Guide - Live Blog" href="http://live.gizmodo.com/" target="_blank">Gizmodo</a></li>
<li><a title="Live Update: Apple March 7 press event | Macworld" href="http://www.macworld.com/article/165632/2012/03/live_update_apple_march_7_press_event.html" target="_blank">Macworld</a></li>
<li><a title="PCMag.com" href="http://www.pcmag.com/" target="_blank">PC Magazine</a></li>
<li><a title="LIVE Apple iPad 3 Launch Event Coverage! | PluggedIn" href="http://www.pluggedin.co.uk/article/live-apple-ipad-3-launch-event-coverage" target="_blank">PluggedIn</a></li>
<li><a title="SlashGear Live Coverage - Macworld, WWDC, and Special Events" href="http://live.slashgear.com/" target="_blank">SlashGear</a></li>
<li><a title="Coming Wednesday: Our Live Apple iPad Event Coverage | Techland | TIME.com" href="http://techland.time.com/2012/03/06/apple-march-2012-ipad-event-live-blog-coverage/" target="_blank">Time</a></li>
<li><a title="Live from Apple's iPad 3 event in San Francisco | The Verge" href="http://live.theverge.com/Event/Live_from_Apples_iPad_3_event_in_San_Francisco" target="_blank">The Verge</a></li>
</ul><p><a title="CNET | Buzz Out Loud" href="http://cnettv.cnet.com/#" target="_blank">CNET&rsquo;s Buzz Out Loud</a>&nbsp;and <a title="iMore Live Coverage of Apple's iPad 3 Event" href="http://www.imore.com/podcasts" target="_blank">iMore</a> will&nbsp;be doing live video commentary&nbsp;during the event on their podcasts.</p>
<p>These sites usually live blog&nbsp;Apple events, but they have not confirmed yet:</p>
<ul><li><a href="http://www.tuaw.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">TUAW</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">ZDNet</a></li>
</ul><p><a title="Rumor Has It | CNET" href="http://cnettv.cnet.com/8301-33245_53-57387055-288.html?tag=mncol;txt" target="_blank">Emily Dreyfuss, from CNET, plans on trying to sneak into the Apple event</a>, so if all of the&nbsp;other sites are bogged&nbsp;down, that should be&nbsp;entertaining. Also, apparently Financial&nbsp;Post has worked out the kinks in their <a title="Deemable | Back To The Future" href="//tag/back-to-the-future/" target="_blank">Mr Fusion powered Delorean</a>, because they&nbsp;have posted&nbsp;<a title="Apple's iPad 3 event: Read tomorrow's live blog today!" href="http://business.financialpost.com/2012/03/06/apples-ipad-3-event-read-tomorrows-live-blog-today/" target="_blank">tomorrow&rsquo;s Apple iPad 3 live blog today!</a> They will be covering the event tomorrow again, as well. The Motley Fool will also be live blogging the <a title="The Motley Fool" href="http://www.fool.com/investing/general/2012/03/05/kodak-to-apple-bring-it-on.aspx" target="_blank">Apple iPad press conference</a> discussing what the event means for investors.</p>
<p>Here are the times that the Apple event will be held in your time zones:<br>
07:00AM &ndash; Hawaii<br>
10:00AM &ndash; Pacific<br>
11:00AM &ndash; Mountain<br>
12:00PM &ndash; Central<br>
01:00PM &ndash; Eastern</p>
<p>Let us know in the comments where you are planning on hanging out for the Apple iPad 3 announcement, and if you&rsquo;re reading this article outside of the United States, leave your time zone in the comments below, too.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2012/03/want-to-watch-the-apple-ipad-3-event-live-good-luck/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
