<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; problems with add ons</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/problems-with-add-ons/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#45 Deemable Tech and The Podsters</title>
		<link>/2013/08/deemable-tech-and-the-podsters/</link>
		<comments>/2013/08/deemable-tech-and-the-podsters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 03:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email attachments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nike+ FuelBand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outlook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[printing contacts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[problems with add ons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Green Light Show]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7796</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/08/DJShottGreenLightShow-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="DJ Shott Green Light Show" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />On this episode of Deemable Tech, Ray and Tom finally get a question they&#8217;re not qualified to answer: How do you make a podcast?! Sound ridiculous? Most podcasts are not recorded in an amazing studio like WJCT&#8217;s, and most podcasts <a href="/2013/08/deemable-tech-and-the-podsters/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/08/deemable-tech-and-the-podsters/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/08/DJShottGreenLightShow-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="DJ Shott Green Light Show" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/08/DJShottGreenLightShow.png" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-7803" alt="DJ Shott Green Light Show" src="/media/2013/08/DJShottGreenLightShow-300x165.png"  width="300" height="165"></a></p>
<p dir="ltr">On this episode of Deemable Tech, Ray and Tom finally get a question they&rsquo;re not qualified to answer: How do you make a podcast?! Sound ridiculous? Most podcasts are not recorded in an amazing studio like WJCT&rsquo;s, and most podcasts do not have incredible producers like Sean Birch. In other words, Ray and Tom have no credible experience in producing a real podcast! So, Ray invited DJ Shott, host of <a href="http://greenlightshow.com/">The Green Light Show</a>, a comedy podcast recorded in Jacksonville, to come to the studio to talk about what it&rsquo;s like to really produce a podcast. A word of warning, The Green Light Show is a very explicit comedy podcast that holds nothing back. So, if you get offended at the Comedy Zone, The Green Light Show probably isn&rsquo;t for you. But if you like comedy that gets really raunchy, check out The Green Light Show, and subscribe to <a href="http://greenlightshow.com/itunes">The Green Light Show in iTunes</a>. However, no need for a warning about this episode. Ray, Tom&nbsp;and DJ were perfect gentlemen, and refrained from any potty language during the show.</p>
<p dir="ltr">After they talked about podcasting, Ray and Tom asked DJ about his <a href="http://www.amazon.com/s/?_encoding=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;field-keywords=nike%20fuelband&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;rh=i%3Aaps%2Ck%3Anike%20fuelband&amp;sprefix=nike%20fuel%20ban%2Caps%2C449&amp;tag=deemtech-20&amp;url=search-alias%3Daps" target="_blank">Nike+ FuelBand</a><img style="border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" alt="" src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=deemtech-20&amp;l=ur2&amp;o=1" width="1" height="1" border="0"> and got his take on it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">After the break, Ray and Tom recapped what DJ talked about. Ray mentioned a website where you can easily create a podcast, but he couldn&rsquo;t remember the name of the site. The site is <a title="BuzzSprout - Create and publish your own podcast. " href="http://www.buzzsprout.com/?ref=Deemable" target="_blank">BuzzSprout</a>. If you aren&rsquo;t tech savvy but you want&nbsp;to start a podcast, BuzzSprout is a great resource. You can try it out for free to find out if you like the service, and it&rsquo;s free forever. If you decide to upgrade, paid plans start at only $12 per month.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Also, Ray and Tom answered questions about printing contacts from Outlook, email file attachments that cause the Internet to disconnect, and how to block pop-ups on Internet Explorer and Chrome.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Don&rsquo;t forget, we&rsquo;re still in the middle of the $50 Amazon Gift Card giveaway! If Deemable Tech gets at least 500 subscribers on iTunes and at least 200 subscribers on YouTube by the end of August, we are going to give away an Amazon Gift Card worth $50!</p>
<p>To be eligible to win the $50 Amazon Gift Card, you need to subscribe to us on&nbsp;<a href="http://youtube.com/DeemableTech">YouTube</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/deemable-tech/id540595466" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iTunes</a>, like us on&nbsp;<a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable">Facebook</a>&nbsp;and follow us on&nbsp;<a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable">Twitter</a>. Then, send us an email at&nbsp;giftcard@deemable.com.&nbsp;In that email, include your Facebook name, Twitter and YouTube username. We&rsquo;ll pick one eligible email at random and we&rsquo;ll announce it on the show.&nbsp;The links to all of our social network profiles are in the top right corner of the website under the heading, Follow Deemable Tech.</p>
<p>Also, the Deemable Tech app is now available for&nbsp;<a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=n4MZJN75Txs&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/deemable-tech/id671758316" target="_blank" rel="external nofollow">iPhone, iPod touch and iPad in the App Store</a>&nbsp;and for&nbsp;<a>Android phones and tablets in the Google Play store</a>. You can find a link to the app simply by visiting&nbsp;<a href="http://deemable.com/2013/07/44-angel-torres-aurora-app-2-0-and-deemable-tech-app-1-0/Deemable.com">Deemable.com</a>&nbsp;on your mobile device.</p>
<p>One last thing! Don&rsquo;t forget to vote for Ray and Tom in Folio Weekly&rsquo;s Best of Jax for Hottest Local Celebrity. Go to <a title="Folio Weekly Best of Jax" href="http://folioweekly.com/bestofjax" target="_blank">http://folioweekly.com/bestofjax</a> to enter your vote!</p>
<span class="embed-youtube" style="text-align:center; display: block;"><iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="752" height="453" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GuFu2PisR1M?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
<p><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-7796-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-04.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-04.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-04.mp3</a></audio><br><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-04.mp3">#45 Deemable Tech and The Podsters</a></p>
<p>DRAFT TRANSCRIPT</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: From WJCT studios in Jacksonville, Florida, I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister,</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: I&rsquo;m Tom Braun,</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: and this is Deemable Tech, tech help worth listening to.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: This week&rsquo;s episode of the Deemable Tech podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at a small orange dot com.</p>
<p dir="ltr">And, by audible.com &ndash; Deemable Tech listeners can get a FREE audiobook download at <a href="http://www.audibletrial.com/Deemable">audibletrial.com/Deemable</a> Over 100,000 titles to choose from for your iPhone, Android, Kindle or mp3 player.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Got a question about your computer, smart phone, tablet or the Internet? Give us a call us at One Eight Eight Eight, Nine Seven Two, Nine Eight Six Eight, or send us an email at <a href="mailto:questions@deemable.com">questions@deemable.com</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: So, if you listened to last week&rsquo;s episode, you know that we are in the middle of a contest. If we reach 200 subscribers on YouTube and 500 subscribers on iTunes we are going to give away a $50 Amazon Gift Card. Here&rsquo;s what you have to do to be eligible. First, Subscribe to us on YouTube and iTunes. Then, like us on Facebook, and follow us on Twitter.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Then, send us an email to <a href="mailto:giftcard@deemable.com">giftcard@deemable.com</a>. In that email, tell us your Facebook name, Twitter and YouTube username. &nbsp;We&rsquo;ll pick one eligible email at random and we&rsquo;ll announce it</p>
<p dir="ltr">To make it easy for you, the links to our Facebook, YouTube, iTunes and Twitter accounts are all available at the top-right of our website under the heading, &ldquo;Follow Deemable Tech&rdquo;</p>
<p dir="ltr">So, go subscribe, like and follow us, and get your emails in so you can win that $50 gift card.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Hey Ray, I just wanted to tell you that you look great tonight.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Thanks Tom, you don&rsquo;t look too bad yourself.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Ray, we&rsquo;ve often been complimented that we really have faces for radio. And to commemorate that, we&rsquo;ve entered ourselves into Folio Weekly&rsquo;s yearly Best of Jax contest under the Hottest Local Celebrity category. Because, listeners, we know that when you think of Hot Local Celebrities you think of Ray and Tom.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: <a href="http://folioweekly.com/bestofjax">folioweekly.com/bestofjax</a>&nbsp;*blah blah blah*</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Alright, Ray, should we answer some listeners questions.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: I think we should.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: OK, let&rsquo;s take a look at Carlos&rsquo; question.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Carlos writes:</p>
<p dir="ltr">Hey Ray and Tom,</p>
<p dir="ltr">I&rsquo;d really like to start a podcast, but I have no idea where to begin. Would I have to buy studio time? Don&rsquo;t some people podcast out of their house? What kind of equipment would I need to do it that way? Thanks, love your show! Carlos</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: You know what Tom? I think we have found a question that we are not qualified to answer.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Why is that Ray? We do a podcast almost every week.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Well, Deemable Tech is really not like most podcasts. Most podcasts aren&rsquo;t recorded at radio stations. So, we&rsquo;ve invited somebody who has experience doing a podcast the real way.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Joining us in the studio we have DJ Shott, the host of the Green Light Show.</p>
<ul><li>Describe your show to us. What is your podcast about?</li>
<li>Why did you want to start a podcast?</li>
<li>How did you get started podcasting?</li>
<li>Where do you record and stream your show from?</li>
<li>What kind of equipment do you use? Mics, soundboards, headsets, computers, Internet connection&hellip;</li>
<li>What software do you use? Ustream, Audacity, Garageband, WordPress, etc.</li>
<li>How long does it take you to prepare for the show? How long does it take you after the show is over?</li>
<li>What have you done to grow your audience?</li>
<li>Is the show making any money?</li>
<li>Where do you see your show going from here?</li>
<li>What has been the most rewarding thing about producing a podcast?</li>
<li>What has been the most challenging thing about producing a podcast?</li>
<li>Was there ever a time when you just felt like giving up? Why?</li>
<li>If people dare, where can folks find your show? (EXPLICIT content!)
<ul><li><a href="http://greenlightshow.com/">http://Greenlightshow.com/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://facebook.com/greenlightshow">http://Facebook.com/greenlightshow</a></li>
<li><a href="http://twitter.com/greenlightshow">http://Twitter.com/greenlightshow</a></li>
<li><a href="http://greenlightshow.com/itunes">http://greenlightshow.com/itunes</a></li>
</ul></li>
</ul><p>Next question:</p>
<p dir="ltr">Marvin writes, I have an HP computer &nbsp;with Windows XP.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I have been trying&nbsp;to print my contact list alphabetically from Outlook. The left half of the page prints out, but the &nbsp;right half is hidden and will not print. It is laborious to have to &nbsp;click on an individual&rsquo;s name to get the whole address, etc.</p>
<p dir="ltr">This is frustrating, because I want to print out a hard copy to keep by my desk so I do not want to have to have the computer turned on.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Any ideas?&nbsp;Thanks.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Hi Marvin, thanks for the question.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The first thing I would do is check your printer settings when you are printing. Just before you click the print button that prints the actual page you should see the screen where you select what printer you want to print with. While you&rsquo;re on this screen you can make changes to the print settings.</p>
<p dir="ltr">What this screen looks like and what options it gives you depend on a lot of different factors: what operating system you&rsquo;re running, what kind of printer you have, what program you&rsquo;re launching from, etc. There should be a button on this screen for printer preferences or advanced settings. Click that, and then look for an option that says something like ?Fit to page? or ?Fit to paper size? or ?Shrink to fit?. Most printers have a setting like this which will automatically resize a page that is too big to fit on the paper. You may have to click a different tab to find it. Just look around, you won&rsquo;t hurt anything!</p>
<p>Once you find ?Fit to page?, select it. Then click the OK button to get back to the print screen. Now go ahead and print. Hopefully the right side of the page is no longer cut off!</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Cool. So, that solves the problem.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Wait, there&rsquo;s one more thing Marvin may need to know about and it&rsquo;s kind of a doozy. If he has Outlook 2003, it actually prints using Internet Explorer. So he needs to go into an entirely different program to change his settings!</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Wow, that&rsquo;s convenient.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Yeah. So Marvin, if you have Outlook 2003, open up Internet Explorer, go to Internet Explorer, then select ?Page Setup? from the File menu. There you should find the Shrink to fit option. Check it, and boom. Happy printing!</p>
<p dir="ltr">Richard writes, When I try to attach an attachment to an email, Internet Explorer looses connection to the Internet. I am using Windows 7 with latest patches applied by Window&rsquo;s Update and IE 10. This email attachment problem happens on my Gmail and a friend&rsquo;s yahoo mail.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Thanks for letting us know what versions of Windows and Internet Explorer you are using, Richard.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Based on what you&rsquo;re describing, my first guess is that your copy of Internet Explorer has an add-on that is being a little too helpful. Possibly you have a security or anti-virus add-on such as Norton that&rsquo;s malfunctioning and interfering with uploading files. To be on the safe side, start by disabling all the add-ons in Internet Explorer.</p>
<p dir="ltr">You can do this by clicking on the settings menu and then going to Manage Add Ons and disabling them one by one. But if you have a lot of them it&rsquo;s quicker to click on the Tools menu and then under ?Toolbars&rsquo; you should see an option that says ?Disable Add Ons&rsquo;. Click on that to bring up the dialogue box that will allow you to do that.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Once you&rsquo;ve done that you will need to reboot your computer. When it comes back up, open up Internet Explorer and see if you are able to add attachments in Gmail now. If you are, you can start enabling add ons one by one through the manage add-on menu until you figure out which one was causing the problem. Or just leave them all off.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Again, if you have something like Norton Anti-virus it&rsquo;s a good bet that it&rsquo;s add ons are causing the problem.</p>
<p dir="ltr">If this doesn&rsquo;t resolve your problem, well&hellip; try a different browser? You know, Chrome is looking very nice this time of year&hellip;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Bill writes, Question: I just read your response to Christine&rsquo;s question about browsers in April, and have a follow-up question. Is there any way to completely block pop-up ads while running Chrome or IE? Or is Firefox&rsquo;s add-in the only solution? On both Chrome and IE, I have adjusted the settings to block pop-ups but that doesn&rsquo;t stop them on many sites I visit. I realize that those annoying ads are paying for these otherwise free websites, but I have to wonder what&rsquo;s the point of blocking pop-ups when so many get through anyway, slowing down the page loading to the point that it reminds me of being on dial-up.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Thanks!</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: Excellent question, Bill. You turn on the pop-up blocker and you still get pop ups! What&rsquo;s up with that?</p>
<p dir="ltr">The thing you have to understand is that pop-up blocking is an arms race. Just like you can&rsquo;t tell your computer to block all viruses, you can&rsquo;t really tell it to block all pop-ups. Every time there&rsquo;s some new advance in pop-up blocker technology, the people making the pop up ads just get smarter.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: To make things even harder on the makers of pop up blockers, you can&rsquo;t just block all pop ups everywhere. there are lots of legitimate pop ups people want to see. Blocking all pop ups would make too many sites non-functional.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So the ?block pop ups&rsquo; options in Internet Explorer and Chrome walk a fine line.</p>
<p dir="ltr">TOM: If you&rsquo;re really serious about blocking pop-ups in Internet Explorer or Chrome you need to download an add-in or extension that does so, much like you did for Firefox. On Chrome, check out <a href="https://adblockplus.org/en/chrome">Adblock Plus</a> or <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/better-pop-up-blocker/nmpeeekfhbmikbdhlpjbfmnpgcbeggic?hl=en">Better Pop-up Blocker</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Your options are more limited on Internet Explorer, but there&rsquo;s an add on called <a href="http://download.cnet.com/Smart-Popup-Blocker/3000-7786_4-10282837.html">Smart Pop-up Blocker</a> that will block most pop-ups. It&rsquo;s no 100%, but it&rsquo;s the best we could find.</p>
<p dir="ltr">RAY: Just a friendly little PSA about pop-up blocking: many free websites are ad supported. When you visit your favorite site and you&rsquo;ve got a pop-up blocker running, you may have avoided seeing that annoying pop-up ad but you&rsquo;ve also cost that site some ad revenue. So be sure to deploy your pop-up blocker judiciously. Most pop-up blockers give you the ability to allow pop-ups for certain sites. Be sure to allow them for sites you want to support!</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 2em;">OUTRO</span></p>
<p dir="ltr">Thanks for all your questions, and keep them coming. Call us at our toll-free number, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email at questions@deemable.com. Also, subscribe to the show! Search for Deemable Tech on iTunes or point your favorite podcast app to dmbl.co/pod.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Our producer is Sean Birch. Thanks to Robert Snyder for Video Production Assistance. I&rsquo;m Ray Hollister, I&rsquo;m Tom Braun, and this is Deemable Tech. Thanks for listening. Have a great week.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#45 Deemable Tech and The Podsters" data-link="/2013/08/deemable-tech-and-the-podsters/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#45 Deemable Tech and The Podsters" data-link="/2013/08/deemable-tech-and-the-podsters/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/08/deemable-tech-and-the-podsters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/02/DeemableTech_2013-08-04.mp3" length="0" type="" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
