<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; foodies</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/foodies/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Google Adds New Recipe Search Feature</title>
		<link>/2011/03/google-adds-new-recipe-search-feature/</link>
		<comments>/2011/03/google-adds-new-recipe-search-feature/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 12:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vicky Ozment]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple cobbler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foodies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Recipe Search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google with Recipe View]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rich snippet markup]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=548</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/03/googlrecipesearch-150x150.gif" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Screen shot of Google Recipe Search" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />Google has added a new feature to help&#160;its users&#160;search for recipes online. Whereas a generalized search will return a mix of recipes and&#160;unrelated&#160;articles to&#160;sift through, &#160;Google Recipe Search allows recipe hunters to refine their results to just recipes.&#160;Users can then <a href="/2011/03/google-adds-new-recipe-search-feature/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/03/google-adds-new-recipe-search-feature/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2011/03/googlrecipesearch-150x150.gif" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Screen shot of Google Recipe Search" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><a href="//wp-content/uploads/2011/03/googlrecipesearch.gif" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-584" style="margin: 0 10 10 0;" src="//wp-content/uploads/2011/03/googlrecipesearch.gif"  alt="Screen shot of Google Recipe Search" width="240" height="240"></a>Google has added a new feature to help&nbsp;its users&nbsp;search for recipes online. Whereas a generalized search will return a mix of recipes and&nbsp;unrelated&nbsp;articles to&nbsp;sift through, &nbsp;<a title="Google Recipe Search" href="http://www.google.com/landing/recipes/" target="_blank">Google Recipe Search</a> allows recipe hunters to refine their results to just recipes.&nbsp;Users can then narrow down results based on ingredients, cook time, and/or the number of calories in a dish.&nbsp; Results include user ratings, ingredient lists, and thumbnail images to further aid in selection.</p>
<p>To see how helpful this new feature can be, I tried it myself with a search for apple cobbler. Within seconds, I found a recipe that had two of my specialized ingredients in it (oats and brandy, if you&rsquo;re wondering).&nbsp;&nbsp;Being fond of trying new recipes, I know how time consuming it can be&nbsp;to search the Internet for them.&nbsp;There are many&nbsp;cooking sites.&nbsp;A standard search will lead you to recipes on several of these sites, each one of which has to be searched in turn for the right version of&nbsp;the dish in question.&nbsp;Google&rsquo;s new feature takes the guesswork out of the equation.</p>
<p>Say you&rsquo;re a busy mom or dad who has to make dinner in a hurry.&nbsp;You can custom search for recipes that take less than 15, 30, or 60 minutes to complete.&nbsp;On a diet?&nbsp;Just select the settings for&nbsp;dishes containing fewer than 100, 300, or 500 calories.&nbsp;You can even&nbsp;type in holidays such as Easter or Mother&rsquo;s Day to find appropriate recipes. In terms of saving time and effort, this&nbsp;new tool is&nbsp;a wonderful addition to Google&rsquo;s search capacities.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, one&nbsp;criticism of&nbsp;this&nbsp;feature&nbsp;is that you have to pick from a limited list of ingredients when wanting to use them to narrow your search. Sometimes, the specific ingredient you use&nbsp;may not be listed.&nbsp;Perhaps in the future, Google&nbsp;could&nbsp;remedy this by offering a textbox&nbsp;allowing you to&nbsp;enter&nbsp;your own ingredients.</p>
<p>Another drawback is that the results are currently from a limited number of sources.&nbsp;Several test searches revealed just three or four cooking sites consistently getting the lion&rsquo;s share: AllRecipes.com, Food.com, and FoodNetwork.com. <span style="color: #000000;">T</span>hough there is nothing wrong with these sites, there are many other good ones as well, and users might be missing out on them.&nbsp;This might mean that if the recipe you want is not on a main site, you may have trouble finding it using this tool. For example, one recipe I searched for could not be found.&nbsp;It was so specific that only a generalized search&nbsp;could find&nbsp;it.&nbsp;Sounds ironic, doesn&rsquo;t it?[smartads]</p>
<p>The magic behind Google Recipe Search,&nbsp;<a title="Recipes - Webmaster Tools Help" href="http://www.google.com/support/webmasters/bin/answer.py?answer=173379" target="_blank">rich snippet markup</a>,&nbsp;is also the culprit causing the problem. Without getting too technical, the new search feature uses little chunks of computer language called rich snippet markup to distinguish between what is a recipe and what is not. These bits of code do not show up when you are reading the page. They are hidden in the website, much like the &lt;em&gt; html code that makes a word <em>italicized</em>, or the &lt;strong&gt; html code that makes a word <strong>bold</strong>. You do not have to read them; the computer does it for you. In the same way, Google&rsquo;s search engine knows the difference between a recipe for an apple cobbler and the <a title="Apple - iPod touch - Technical specifications for iPod touch." href="http://www.apple.com/ipodtouch/specs.html" target="_blank">technical specifications for an Apple iPod</a> because the website with the&nbsp;apple cobbler has little bits of code that specifically tell the search engine it is a recipe.</p>
<p>From&nbsp;the point of view of a food writer, I believe this additional markup could cause&nbsp;up-and-coming writers&nbsp;to see fewer hits to their sites. Google does provide the tools for recipe publishers to add <a title="Recipes - Webmaster Tools Help" href="http://www.google.com/support/webmasters/bin/answer.py?answer=173379" target="_blank">rich snippet markup</a> to their webpages so that they show up in Google Recipe view. However,&nbsp;many writers are not fluent with basic html code, let alone this new code that Google has created. This creates a tough learning curve for smaller sites without technical staff comparable&nbsp;to the above mentioned websites. As Google&rsquo;s new feature becomes more commonly used, I hope that coding your recipe with rich snippets will one day become as easy as&nbsp;clicking the &ldquo;B&rdquo; icon to make your font bold.</p>
<p>Overall, this is a great new feature for cooks and foodies everywhere. I would recommend getting the best of Google by using both the generalized and refined searches, depending on need.&nbsp;To use the new feature, just click <a title="Recipes" href="http://www.google.com/landing/recipes/">&ldquo;Recipes&rdquo;</a> on the left side&nbsp;of Google&rsquo;s&nbsp;result page.</p>
<p>Here is a video from Google Chef&nbsp;Scott Giambastiani explaining Google Recipe Search:</p>
<p>&ndash; <a title="Ray Hollister | Deemable" href="//author/rayhollister/" target="_blank">Ray Hollister</a> contributed to this article.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/03/google-adds-new-recipe-search-feature/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
