<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; eSports</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/esports/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#96 I need to Alphabet that</title>
		<link>/2015/08/96-i-need-to-alphabet-that/</link>
		<comments>/2015/08/96-i-need-to-alphabet-that/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 20:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[abc.xyx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eSports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hard drive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Larry Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sergei Brin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solid state drive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sundar Pichai]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10222</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/08/AlphabetSoup-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Alphabet Soup" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />If you&#8217;re listening to Deemable Tech on the&#160;website, make sure to&#160;subscribe to the show on iTunes&#160;or&#160;on Stitcher.&#160;And, while you&#8217;re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show. If <a href="/2015/08/96-i-need-to-alphabet-that/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/08/96-i-need-to-alphabet-that/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/08/AlphabetSoup-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Alphabet Soup" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-10224" src="/media/2015/08/AlphabetSoup.jpg" alt="Alphabet Soup" width="350" height="350">If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on the&nbsp;website, make sure to&nbsp;subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>.&nbsp;And, while you&rsquo;re there, leave a review. The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>If you have a&nbsp;response or&nbsp;comment for the show, give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="/media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="/media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there.</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10222-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-14.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-14.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-14.mp3</a></audio><h1>THE RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3>A is for Alphabet, G is for Google</h3>
<p>In our top story this week, tech giant Google announced a major corporate restructuring which included, to everyone&rsquo;s surprise, a name change. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fabc.xyz%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHXep9B5Ns8_XYn4ukdwSNPWU8OLQ">A new holding company has been created called Alphabet</a>. Alphabet is made up of a collection of companies including Google. Google itself is being slimmed down so that just the products and services traditionally associated with it, such as Google Search, Gmail, and Chrome, are part of it. Unrelated projects such as Google&rsquo;s famous &ldquo;moonshot&rdquo; projects, Google Fiber, and its research into self-driving cars will be spun off into their own companies, all under the Alphabet umbrella.</p>
<p>As part of the restructuring, Google&rsquo;s Senior Vice President Sundar Pichai has been made CEO of the new, slimmer Google, while Larry Page and Sergei Brin are taking control of Alphabet.</p>
<p>For the moment, no branding is changing, so if you want to search something you don&rsquo;t suddenly have to &ldquo;Alphabet&rdquo; it and you won&rsquo;t be checking &ldquo;Alphabet Mail&rdquo; anytime soon on your &ldquo;Alphabet Phone.&rdquo; At least, we sure hope not.</p>
<p>You can check out the new company&rsquo;s website and a letter from its founders at <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fabc.xyz&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFA5do-Hgq6YpPtjla53IsO7UTFow">abc.xyz</a>.</p>
<h3>Why not Alphabet.com?</h3>
<p>You might be asking yourself, why didn&rsquo;t Google just go with Alphabet.com? Well, it turns out, even the mighty Google can&rsquo;t just have any domain name they want. The New York Times is reporting that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.nytimes.com%2F2015%2F08%2F12%2Ftechnology%2Fgoogle-creates-alphabet-but-runs-into-bmw.html&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGNuAzRhhD1Ngm7mX8Q5KzjMQwANQ">car manufacturer BMW already owns Alphabet.com</a>&nbsp;and they are not interested in selling it.</p>
<p>Alphabet is a subsidiary of BMW that provides vehicle fleet services. Micaela Sandstede, a BMW spokeswoman in Munich. She described the website as a &ldquo;very active&rdquo; part of Alphabet?s business. Which is ironic, because the website has been inaccessible ever since the Google Alphabet (or is it Alphabet Google?) announcement, presumably because of the increase in traffic. It makes us feel better knowing that even mega-companies like BMW have issues keeping their website running when they get hit with a ton of traffic.</p>
<p>The article points out that it would only be trademark infringement if it creates confusion with customers&hellip; which wouldn&rsquo;t be an issue if Google and BMW were in entirely different industries, which they were, right up until Google entered the automobile industry with self-driving cars and Android for automobiles.</p>
<h3>Android flaw that got patched actually not patched</h3>
<p>You may recall that a couple of weeks ago we talked about a major security flaw in Android that allowed a remote attacker to execute code using a vulnerability in Hangouts. Google rushed out a patch for the vulnerability, which has now been codenamed &ldquo;Stagefright,&rdquo; and it was just a matter of getting it out to the phones for all the different carriers. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.bbc.com%2Fnews%2Ftechnology-33914826&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFyNAmdZ7qKlCEW9nycKeGHFF49rA">Except, according to the BBC, it turns out that the patch doesn&rsquo;t work &ndash; or at least, that it is easy to bypass</a>. Better keep Hangouts disabled for the time being.</p>
<h3>How to lose an internship at Facebook</h3>
<p>If you figure out a huge flaw in the company you are going to start an internship at, perhaps it&rsquo;s a good idea to keep it to yourself. According to Boston.com, Aran Khanna created a web-app demonstrating a <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.boston.com%2Fnews%2Fnation%2F2015%2F08%2F12%2Fharvard-student-loses-facebook-internship-after-pointing-out-privacy-flaws%2FzASZFdUjn6PoliUiR9kVHJ%2Fstory.html&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHRamxJO6tv_zofZD5NQjuEt94ChA">huge privacy flaw in Facebook Messenger</a>&nbsp;shortly before he was to begin his highly coveted internship at Facebook. Facebook Messenger stored your location automatically and shared it with anyone you chatted with on the app. Khanna&rsquo;s web-app took that information and placed it onto a map showing where everyone you had chatted with was when they sent the message.</p>
<p>He tweeted about his app and posted it on Reddit and Medium, and a few days later, Facebook asked him to disable it, and then let him know that his internship was also disabled.</p>
<p>According to Khanna, he wasn&rsquo;t fired from his internship because of the app, but because of the way he described Facebook?s user data collection. Khanna says the Medium post wasn&rsquo;t in line with the high ethical standards expected of interns.</p>
<h3>Drones make bears nervous</h3>
<p>Drones seem like an ideal method for wildlife biologists to study the habits of wild animals such as bears, but it appears that there is a catch. NPR reports that a&nbsp;new study shows that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fnews.wjct.org%2Fpost%2Fdrones-increase-heart-rates-wild-bears-too-much-stress&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGg9ueEd_jKKcBMlu7XPsDxl0VJzA">the presence of drones make bears nervous, elevating their heart rates by as much as 400%</a>. Mark Ditmer, a biologist at the University of Minnesota, St. Paul, flew a drone near bears that had been previously implanted with heart rate monitors to study their hibernation states. Although the bears appeared outwardly unphased, all of them showed elevated heart rates when buzzed by the drone.</p>
<h3>Meet the world?s biggest hard drive</h3>
<p>Samsung has unveiled a new device with the catchy name of PM1633a. According to The Verge, it&rsquo;s a 2.5 inch solid state drive, and it packs a whopping 16 terabytes of storage space, making it essentially <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2015%2F8%2F14%2F9153083%2Fsamsung-worlds-largest-hard-drive-16tb&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHgNTyAaD04c7pGArfntuH5F2nUaw">the biggest hard drive </a>ever. Samsung has not announced a price tag, but they plan to sell servers with up to 48 of these drives installed, which they are calling JBOF. One JBOF should hold about 768 TB. JBOF stands for Just a Bunch Of Flash.&nbsp;Before you ask, the next step up after terabyte is petabyte.</p>
<h3>Still No Apple TV</h3>
<p>Apple TV, the long delayed, rumored, mystical device and service is further delayed. Bloomberg is reporting that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.bloomberg.com%2Fnews%2Farticles%2F2015-08-13%2Fapple-said-to-delay-tv-service-to-2016-as-negotiations-stall&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEGeYwAhP1_D9GOzno1kbmFjkS4kw">negotiations between Apple and the big TV networks are holding up the works</a>. According to Bloomberg, Apple was to announce a new live &nbsp;streaming TV service at its Sept. 9 press event, but instead Buzzfeed News says <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.buzzfeed.com%2Fjohnpaczkowski%2Fapple-will-debut-new-apple-tv-in-september%23.raEzRlaNe&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEy3coy8AaLbXsb6FxenUSNmfnkIw">Apple is only announcing a beefed up Apple TV set-top box</a>.</p>
<h3>eSports Drug Testing</h3>
<p>Top-ranked Counter Strike: Global Offensive player Cory &ldquo;Semphis&rdquo; Friesen admitted in an interview last month that he and his competitive eSports team &ldquo;were all on Adderall&rdquo; during a recent tournament. According to NPR news, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fnews.wjct.org%2Fpost%2Fvideo-game-league-announces-random-drug-tests-competitors&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHYnOgNnD_uKIYc4_FoZK3htuwAmQ">at least one eSports league has decided that it is not okay with that</a>. The Electronic Sports League, which sponsored the $250,000 tournament Friesen and his team took part in, has announced a ban on drugs and alcohol during its tournaments and will be instituting random drug testing during its tournaments going forward. The League says the substances banned include those prohibited by the World Anti-Doping Agency. The first random drug testing at a League event will occur at ESL One in Cologne later this month.</p>
<h3>LOL is OOS (Out of Style)</h3>
<p>You may have seen an article from the New Yorker back in April about <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fculture%2Fcultural-comment%2Fhahaha-vs-hehehe&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGT6rqMpHqHc8PxweQLu0iN7cNApA">how we express laughter online</a>&nbsp;&ndash; appropriately known as e-laughter &ndash; and the increase in the use of &ldquo;hehe.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This piqued the interest of the he research team at Facebook, who decided to <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fresearch.facebook.com%2Fblog%2F1605690073053884%2Fthe-not-so-universal-language-of-laughter&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGJXlm_qj74ayt6m0xIkOIw66f6fQ">look into how users showed amusement</a>. They did so by analyzing posts and comments from last week of May. Don&rsquo;t worry &ndash; they only looked at ones that had &ldquo;at least one string of characters that matched laughter&rdquo; and they left out private messages.</p>
<p>So what did their study find? Well, among other things, the form of e-laughter that is used more than any other is &ldquo;haha&rdquo; &ndash; which they found is used over 50% of the time. In second place are emoji, followed by &ldquo;hehe&rdquo; in third. And it last place&hellip; our dear friend &ldquo;LOL.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The first text speak that many of us learned is now used only about 2 percent of the time.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fmic.com%2Farticles%2F123648%2Fhaha-lol-or-emoji-facebook-knows-how-you-laugh&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNE3y7VntKNYrYhphfVeXxJUQmT42g">Mic.com has a great breakdown</a>&nbsp;of all of Facebook&rsquo;s findings, including which phrases are most popular among different age groups and states.</p>
<hr><p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there.</p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#96 I need to Alphabet that" data-link="/2015/08/96-i-need-to-alphabet-that/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#96 I need to Alphabet that" data-link="/2015/08/96-i-need-to-alphabet-that/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/08/96-i-need-to-alphabet-that/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/08/DeemableTech_2015-08-14.mp3" length="27316451" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
