<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; ThinkGeek</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/thinkgeek/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#86 The Episode Where We Did Not Run Out of News</title>
		<link>/2015/06/86-the-episode-where-we-did-not-run-out-of-news/</link>
		<comments>/2015/06/86-the-episode-where-we-did-not-run-out-of-news/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 22:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Birch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GIFs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hackers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lego Worlds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NetFlix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ThinkGeek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Valve]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=10067</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/06/Apple_I_Computer-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="An example of an early Apple I computer on display in the Smithsonian Museum.

Photo credit: Ed Uthman / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />This week, Ray, Tom and Sean discuss the Federal&#160;Office of Personnel Management being hacked, Facebook finally adding support for GIFs, and a woman who didn&#8217;t realize the old computer she was throwing out was really a piece of Apple history <a href="/2015/06/86-the-episode-where-we-did-not-run-out-of-news/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2015/06/86-the-episode-where-we-did-not-run-out-of-news/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2015/06/Apple_I_Computer-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="An example of an early Apple I computer on display in the Smithsonian Museum.

Photo credit: Ed Uthman / Flickr" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>This week, Ray, Tom and Sean discuss the Federal&nbsp;Office of Personnel Management being hacked, Facebook finally adding support for GIFs, and a woman who didn&rsquo;t realize the old computer she was throwing out was really a piece of Apple history worth $200,000. The guys are also joined by Ryan Thompson of <a href="http://gamesartandmusic.com/" target="_blank">GAAM (Games Arts and Music)</a> to look at some of the week&rsquo;s top video games news, including Lego&rsquo;s new &ldquo;Minecraft killer&rdquo; game, Lego Worlds. All that and a whole lot more on this week&rsquo;s Deemable Tech!</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re listening to Deemable Tech on our website, would you subscribe to the show <a title="Subscribe to the Deemable Tech Podcast in iTunes!" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes">on iTunes</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a title="Listen to Deemable Tech on Stitcher" href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank">on Stitcher</a>? And, while you&rsquo;re there, would you leave a review and say a few nice things about us? The more subscribers we have and reviews we get, the more people will find our show.</p>
<p>The Deemable Tech Podcast is brought to you by A Small Orange, Homegrown Hosting. A refreshingly different approach to web hosting. On the web at <a href="http://asmallorange.com/">asmallorange.com</a>.</p>
<p><a title="Click here to subscribe to the Deemable Tech podcast on iTunes" href="http://dmbl.co/itunes" rel="attachment wp-att-5275"><img class="alignnone" title="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" src="//media/2012/07/subscribe_on_iTunes.jpg" alt="Subscribe to Deemable Tech on iTunes" width="160" height="59"></a><a href="http://dmbl.co/stitcher" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9769" title="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" src="//media/2015/02/HearUsOnStitcher.png" alt="Hear Deemable Tech On Stitcher Radio" width="183" height="61"></a></p>
<p>Make sure to&nbsp;share Deemable Tech on the forums, <a href="http://facebook.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/Deemable" target="_blank">Twitter</a>&nbsp;and all over the interwebs.</p>
<p>Thank you to our Redditors&nbsp;who&nbsp;have been helping us decide what stories we talk about on the show. Go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a title="Deemable Sub Reddit" href="http://deemable.com/reddit" target="_blank">Deemable.com/reddit</a> will take you there. We&rsquo;re also looking for a new admin to help manage and moderate our subreddit page. Submit a text post to our subreddit explaining why you would make a great admin.</p>
<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-10067-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%; visibility: hidden;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-05.mp3?_=1"></source><a href="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-05.mp3">http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-05.mp3</a></audio><h1>THIS WEEK&rsquo;S RUN DOWN</h1>
<h3><b>Woman junks $200,000 Apple I prototype</b></h3>
<p>Okay, so you&rsquo;re cleaning out the attic and you spot an old computer moldering in the corner, so you decide to cart if off to the electronics recycler. Stop! Is that an Apple I computer? Because if it is, it might be worth as much as $200,000!</p>
<p>Now the chances that you have an Apple I in your attic are slim, because only about 200 were ever made and they weren&rsquo;t commercially available like their predecessor, the Apple II. But a woman in Silicon Valley apparently did have one lying around, as <a href="http://news.wjct.org/post/silicon-valley-recycling-firm-seeks-mystery-apple-i-donor">she showed up last month at a local recycler on dropped one off along with a bunch of junk</a>, saying her husband had died and she was cleaning up.</p>
<p>The recycler is now searching for the woman because it is their policy to split half the proceeds of any sales with donors. Unfortunately, the woman left no information. In fact, when they asked her if she wanted a tax receipt, she said &ldquo;No, I don&rsquo;t need anything.&rdquo;</p>
<div id="attachment_10077" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2015/06/Apple_I_Computer.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="wp-image-10077" src="//media/2015/06/Apple_I_Computer-300x182.jpg"  alt="An example of an early Apple I computer on display in the Smithsonian Museum. Photo credit: Ed Uthman / Flickr" width="400" height="243"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">An example of an early Apple I computer on display in the Smithsonian Museum.<br> Photo credit: Ed Uthman / Flickr</p></div>
<h3><b>Science teacher suspended for using cellphone jammer to crack down on cell phones in class</b></h3>
<p>This next news story was submitted by redditor <i>FrakinBeast</i>:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.news4jax.com/news/teacher-suspended-for-jamming-cell-phones/33371066">A Tampa Bay area science teacher has been suspended after he allegedly used a signal jammer to prevent his students from using their cellphones during class</a>. The school board issued instructor Dean Liptak a five day suspension without pay, saying that he might have interfered with people trying to dial 9-1-1. It is not clear where Liptak acquired the jamming device, but they are available online. On its website, the FCC reminds consumers that &ldquo;It is a violation of federal law to use a cell jammer or similar devices that intentionally block, jam, or interfere with authorized radio communications such as cell phones, police radar, GPS, and Wi-Fi.&rdquo;</p>
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2015/06/florida-science-teacher-suspended-for-signal-jamming-students-cell-phones/">This is not Dean Liptak&rsquo;s first run-in with the school board</a>. He is a former professional wrestler and has previously been reprimanded for test questions referencing the velocity of a student thrown against the wall by a teacher, and the mass of a car running over a baby.</p>
<h3><b>Facebook adds GIF support</b></h3>
<p>After years of waiting, you can now share animated GIFs on Facebook! The site finally added <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/amitchowdhry/2015/06/01/facebook-starts-supporting-animated-gifs/">support for GIFs</a> this past week, and using it is as easy as posting a link.</p>
<p><img class=" aligncenter" src="http://www.reactiongifs.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/orson_wells_Slow-Clap.gif" alt=""></p>
<p>Just like videos from YouTube, you simply copy and paste the link for a GIF into your status update window, wait for it to load, and hit post.</p>
<p>Also like videos, your auto-play settings affect animated GIFs. Depending on how you have those set, GIFs will either automatically start looping or they will show up as a still image with a little white circle that says &ldquo;GIF&rdquo; in the middle which you have to click to play.</p>
<p>We should note that while you can now post animated GIFs using links, you still can&rsquo;t upload them directly from your computer or phone.</p>
<h3><b>Facebook also tests pronunciation tool</b></h3>
<p>In other Facebook news, they have started testing <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/tech/facebook-testing-new-name-pronunciation-advice-116664180304.html">a feature that will let you tell the world how to pronounce your name</a>. On certain profiles, a phonetic pronunciation of the user&rsquo;s name is displayed in their details. You can also click that pronouncer to hear an audio clip of how to say the name.</p>
<p>They are just focusing on English speakers in the US at the moment. It looks like most people who fall into that category have this feature, which you can find in the About tab on your profile. Look under the &ldquo;Details About You&rdquo; menu for the &ldquo;How do you say your name?&rdquo; feature.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;ll see that Facebook offers three suggestions on how they think your first and last names are pronounced, or you can enter your own pronunciation.</p>
<h3><b>Amazon Prime launches same day delivery in 14 cities</b></h3>
<p>Good news for Amazon Prime members living in New York City, Seattle, San Francisco, Tampa Bay, and ten other select cities &ndash; you never have to leave your home again! <a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2015/05/amazon-prime-launches-free-same-day-shipping-in-14-cities/">Amazon is rolling out free same day delivery in your area</a> for orders of $35 and up. For orders that don&rsquo;t qualify for free same day delivery, it costs $5.99, truly a bargain when it comes to avoiding the unwashed masses! In fact, even if you live in one of the chosen fourteen cities you may not qualify for same day delivery, depending on <i>where</i> in town you are. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/b?ie=UTF8&amp;node=8729023011">Amazon has a zip code search page</a> where you can check your eligibility.</p>
<p>Amazon has been rumored to be working on same day delivery for years. Expect these fourteen cities to just be the tip of the iceberg.</p>
<h3><b>IRS and OPM hacked</b></h3>
<p>The Office of Personnel Management, basically the HR department of the entire Federal government, was hacked this week. According to a letter released by the OPM,<a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/news/officials-administration-hit-by-massive-data-breach/"> almost 4 million current and former federal employees may have been impacted</a>, including yours truly. The source of the hack has not been confirmed yet, but CBS News White House Correspondent Major Garrett is saying all signs point to Chinese hackers.</p>
<p>As a former IRS employee, Ray is terriefied. The Office of Personnel Management has more personally identifiable information on him than his wife and his mother combined.</p>
<h3><b>Netflix probably not planning to ruin everything</b></h3>
<p>This week some <a href="http://mashable.com/2015/06/01/netflix-not-getting-ads/">news outlets reported that Netflix was experimenting with pre- and post-credits-roll advertising</a>. This had some folks in an uproar &ndash; was Netflix about to devolve into a Hulu Plus-style cesspit of insidious advertising? Well, probably not. Think less Hulu Plus, more HBO. Netflix says it is experimenting, just experimenting mind you, with showing previews for Netflix&rsquo;s own original series at either the beginning or end of streaming content. If this is in fact the case, this seems fairly innocuous to us and could even be welcome if the previews are well done and well targeted.</p>
<h3><b>How did Vanity Fair keep Caitlyn Jenner a secret?</b></h3>
<p>According to Mashable, Vanity Fair went to great lengths to make sure <a href="http://mashable.com/2015/06/01/caitlyn-jenner-protected-exclusive/">the story did not leak out</a>. The story and photos were edited on a computer that was air-gapped. All network connections, Wi-Fi and bluetooth connections were disabled, and every night the files were deleted from the computer. The photos were even hand delivered to the printer.</p>
<h3>GameStop to purchase ThinkGeek</h3>
<p>In a surprise turn of events, game retailer GameStop appears to be <a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2015/06/gamestop-outbids-hot-topic-for-thinkgeek-parent-company-purchase/" target="_blank">buying nerd-themed online retailer ThinkGeek</a>. ThinkGeek was set to be acquired for a cool $122 million by mall retailer HotTopic when GameStop swooped in and topped them with a $140 million offer. The acquisition will allow GameStop to display ThinkGeek merchandise in its stores, a move which has obvious synergies.</p>
<h3><b>Valve begins offering refunds for all Steam games</b></h3>
<p>Valve, the company behind the popular Steam PC game store and download client, announced this week that it is <a href="http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2015/06/valve-begins-offering-refunds-for-all-steam-games/" target="_blank">changing its refund policy</a>.</p>
<p>It used to be that Valved that only offered refunds for games purchased through Steam in extreme circumstances. Their new policy, however, applies to all games.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Maybe your PC doesn&rsquo;t meet the hardware requirements; maybe you bought a game by mistake; maybe you played the title for an hour and just didn&rsquo;t like it,&rdquo; the policy reads. &ldquo;It doesn&rsquo;t matter. Valve will, upon request via help.steampowered.com, issue a refund for any reason, if the request is made within 14 days of purchase, and the title has been played for less than two hours.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This does not necessarily mean you can try out games for free, though. Steam said they reserve the right to decline a refund if they think a user is abusing the system.&nbsp;BUT they will allow you to return a game right before one of the famous ridiculous sales and then repurchase that game for the newer, lower price.</p>
<h3><b>Lego Worlds Launches</b></h3>
<p><a href="http://lego.gizmodo.com/lego-worlds-is-basically-minecraft-but-with-those-plast-1708195154">TT Games and the Lego Group have made Lego&rsquo;s hotly anticipated &ldquo;Minecraft Killer,&rdquo; Lego Worlds, available as an early access beta on Steam</a>. For under $15 you too can help TT Games and The Lego Group debug their open world plastic brick building paradise. <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2015/06/01/lego-worlds/">Lego Worlds lets players</a> build existing sets, do free-form building and even customize your own mini-figs. Still missing from the game is any form of multiplayer. Possibly Lego is concerned about players sharing certain types of <a href="http://www.exquisitetweets.com/tweets?eids=SOlZp2L8I8.SOl4CsO6YC.SOmhNAiuES.SOmlJ2T2Gq.SOmpjeGn1w.SOmwta15gX.SOmB4207kO.SOmJPgkOFU.SOmOl1j08a.SOmW0jPTRA.SOm72fKFfE.SOncwNl2SP.SOnlkgH05k.SOntnuAhGw.SOqg0uZR8K.SOqkXGJtbU.SOqrXBJruS" target="_blank">anatomically-correct&nbsp;tall buildings</a>.</p>
<p>&mdash;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If you have a suggestion, or just have a comment for the show. Give us a call and leave us a voicemail, 1-888-972-9868 or you can send us an email to feedback at deemable&nbsp;dot com.</p>
<p>And, don&rsquo;t forget to help us to decide what stories we talk about on the show, go to our subreddit page and submit a story, and vote other stories up or down. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fdeemable.com%2Freddit&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFBdyzC8hbWRsh1Un-185M3JttYnQ">deemable.com/reddit</a>&nbsp;will take you there.</p>
<p><em>Photo Credit: <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/euthman/281712899/in/photolist-qTRqX-8Yg65f-5VKByX-5LaoaK-cs6BwA-4vMCqL-n9ZpnN-oa2Tf1-atEdpR-5sh5MY-3mDkS3-51zkT3-8TWp2c-5tBAg4-4CckKu-aw8CwB-5GJo64-4Bfxya-96mYuq-hzB1t-5KWjsg-z8z6J-oybqk-729b4-4CeU33-9hHpjg-4BdXk9-5n9at-5E8otF-cJXbXw-4nficR-atvnG7-6QWc7V-pTGr2-5whRwW-PBm9R-5BkosD-4CeU5L-6UQ4Gb-CRZe6-4w9tXh-7x8Cg-4sbJ3S-4BfNv1-4LWkRy-2xnYty-55d1tu-7VR3pU-5yhFqq-5yk9cA" target="_blank">&ldquo;Apple I Computer&rdquo;</a> by <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/euthman/" target="_blank">Ed Uthman</a> is used under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank">CC BY-SA 2.0.</a></em></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="#86 The Episode Where We Did Not Run Out of News" data-link="/2015/06/86-the-episode-where-we-did-not-run-out-of-news/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="#86 The Episode Where We Did Not Run Out of News" data-link="/2015/06/86-the-episode-where-we-did-not-run-out-of-news/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2015/06/86-the-episode-where-we-did-not-run-out-of-news/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://cpa.ds.npr.org/wjct/audio/2015/06/DeemableTech_2015-06-05.mp3" length="60105161" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>April Fools&#8217; Internet Round Up 2013</title>
		<link>/2013/04/april-fools-internet-round-up-2013/</link>
		<comments>/2013/04/april-fools-internet-round-up-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 15:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ray Hollister]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[April Fools' Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gmail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sprint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ThinkGeek]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=7081</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/04/DeemableTechTatts-e1364831711881-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Deemable Tech Tattoos" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" />The Internet loves April Fools&#8217; Day. We didn&#8217;t pull any pranks this year; we&#8217;re too mature for all of those shenanigans. Also, we were too busy getting our new Deemable Tech tattoos.&#160;However, if you enjoy all&#160;that tom-foolery, here&#8217;s a break <a href="/2013/04/april-fools-internet-round-up-2013/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2013/04/april-fools-internet-round-up-2013/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="/media/2013/04/DeemableTechTatts-e1364831711881-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="Deemable Tech Tattoos" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="attachment_7083" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://deemable.com/media/2013/04/DeemableTechTatts.jpg" class="gallery_colorbox"><img class="size-medium wp-image-7083 " alt="Deemable Tech Tattoos" src="//media/2013/04/DeemableTechTatts-300x200.jpg"  width="300" height="200"></a><p class="wp-caption-text">What do you think? I think the artist did a great job. Sean wanted his on the right because he&rsquo;s left-handed.</p></div>
<p>The Internet loves April Fools&rsquo; Day. We didn&rsquo;t pull any pranks this year; we&rsquo;re <a href="http://deemable.com/2013/03/episode-eh-its-easter-go-read-a-book/">too mature for all of those shenanigans</a>. Also, we were too busy getting our new Deemable Tech tattoos.&nbsp;However, if you enjoy all&nbsp;that tom-foolery, here&rsquo;s a break down of the best April Fools&rsquo; Day pranks for 2013. We&rsquo;ll keep it updated throughout the day.</p>
<p>Google has built a reputation for almost every product at Google putting out several April Fools&rsquo; pranks each year. Starting with the one that made the front page, here are Google&rsquo;s pranks for the year.</p>
<ul><li><span id="hpplink"><span style="color: #ff0000;">New!</span> What&rsquo;s that smell? Find out with <a href="http://www.google.com/landing/nose">Google Nose</a>&nbsp;</span>
<ul><li><span id="hpplink"><em>Smells like a winner. </em></span></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H542nLTTbu0">YouTube&rsquo;s ready to select a winner</a>.
<ul><li><em>And they&rsquo;re closing, YouTube?! God, Please No!! What am I supposed to do when I am supposed&nbsp;to be working? They have Facebook blocked at work!</em></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="http://gmailblog.blogspot.com/2013/03/introducing-gmail-blue.html">Gmail Blue</a><em></em>
<ul><li><em>For those days you miss WordPerfect 5.1 on DOS. (Wait, does anyone have days like that?)</em></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Google Maps&nbsp;finds pirate, William ?Captain? Kidd&rsquo;s treasure&nbsp;map and adds <a href="http://google-latlong.blogspot.com/2013/03/find-treasure-with-google-maps.html">Treasure Mode</a>
<ul><li><em>It looks like he didn&rsquo;t bury any treasure in Jacksonville.</em></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="https://plus.google.com/100549881469536411122/posts/6cbXigttnUL">Google+ adds emoticons to your pictures.</a>
<ul><li><em>Because apparently seeing your face isn&rsquo;t enough to know how you feel, because &ldquo;when it comes to expressing yourself, nothing beats the richness and elegance of a few properly placed colons, parentheses, letters and hyphens.&rdquo;</em></li>
</ul></li>
</ul><p>Another site that has become famous for their hilarious April Fools&rsquo; hijinks is the specialty online retailer <a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/">ThinkGeek</a>. Many of <a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/stuff/looflirpa/">their past April Fools&rsquo;&nbsp;jokes</a>&nbsp;have been so genius&nbsp;that they have gone on to become real products. Here&rsquo;s a selection of this year&rsquo;s pranks.</p>
<ul><li><a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/f486/?pfm=AprilFools_homepage_Featured_4_f486">The Eye of Sauron Desk Lamp</a>
<ul><li><em>Don&rsquo;t take off your wedding ring and leave it on the night stand next to this lamp.</em></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/f487/?pfm=AprilFools_homepage_Featured_5_f487">Play-Doh 3D Printer</a>
<ul><li><em>Why do only thermoplastics and metals get to have all the 3D printing fun?</em></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/f48a/">Bane Mask Walkie Talkies</a>
<ul><li><em>You will buy these, then when it is done and Gotham is ashes, then you have my permission to die.</em></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/f489/">Death Star Trench Toss</a>
<ul><li><em>Practice taking advantage of the universe&rsquo;s worst design flaw ever made.</em></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/f483/">Batman Family Car Decal Set</a>
<ul><li><em>I hate those stupid family car decals.</em></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/f488/">Creeper Body Pillow</a>
<ul><li><em>Ah, Creepers, what would Minecraft be without them? More fun. that&rsquo;s what it would be. More. Fun. Kill them with a <a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/ea12/">Minecraft&nbsp;Foam Sword, also from ThinkGeek</a>.</em></li>
</ul></li>
</ul><p>Other sites:</p>
<p>Ready to learn how to fly in a wingsuit?&nbsp;Why not learn from an expert that was made that way? For $50 you can take <a href="http://www.zozi.com/experiences/5068">wingsuit lessons from a flying squirrel</a>!</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.twitter.com/2013/03/annncng-twttr.html">For $4 dollars a month, you can use Twitter premium</a>. &ndash; <em>Tme&nbsp;2 drp&nbsp;d vwls. Twttr&nbsp;s nw chrgng&nbsp;4 vwls.</em></p>
<p>Sprint launches <a href="http://now.sprint.com/specs/">Sprint Specs</a>.&nbsp; &ndash; <em>Never look rude again when you&rsquo;re completely ignoring someone.</em></p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;Update 1:03:45 PM EDT</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://youtu.be/5byDhm-E-YE">The White House has gotten into the act. </a>&ndash; <em>You might not agree with his policies, but <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cyy9h6R6-Ok">Kid President sure can get the world to dance</a>. </em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oYXcTAIdV08">Pokester</a> &ndash; <em>It&rsquo;s time for a social network that only lets you do one thing, poke someone. (Thanks, reader&nbsp;Joey for the heads up.)</em></p>
<p>Search for &ldquo;Google&rdquo; on <a href="http://bing.com/">Bing</a>. Try not to get confused.</p>
<p><a href="http://imgur.com/blog/2013/04/01/upload-via-snail-mail/">Upload images to Imgur by mail</a>!</p>
<p><strong>Update 1:37:32 PM EDT</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.virgin.com/richard-branson/blog/virgin-atlantic-launches-worlds-first-ever-glass-bottomed-plane">Virgin launces glass-bottomed plane.</a>&nbsp;&ndash; <em>As if air&nbsp;travel isn&rsquo;t scary enough.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://blog.wolframalpha.com/2013/04/01/introducing-the-wolframalpha-handwritten-knowledge-engine/">Hand written search results from Wolfram Alpha.</a> &ndash; <em>Basically, it&rsquo;s a bunch of nerds being forced to do your homework.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://scopemouthwash.com/bacon/">Scope Bacon</a> &ndash; <em>We&rsquo;re actually still not sure if this is a hoax or not. We are hoping that it is. We are really hoping that it is.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.kayak.com/dates">Kayak adds Dates.</a> &ndash; <em>Compare hundreds of dating sites at once!</em></p>
<p>Toshiba launches the <a href="http://us.toshiba.com/tubetop/">Toshiba TubeTop</a>, the world&rsquo;s first inflatable laptop. &ndash; <em>How many times have I wanted to surf the web while I was swimming in the pool? (That&rsquo;s not a joke. I can think of at least 5 times off the top of my head!)</em></p>
<p><a href="http://digg.com/">Digg</a>&nbsp;+ <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Konami_Code">Konami code</a>&nbsp;+ <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rickrolling">Rick Astley</a> = hilarious. &ndash; <em>Just go try it.</em></p>
<p><strong>Update&nbsp;2:54:11 PM&nbsp;EDT</strong></p>
<p>iFixit finds the least repairable tech product on the market: <a href="http://www.ifixit.com/Teardown/Orange+Teardown/13470/">the Orange</a>. After a complete teardown, they find it cannot be put back together at all. <a href="http://www.orange.com/en/home">Orange mobile</a> has not responded.</p>
<p>Nokia changes how you do TV dinners with a <a href="http://conversations.nokia.com/2013/04/01/nokia-turns-up-the-heat-with-its-first-microwave/">smart microwave</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.shophex.com/blog/news/apple-newton-cross-body-bag-from-hex-makes-beaming-and-faxing-documents-a-breeze/">HEX announces new cases for the Apple Newton.</a></p>
<p>Funny Or Die announces the <a href="http://www.funnyordie.com/videos/b668767cf6/darkwing-duck-the-movie-kickstarter-project">Darkwing Duck</a>, <a href="http://www.funnyordie.com/videos/314ecd2314/the-wings-serenity-movie-project">Wings</a>, <a href="http://www.funnyordie.com/videos/edd4c4228d/sliders-the-movie">Sliders</a>, <a href="http://www.funnyordie.com/videos/bc3ee45025/the-family-matters-movie">Family Matters</a> and <a href="http://www.funnyordie.com/videos/bd06aebe56/baby-sinclair-from-the-dinosaurs-one-man-show">Baby Sinclair from Dinosaurs</a> Kickstarter movie projects.</p>
<p>Two of our favorite news sources, NPR and WJCT, pulled off their own April Fools Pranks. NPR&rsquo;s Morning Edition aired this story, <a href="http://www.npr.org/2013/04/01/175886251/hootie-and-the-time-travelers-love-the-90s">Hootie And The Time Traveler Love The 90s</a>, and WJCT 89.9 FM aired <a href="http://news.wjct.org/post/amusement-park-proposed-shipyards-property">Amusement Park Proposed For Shipyards Property</a>.</p>
<p><strong>&nbsp;Have you found some that we haven&rsquo;t seen yet? Let us know in the comments down below.</strong></p>
<div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656494" data-app="share_buttons" data-title="April Fools' Internet Round Up 2013" data-link="/2013/04/april-fools-internet-round-up-2013/" data-summary=""></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas" data-app-id="14656501" data-app="recommendations" data-title="April Fools' Internet Round Up 2013" data-link="/2013/04/april-fools-internet-round-up-2013/" data-summary=""></div></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2013/04/april-fools-internet-round-up-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
