<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: The World&#8217;s Most Wanted: Osama bin Laden</title>
	<atom:link href="/2011/05/the-worlds-most-wanted-osama-bin-laden/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2011/05/the-worlds-most-wanted-osama-bin-laden/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 19:14:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: Missing May &#124; Deemable</title>
		<link>/2011/05/the-worlds-most-wanted-osama-bin-laden/#comment-340</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Missing May &#124; Deemable]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 22:34:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=2934#comment-340</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[...] The World&#8217;s Most Wanted: Osama bin Laden [...]]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] The World&#8217;s Most Wanted: Osama bin Laden [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Eric Imhof</title>
		<link>/2011/05/the-worlds-most-wanted-osama-bin-laden/#comment-303</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Imhof]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 13:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=2934#comment-303</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I didn&#039;t attack you personally. I asked questions about the premises of the article you wrote. 

And for the record, asking such questions, such as demanding proof for claims made by the government, is never, in my (anti-fascist) estimation, &quot;wasted energy.&quot;]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I didn&#8217;t attack you personally. I asked questions about the premises of the article you wrote. </p>
<p>And for the record, asking such questions, such as demanding proof for claims made by the government, is never, in my (anti-fascist) estimation, &#8220;wasted energy.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: David Ahn</title>
		<link>/2011/05/the-worlds-most-wanted-osama-bin-laden/#comment-302</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Ahn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 05:16:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=2934#comment-302</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am well aware of the many sides of the 9/11 story, I&#039;ve seen Zeitgeist, Fahrenheit 911, and many other documentaries supporting the 9/11 &quot;Truth&quot; movement. I am well aware of the business ties between the Bush and bin Laden families. I am well aware of the enormous amount of profit that the Carlyle Group and other American defense contractors have reaped from the ridiculous &quot;War on Terror&quot;. Also, I do not agree with any of our country&#039;s military policy concerning Iraq and Afghanistan, but I will be damned if I don&#039;t support the troops that serve our country. They didn&#039;t choose war, it was team Bush backed by corporate America who decided that fate without the approval of Congress.

The above article that I wrote was mostly about the use of technology, and if you had read it carefully, you will see that I referred to Osama bin Laden as the &quot;suspected&quot; mastermind behind the 9/11 attacks. As far as whether or not bin Laden was even killed, neither you nor I have the resources to verify this, but I will take their word for what it&#039;s worth until proven otherwise. In the end, Osama bin Laden has done more harm than good in this world and if he was indeed killed, then are we not better off because of it?

Instead of attacking me personally, maybe you could use that wasted energy and write an article to disprove what was written with concrete evidence. Until then, I will continue to report the news with what information I do have access to.

Thanks for reading though!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am well aware of the many sides of the 9/11 story, I&#8217;ve seen Zeitgeist, Fahrenheit 911, and many other documentaries supporting the 9/11 &#8220;Truth&#8221; movement. I am well aware of the business ties between the Bush and bin Laden families. I am well aware of the enormous amount of profit that the Carlyle Group and other American defense contractors have reaped from the ridiculous &#8220;War on Terror&#8221;. Also, I do not agree with any of our country&#8217;s military policy concerning Iraq and Afghanistan, but I will be damned if I don&#8217;t support the troops that serve our country. They didn&#8217;t choose war, it was team Bush backed by corporate America who decided that fate without the approval of Congress.</p>
<p>The above article that I wrote was mostly about the use of technology, and if you had read it carefully, you will see that I referred to Osama bin Laden as the &#8220;suspected&#8221; mastermind behind the 9/11 attacks. As far as whether or not bin Laden was even killed, neither you nor I have the resources to verify this, but I will take their word for what it&#8217;s worth until proven otherwise. In the end, Osama bin Laden has done more harm than good in this world and if he was indeed killed, then are we not better off because of it?</p>
<p>Instead of attacking me personally, maybe you could use that wasted energy and write an article to disprove what was written with concrete evidence. Until then, I will continue to report the news with what information I do have access to.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading though!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Eric Imhof</title>
		<link>/2011/05/the-worlds-most-wanted-osama-bin-laden/#comment-300</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Imhof]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 01:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=2934#comment-300</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You&#039;re taking the US government at its word? What evidence do you have that Bin Laden was killed in this manner, or killed by the Seals at all, at this time, or, for that matter, that he was even responsible for the attacks for which he is given credit? Why in the world would one ever trust the CIA? Have you been &quot;living under a rock&quot;?]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;re taking the US government at its word? What evidence do you have that Bin Laden was killed in this manner, or killed by the Seals at all, at this time, or, for that matter, that he was even responsible for the attacks for which he is given credit? Why in the world would one ever trust the CIA? Have you been &#8220;living under a rock&#8221;?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
