<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deemable Tech &#187; Brandon Jolly</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/brandon-jolly/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Tech news worth talking about and tech help worth listening to</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 19:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.28</generator>
	<item>
		<title>App Review: Angry Birds [KIDS]</title>
		<link>/2011/04/app-review-angry-birds-kids/</link>
		<comments>/2011/04/app-review-angry-birds-kids/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brandon Jolly]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deemable.com/?p=1897</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Angry Birds is a fun, puzzling game with a cute story line. Though it is a simple game, it has more than 9,500 reviews in the App Store with a four star rating or above. Angry birds has 240 levels <a href="/2011/04/app-review-angry-birds-kids/#more-'" class="more-link">more »</a><p class="more-link-p"><a class="more-link" href="/2011/04/app-review-angry-birds-kids/">Read more &#8594;</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><p>Angry Birds is a fun, puzzling game with a cute story line. Though it is a simple game, it has more than 9,500 reviews in the App Store with a four star rating or above. Angry birds has 240 levels and five episodes, plus the famous Golden Egg levels. In this game you use catapults to shoot birds of different shapes and colors at the green pigs. The green pigs have taken the birds&rsquo; eggs! this makes them mad&hellip; Angry Birds!  Pop the pigs and get your eggs back. Angry Birds is very addicting and is the best game of the year! One reviewer wrote, the &ldquo;Most Addicting best game ever!&rdquo; I can certainly tell why he said that, and quite frankly I agree. I bought Angry Birds over a year ago, and I still wake up and play it every morning.&nbsp;Other reviewers wrote, &ldquo;As if I&rsquo;m not on my phone enough, I just cant put it down!&rdquo;, and &ldquo;This game is the bomb, it&rsquo;s challenging and takes you to levels you never thought possible!&rdquo;. Angry Birds starts out as an easy-going game and slowly works its way up in difficulty, but if you get stuck on a level while playing on your iPhone or iPod, there is an in-app purchase called the mighty eagle. This purchase gives you the ability to &ldquo;fly&rdquo; through any difficulties you may be having in the game. When you use the eagle, you catapult a fish cookie and a eagle stops in and destroys all the pigs. If you use the eagle, it has a recharge time of one hour; you can advance one level per hour or more! This game is highly addictive, extremely fun, and may never get old! Angry Birds is available on Android, Web OS and iOS.</p></body></html>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2011/04/app-review-angry-birds-kids/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
